Departure
Eugeo.
Hey, Eugeo, get a hold of yourself!
When I count to three,
we're going to slam into those four.
And then knock over those fires.
Okay.
Don't lose that glowing grass.
Once the fires are out,
pick up a sword from the ground.
I'll take care of that huge one.
While I'm doing that,
keep the others away from me.
I've... never fought with a sword before!
It's the same as an ax. Come on!
One...
Two...
Three!
Eugeo!
Just drive back any that get too close!
Even if you say to...
I see. They don't like the light from this grass.
You think you can challenge
the great Ugachi the Lizard Killer?
You're wrong,
I'm not going to challenge you,
I'm going to beat you!
Sword skill...
Sharp Nail!
Kirito, are you all right?
This hurts too much.
In a virtual world,
no way would I feel... pain like this!
You little White Ium brat!
How dare you slice off my arm!
I won't forgive you!
I won't forgive you for this!
I could tear you apart, devour you,
and still never live this humiliation down!
I'm scared...
But I've got to go!
If I don't, it'll be just the same as when Alice...
Die!
Kirito!
This time...
...I'll be the one...
...to protect you!
Eugeo, run!
Eugeo!
Eugeo.
Stay with me! Eugeo!
W-We promised each other as kids, remember?
Me, you and Alice.
We were born on the same day,
so we're going to die on the same day.
This time...
...I'm keeping it.
That's right.
I couldn't keep that promise, either, but...
Die!
You lowly White Ium! I'll put you in your place!
I'm not an Ium!
I'm Kirito the Swordsman!
So what if you are?
He might also be an Artificial Fluctlight.
But...
...I absolutely can't lose here!
Sword Skill...
Sonic Leap!
I've taken the head of your boss.
If any of you still want to fight, come on!
Those who don't,
return to the land of darkness right now!
Hang in there!
Selka! Please wake up!
Kirito? Is that you?
Yeah. We came to rescue you. Are you okay?
Y-Yes. I'm fine.
Wh-What?
Eugeo's been badly hurt.
So...
Impossible.
A wound like this...
It's beyond my sacred arts abilities.
You have to try, even if it's impossible.
You're Alice's younger sister, aren't you?
I can never be like my sister.
The most I can heal are simple scratches.
You're the one Eugeo came to save, Selka!
Not Alice!
He came to save you!
Normal healing arts would take too long.
We'll have to try a dangerous high-level sacred art.
Kirito, I'm going to need your help.
All right. Say the word. I'll do anything.
Give me your left hand.
If I fail, we might both lose our lives as well.
I hope you're prepared.
If that happens,
make it so only my life is lost.
I'm ready anytime.
System Call.
Transfer Human Unit Durability.
Right Hand Self to Left.
So Selka's transferring my life and her own?
Kirito? Are you... still okay?
No problem.
More... Give more to Eugeo.
Kirito, Eugeo, I'll be waiting for you... always.
At the top of the Central Cathedral.
I'll always be waiting for you both.
You're...
K-Kirito?
Fifty!
How's your wound, Eugeo?
Yeah, after resting for an entire day,
it seems to be completely healed.
Hey, Eugeo, do you remember?
When we were inside that cave,
you said something strange.
You made it sound like
I'd always been friends with you and Alice.
I remember. But that can't be right
cause I only just met you.
For some reason,
I felt so sure about it in that moment.
That me, you and Alice...
...were born in this village,
and grew up together.
I think we were together
the day Alice was taken away, too.
I see.
By the way, when Selka used that sacred art,
did you hear someone's voice?
No. I was completely unconscious.
Did you hear something?
No, it was just my imagination.
Forget I asked.
Now then, let's get to work.
Here. Do your best!
I'm going to use this.
H-Hey, Kirito!
You can use that sword?
Well, just watch.
Because of that goblin battle the other day,
my Object Control Authority
has exceeded this sword's number.
If so...
See?
I bet you can swing it too, Eugeo.
Kirito, can you...
can you teach me to use a sword?
I want to bring Alice back.
Eugeo.
Because of me,
Alice and her family have suffered.
For the past six years,
I've never, ever stopped regretting it.
Wondering why I couldn't do anything
to save Alice?
I... want to become strong!
So I'll never make the same mistake again!
So that I can regain what I've lost.
That's why...
I want to become a swordsman!
All right. I'll teach you.
Everything that I know.
But the training's going to be tough.
That's what I was hoping for.
By the way,
what style is your sword technique?
My technique...
...is the Aincrad Style.
All right. Go ahead, Eugeo.
- H-Hey! Look!
- What is that?
It's like a dream.
I never thought I'd see this day.
I didn't believe in destiny at all.
But...
Kirito, I've been waiting in this forest
for the past six years for you to come.
Yeah. I'm sure...
...that I woke up in this forest
so I could meet you, Eugeo.
What, you're alone?
Yeah, Eugeo was summoned by the village elder
and went off somewhere.
I see.
But chopping down the demon tree
is amazing, huh?
I guess it was the fruit of Eugeo's labor!
I've got to study harder, too,
so I can perfect my sacred arts skills as a Sister!
Not that I can ever be like my sister...
Actually, I didn't go into that cave
to imitate my sister.
I just wanted to be even a little bit closer to her...
To go as far as I could.
To keep going until I couldn't go any further.
That's where I wanted to make sure
there was no way I could ever take her place.
No, you're amazing.
You went so far into that dark cave.
You did something only you could do.
Something only I could do?
You're not Alice's replacement.
I'm sure there's a talent that's unique to you.
So just take your time and develop it.
Okay.
Everyone! Could I have your attention?
The greatest wish of Rulid's founding ancestors
has been fulfilled at last!
The demon tree has been felled!
A triumph achieved by the son of Orick, Eugeo!
According to tradition, having completed his task,
Eugeo is given the right to choose his next Calling!
All right. Go ahead
and choose whatever path you wish
I...
I will become a swordsman!
I'm going to hone my skills...
...and head to the central city one day!
Eugeo. Surely you're not...
No. I won't ask you why.
After all, it's your right
to choose your next Calling.
As the elder of Rulid, I hereby approve
Eugeo's new Calling to be a swordsman!
Selka.
Eugeo.
Selka, there's something I want to tell you.
Wh-What?
I'm going to the central city
and bring Alice back.
My sister...
It's something I've been thinking about
for the last six years.
But I had no idea how to go about it.
But then I met Kirito,
and I finally have hope of bringing her back.
If Kirito's with me,
I feel like I can accomplish anything.
I know you and your family have suffered,
and I'm so sorry.
But I'll definitely bring Alice back.
So I want you to believe in me, and wait.
That's something only you can do, right?
Yeah.
I'll wait. So please...
...make sure all three of you come back!
Right! I promise!
All three of us will definitely come back!
It's a promise.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Kirito.
Yo.
All right, let's go.
Okay.
I wonder what kind of place the central city is?
No idea.
Well, it's got to be bigger than Rulid, right?
That's probably true.
The wind feels a little damp.
We should probably get going now.
Kirito?
R-Right.
All right, let's go, Kirito.
Sure!
Next time: Ocean Turtle.