North Centoria
Swordcraft Academy
March 1, 380 in the time
of the realm of humanity
Kirito?
Kirito!
Five more minutes.
Kirito! I know it's our day of rest,
but you sleep too much!
Morning, Eugeo.
Morning!
It's sunny out today,
so why don't we go into town?
Swordcraft Academy
North Centoria
District Six
March 1, 380 in the time
of the realm of humanity
Thanks a lot!
Delicious!
That's unseemly, Kirito.
Well, you can't beat fresh out of the oven.
You have to eat it right away.
Some things never change, huh, Kirito?
Guess not!
I can't believe how time flies.
It's already been two years
since we left Rulid, huh?
Yeah.
And so much happened in that time, huh?
Two years ago...
...we arrived in Zakkaria...
...and while living and working on a farm,
we honed our swordsmanship skills.
We won the Swordfighting Tournament,
and joined the Zakkaria garrison.
Who would've thought
that after reaching the capital,
we'd actually get into the Swordcraft Academy?
Sometimes I think I'm dreaming.
Come on now.
It's already been a year
since we moved into the dorm.
Shouldn't you be used to everything by now?
I guess so.
Kirito?
Liena-senpai!
What a coincidence.
- Good morning!
Good morning. And you're... Eugeo, wasn't it?
Yes!
Don't be so nervous.
What brings you here today, Liena-senpai?
I went home,
but they asked me to pick up some things.
W-Would you like us to help you?
You'd help me?
But you're Golgorosso Balto's page, aren't you?
I'm sorry, I was out of line. Forgive me!
Not to mention...
If anything,
shouldn't my own page have offered first?
Well...
Really!
I appreciate the offer.
But I won't be making any big purchases,
so I'll be fine.
This is your day of rest, after all.
It's all right to forget about work.
Although that work
will be coming to an end soon.
Since we'll be graduating.
I wish I could've learned more from you.
As your mentor,
no words could make me feel more blessed.
I look forward to tomorrow as well!
I look forward to it, too!
Right.
Why are you so rattled?
Well, Sortiliena-senpai is so beautiful
and has such a presence, you know?
That's true.
I'm a nervous wreck
whenever we spar during training.
Golgorosso-senpai has a lot of drive, too.
I still haven't won a single point
off Golgorosso-senpai yet.
Me neither.
That power of Liena-senpai's...
To think that she's second seat in her class.
Makes you wonder just how strong
First-Seat Volo-senpai is.
Who knows?
I can't imagine beating those upperclassmen.
Can't imagine it, huh?
Swordcraft Academy
Primary Trainee's Dorm
March 1, 380 in the time
of the realm of humanity
Good night, Kirito.
Yeah, good night!
After spending two years here,
I've learned the mechanisms of this world
can't be measured
in simple numerical terms alone.
The only three things visible on your status
are your life, your Object Control Authority,
and your System Control Authority.
If your Object Control Authority is low,
it hampers your ability
to even hold up a higher-class weapon.
Conversely, if your stats far surpass that class,
it feels ridiculously light.
Your System Control Authority
is related to the sacred arts.
If you're low-level, you can only use simple spells,
But in the same way, you can use
sophisticated spells once you level up.
That part is no different than any other game.
Most importantly, and it's a system
that didn't exist in SAO or ALO,
is that a mental image
can affect these parameters.
If you have the confidence, the ego to win,
your individual power is amplified many times over.
That's what makes Liena-senpai so powerful.
She's received top-notch training
in swordsmanship since she was a child.
The confidence that she won't lose.
In other words, if you can imagine yourself
to be more powerful than anyone,
that gives you the potential
to rewrite the laws of the world.
Elite Disciples' Dorm
Training Hall
March 7, 380 in the time
of the realm of humanity
As expected of you, Liena-senpai.
You've made some progress yourself, Kirito.
No, I still have a long way to go.
Don't be so modest.
I know you still have some latent power
that you're hiding from me.
When I chose you as my page a year ago,
it was because I sensed a similarity
in our sword styles.
But in the last year, it's become clear
how unrefined my sword skills are.
You're really powerful, Liena-senpai.
In the end, I wasn't able
to beat you once during training.
Nor have I managed to defeat him
in the last two years.
Are you talking about
First-Seat Volo Levantein?
Yes.
To be honest,
whenever I face Volo, I can feel myself falter.
No matter how hard I train,
I just can't convince myself
that I can withstand his powerful sword.
Senpai...
However.
That's not why you can't defeat me.
There's more to the Aincrad Style
that you haven't shown me, isn't there?
I want to know everything about you as a swordsman
before I graduate the day after tomorrow.
This wooden sword can't...
I understand. But forgive me.
Could you wait for just one more day?
I promise to show you tomorrow.
The greatest skill I can wield.
Tomorrow's a day of rest.
Training is forbidden, remember?
I-It won't be training, though.
U-Um... It's your graduation gift!
I'm sure it's okay to give someone
a present on a day of rest, right?
I've never heard of
giving someone a sword skill as a gift.
But I'll gratefully accept it.
Right! It'll be my pleasure.
Primary Trainee Kirito has returned!
You've arrived 38 minutes after curfew.
My mentor, Elite Disciple Sortiliena Serlut,
told me to extend my training session.
It's a page's duty to receive the instruction
of a disciple, so very well.
But you seem to view this
as permission to break curfew, do you not?
N-Not at all, Ms. Azurica!
My only goal is to hone my sword skills
as much as I can.
Breaking curfew is an unintended result.
Mealtime is in 17 minutes.
Make sure you're not late for that.
You're late, Kirito!
Sorry! Liena-senpai gave me
a special training session.
Looks good!
I can't tell you how envious I am, Lord Raios.
After we toiled so hard to clean this cafeteria,
they get to waltz in and merely eat.
No, seriously, I envy them!
Hey, don't be like that, Humbert.
I'm sure that even those page trainees
have struggles of their own we can't even fathom.
I suppose you have a point.
The pages are at their mentors' beck and call.
I hear that they can't say no to anything.
They're an eccentric bunch
that cherry-picks commoners to be their pages.
They must issue the most outlandish orders!
Don't pay any attention to them, Kirito.
By the way, Kirito, how's your garden doing?
Better and better each day!
It should be ready in time for graduation.
Oh, yeah? I'm looking forward to it!
They're really thriving, huh?
They're already starting to bud.
Well, I did mess up three times to get to this point.
I really hope they'll bloom this time.
Giving Liena-senpai flowers you raised yourself
as a graduation gift...
It's surprising.
I know.
Still, even after spending two years together,
I had no idea you enjoyed this kind of thing.
Yeah. That makes two of us.
You never know, this could be a sign
that your memories are coming back.
Like, maybe you used to grow flowers
before you showed up in Rulid Village?
Or maybe that was your Calling?
Y-Yeah, could be! I'm going to get some water.
Hey, Kirito.
What will you do
if you do regain your memories?
What will I do?
You're training to become an Integrity Knight
to keep me company, aren't you?
In my quest to find Alice,
who was taken away by the Axiom Church.
But when you get your memories back,
you'll go home...
Even if I do get my memories back,
I'm not going home.
I was a swordsman.
That's the one thing I'm certain of.
And what swordsman wouldn't strive
to become an Integrity Knight?
I'm... a weak person.
If I hadn't met you, I'd probably still be
swinging that axe every day, even now.
Using my Calling as an excuse
to never try to leave the village.
The only reason I got into this academy
was because you led the way.
Even so...
When you said you weren't going home
even if you got your memories back...
it filled me with such relief.
Listen. Let me say that I couldn't have
made it to the capital on my own, either.
I didn't know how to get here,
and my memory's unreliable.
And what's more, I didn't any money.
The reason you and I have a place at this academy
is because we were together.
And it will stay that way.
We've got to stick together.
We can wait to struggle on our own
after we're Integrity Knights, right?
That's right.
And to do that, first we have to place in the top 12
on the Advancement Exam, huh?
Well, my sacred arts skills
are a little shaky, you know?
Help me with that
when we get back to our room.
Okay. If you want, I can spend
our day of rest tomorrow helping you.
Uh, tomorrow's not good.
Oh, that's right!
Right. It's the day it's going to be ready.
That's something to look forward to!
I mean, I've waited a whole year!
I can't wait to use it!
March 8 in the time of the realm of humanity
North Centoria District Seven,
in front of Sadore's Metalworking Shop
Look at this!
These black-brick grindstones
are supposed to last three years,
but that's six demolished in one year!
I'm really sorry.
You can only shave a sliver off that branch,
no matter how hard you try!
How much time do you think I spent
on this one sword?
Gigas Cedar Forest
March 31, 378 in the time
of the realm of humanity
This one branch of the Gigas Cedar is the part
that absorbed the most of Solus' blessings.
Take that with you.
When you get to the capital,
you should leave this branch
with a craftsman by the name of Sadore.
I'm sure he'll fashion a wonderful sword for you.
In the first place,
my Calling is that of a metalsmith, so...
S-So... is the sword done?
Young man.
We haven't discussed payment yet, have we?
Don't worry, Kirito.
Just in case, I brought all my money.
I might consider letting you have it free of charge.
However! That's only if
you can swing this monster, all right?
The second I was done forging this thing
into a sword, it actually got heavier.
A monster, is it?
What's wrong, Kirito?
No, it's nothing.
That was amazing, Kirito!
So a trainee from the academy
is able to swing it, huh?
It's a fine sword.
You bet it is!
And like I promised,
that sword is yours.
Thank you very much!
Okay, I'm going to take some practice swings.
Don't be late for dinner, all right?
Right!
For some reason,
sword skills exist in this world, too.
I could only manage two-hit strikes
with my wooden practice sword.
But if I use this sword...
Looks like I'll be able
to keep my promise to Liena-senpai.
Come to think of it, I couldn't unleash the five-hit strike,
even with the Blue Rose Sword,
but I wonder if this one can?
I guess it's no use.
First-Seat Levantein?
Please forgive me, Elite Disciple Levantein!
I respectfully apologize for my rudeness!
You're Elite Disciple Serlut's page, right?
Yes. I'm Primary Trainee Kirito.
I see.
Training with the sword is forbidden
on days of rest.
N-No, First Seat! This isn't training.
Right. I was just trying out my new sword.
I just couldn't wait until tomorrow.
You seemed to be quite fired up
for someone taking test swings.
But you're not unlike myself.
Trying every which way to contrive a reason
for wielding your sword, even on a day of rest.
I mean that you're not the only one.
Then...
Yes. I'll overlook the fact
that you were swinging your sword on a day of rest.
I am grateful for your generosity.
It's too soon to thank me, Trainee Kirito.
Y-Yes?
I never said that I'd forgive you for this.
Swordcraft Academy
Main Training Hall
How did word spread so fast?
Kirito!
What did you do?
Well...
No... the fact that you didn't get into any trouble
for a year is a miracle in itself.
As expected of my partner!
Lord Levantein! What's the meaning of this?
Your page was a bit disrespectful to me.
Since I didn't feel that
it warranted a serious punishment,
I intend to settle things
by sparring with real swords.
What did you say?
I'm sorry for worrying you, Senpai.
I'll be fine!
In fact, I'm honored to get the chance
to spar with the first seat.
Kirito... what are the rules of your duel?
Since we're using real swords,
wouldn't that be stop-short?
Oh, I forgot something.
I don't do stop-short fights.
All of my personal matches end
when one side takes the first point.
Kirito has never fought a match with real swords!
Yes. Of course, this match can't happen
without both our consent.
If you refuse, we'll have no choice
but to go with stop-short.
I'm going to let you choose, Trainee Kirito.
Don't do it, Kirito. Volo's powerful.
It's too dangerous.
I'll leave the method up to you, Lord Levantein.
After all, I'm the one being punished.
Next time: Swordsman's Pride.