Kirito.
Liena-senpai.
Kirito, I believe in your strength.
Since I believe in your strength,
I'll teach you something.
There's a family rule
hidden within Volo's Levantein family.
"Soak this sword in the blood of the mighty."
"Doing so will make their power your own."
Did you say blood?
Yes. Volo's been engaging in these one-point duels
with real swords even before he started here.
Those experiences allow him to produce
his mighty sword.
I see. The power of his imagination, huh?
"You become stronger by absorbing
the blood of powerful enemies."
This Levantein family rule
is imbuing Volo's sword with power.
He's planning to convert your sword strength
into blood, absorb it, and feed on it.
However, let me say it again. I believe in you.
You're not the kind of swordsman
who'd fall so easily to that man.
You haven't forgotten
what you promised me yesterday, have you?
Promise...
That's right.
I promised to show you everything I have.
Then show it to me now, Kirito!
Right. I'll fulfill my promise to you now.
Are you ready yet, Trainee Kirito?
Yes.
Elite Disciple Serlut,
will you serve as our witness?
Very well.
The one-point match between Elite Disciple Levantein
and Novice Trainee Kirito will now begin.
As has been mutually agreed,
both will use real swords.
Real swords?
Swordsman's Pride
Well, well! Is it customary to dye swords black
in the hinterlands, Lord Raios?
Don't be like that, Humbert.
Those pages must be too busy
to polish their swords, that's all.
The High-Norkian Style,
Heavenly Mountain-Splitting Wave stance.
So he's starting off with his secret skill?
That's the two-handed,
heavy one-hit thrust skill, Avalanche.
And not just any Avalanche, either.
His power of imagination
should be amplifying its force.
But I can't afford to dodge it.
If I'm going to keep my promise to Liena-senpai,
I have to block his strike!
I'll counter with a greater amount of strikes
with a four-hit strike, Vertical Square!
He stopped it!
If I can endure this one,
I’ll still have my fourth hit!
Is this what Volo's shouldering?
The Levantein family's...
Is this the source of his power,
the strength of his imagination?
But I also...
I also...
I also can't afford to lose here!
Did his sword just grow?
That's enough!
M-Ms. Azurica?
We have no choice
but to obey any ruling of hers.
Uh... why is that?
Because seven years ago,
during the Four Empire Unification Tournament,
she was the first swordsman
to represent the North's Norlangarth Empire.
The punishment for Trainee Kirito
is hereby concluded!
From now on, be careful
not to fling mud onto anyone.
It went back to its normal size.
I thought you had gotten slashed.
Yes. I thought that, too.
And yet you refused to surrender.
You hopeless idiot.
That was a magnificent, spectacular fight, Kirito.
I'm truly grateful.
It's too bad that I couldn't have it all to myself,
but as you promised, you showed me a fight
with you using all of your strength.
Thank you.
O-Oh, but it was a draw.
Achieving a draw against Levantein
is not enough for you?
N-No, that's not what I meant.
It's no longer a matter of winning or losing.
Seeing you in battle taught me something...
something extremely important.
Why don't we have
a light celebration in my room?
Let's invite Eugeo
and Lord Golgorossa, too, shall we?
Right!
It struck me once again today
as I was watching your match.
Your Aincrad Style has endless potential.
I used to see my own Serlut Style
as a practical sword skill, but it's still too rigid.
You're not going there again, are you?
I've never once beaten you, Senpai.
The diversity of attacks in the Serlut Style
is nothing more than stunning.
Actually, Kirito...
Because a distant ancestor of the Serlut family
displeased the emperor,
we are forbidden from passing down
our official sword skill, the High-Norkian Style.
So we had no choice but to hone our actual
combat skills, rather, our irregular sword skills.
That's the Serlut Style.
It's not that I resent it.
On the contrary,
I've always been proud of our style.
But somewhere in my mind,
I might have had some doubts.
For two years,
I think the reason I couldn't defeat Volo
is because he passes down the High-Norkian Style.
Senpai...
But you're different.
Despite also being a wielder of a unique style,
you don't feel inferior compared
to those trained in the traditional styles.
Watching you closely for a year,
and seeing you fight against Volo today...
I think I finally understand the reason.
Being the successor to the Serlut Style
fills me with great pride and also joy.
As well as becoming your mentor, too.
Liena-senpai, I'm counting on you to defeat
First-Seat Volo in your final ranking exam match.
Right!
Well, well! Perfect timing.
I was just about to go look for you.
What do you want?
Needless to say, I wanted to compliment you
on your dazzling combat style.
Well, those stunt-oriented sword skills of yours
must've unnerved even the first seat,
don't you agree?
Are you picking a fight with me?
Of course not!
A high-ranking nobleman
would never pick anything with a commoner.
Even if we do dole out charity!
In honor of your stunt,
no, your valiant battle, I extend you this gift.
Please accept it.
Now then, with that, we shall excuse ourselves.
Good night, Sir Kirito.
Don't let it get to your head!
At first, it was just an experiment.
A flower that never blooms
in the Northern Empire, the zephilia.
Liena-senpai said they were her favorite flower.
I wanted to see if I could make them bloom
using the power of my imagination.
But along the way,
I'd started identifying with these flowers
that are fighting so hard to bloom in foreign soil.
Cut off from the real world,
from those I cared for, from those I loved...
I'd been trying to share
my loneliness and pain with these flowers
of not knowing when I would ever
be reunited with them.
I'm sorry.
Believe in them.
In the strength of these flowers
that have grown this much in foreign soil.
Who're you?
As well as your own strength,
who has nurtured them until now.
But they're all dead now.
It'll be all right.
The roots in the soil are still trying to live.
Not to mention, you sense it, don't you?
The numerous sacred flowers in these planters
want to save their tiny friends.
Impossible.
I can't cast advanced sacred arts like that.
All spells are about "Meaning."
They're no more than tools for guiding
and arranging what you call "images."
Now, feel it.
The flowers' prayers.
The laws of the world.
The intent that emerges from the heart.
"Meaning."
Please, can you share
just a little bit of your power, your life?
Imagine the flowers' life force flowing into
the zephilia's roots, using me as their catalyst.
That voice just now...
Thank you.
Swordcraft Academy
Main Training Hall
March 31, 380 in the time
of the realm of humanity
SERLUT
LEVANTEIN
That's the match!
And so, Liena-senpai
graduated the North Centoria Swordcraft Academy
as its top-ranked student.
And after our Advancement Exam,
Eugeo and I were ranked seat five and six,
and were promoted to Elite Disciples.
Swordcraft Academy
Elite Disciple Dorms
April 10, 380 in the time
of the realm of humanity
Now reporting to Elite Disciple Eugeo!
I have completed today's cleaning!
Good job, Tiese.
You're free to go back to your dorm room now.
And, um...
Sorry, Ronie.
I've told him numerous times to be back
before you're done cleaning the room.
Oh, n-no! My duty as a page only ends
when I've made my report!
I can put in a word for you, too, so you could
get your mentor changed to someone else.
If you serve under him,
it's definitely going to be a long year for you.
O-Oh, not at all!
Hey, hey!
What are you talking about
when I'm not around?
Elite Disciple Kirito, allow me to report!
Today's cleaning
has been completed without issues.
Okay, good job.
Listen, Kirito.
These two are much busier than you, so try
to get back here before they're done cleaning.
Also, why do you have to come through
the window, anyway?
Going through this window is the shortest route
when you're coming from East Third Street.
Ronie and Tiese, if you remember that,
it'll come in handy someday.
Y-Yes!
Don't teach them stuff
they don't need to know.
If you went to East Third Street,
that bag must be from...
If you want some, then just say so, Eugeo.
Here. Have these with your roommates
when you get back to your dorm.
Th-Thank you very much, Elite Disciple!
To ensure the life of the goods won't decrease,
we will now return to our dorm at top speed!
See you tomorrow!
I knew it! These are honey pies
from the Prancing Deer Cafe!
Let's hurry back before they get cold!
- Yeah!
- Let's go!
What is it?
Oh, it's nothing, really.
I was just wondering if perhaps
Elite Disciple Kirito has forgotten why we're here?
Like I'd forget.
We've finally made it this far.
Yeah.
It won't be long now, huh?
Next time: Nobleman's Responsibilities.