March 23, 380 in the time
of the realm of humanity
Isn't that the four-thirty bell?
You're right. Is it that late already?
Ronie and Tiese are late.
They've never been late to clean before,
have they?
I have a bad feeling about this.
I'll go check the primary trainees' dorm.
They might be on their way here,
so you stay and wait for them.
Hey, Kirito, you should use the front—
Jeez, he's always in such a rush.
Thank goodness! We were worr—
Um... are you Elite Disciple Eugeo?
Yes. And you are?
I-I'm Primary Trainee Frenica Cesky.
I-I apologize for coming to see you
without an appointment.
But I just don't know what to do!
You're... Frenica?
Um, I know you've gone out of your way
in regard to my issue with Lord Humbert Zizek.
I thank you from the bottom of my heart.
However, tonight,
Lord Zizek has ordered me to... um...
He's ordered me to perform a service
that's difficult to explain.
I-If he continues to give me these kinds of orders,
I-I'd rather leave the academy!
I confided in Tiese and Ronie about this.
When they heard this, they said they'd go
plead with him to spare me, and left the dorm.
I've been waiting,
but they still haven't returned.
What?
You wait here.
So that was their goal all along?
Not to target me, but Tiese and Ronie!
Taboo Index
Please come in.
We just opened a 50-year-old bottle
from the western empire, so why not join us?
It's not something a commoner
would ever get to taste.
No, that's fine.
Actually, Elite Disciple Zizek,
I wanted to ask if my page,
Primary Trainee Tiese Schtrinen,
and Disciple Kirito's page, Primary Trainee
Ronie Arabel, happened to visit your room?
So those two are yours and Sir Kirito's pages?
To suddenly visit the first-seat elite disciple,
who stands at the pinnacle of the student body,
as well as the second-seat elite disciple,
they're certainly brave for primary trainees!
No wonder they're your pages.
That said, they do need to be careful.
Assertiveness can sometimes be taken
as rudeness or disrespect.
Wouldn't you agree, Disciple Eugeo?
I will hear your valued opinion another time.
Where are Tiese and Ronie right now?
What's this?
Wh...
What's the meaning of this, Lord Raios?
These measures were unavoidable, Sir Eugeo.
Since Primary Trainees Schtrinen and Arabel
disrespected us to an outrageous degree.
Disrespected how?
These two lesser noble girls had the gall
to accuse me, a fourth-rank nobleman,
of needlessly abusing my own page
and satisfying my own lust, offending me greatly.
After all I've done as the second-seat elite disciple
to guide Frenica down the proper path!
And that's not all, Sir Eugeo.
They made the absurd claim that
as Humbert's roommate, I was just as accountable.
I mean, the daughter of a mere sixth-rank noble
asking me, the eldest son of a third-rank noble,
"Have you no pride as a noble?"
To have said such a thing...
Still, Lord Raios, even if everything happened
the way you described,
binding them with ropes
and locking them in your bedroom
is surely a flagrant deviation
from the disciple punishment authority!
Disciple punishment authority?
Have you forgotten what the academy rules say?
That "regarding all punishment,
higher law take precedence!"
Higher law, as in the Taboo Index,
not to mention the Basic Imperial Law.
In other words, as a third-rank noble's eldest son,
what I can exercise on those sixth-rank noble girls
isn't the disciple punishment authority,
but the nobles' judicial authority...
...as is my right!
Hold still. I'm going to discipline you now.
Stop it!
Don't move, commoner!
This is a lawful judgment by a noble according
to the Basic Imperial Law and the Taboo Index.
And to obstruct such a judgment
is a serious criminal act.
If you take even one step closer,
you'll become a criminal who has broken the law.
That's...
My legs!
No! No!
Senpai! Senpai!
After all, there are things you shouldn't do,
even if it's not forbidden by law.
On the other hand,
there might be things you should do,
even if they're forbidden by law.
N-No! No!
No! Help me! Help me, Eugeo-senpai!
Eugeo-senpai!
Tiese and Ronie worked up the courage
to help their friend,
only to be punished by such a cruel law.
A law that can't deter Raios and Humbert,
who ensnared them and are now about to defile them.
If upholding such a law is the "right" thing to do...
I...
What's... this?
No, this is the same as that time.
Unforgivable. It's absolutely...
...unforgivable!
No! No! Senpai!
A-Arm... My arm is... bleeding!
So much blood! My life is decreasing!
Lord Raios, a sacred arts spell...
No, a normal spell won't heal this in time!
Your life! Please share some of your life!
Magnificent! I've never seen
anyone commit such a crime before.
Though the nobles' judicial authority generally
only applies to lesser nobles and tenant commoners,
exceptions can be made
for heinous criminals who've broken a Taboo!
I've never cut off someone's head
with my sword before.
This will make me even more powerful!
Disciple Eugeo...
No, heinous criminal Eugeo!
I, Raios Antinous, a third-rank nobleman's heir,
in accordance with the nobles' judicial authority,
shall now execute you!
Kirito.
Put away your sword, Raios!
I won't let you hurt Eugeo!
So you finally showed up, Disciple Kirito?
However, you're a bit too late.
That country bumpkin there is a heinous criminal
who violated the Taboo Index!
No, you stand back and watch.
Just like those flowers that day,
witness this criminal's head being cut off!
I don't care about your taboos and noble rights!
Eugeo's my friend.
And you...
are scum lower than the goblins
from the land of darkness!
To think that two country bumpkins
would commit such grave crimes.
This means I can get rid of you both
at the same time.
What a wonderful day!
Surely this is the guidance of Stacia!
It's fine.
My secret skill will demolish that piece of junk!
Come on then, Raios!
How's that? How's that?
As if I, Raios Antinous, would fail to keep up
with a mere commoner like you!
Kirito.
Arms! My arms are...
bleeding... They're bleeding!
Humbert!
Bleeding... Stop my bleeding!
Untie your rope, and bind my arms instead!
No!
U-Untying it will reduce my life!
That order is a violation of the Taboo Index!
Taboo? But...
My blood is... Humbert!
You... Taboo...
But... My life will...
Taboo... Life... Blood! Taboo!
Life... Blood... Taboo...
Life... Taboo... Life... Taboo...
Life...
Use this to stop the bleeding.
Life... Taboo... Life... Taboo...
What was that?
Did something happen to the Fluctlight?
Lord Raios is...
He's... He's... You... You...
Murderer! Monster!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Eugeo-senpai!
It's... It's all my fault!
No, it's not. You're not to blame.
I... It's because I didn't think it through.
You're not responsible.
B-But...
But...
It's all right. After all, you and Ronie are safe.
I'm the one who should apologize.
Sorry. For subjecting you to such a horror.
I've seen this before.
Somewhere, long ago, I saw this before.
Don't let Tiese and Ronie hear this!
Singular unit detected.
Tracing ID.
Coordinates fixed.
Report complete.
Murderer! Monster!
Now I'm just like those goblins.
You're a human, Eugeo. Just like me.
Every time you make a mistake,
you continue to struggle to find its meaning.
You're a human.
Kirito.
Come out.
Come closer.
System Call. Generate Luminous Element.
Reconstruct Lost Organ.
Try to open your eye.
Yes.
Thank you very much, Ms. Azurica!
No, actually, Disciple Eugeo and Disciple Kirito,
I need to hand you over to your escort.
Before that, I'll say only this.
Disciple Eugeo.
You've broken a seal I was never able to break.
Therefore, you should be able to go
where I was never able to go.
Believe in that sword, and in your friend.
Disciple Kirito.
I was never able to get to know
who you really are.
Nevertheless, when you reach that tower,
something will definitely happen.
I'll be here, praying that you'll find the light.
Forever.
I've seen this combination
of blue and gold before somewhere.
I am the overseer of the capital city of Centoria,
an Integrity Knight of the Axiom Church...
Alice Synthesis Thirty.
Next time: Central Cathedral.