Why?
Why did you lose to the Synthesis Ritual?
Wasn't the reason
you trained to be a swordsman
and left Rulid Village
to head for the capital city, Centoria,
to bring back your cherished childhood friend, Alice?
The 32nd Knight
Eugeo.
You and I have never fought seriously before,
have we?
I've thought about it a lot.
Which one of us would win
if we seriously crossed swords?
To be honest,
I always thought you'd surpass me one day.
I've never shown you this skill before!
Burst Element.
Is that person really your partner, Eugeo?
What do you mean?
You're the one who said
that Eugeo had already been synthesized!
That's true, but...
I'm not sure how to say this.
For someone who just
became an Integrity Knight,
he seems too accustomed to battle.
For instance,
the Incarnate Arms skill he used earlier,
as well as that Aerial Element skill just now,
makes it hard to believe he's a novice.
Should I fight him next?
I'll do it.
I'm counting on you, partner.
I promise to give you a name
when this fight is over.
So lend me your strength!
Let's go, Eugeo!
Does the skill you just used have a name?
Baltio style. Storm Wave.
Baltio style? Golgorosso-senpai's sword style.
Eugeo, do you...
do you remember who taught you that sword skill?
I don't know or care.
She's the only one I need to know.
It's for her sake that I take up my sword,
and I live in order to eliminate her enemies.
There's no doubt.
Just like Eldrie and Alice, now Eugeo has...
The Piety Module is inserted in a way
that blocks links to memories.
This seals away the past
of the person becoming an Integrity Knight,
while simultaneously forcing absolute fealty
to the Axiom Church and the pontifex.
What kind of memories originally existed
where the module's embedded?
If I can figure that out...
No, words won't be enough
to break Administrator's art!
What I infuse my sword with
will reach his soul.
That's what I'm going to believe!
Eugeo!
Remember!
There are people who are precious to you!
Selka, who's waiting back in Rulid Village
for our return!
Golgorosso-senpai and Liena-senpai,
who instructed us at Swordcraft Academy!
Tiese and Ronie, who worried about us
right up till the moment we said goodbye!
And above all...
wasn't your wish
to go back to Rulid with Alice?
You have to remember, Eugeo!
Eugeo.
Alice.
Did you remember, Eugeo?
Eu... geo...
Kirito!
Enhance Armament.
Eugeo.
Why?
Have you dealt with those rebels,
Number Thirty-two?
I've sealed the two rebels in ice,
Your Eminence, Prime Senator.
That's fine, but...
you did finish them off properly, didn't you?
No, I did not finish them off, Prime Senator.
Since the pontifex's order was to stop the rebels.
That won't do! That just won't do!
When you speak to me, remember to call me,
"Your Eminence, Prime Senator."
"Your Eminence," got that? "Your Eminence"!
The next time you forget the "Your Eminence,"
you'll be turned into a horse as punishment!
You'll carry me on your back,
and while you're on all fours, I'll go "hi-yo"!
Now then, I think I'll go
carry out Her Eminence's orders.
Lady Pontifex.
Welcome back, Eugeo.
You've taken care of your errand.
Yes.
Well done! In that case,
I should give you a reward.
Please climb onto the bed.
All right, Eugeo, as promised,
let me give you what you desire.
Love that's meant only for you.
Yes.
But first, let me heal that wound for you.
Also,
let me have another good look at your face.
Since there was a convenient hole
in your memory,
I inserted the module there,
but perhaps I shouldn't have been lazy.
Let's redo your synthesis.
You can have your reward after that,
all right, Eugeo?
Just lie still.
This is an improved module
I had just completed.
Synthesizing you with it allows you
to use the power of "Meaning" immediately.
Will you show me your memories again?
This time, I'll insert it into the location
of what you hold most dear.
I've made it so you can move your mouth.
Now, chant the command I taught you earlier.
Did you forget it?
What am I going to do with you?
It's "Remove Core Protection."
M...
Mo...
Mo... ve!
You...
For you to have regained your senses...
You certainly fooled me.
Not to mention, that prop is the handiwork
of that little brat from the Library, no?
But that's too bad.
No metal object of any kind
can damage my skin now.
You poor child.
Just when I'd promised you
that if you gave all of yourself to me,
I'd love you back the same amount.
That eternal love you've been seeking all your life,
that eternal control...
you were so close to obtaining it!
Eternal... love?
Eternal... control.
That's right, Eugeo.
If you entrust everything to me,
the thirst that's been making you suffer
will be quenched instantly.
All the fears and worries you've been carrying
will be erased.
This is your last chance, Eugeo.
Use the sword at your waist
to shatter that toy.
Do that, and I shall forgive your heinous crime
with my tremendous amount of love.
To love is to control, and to be controlled.
You're the pitiful one,
for having no other way to say it!
I'm sure you were once the same way.
Starved for love and sought it out,
but you were never given any.
Love isn't about control.
Nor is it something you can gain as a reward
or in a transaction.
The same way you water flowers,
you give it continuously.
I'm sure that that's what love is!
How disappointing.
I was going to forgive a sinful young boy
for rebelling against the Axiom Church
and try to save his soul,
but this is how you speak to me?
Maybe it would be a waste
to kill you and turned you into a jewel.
It will take some time, but perhaps
I'll use force synthesis on you, just like her.
Like her?
That's right.
Thirty, whom you're so infatuated with.
Because she also refused to chant the command,
the automated senators worked on her for days
to forcefully disable her protection.
Alice?
Well, I was asleep,
so I wasn't actually watching,
but it must have been so agonizing for her.
Well? How do you feel about
getting to at least share that experience?
Shatter.
That sword...
Now I see.
Please save me!
Please save me, Your Eminence, Pontifex!
You!
H-He's a traitor, Your Eminence!
He claimed that he sealed away Thirty
and the other one, but he went easy—
Let go!
Kirito.
Yo, Eugeo!
Sorry.
I gave in to Administrator's temptation,
and ended up hurting you both.
I thought I should at least atone for it
by my own hand.
You're being so cold, Eugeo.
I knew that's what you were thinking right away.
You're the same as always.
Alice.
Is that the pontifex, Administrator?
That's right.
She hasn't changed at all after six years.
It was almost time
to reset Bercouli and Fanatio,
but I've only used you for six years, right?
Your logic circuits don't seem to be malfunctioning.
Could it be the influence of that irregular unit?
How amusing.
Hey, Alice, there must be something
you want to say to me.
I won't get mad. So say it now.
Lady Pontifex,
our glorious order of Integrity Knights
has been destroyed as of today.
All because of the swords
of the two rebels beside me,
as well as the endless obsession and deception
you built along with this tower.
My ultimate mission is to safeguard a tranquil lifestyle
and peaceful sleep for those without swords.
Therefore, Lady Pontifex, your actions
are unquestionably detrimental to the well-being
of those who reside in the Human Empire.
Shut... Shut your mouth!
Y-You lowly, defective puppet knight!
You wretched knights are merely puppets
that can only do as I order you to.
It doesn't seem to be a logic circuit error, after all.
And her Piety Module is still functioning.
Meaning that she disabled the Code 871
imposed by that person of her own volition?
Rather than by a sudden emotional burst?
Code 871?
Is she talking about the Seal of the Right Eye?
Well, I won't know anything more
unless I run an analysis.
Now then. Chudelkin?
Since I'm so generous, I'm giving you the chance
to restore your ruined reputation.
Let's see you render those three powerless
with your arts.
Y-Y-Your Eminence, Pontifex!
What, Chudelkin?
I, Prime Senator Chudelkin,
for the first time in my many years of service,
beg to present to you a most insolent request!
I shall gladly risk my life annihilating these rebels.
Therefore!
Once I've carried out my mission,
if Your Eminence... Y-Your Eminence...
If you would allow me touch your exalted body
with my own hands and kiss you,
A-A-A-And then spend the night of my dreams with you...
Please... please... please grant me that wish!
Very well, Chudelkin.
I swear on the goddess of creation, Stacia.
When you've fulfilled your mission,
every inch of my body
will be yours for the taking, for one night.
I am overcome with supreme joy at this moment.
And now... and now, I...
My fighting spirit's been amplified!
I'm overflowing with energy!
To be more specific...
I am invincible!
System... Call!
Generate...Thermal... Element!
Let me show you.
My greatest, ultimate sacred art...
Come forth, genie!
Burn these rebels to ash!
Next time: Titan of the Sword.