"This story is fiction.
All names of characters, places and
organizations in the story are fictional.
Follow the traffic rules and drive safely."
Information, it's an era
where it travels in a second
But you don't know what
choice you should take
"Money can't buy my love"?
Guys who say that crap
get the lariat three times
Following the manual you just hold each other
You don't realize there is no love
Before you suffocate, shout Ho!!
In the midnight dream
You can't even take a breath
in the sleepless city
Never showing weakness but laughing
Safety is in lies, truth is empty
On the edge of danger,
I wanna shout and break out!
Now we gotta start let's get move!!
Let's move into the brand new world
Let's dive into the brand new trip
Frightened by the wide world
We've just begun, now we go
full speed and funky beat
We will shine around the world
Trip to the world
Yo! Here we go unknown world
We newborn travelers
The unfamiliar walk is still charming
The place you want to go is under your feet!
So many people in this world
It's not as if there isn't
backstabbing once in a while
Let's warp past these boring things
And go straight to our reason for living
That's our law!
That was dangerous!
What terrible driving...
Hey, you.
Hang in there. Are you all right?
I'm sorry, it's all my fault.
I'm very sorry...
Hang on! I'll call an ambulance!
"Act 3: The Downhill Specialist Appears"
What?!
Iketani got in an accident?
When did it happen?
Last night, he hit a guardrail
while coming down Akina.
Was he hurt?
Not too badly...
It's only minor whiplash...
...but he's really upset about the whole thing.
I heard his car is pretty messed up.
Then what about the meet on Saturday?
It's hopeless...
Anyway, we need to find
a substitute for Iketani.
"Automobiles"
Welcome.
Iketani?
It's all right for you to go out?
I'm okay. How's my car?
It's in the back garage, but we
still haven't done anything.
We can't do anything until the parts arrive.
"Fujiwara Tofu Shop"
Excuse me. Fried tofu, please.
Yes... I'm coming.
You got in an accident?
Yes.
The meet is pretty soon. What will you do?
I came to ask you a favor
about that, Mr. Fujiwara.
--A favor?
--Yes.
At the meet...
...can you please drive in my place?
I beg you, Mr. Fujiwara!
Ouch!
My neck...!
Don't die.
Mr. Fujiwara, I'm sure you
know how a street racer feels.
I can't let the local drivers lose.
Hey, even if an old guy
like me went out there,
he would just be out of place.
I grew up racing on Akina.
Those Akagi Red Suns obviously
are making fools of Akina's drivers.
I can't stand it!
I want to show them that Akina
has a street racer with true skill!
Mr. Fujiwara, you are the one who can do it!
You have already defeated Akagi's
fastest, the Takahashi Brothers.
I beg you, Mr. Fujiwara.
"We accept credit cards"
What is this? We're already closed!
"Fujiwara Tofu Shop"
Don't be rude. High octane, fill it up.
How cheeky. You want me to put
high octane in that Eight-Six?
It must have been you, Yuichi.
You told the weird rumor to that kid, Iketani.
Sure. It wasn't a lie either.
So what about it?
He came again today,
with a bandage on his head and a neck brace.
He asked me to drive in his place.
Well, I can't say that I hate that kind of guy.
If you don't hate him,
then why don't you do it?
Iketani is a good guy.
No, thanks.
I don't want to go sticking my
nose into these kiddie fights.
That's not my style.
So then it's all right if a kid
shows up at a kiddie fight, right?
Are you talking about Takumi?
That's right.
He's gotten pretty good, right?
He still has a ways to go...
If it's Akina's downhill,
he wouldn't lose to anybody.
Well, except me, of course.
Your competitive spirit is showing.
I wonder where he got his
stubborn nature from...
But even if I order him to go race,
that won't make him want to.
Well, because of those
bandages on Iketani's head,
I'll try to think of a good strategy.
A promise should never be broken.
There are only two kinds of people that I hate.
People who break their promises
and people who smoke.
I want to use the car this Sunday.
Sunday... you can't.
Why not?
I'll take care of the morning delivery.
That's not the problem.
I need to use it to go to
a town meeting on Sunday.
Really? This is bad...
I really need the car on Sunday.
It must be a girl.
None of your business.
Quit being so stubborn. Just let me use it.
It's just a crappy old car...
I'll take it if I want to.
A car won't move without a key.
I'll put it on a string and
wear it around my neck.
Not fair!
If you really want it that bad,
I'll think about it.
Really?
But there is a condition.
Condition?
Saturday night, go meet some brat
who's known as the fastest on Akagi
and beat the pants off him
on Mt. Akina's downhill.
What?
If you do that, you can use
the car with no conditions,
and you'll get a full tank of gas.
Full tank of gas?
Full tank of gas...
This offer is truly irresistible.
I'm out of money, too.
What're you going to do?
Well, let me think a minute.
Fine, take all the time you need.
"Takahashi"
I'm coming in.
Keisuke, good timing.
I wanted to ask you something.
What is it, brother?
The Eight-Six that you saw on Akina...
Can you describe the speed of the car,
theoretically speaking?
Oh, gimme a break.
Unlike you, I'm not good at that kind of stuff.
Like I always say,
the most important part
of driving technique is here.
Whenever you battle somebody,
you can stay behind them and
learn whatever you want to know.
From your opponent's habits and weaknesses
to how well their suspension is set up.
Your ability to analyze is almost scary.
In my opinion, the fact that
you can drive without thinking
and still keep up with me
means that you're the one who's truly scary.
If you could apply theories to your skill,
you'd be the ideal driver.
I lost because I didn't know
the road and I was careless.
I've never been disgraced like this before.
The inside of that Eight-Six must be a monster.
A monster, you say?
This is getting more interesting...
Tomorrow is the meet.
Maybe I should go and watch.
Takumi!
Saturday has arrived!
What about it?
What do you mean,
"What about it?"Today is the meet!
The meet with the Akagi Red Suns!
You promised that you'd borrow the
Eight-Six and we'd go watch, right?
Sure. Speaking of which...
This is getting a bit complicated.
What did you say?
You'd better not be trying to tell me
that you don't have the time...
No, that's not the reason...
If you back out at the last minute,
you can kiss our friendship goodbye.
Every day I've counted the days
on my fingers, waiting for today.
I know.
Excuse me!
Fried tofu, please.
Oh, it's you again.
You don't give up, do you...
Mr. Fujiwara, I beg you.
At today's meet...
I might do it...
I might do it, that's what I said.
On Akina tonight...
Honestly?!
Ouch... My neck...
Hey, are you okay?
Are you really going to come?
I can't say for certain, but...
...I would say there's about a 50/50 chance.
What time does it start?
The gathering begins at eight o'clock,
but the time attack begins at ten.
Ten o'clock...
If an Eight-Six hasn't shown up
by ten, you can give up on waiting.
You'll have to do it on your own.
I'll be waiting, Mr. Fujiwara.
I have faith that you'll definitely come.
It's not definite. I said it's 50%.
No, you've already decided to come.
Our team will be waiting for you!
Well, then, Mr. Fujiwara...
We'll be waiting for you on
the top of Akina at 10 o'clock.
I just can't be cold to an eager guy like him.
If Takumi won't do it, then should I go?
No, no, I shouldn't. I'm getting excited.
Did something fun happen?
You seem different today.
Really?
Aren't I always like this?
You look happy about something.
Actually, I'm going to the ocean
with my friend tomorrow.
I'm really excited about it!
Friend? You mean a boy?
What? Of course not! I'm going with a girl!
I see. Well, let's go to the department store,
and I'll buy you a new bathing suit.
It's okay. I already bought one on my own.
I don't need two of them.
I'd like to see you in your bathing suit.
That's funny!
You've already seen everything.
You're such a perv, Papa!
I wonder if tomorrow will be sunny.
Don't ask me such a stupid thing.
The weather is great all over Japan.
Are you going somewhere?
I'm going to the ocean.
Ocean?
What?!
I'm jealous! I want to go to the ocean, too!
Could it be...?
You're going with a girl?! A girl?!
Sort of...
Who is it? Do I know her?
Is she cute? Does she have big ones?
She's very cute.
Natsuki... Mogi...?
Yeah.
It's cruel of you not to tell me.
Sorry, but the situation didn't
give me a chance to invite you.
Next time, okay?
Please don't cry.
What's going to happen at today's battle?
I heard that the Red Suns have
won every battle they've been in.
The outcome is already obvious.
Akina will be totally defeated.
However, the fastest team in
Gunma is not the Red Suns...
It's us, the Myogi Night Kids.
Takeshi, it's about time.
Yeah, let's go.
Born with only the purpose of running fast...
A pure thoroughbred... the R32.
It won't lose to Akagi's dumb rotaries.
Amazing.
The mountain is lit up like a festival.
Rumors about this battle
between Iketani's team
and Akagi's fastest team
have spread all over the place.
Which side will win?
Takumi's Eight-Six is Bunta's Eight-Six.
It can't lose.
It's been a while since I've gotten this excited.
Wow, so many people!
I've never seen such a huge crowd on Akina.
The Red Suns brought them all
here to show off their speed.
If we lose tonight, we'll be humiliated.
By the way, the Eight-Six that
you were telling us about...
Is it for real, Iketani?
Yes.
I don't have any faith in that Eight-Six.
I heard that Keisuke Takahashi's FD3S
is lightly tuned for mountain driving.
But even still, there is a rumor
that it's putting out over 350 HP.
The difference in power is too great.
Even on the downhill, there's
no way an Eight-Six can compete!
Iketani, are you sure you
didn't hit your head too hard?
An Eight-Six is an Eight-Six,
but this is not a normal Eight-Six.
Keisuke Takahashi said it himself...
On the outside, it's a normal panda Trueno,
but inside, it's a monster machine.
Trust me.
I'm sure he will come.
If he doesn't come...?
There is a huge crowd here.
I don't want them to say
the Speed Stars ran away.
If he doesn't come...
If he doesn't come...?
Kenji, represent our team and drive like hell!
You must be joking.
A bunch of cars are coming.
You can hear the rotaries.
The Red Suns!
They're here! The Red Suns!
They're finally here.
Wow, the Takahashi Brothers are so popular.
I heard that their father owns
a big hospital in Takasaki.
You can't win against the rich...
Driving skill is determined
by how much you can spend
on gasoline and tires.
"Hill Top Seki Touge Transport"
What the hell is Takumi doing?!
The meet is starting!
Even though I really made sure...
That stupid Takumi...! Idiot! Jerk!
You're not my friend anymore!
That hurt!
I can't wait anymore!
I'll have to go on my scooter.
Let's begin the time attack at 10 o'clock,
according to schedule.
It should be easier since it's late
and there aren't many other cars.
We'll use radios at the start and finish points
in order to time the runs.
In order to allow the drivers to run
full-bore and as fast as they want,
officials will be placed at the blind corners,
and in the event of oncoming traffic,
we will use lights to signal the driver.
I see.
Seems like they've done this a lot.
Yeah. They probably do
time attacks everywhere.
Well, now that I've said that,
let's enjoy some free runs until 10 o'clock.
The galleries are packed.
The Eight-Six hasn't shown up.
I wonder why...
Do they intend to conceal their
secret weapon until the last moment?
What is it? Starting to feel like going?
Sure, but I don't really want to.
Why not? You've got no
confidence that you'll win?
Drive like you normally drive,
and you won't lose.
It's here!
Keisuke's FD3S!
Incredible! Such a fast entry speed!
Next is Ryosuke Takahashi!
Run! Look out!
That's Ryosuke Takahashi for you.
His skill is the real thing.
Amazing! They can get
so close without hitting?
That's their signature Parallel Drift!
Approaching the other car
is the toughest part.
During the drift,
if you lack the skill to freely
change your speed and line,
then you can't do it.
But this is just a performance.
Driving for time attack is different!
You still haven't come, Ghost of Akina.
My only opponent is you.
Show yourself, Eight-Six!
"Green Shopping Street"
Do I need a paper cup today?
You don't need it. You're not
carrying any tofu in the back.
This isn't a regular delivery,
so play as hard as you can.
Full tank of gas, don't forget.
I know, I know.
Well, I'm going.
Okay.
My pride says you gotta be wild and tough
So no one intervenes
Never stop, I don't want to stop
Even if you cry because of a sacrificed love
Aim for the peak, sweep the winding street
Beep beep! The warning chime is so cheap!
The sheep should clear the road
'Cuz I'm never gonna stop, streak my dream
Easy motivation is total stimulation
You tried to escape,
but anywhere is a safety zone
Something is within your grasp
and something is forgotten
Even if the world ends it will never change
Beasty shout, no one can touch you
Cross over now to the time of an intense dream
Rage your dream, split the darkness
Like a streak to the peak
Erase the freezing darkness worldwide
Rage your dream, and open the road
Di-ding down, another round never slow down
A point 01 second knockdown
Reverberations left behind,
disappear to the next town
The losers are left in the dust
Let's ignore the constraints of logic
'Cause they're a pain
A streaker runs naked across the street
Something they would know
Rage your dream,
continue on the unending road
Don't look back on your love or your past
Go forward and you'll shine brightly
Rage your dream, you're living in the now
Okay, today's guest is famous
for his aggressive driving.
Member of the Red Suns,
--Keisuke Taka--!
--Give me that!
Hurry up and show yourself, Ghost of Akina!
Maybe you got scared and ran away?
Well, do you think you'll win this time?
Shut up! Of course I will!
Whatever it takes, I'll get my revenge!
Next time on Initial D, finally, "Into the Battle!"
Who will win?
It's a high tension battle
between the FD and Eight-Six!
Don't miss it!