"This story is fiction.
All names of characters, places and
organizations in the story are fictional.
Follow the traffic rules and drive safely."
Information, it's an era
where it travels in a second
But you don't know what
choice you should take
"Money can't buy my love"?
Guys who say that crap
get the lariat three times
Following the manual you just hold each other
You don't realize there is no love
Before you suffocate, shout Ho!!
In the midnight dream
You can't even take a breath
in the sleepless city
Never showing weakness but laughing
Safety is in lies, truth is empty
On the edge of danger,
I wanna shout and break out!
Now we gotta start let's get move!!
Let's move into the brand new world
Let's dive into the brand new trip
Frightened by the wide world
We've just begun, now we go
full speed and funky beat
We will shine around the world
Trip to the world
Yo! Here we go unknown world
We newborn travelers
The unfamiliar walk is still charming
The place you want to go is under your feet!
So many people in this world
It's not as if there isn't
backstabbing once in a while
Let's warp past these boring things
And go straight to our reason for living
That's our law!
He's caught up with me?!
What's happening? I must be going crazy!
This is the straightaway
in front of the skating rink.
The two of them just passed!
He's on Keisuke's bumper!
Akina's Eight-Six is unbelievably fast!
Keisuke's FD has never had
anyone keep up with it this far!
Man, I've got goosebumps...
Great attack!
That Eight-Six's attack was aggressive.
It was an incredible kamikaze technique!
My old man...
Unless I pass that car,
he won't admit that I won...
There's no other way...
I guess I have to do that...
A full tank of gas is riding on this...
The setup point is in the next
five consecutive hairpin curves!
"Act 5: Dogfight!"
Damn!
What's going on? Of all days,
today the FD feels extremely slow!
Is the secondary turbine still working?
This is the top of the mountain.
Can you hear me?
Ryosuke?
Pretty soon,
the two will reach the five
consecutive hairpins up there.
Give me the play-by-play.
Tell me what's happening in
as much detail as possible.
Okay. They're very close to us now.
I can hear the sound of tires
squealing. They'll be here soon!
Here they come!
Keisuke's FD! And the Eight-Six!
They're neck and neck!
Wow! Great! That Eight-Six is amazing!
It did a perfect braking-drift!
Keisuke is losing ground.
His recovery is great, too!
It's so close to the guardrail!
They're going into the second
hairpin! There's no gap now!
Recovery is the same for both of them!
The FD got close to the outside!
The Eight-Six is...!
The hairpin is coming!
But he's not slowing down!
What is he thinking?
The Eight-Six is going into the
hairpin at an incredible speed!
Are his brakes out?!
What's that?!
Keisuke was passed! Easily on the inside!
That can't be true...
We don't understand
what's happening! Be exact!
But...we were watching it...
...and a car shouldn't be able to turn
at a speed exceeding the tire's grip, right?
But that Eight-Six turned in a weird way.
It was kind of like a roller coaster,
even though that line was
supposed to be bad on the inside turn.
I have no idea what happened!
I know what the Eight-Six did.
What?
It's a stupid thing, but no one can imitate it.
And it can happen only here on Akina.
I can't believe anyone would
try something so stupid.
I've got something to look forward to...
Akina's downhill specialist...
You will be beaten by...
...me, Takeshi Nakazato of the Myogi Night Kids!
This is the finish line! I can
hear the sound of their engines!
They're almost here!
Here they come! Which one's in the lead?!
It's the Eight-Six!
Wow! What's going on?!
Keisuke's FD is coming, too!
But there is too much of
a gap for him to cover!
The Eight-Six easily wins!
Crap!
My FD beaten by an Eight-Six?!
That's impossible!
350 horses defeated by a shabby Eight-Six?!
The Eight-Six just crossed the finish line!
Keisuke has lost!
We did it!
Am I having a nightmare?
I lost to an Eight-Six?! Twice?!
Wow! He won! That spacey Takumi!
Great! It's too cool! I'm totally numb.
I feel like I'm going crazy.
--He did it!
--Yeah!
Iketani! Don't cry! You idiot!
I don't know why... But I'm happy...
Let's take lessons from him...
Like drift control, and picking a line...
Let's put the Speed Stars' sticker
on it without him knowing!
Oh! I volunteer to do that! Iketani!
All right. I'll count on you...!
It was a clear loss.
Let's admit it with some grace.
How about the timed run
for the uphill, Ryosuke?!
The uphill doesn't mean anything.
By tomorrow, rumors will
spread among the street racers
that the undefeated Red Suns
lost to an Eight-Six from Akina...
We will have to get even soon...
...with my FC.
A full tank of gas...
That's what you promised.
You promised!
I see... He won...
I knew he would win even
before the race began...
This right is where I was
passed by the Eight-Six.
I just don't get it.
How could the Eight-Six,
which isn't good on inside corners,
go through it faster than my FD?
Just remembering it gives me the creeps.
He may be a real ghost...
Keisuke...
Tell me exactly what happened at that time.
Was there anything strange?
Come to think of it, I heard a
strange sound. Like scraping!
A strange sound?
I see... Now I understand.
What?
Should I tell you why you lost?
He used this.
--A drainage ditch?
--Yes.
He dropped his inside tires
into the ditch on purpose
and resisted the centrifugal
force by hooking it.
In that way, it is theoretically possible to gain
more cornering force than the tires can grip.
It is too obvious and simple,
and it's a ridiculous idea.
It wouldn't be successful
if he'd never done it before.
I assume that he probably
practices like this regularly.
He must have run Akina for many years.
Damn!
The mountain downhill is fun
because this kind of thing happens.
It's been a while
since I've met a target that
I can get excited about.
Let's cancel the expedition
we were planning for next week.
Until we have a complete victory
at Akina, we can't move on.
I'll beat the Eight-Six!
"Green Shopping Street"
Bunta! Are you in?!
"Closed Today"
It's me!
Oh, it's hot.
Oh, it's Yuichi...
Good timing!
I have a meeting at the Chamber of Commerce.
Sorry to bother you,
but can you give me a ride?
What? Are you using me as a taxi?
I heard Takumi was great...
Iketani and the others have been
excited about it all morning.
It's not particularly great.
I've heard that the expectations
of kids these days are pretty low.
He doesn't like driving cars.
Is that right? I can't believe it.
He has such a great technique.
To him, driving a car equals
helping with my business.
I've forced him to do it
since he was in junior high,
so he can't imagine that driving is fun.
I see...
He's somewhat cynical about it.
But the chase on the
downhill of Akina last night
might have given him
something to feel passionate about.
Speaking of which, I didn't see the Eight-Six...
Where is Takumi?
I don't know what's going on,
but he went somewhere
this morning in a good mood.
"Fujiwara Tofu Shop"
Wow! It's cold!
Takumi, you're...
...a very good driver.
Really?
To tell you the truth, I usually get carsick.
So I brought medicine for it.
But I didn't feel sick at all
when you were driving.
This is the first time I didn't get sick
after being in the car for so long.
Do you ride in cars that often?
Oh... not that often...
Just when my family goes
out and my father drives...
She is strange...
I was just driving like I usually do
so I don't spill the water in the paper cup.
It was strange yesterday...
The car running in front of me
was getting closer and closer,
and the next thing I knew...
...I found myself getting a
charge out of chasing it.
I've never thought driving was fun before...
Even today, when I was
driving with Mogi next to me,
it was a lot of fun.
Driving isn't that bad...
Hey, Takumi.
Hey! Hello!
You were daydreaming just now.
Were you spacing out?
You're rude, Takumi.
When a person has a cute girl with him,
do you think he should be off
in his own little world? Really!
Sorry! What did you say?
I just asked if you have a girl you like.
I don't have anyone in particular...
Although I do have someone I
can't help thinking of a little...
How about you?
I also have...
...someone I can't help thinking of a little.
What are you saying? Don't be a copycat.
Boy!
I don't know how many times
I was asked the same thing this morning.
"Who was in that Eight-Six yesterday?"
I was asked many times, too.
Anyway, he beat Keisuke Takahashi.
It's no surprise that people are talking.
I got a little carried away...
I told everyone that the Eight-Six was
the secret weapon of the Speed Stars.
We have to find a way to get
Takumi to join the Speed Stars.
Otherwise, we'll be embarrassed later.
Iketani! Leave it to me!
Because I'm his best friend,
I'll make him do it.
Are you sure, Itsuki?
Of course!
I know his weak points, too...
But in return, please let
me join the Speed Stars!
If Takumi will join us, you're in. Right?
Yeah...
Lucky! The negotiation was successful!
But how are you going to get a car?
I'm glad you asked!
I've already made up my mind!
Oh! You've finally saved up the money!
I'll ask my dad to sign for me
and get a loan for an Eight-Six!
Takumi has a Panda Trueno,
so I'll look for a red or black Levin...
...and someday we'll be
called the Eight-Six Pair,
the fastest in Akina.
But, Itsuki...
...Takumi's Eight-Six is not a normal Eight-Six.
That's right.
It was faster than the FD
with 350 horsepower...
It must have incredible tuning.
I'd like to take a peek under the hood.
Instead of that, why don't you go along
when he goes for Akina's downhill record?
Wow! That's a good idea!
I want to ride, too!
We can go where no one has gone before!
--I can't even imagine it...
--Yeah...
I bet it's greater than any
extreme roller coaster.
Yeah...
Crap! Right now, Takumi is...!
"Beach House"
Wait a minute! Takumi!
Excuse me! Could you take our picture?
All right.
What's this? We're going to take a photo?
We came all this way. It's for our memories.
Smile! Smile!
Here we go.
Excuse me! One more!
Please take one more picture!
That's enough...
Never mind, never mind!
Oh! That white FC!
That's Ryosuke Takahashi.
Finally, Red Suns' No. 1 showed up!
What for?
Must be revenge for his brother.
Can you think of anything else?
That was just yesterday!
He came here already?!
He must be really mad about being
beaten by the Eight-Six. I wonder...
That's an R32 I've never seen here.
A black R32...
Something about it makes me shiver...
Who is that?
My pride says you gotta be wild and tough
So no one intervenes
Never stop, I don't want to stop
Even if you cry because of a sacrificed love
Aim for the peak, sweep the winding street
Beep beep! The warning chime is so cheap!
The sheep should clear the road
'Cuz I'm never gonna stop, streak my dream
Easy motivation is total stimulation
You tried to escape,
but anywhere is a safety zone
Something is within your grasp
and something is forgotten
Even if the world ends it will never change
Beasty shout, no one can touch you
Cross over now to the time of an intense dream
Rage your dream, split the darkness
Like a streak to the peak
Erase the freezing darkness worldwide
Rage your dream, and open the road
Di-ding down, another round never slow down
A point 01 second knockdown
Reverberations left behind,
disappear to the next town
The losers are left in the dust
Let's ignore the constraints of logic
'Cause they're a pain
A streaker runs naked across the street
Something they would know
Rage your dream,
continue on the unending road
Don't look back on your love or your past
Go forward and you'll shine brightly
Rage your dream, you're living in the now
Damn! You traitor, Takumi!
All of a sudden you're strolling in!
He went to the ocean with Mogi
and without me, his best friend!
You wanted to see Natsuki
in her swimsuit, didn't you?
Of course!
Takumi was alone with her.
He must have done something
with her! I'm sure of it!
Next time on Initial D!
A new battle is in the air...
Don't miss it!