"This story is fiction.
All names of characters, places and
organizations in the story are fictional.
Follow the traffic rules and drive safely."
Information, byousoku de tsutawaru jidai
Demo choice no shikata ga wakaranai
Money can't buy my love nante
Nonkina yatsu ni wa rariaato sankai
Manyuaru doori ni tada dakiai
Ai ga nai koto ni ki ga tsukanai
Chissoku suru mae ni sakebou ze ho!!
In the midnight dream
Iki sae tsukenai nemurenai machi
Suki mo misezu ni waraiatte
Uso sae safety honto ga empty
Abunai gurai ni wanna shout and break out!
Now we gotta start let's get move!!
Let's move into the brand new world
Let's dive into the brand new trip
Hiroi sekai ni obieteru
Hajimatta bakari no now we go
full speed and funky beat
Kitto kagayaku around the world
Trip to the world
Yo! Here we go unknown world e to
Umareta bakari no tabibito
Narenai ashidori mo mata aikyou
Kimeru toko dake no bashitto!
So many people in this world
Toki ni chuushou toka mo nai wake janai kedo
Tsumannai toko wa warp shitekou
Suji dake wa tooshi ikiteru
That's our law!
That car, which is fast on the straightaways,
is following me...
Should I wait for a moment?
R-Three-Two, GTR (BNR32, GT-R)!
Let's see just how good it is...
So that's how you come out...
That's all I needed.
"Act 6: A New Challenger"
Is it okay to drop you off
at this kind of a place?
It's all right, because my house is right there.
You said this car was pretty sad-looking,
but I like this car.
It runs smoothly,
and it's small and cute...
What kind of car is this?
It's a Trueno.
Trueno...
Let me ride in this Trueno again.
I had fun today, Takumi!
Bye-bye. I'll call you later.
She called you cute...
What are you going to do?
I can keep up with Ryosuke Takahashi!
As I thought, this GT-R is the best.
Even though the driver is good,
with the out-dated FC,
this is its limit, isn't it...?
I'm Ryosuke Takahashi.
I'm a member of the Red Suns.
I know.
I'm Takeshi Nakazato.
I belong to a team at Mt. Myogi
called the Night Kids.
Takeshi Nakazato of the Night Kids...?
Are you the fastest street racer
on Mt. Myogi's downhill?
I'm honored to be recognized by
the superstar, Ryosuke Takahashi.
But I've heard Nakazato of the Night Kids
is driving an S13, if I remember correctly...
It doesn't matter...
So what is a street racer
from Myogi doing at Akina?
Hang on a minute. Let's not talk about me.
You belong to Akagi, don't you?
Didn't we come here for the same reason?
I wanted to meet the Eight-Six I saw yesterday.
The one using the R32
tries to bite the Eight-Six?
With the R32, which is
tuned for 380 horsepower...
What?
I can see it easily
by looking at the exhaust
and its power on the straightaways.
But the result is obvious.
On the uphill, the Eight-Six
is no match for the R32.
On the downhill, there is no way
your R32 can beat the Eight-Six.
What did you say?
Are you saying my R32 will lose
to the Eight-Six on the downhill?!
Don't take it personally.
I'm just saying what I think.
You don't have much nerve.
Even though your brother lost,
there's no need to be so intimidated.
It's just an Eight-Six.
Once you race against it, you'll see.
I'm the only one who can beat him.
Don't joke with me.
You've already said it, and now
I can't walk away no matter what.
I'll beat the Eight-Six and
make you eat your words.
You can be arrogant for now.
Don't forget that I am Nakazato from Myogi!
I'm telling you now
that the rotary is not a match for this R32!
...driving an S13, if I remember correctly...
That's right... since that time, I have changed.
Damn! I can't pass it!
Even if I get close in the corner,
he pulls away in the straightaway...
I have better technique as a racer!
Crap! How could I lose?!
With this S13, I can't beat an R32,
no matter what I do...
I, who was called the fastest
street racer on Mt. Myogi's downhill,
lost to an R32, which can't even do a drift...!
All cars have their limits.
No matter how excellent
the driver's technique is,
you can't drive beyond the car's limit.
Even that Eight-Six...!
Good morning!
Hey!
Here, Iketani!
What's that?
Fried tofu.
It's left over from yesterday.
My father told me to bring it to you.
Oh, really?
I'll put it in the refrigerator.
Wow... I'm surprised he thought of me...
--By the way, Takumi...
--Yeah...?
Is it true that you've been delivering tofu
to Lake Akina for the last five years?
Yeah...
I thought we were friends.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because if I talked about it,
we could have gotten into trouble...
Well... I guess so...
Five years ago,
we were just starting junior high...
You've driven much longer than I have.
Since junior high,
you've been driving every day,
even in the snow and rain, on Mt. Akina.
It's early in the morning.
So I don't see anyone...
No, not that! Those corners!
Weren't you scared?
Well... in the beginning, I was scared.
But the fear was completely
gone within six months.
When I accelerate, the tires slip naturally.
So it took another half year
until I could slip and control them as I wanted.
That means...
...you mastered the downhill in a year.
If you do it every day,
your nervousness about
slipping disappears quickly.
I had nothing to do,
so I started to see how close
I could get to the guardrails...
Would a normal person do
something that dangerous?!
I never thought it was dangerous.
When I'm at my best, I can
get as close as about 1 cm.
One... one centimeter?!
Unless I find fun stuff to do like that,
it's pretty boring
helping with my father's business.
That's why I've never thought I
wanted to improve as a driver...
But I would get impatient,
and would want to get home faster.
So when I don't have tofu on the way back,
I go as fast as I can.
--Takumi... can I ask you a question?
--Yes...
How do you drive when
you have tofu in the car?
If you go too fast, you'll
damage the tofu, won't you?
I can't go very fast on the uphill...
My father puts water in a paper cup
and puts it in the cup holder.
If I can drive without spilling the water,
he says I won't damage
the tofu, even if I'm going fast.
In the beginning, I found it to be very difficult.
Even when I drove slowly, it spilled all over...
I would think so...
Brake, steering wheel, shifting, gas pedal...
If even one of them is a
little rough, the water spills.
My father often says to roll
the water in the paper cup.
Roll the water in the cup?
I suppose it's the surface tension...
The water's surface tension
makes it roll around the rim of the cup.
At each corner,
I roll the water to the edge
of the rim as I drive up the hill.
It took me a long time
to be able to drift without spilling the water.
Drift without spilling the water?!
Can you really do that?!
Don't lie! You're just joking, right?!
The primary point in controlling
a car is the center of balance.
The Drift King, Keiichi Tsuchiya,
also says so in the video...
In order to drive without spilling
the water in the paper cup,
you have to master the car's center of balance.
Not to mention drifting...
It's impossible to do that!
I'm not lying!
Just because you beat Keisuke Takahashi...
You're carrying it way too far! I know better...
--Oh, a customer.
--Oops...
Welcome!
Fill it up with high octane? Yes, sir!
Amazing, Bunta...
His technique is way above
just a regular mountain racer...
Thank you very much!
Takumi! I have a favor to ask.
Can you let me ride next to you
when you do the downhill at Akina?
"Fujiwara Tofu Shop"
You want to use the car?
At this time of the day?
Oh, well, I didn't think you'd let me.
That's all right. It's not a big deal.
I don't mind.
Are you sure?
Don't you need the car for anything?
Like a meeting at the Chamber
of Commerce or something?
You'd better think a little bit.
What are you talking about?
You sound like you'll be in trouble
if I don't have to use the car.
Well, no... I didn't mean that...
Then take the car.
But in return, you need to
pick me up at my meeting.
So you do have a meeting!
My heart is really beating fast!
It's like just before getting on the
extreme ride at the amusement park.
Oh, shoot! Lucky you! I'm envious!
I don't think it's that much fun.
I'm going, Iketani.
Yeah! I can count on you, Takumi! Go all out!
Shoo, shoo! Get away, you guys!
It sounds great!
It's the best! A turbo can
never sound like that!
The first corner is coming up.
I'll figure out what he does different from me,
and then steal his technique...
Hey...! Hey!
Takumi! Brake!
How... How can he control the car like this?
What's going on?!
Incredible...
The speedometer warning sound is on!
That means it is way over 100 km/hr.
We're coming up on the next corner!
The Eight-Six is back already?
I wonder what happened.
It's too early to return from the bottom.
He passed out...
Takumi!
Which corner was it?
The third one...?
"Iketani Passes Out!"
Wow! I... I saw it!
The agonized cry of his last
moment echoed through Mt. Akina!
The scary downhill!
Iketani, in the third corner...
...passed out!
It must be true...
Wow! Mr. Tachibana! Why are you here?!
I was curious...
I suppose I'm not welcome...
Take your time...
I know that guy.
Nakazato of the Night Kids
has no opponent in Myogi.
I can't be impressed
by the technique of a person who drives a R32.
It's just that the car is fast. That's all.
I wonder if that's true...
You don't think so, brother?
Here we go again. Keisuke hates the R32.
But, Ryosuke...
I don't think it's good if
Nakazato defeats him first.
If the Night Kids beat
the Eight-Six that we couldn't beat...
...it may look like the Red Suns
are a notch lower than the Night Kids.
That's the way rumors go...
I think that's Nakazato's plan.
I don't think you need to worry about it.
There is no one in the Night Kids
who can beat the Eight-Six.
As long as it's the downhill of Akina,
no one can beat him.
Only my brother can handle it.
The Eight-Six is fast and on a higher level.
I don't get it...
Why can't the new state-of-the-art cars
with high power beat the Eight-Six?
Sometimes a car has too much
power to do the job. That's all.
What?!
The turbo power is a strong
weapon on the straightaway,
but coming out of the corner,
it hinders the car's behavior.
It's like a double-edged sword.
From that aspect...
...once the Eight-Six is set,
it can go faster and faster.
On the technical courses
where the straights are short,
sometimes the car that
is aggressive can be faster,
even though it doesn't have much power.
Keisuke's turbo, which had increased power,
had the opposite effect...
That's right...
On the downhill of Akina,
the total amount of time I could use...
...all of its 350 horses was very little.
Right after the moment I thought
I had pulled far away from him,
I had to brake for the next corner,
and the time it took before I could
accelerate was too long, and it irritated me.
Well, that is what happens
with the FR that transmits power
to the road surface using only the rear tires.
Hey, wait a minute!
Then what will happen
with the R32 that is a 4WD?
The ATTESA E-TS System
can give stable traction
even when giving it the gas,
so he can use the turbo power
as much as he wants, can't he?
Nakazato's R32 may
be able to beat the Eight-Six...
Thank you very much!
Welcome!
"Yuno Hana Manju"
"Pharmacy"
"Tagawa Liquor"
But I feel strange...
The way I look at you has changed...
What's that?
Have another onsen-manju ["hot spring bun"].
Yeah...
When you're doing that,
it's the regular Takumi.
A spacey guy who looks
sleepy and eats manju.
Calling me a spacey guy is pretty rude.
But...
...once you're in the
driver's seat of the Eight-Six
and jump onto the mountain...
...you are the pride of
the street racers in Akina!
The hero everyone admires!
Really?
Is that right?
It's embarrassing...
I told you I'm not talking about now!
Now you're just a spacey
guy who is eating manju.
To tell you the truth, I feel kind of strange...
About what?
During the last race,
and yesterday when I had Iketani ride with me,
I was just driving as usual.
I don't understand why
everyone is so excited about it.
I've never done anything that
makes other people happy.
I'm starting to think...
...that driving is becoming fun...
--Hey!
--What?
A black R32?
That's the one we've seen a lot recently.
Crap! He's on my bumper!
Don't let it pass us! Try hard!
Yeah... On the downhill,
the difference in power is smaller.
We have the Eight-Six that beat the FD!
Small fish!
He passed on the outside!
What a thrill! A completely
different level of acceleration.
As I thought...
...in reality, it is impossible
to race and beat a power car...
...with a gutless car.
This is an amazing machine.
Since I switched to this car,
my former rivals are no longer a match for me.
I lost the opponents who
made me run seriously.
The drift game,
which has become popular recently
but is just flash, is not my style.
Unless it is an extreme battle,
which attacks with gripping tires
and makes me concentrate totally,
I have no use for it.
Come out!
Akina's Eight-Six!
At first glance, I felt it!
You are enough of an opponent for me.
My pride says you gotta be wild and tough
Sou tanin wa kaizai shinai
Never stop, tomaritakunai
Gisei ni natta ai ga cry shite mo
Peak mezashite, sweep the winding street
Beep beep! Keikokuon wa so cheap!
Sheep-tachi wa michi wo akero
'Cuz I'm never gonna stop, streak my dream
Easy na motivation subete wa simulation
Nigetemitatte doko demo safety zone
Nani ka wo te ni irete nani ka wo wasureteku
Sekai ga kowaretemo kawaranai
Beasty shout, dare no te ni sae oenai
Hageshii yume jikan sae mo ima koeteku
Rage your dream, yami o harisaite iku
Like a streak to the peak
Sekaijuu no kogekitta yoru o keshiteku
Rage your dream, michi o hiraiteku
Di-ding down, another round never slow down
Konma zero-ichibyou de knockdown
Yoin nokoshikietekou to the next town
Hokori mau haishachi ni hau
Rikutsu dake no nougakitachi
Jamakusai kara shikato shitekou
Streaker satte yuku street no mukou
Something they would know
Rage your dream, tsuzuku hatenai michi wo
Ai mo kako mo furimukazu
Yukeru anata kagayaiteiru
Rage your dream, ima o ikiteiru
I heard about it!
You were a very famous
street racer in Akina once.
Yeah. I often drove with Bunta.
Now in Akina, Takumi is going to have
to race with Nakazato of the Night Kids.
Yeah... But Takumi doesn't want to race.
What?! Then we can't see them race!
Don't worry. I have an idea.
Leave it to me.
Next time on Initial D, "A Racer's Pride."
Don't miss it!