Disgusting!
They don't go together at all.
What a devastatingly poor pairing.
Squid tentacles and peanut butter...
I can't help but laugh.
It's so disgusting.
Souma.
Your friend is here.
Okay!
Let's do this!
Enjoy.
Dig in!
Thank you!
Oh, the cooking battle's on!
So Mayumi's the judge today?
You think...
...today's the day he'll...
Shh! Mayu's making up her mind!
This one!
It's over!
The old man wins once again!
Souma.
You still need more training.
Looks like I've lost today.
Say that after you win at least once.
You're closing in on 500 losses, aren't you?
Huh?!
Don't get cocky!
That was only the 489th time you've won!
So like I said, you're getting close.
Shut up, old man!
The owner's Chinese fried rice is seriously the best!
It's amazing we can eat food
this good so close to home!
We're so lucky!
I can't get enough!
B-But yours was really good too, Yukihira-kun!
I've never had such delicious Chinese fried rice!
Thanks.
I have a new dish that I came up with earlier today.
Would you like some?
Really? I'd love to try it!
Grilled squid tentacles in a peanut butter dressing.
Huh?
Mayu!
Whoa, he's at it again!
This one's even crazier than last time!
Here, dig in. It's so outrageous that you'll be howling in laughter.
N-No...
No!
The taste of the tentacles took
a turn in the wrong direction.
It was as if my entire body was being violated.
Well, that's what the girl said some time later.
Cooking is an endless wasteland.
A wasteland littered with countless flavors, both delicious and disgusting.
And I want to see what lies beyond that horizon.
Shut up, idiot! Keep your wanderlust to yourself!
Hang in there, Mayu! How are you feeling?
The squid... The squid is...
Yukihira is always so happy
to make people eat his mistakes.
If it weren't for that quirk,
he'd be a decent chef.
But the dried sardines with strawberry jam combo
I dreamed up was worse still, huh, Souma?
Oh, I remember that.
That was a nasty mess of epic proportions.
Right?
But the peanut butter tentacles are worse!
No way! Sardines with jam are worse!
Peanut butter tentacles are worse!
Well, with a dad like that,
I guess he would turn out that way.
Mine was worse!
Here's your liver and garlic chives.
Could I get the pork and tofu set?
I'll have today's special.
Got it.
One pork and tofu, one special!
Whew, I'm stuffed.
That was great.
Thanks for the meal.
Thanks for coming!
Thank you for coming!
Souma.
When you're done, kill the flame on the charcoal grill.
For that Chinese fried rice, I should've shaken the pan three more times.
I'll be graduating from middle school soon.
Then I'll be able to spend more time on my cooking.
I want to surpass Dad as soon as I can!
Then I'll take over as chef of this restaurant!
Welc—
Pardon us.
It looks like you're still open,
but please forgive us for barging in.
I'm an urban planner, Minegasaki.
What would you like?
Huh?
Today, we recommend the
splendid alfonsino sashimi and...
No, I'm not here for that.
I'm following up on what we discussed the other day.
We'd love to bring this comfortable and luxurious urban apartment building,
designed in the "Garden Residence" style, to this town—
We get it.
You people are land sharks,
and you want us out of here.
We've heard all this before.
Go home.
We have no intention of shutting this place down.
Then...
I'll just leave my card here.
You can call me any time.
But, sir, with the economy as it is,
running a hole-in-the-wall like this will become increasingly difficult.
I hear many restaurants agonize every day
about managing their stock.
We don't have that problem.
Is that so?
Yukihira takes the responsibility...
of giving our customers what they want.
Oh, how wonderful!
You're everything the service industry should be!
But if you can't serve what your customers want,
how will you take responsibility?
If that day ever comes,
we'll close up shop gracefully and go out of business.
Can I hold you to that?
Yeah.
Then I'll see you again soon.
Dad! The salt! Throw the salt!
Nope. That'd be a waste of salt.
What do you wanna do now?
Hm, karaoke?
With what rules, then?
How about anime songs?
You say that every time.
Mayu!
Don't make fun of anime songs!
Hey, Dad?
Yeah. You home yet?
No, I picked up some stuff for breakfast.
What's up?
I'm out taking care of some business.
Yeah? That's unusual.
I won't be home until tomorrow,
so you don't have to open the restaurant.
Okay.
Hey.
What do you plan to do after middle school?
What else? I'll study cooking at the restaurant.
I see.
What was that about?
And...
what's so important that he'd close
the restaurant for a day?
My dad doesn't talk about himself much.
Now that I think about it, I know very little...
about my dad as a chef.
Huh?
The meat is ruined?
The fridge is completely...
A burglar? No, a burglar wouldn't do this.
Oh, my!
The ambiance is so much more
pleasant compared to yesterday.
Maybe it's because that ugly sign is covered up.
Ah, today I'm in the mood to eat some meat.
That marbled steak I always have in Roppongi is just the best!
The juice just fills up my mouth.
Hey, little boy,
give me the juiciest meat dish you can make.
Oh? Don't tell me you can't satisfy me.
Your customer is asking for meat.
Can't you serve it?
Silly boy, didn't you tell me yesterday...
that if you couldn't serve a customer, you'd go out of business?
Someone decided to give this joint a new coat of paint.
I don't think it's a coincidence.
It must be a sign that you should shut this place down.
A juicy meat dish?
Is that your order?
Swear that you'll never enter this restaurant again,
if I serve a meal that satisfies your palate.
The battle's on!
Wait.
Didn't I tell you to trash the fridge?
W-We did.
There isn't a single scrap of usable meat left.
I asked you for juicy meat!
What are you playing at?
There's nothing you can use!
Impossible!
How did you...
...make such a perfect...
...pork roast?!
It's simple.
I wrapped some potatoes in...
the thick-cut bacon I bought for tomorrow's breakfast.
It's "Gotcha" Pork Roast!
Potatoes?
"Gotcha"?
Roast?
That's right. First, I steam the potatoes.
Huh? What's this atmosphere?
Are you making a fool of me?
I told you to serve me meat!
There's no room for negotiation anymore.
Give this restaurant to me!
Listen to me! Truly successful chefs
work in first class restaurants or luxury hotels
like the ones I've promoted.
This is a failure!
If you ask me, this restaurant
isn't even worthy of existing!
Yukihira
This one dish will tell you whether or not Yukihira...
is worthy of existing.
Dig in.
With every bite,
the fragrant juice of the slow-roasted bacon...
pours into my mouth!
You look like you're enjoying that.
This was devised at the restaurant you just ridiculed.
Should I tell you the secret of this flavor?
Once I've steamed the potatoes to a fluffy consistency,
I chop up fibrous mushrooms,
which will soak up the fat.
Then I dice some sweet onions for sweetness and knead them all together.
After that, I wrap thick-cut bacon around it all...
and roast it slowly in the oven.
That makes the bacon crispy on the outside...
while the potatoes and mushrooms soak up all the savory flavor and fat from the pork.
And so...
a sensual new mouthfeel,
crispy on the outside and juicy on the inside, is born!
A long time ago, while preparing potato salad for a customer,
I made a mistake while plating it,
letting meat drippings soak into the potatoes.
That's where I got the idea for this dish.
From a mistake.
So what?
You can't call this a meat dish!
But... I can't...
stop eating it!
I want to taste more of this meat juice!
Wh-What are you doing?!
If you want any more of this, promise me...
that you'll never come after this restaurant again.
What? Who would promise that?
Oh, I see.
It's a shame, but you leave me with no choice.
I'll have to take this and...
Wait!
I promise! I promise, okay?!
What?
Let me... um...
have some more, please?
Meat juices!
Glad you liked it!
No matter what happens,
I won't let this restaurant go under.
Yukihira is my castle for perfecting my cooking!
Dad...
Looks like something happened.
Nothing important.
Just a rude customer.
Souma.
For the next two or three years, I'm going to...
close the restaurant.
Yeah, I know, I'll have to apologize to our regulars.
Apologize to your son first!
An old friend of mine suggested we work together.
Wha—
I'll be living with them for a while,
so I won't be around.
But you can't just...
Hey, Dad!
As soon as I get my stuff together, I'm leaving.
Wait.
I'll be sending you some money to live on.
I said, wait!
I want to... stay at this restaurant and...
It's time for you to go, Souma.
Go figure out what you've got.
Cooking school?
Why do I have to go to a school like this now?
It's perfect timing, isn't it?
I'm closing the restaurant, and you can earn high school credits there.
Just go study there for three years.
Paying to learn how to cook is so stupid.
A culinary school is just gonna be like...
Okay, today I'll teach you a dish that you can make nice and easy.
Yes, sir!
Gah!
I failed the advancement test!
I'm done for. My life is over.
I beg you!
I'll donate ten million, no, twenty million!
Just rescind my son's expulsion!
What's going on?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
That's Japan's top culinary academy,
with a graduation rate of less than 10%.
It's a super elite institution.
How revolting!
What a terrible soup.
It tasted like I was standing
peacefully under a waterfall,
and then a jukebox came
crashing down on me!
A jukebox?
That's hard to understand.
I-I'm sorry, Lady Erina!
Honestly, I can't even laugh at this.
Not in the least.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the second dish:
God Tongue.
Please enjoy.
Peanut butter tentacles...