This is the last one.
Disgusting!
Ow!
It's incredible that you lot have managed to come up with this many train wrecks.
That last oyster gruel, in particular,
was as if... yes,
as if I were taking a bath with a western lowland gorilla!
Again, we have no idea what you mean.
Family: Hominidae; Genus: Gorilla;
Western Lowland Gorilla
The largest living primate.
Eats primarily fruit, grass, leaves, and vines.
The fur on the back of adult males turn
greyish-white, hence the name "silverbacks."
One male forms a harem with several females...
Her palate is incomparable to that of a mere mortal.
I can tell that you omitted one of the steps in prep work.
I am aware that your restaurant group is expanding,
and that you're trying to increase your efficiency for that reason.
But how dare you presume that gives you the right to defile my tongue with such garbage?
M-My apologies, Lady Erina!
It's time for you to go, Souma.
Go figure out what you've got.
I stick out like a sore thumb.
Why do all the other applicants have butlers and guards and stuff?
Oh, I didn't tell you?
You're taking the transfer admission exam
for one of the best culinary academies in the country.
The graduation rate is less than 10 percent.
It's a super-elite institution.
Best of luck with that, Souma.
At that school—
Hey, Jo!
Please wait a moment!
Where are you right now, Dad?
New York City.
In the Manhattan Royal Hotel's reception hall for VIPs.
That's where I'm cooking now.
Hey, Jo!
I'm so happy you came back to New York!
This is the best dinner ever!
Simmer down, Dr. McFly!
Your blood pressure will go up again!
Delicious.
After taking a medical leave of absence from Congress,
I resigned myself to my fate and thought my life would be complete
if I could eat Yukihira's cooking just one last time.
But this only makes me greedy for more!
Let's come again, sir!
Yes, as many times as possible!
Is Yukihira here?!
Please come back, Master!
We're in the middle of a fast!
What example are you setting—
Bah, silence, silence, silence!
You're telling me to spurn Yukihira's cooking
when it's right in front of me?!
In that case...
I reject my calling!
Master!
Yukihira!
First I went to India, then Italy and Spain.
I just arrived in America yesterday.
The plan is for me to be cooking up and down the East Coast for a while.
Huh?
I don't understand.
Well, let's just say someone called in a favor.
Hey, Souma.
If you can't survive that academy,
you can kiss your pipe dream
of surpassing me goodbye.
Just watch me!
Good.
Then let me tell you the secret to improving your—
He hung up on me.
Where did you go, Yukihira?!
Coming!
Listen up, Souma.
The trick to becoming a good chef is...
finding a woman you want to cook for
for the rest of your life.
So what's next on my plate?
This, Milady.
Judging transfer exams?
So this is the kind of boring work I get for joining the council.
I'll head over after I change.
Damn it...
A pipe dream? Yeah, right.
I'll definitely make it to graduation, damn it!
S-Sorry!
I didn't notice you sitting there.
No need to apologize.
You also wish to transfer in, right?
Take a seat, won't you?
High school qualifying exam results are being announced for Tohtsuki's junior high school,
and exams are being held for people like us hoping to transfer in,
so it's pretty lively today.
I'm Nikaido Yoshiaki.
My family runs a French restaurant.
Oh, what a coincidence.
Mine runs a restaurant too.
That may not be such a coincidence.
The man over there is the heir
to a national restaurant chain,
and that one's family runs a wholesale seafood business that supplies the entire Kanto region.
Almost everyone here has
some sort of tie to the culinary world.
Oh?
What's the name of your place?
It's called Yukihira.
Yukihira...
You serve traditional fare, perhaps?
No way, it's nothing that fancy.
We're a diner downtown.
How dare you sit next to me,
you low-class commoner!
Listen up!
This academy isn't for the likes of you!
It is a sacred grove, an institution of learning for
denizens of the upper echelons of the food industry!
That's the kind of place Tohtsuki Teahouse Culinary Academy is!
A low-born like you won't even make it
past the screening of applications.
Huh?
You haven't even tried Yukihara's food!
You don't get to pass judgment!
Young Master!
Look, someone from a diner thinks he can attend this academy.
You've got to be kidding me.
He should know his place.
This isn't giving me high hopes for this place.
If this is how things are right off the bat,
who knows what sort of pompous ass
I'll get as the examiner.
Hey, is that...
Y-Yeah.
Greetings, transfer applicants.
I am Nakiri Erina, and I have been
assigned to judge today's transfer exam.
A girl?
And she's wearing the school's uniform.
She's the examiner?
What do the instructions from the exam department say?
I'll read it now.
Examinees will first undergo interviews in groups of ten based on their applications.
They will then complete a practical,
in which they will cook up to three dishes.
Those who pass will—
Hmph.
What a waste of time.
I have an idea.
Bring a kitchen work table here.
Y-Yes, Milady!
Cooking ingredients?
What's she up to?
The main ingredient will be eggs.
Make one dish.
Only those whose creations impress my palate will be allowed to transfer into this academy.
C'mon.
Furthermore,
anyone who wishes to withdraw
his application has one minute to do so.
What? One minute?
I'm withdrawing!
What?!
Hey, wait!
Why are you all running?!
You don't know who she is?!
Huh? Nope.
Who is she?
Nakiri Erina has the finest palate known to mankind! A divine tongue!
The God Tongue!
Huh?
Humans typically begin talking
between the ages of one and two.
But her first spoken words, at three months old, were...
Not enough depth of flavor.
Given the small glimpse of her genius already present at birth,
she has been asked to be the taste tester at famous restaurants across the nation since she was young.
All the heavyweights in the food world are her clients!
Any evaluation she makes will spread far and wide in the industry!
If she...
If she were to brand you as an talentless imbecile,
your career in the food world would be over!
I figured most of them were hopeless incompetents.
I can't be bothered to waste my time on such fools.
I believe that clears my schedule for the day?
Uh, yes.
I will be testing new dishes in my private quarters.
Erina-sama's new dishes...
What's the matter, Hisako?
It looks like you wish to ask me something.
Oh, no, well...
Would you like the privilege of trying my cooking?
I... I would!
What a shameless hussy you are.
Oh, please forgive me!
First we'll have to report that no one passed.
Yes.
Hey, so are there no other restrictions on the dish?
What?
I...
have a challenger?
As long as you use eggs,
you can make anything you want.
But are you sure about this?
This is your last chance to—
Man, I was so worried!
I thought you might fail me
before I even got to cook!
How dare you!
Do you know who she is?!
Who is she?
She's the top of her junior high class
and the youngest member
ever of the Elite Ten Council,
the highest decision-making body in the academy:
Nakiri Erina-sama!
Whoa.
What a magnificent knife.
Don't wander off!
Huh?
Let me ask you one last time.
Are you really going to take my exam?
Huh?
But...
I just have to get you to say it tastes good, right?
Of course I'll take the test.
This boy...
Erina-sama.
Yukihira Souma.
His family runs a diner.
It's clear that he's a second-rate cook.
He has no conception of my noble pedigree,
just like a stray dog would have no idea of a gemstone's value.
If that's your attitude,
I'll taste your food.
The food of the bottom feeders of the culinary world.
Then I'll be happy to...
serve you...
our specialty!
Hang onto your seat,
Examiner Nakiri!
Eggs are a fundamental ingredient
in Japanese, Western, and Chinese cuisine across all culinary genres.
Erina-sama tastes egg-based haute cuisine every day.
What will he serve her?
I see that he's using beaten eggs,
but I have no idea what dish he's working towards.
Yukihira Souma-kun, what are you making?
Huh?
You still can't tell at this stage?
Do you want me to fail you right now?!
Listen!
I don't have time to waste on ill-conceived food.
I'm asking you if you have any intention of
making a dish that is suitable for my palate!
Fine, I'll tell you.
What I'm making is the eighth item on Yukihira Diner's secret menu!
Secret menu?
And what manner of elaborate dish would this be?
Rice with seasoning!
Huh?
Cut the crap!
I knew you were a good-for-nothing cook.
What a waste of time.
Erina-sama...
It goes without saying that
it's no ordinary seasoning.
What I'm making...
is rice with transforming seasoning!
Transforming seasoning?
All right!
Almost done!
Yukihira Souma...
What dish is he about to serve?
Thank you for waiting!
No.
Like I initially thought, he's just messing with me!
It really is ordinary.
In the end, it's still the work of a second-rate cook.
It fails to arouse my appetite.
My palate has been called the God Tongue.
Only the most elaborate and refined
haute cuisine graces my dining table.
Indeed, I reside in a gourmet paradise!
How dare he serve something like this to me?
This examination is over.
Erina-sama!
But you haven't seen its true form yet.
What do you mean?
There's something hidden beneath the egg.
Well, keep your eyes peeled.
The true value of a rice seasoning
is only revealed when it's served on rice.
Well, then...
Here we go!
It's melting... from the rice's heat?
And as it melts, it coats the egg.
What is this aroma?
Chicken?
The fragrant, mellow aroma of gently simmered chicken is wafting through the air.
So this is rice with transforming seasoning?
It looks completely different from before.
I wonder what it tastes like.
I suppose I can deign to take one bite.
Hand it over!
Here you go!
I can't believe this!
I forgot to judge it and just savored the taste?!
What was that texture?!
Oh?
You're going for a second bite?
I thought I heard you say one bite only.
Do you have any complaints about that?!
I'm just kidding.
Take your time and eat up.
It's aspic, isn't it?
Bingo!
The cubes are aspic made from chicken wingtips.
Aspic is formed when meat or fish broth
with high gelatin content congeals into jelly.
I simmered chicken wingtips with bonito stock, sake, and light soy sauce,
then finely chopped the aspic
once it cooled and solidified.
When that's sprinkled over hot rice,
the aspic melts and the gelatinous broth coats the egg soboro.
In effect, this aspic is a rich soup infused with the umami of chicken.
The rich flavor and saltiness of this broth...
are enhancing the fluffy egg
soboro's subtle sweetness.
With every bite, the fluffy and gelatinous textures caress the insides of your mouth.
The melted aspic elevates the egg
to entirely new heights.
This is unlike any dish I've ever eaten.
It's an entirely new world of flavor.
So how is it?
Good thing you didn't storm off earlier, right?
S...
Silence!
The evaluation has yet to be concluded!
Even if the menu item is humble in the extreme,
we use our creativity to transform it into a masterpiece!
That is Yukihira cooking.
Even so...
how can I, a denizen of gourmet paradise, accept this?
This, a dish by the personification of all things déclassé!
I can't... accept this.
I just... can't.
This flavor...
It's as if...
I'm being caressed by angel feathers!
Go away!
Stay away!
Stay away, I say!
No!
I don't want to accept it.
but my palate... my body can't help but react.
Sure, we may be a small diner,
and I'm sure you're one of the elites of the culinary world.
But, you know,
I bet there are some things you can't make
if you get too comfortable sneering down at people from your throne.
Erina-sama.
Well? What is it?
Yukihira-style rice with seasoning.
Is it delicious or disgusting?
Tell me!
It's...
disgusting!
What?!
How dare he, how dare he, how dare he?!
Talking down to me like that!
To me, Nakiri Erina!
Unforgivable!
Yukihira Souma...
Tohtsuki Academy has no need for people like you!
Hello? It's Erina.
Please tell Grandfather,
the director of the academy,
that no one passed the exam today.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the third dish:
That Chef Never Smiles.
Please enjoy.