My train's here.
All righty, I'd better get going.
Megumi, you're really leaving, huh?
And you've only just turned 13!
Please don't worry about me, Gramps.
Yeah!
Megumi's cooking's the real deal around these parts!
It's good enough for Tokyo too!
Here, a good luck charm to help you stay focused on your studies.
Okay.
Megumi!
Megumi can be bashful, after all.
Thanks, guys.
When I come back, I'll be a real chef!
I'm Tadakoro Megumi.
My high school life's just begun,
but I'm already on a knife's edge!
Next, we will be presenting the new students with their class badges.
Incoming valedictorian, Nakiri Erina.
Here!
Ah, Erina-sama...
Exquisite as always.
Beautiful and at the top of her class.
She is perfection incarnate!
If I could go on a date with her, just once,
I'd die happy.
Idiot!
Watch your mouth!
You'll get kicked out of the academy!
Yeah.
She's the granddaughter of the don
who heads the food industry mafia!
I know, but still...
We now welcome our keynote speaker:
the director of Tohtsuki Academy,
Nakiri Senzaemon-sama.
S-So terrifying!
The entire Academy-no, the entire
Japanese culinary world is under his thumb!
He's the epicurean emperor!
Calling him a mafia don is an understatement!
He's the devil!
The devil of cooking!
Greetings.
Congratulations on your advancement to the high school division.
During your three years
in the junior high school division,
you attained a basic competency in cooking
and developed your understanding of each ingredient.
In addition to the cooking practicum,
you attended lectures on a variety of topics,
including culinary theory,
nutrition,
public health,
introductory agronomics,
and management.
Now you stand at the threshold
of the high school division.
The challenges you face from now on
will not concern your skills or intellect,
but whether you have the mettle to survive as a culinary professional.
99 percent of you...
are meant to be sacrifices for honing...
the remaining 1 percent!
He called them sacrifices!
He's built up quite a head of steam, Bro.
Yeah, you're right.
Of the 812 students who entered our high school division last year,
only 76 advanced to the second year!
Incompetence and mediocrity will be mercilessly excised from our student body.
A thousand first-years will be whittled down to a hundred by next year,
and we can count those who will graduate from this academy on one hand.
One of that small handful of professionals will be...
will be you!
Hone yourself.
That is all.
All right!
I'm going to make it.
This academy's name holds so much weight because of the intense competition,
allowing only a select few to complete their education.
Should one succeed in advancing to graduation,
their stardom in the culinary world is guaranteed.
But I pity all of those who are of my generation.
Since the moment you were born, you were destined to fight over second place.
The pinnacle of Tohtsuki Academy and of the Japanese culinary world
belongs to me, Nakiri Erina.
Finally, we'd like to introduce a transfer student who will be joining your ranks today.
So one student managed to pass a different exam?
Yukihira Souma.
Go away!
Stay away, I say!
Hmph!
The mere memory of it makes my blood boil.
But never mind all that.
Oh, sorry to be talking to y'all from up here.
I'll never have to see him again.
Just be quick about it, please.
Okay, I'll keep it short.
Just a few words from me.
Uh, I'm Yukihira Souma.
To be honest,
this academy's just a stepping stone to me.
I wasn't expecting to transfer here,
but I don't plan on losing to folks
who've never served a single customer.
Anyway, what I'm getting at is...
I just want to make it clear that
the number one spot is mine!
Looking forward to being with y'all
for the next three years!
You little...
Hey!
I'm gonna kill you!
Die!
Get back here!
Phew, got through that without stumbling.
Hey! You're the one from the exam!
Uh, Nakiri, right?
Man, that was nerve-racking.
I've never had to stand in front of a bunch of people to get an award or anything.
What did you think?
Was I weird?
Who cares about that?!
Yukihira-kun.
Why are you here?!
Huh? What do you mean?
Wouldn't you come if you got an acceptance letter?
Impossible!
Man, you had me scared out of my wits.
You told me it was disgusting.
If you thought it was good,
you should've just said so.
No!
This is all wrong! All wrong!
I rejected him!
What is it?
Is it delicious or disgusting?
It's disgusting!
What?!
I'll say one thing.
I haven't accepted you.
Neither you nor your cooking.
This is a mistake! A mistake, okay?
You're here at Tohtsuki
because someone made a mistake.
The number one spot is yours?
Don't make me laugh.
Every student here has been studying
cutting-edge gastronomy for all of junior high.
I can already tell that an underdog transfer student like you...
doesn't stand a chance against them!
All three years of junior high, huh?
What about it?
I was three years old when I held a kitchen knife for the first time.
I've been practically living in the kitchen for the past twelve years.
You thought I'd let you drag my
restaurant's name through the mud?
That I'd slink away, tail tucked,
after you said my cooking's disgusting?
Just you wait!
I'll make you say "delicious."
I'll use everything I've got in my cooking arsenal!
That transfer student sure was something!
Maybe that's exactly the attitude you need in order to survive at this academy.
You might be right!
Let's give it our best shot!
Right, Megumi?
Huh?
Where's Megumi?
I want out already.
I'm definitely going to be the first one sacrificed.
I got the lowest passing score on the entrance exam,
and I've already received a final notice.
No, I can't give up!
I have to live up to the expectations
of everyone back home!
Anyway, I'm on the brink of getting expelled,
so I should keep my head down and not draw
unwanted attention like that transfer student did!
Yeah!
I'm not going anywhere near that guy!
You'll be divided into different classes and starting your coursework right off the bat.
Today, you'll be cooking in pairs.
Got it?
Nice to meet you.
Why?!
Y-u-m.
Oh, man...
The last time I had to cook during a class was home economics.
Hey, look.
Yeah.
It's the transfer student who was running his mouth off at the opening ceremony.
That guy's all talk.
So... Tadokoro-san, was it?
Why are you doing that weird little ritual like your life depends on it?
Oh! I-I'm doing this to calm down.
Calm down?
Why?
If I get even one more E rating, I'll be expelled.
Huh.
I was told that this is an elite school,
but even here there are people like you, huh?
And here I thought I could survive
by keeping a low profile.
Now I'm paired up with this guy, of all people.
Oh, I'm Yukihira Souma.
Souma's fine, though.
Nice to meet you!
Oh...
Nice to... meet you too.
Th-The stares hurt.
I wonder if he's even noticed.
Attention!
Good morning, my young apprenti.
Good morning.
A-Apple Dannon tea?
That's Roland Chapelle-sensei.
You become responsible for creating a delectable dish
the moment you step into the kitchen.
Neither experience nor status can excuse you from this duty.
In my class, any dish that fails to deserve an A rating
will automatically receive an E rating.
Remember that.
I've got the worst luck.
I can't believe my very first class
is with Chapelle, of all people.
Teach sure looks scary.
He's notorious for being really strict with grades, even for this school.
Last year, he gave E ratings
to all 50 students in his class,
which resulted in 18 of them being expelled.
His nickname is "The Chef Who Never Smiles."
Huh.
Today's menu item is boeuf à la Bourguignonne.
It has been said to be a staple of French cuisine,
but I'll put the recipe up on the whiteboard, anyway.
You have two hours.
Each team should serve the dish as soon as it's complete.
Let us begin.
Start cooking!
Did he just say to add diced cucumbers?
I just have to get through this.
Stay calm and nail each step.
Besides, Souma-kun seemed pretty confident too.
I bet his cooking skills aren't too shabby-
Boeuf bour-what?
What?!
Souma-kun, you've never made it before?!
Nope, I haven't.
It's basically like braised beef sinew, right?
Well, I'm sure we'll manage.
I'll go take a look at the recipe.
I guess I'm screwed after all.
Sauté the mushrooms in butter
before adding them to the pot.
Then you just simmer everything at low heat.
Take the beef out in 40 minutes...
Take the beef out in 39 minutes.
Take the beef out in 38 minutes!
Tadokoro, look!
Look at all of these spices!
I feel like an idiot for getting
all anxious by myself.
Oh, I should probably go get a serving dish in the meantime.
Huh?
Tadokoro, did you lift the lid?
Huh? No.
It has to be simmered for 20 more minutes.
Wh-What's all this white stuff?!
It's salt.
How?!
Wh-What are we going to do?!
We can't use this meat anymore!
We'll have to start all over again!
But it takes more than an hour to tenderize and season the meat!
Then we have to braise the meat in the sauce for at least half an hour to let the flavors mingle.
We only have 30 minutes left.
But if we serve this salt-caked dish,
we'll get an E rating for sure.
Mom...
Sorry, guys.
I'm done for.
I got some spare ingredients.
Huh?
All right, let's put our game face on.
What?
Souma-kun, there's no way
we're gonna finish in time.
That teacher says some pretty good things.
When we're in the kitchen,
we're chefs, not students.
I'm gonna serve a dish, no matter what!
Gimme a hand!
O-Okay!
Here's the salt, pepper, and bouquet garni!
Thanks!
Look at that loudmouth transfer
student getting all fired up.
Whatever, there's no way
he's getting out of an E rating.
Yeah.
Hm.
This is an A.
All right!
Next team!
All of the teams should be finishing up by now.
We've only got the sauce left.
Let's wrap-
Evaluation, please!
All done!
No way.
So tender...
The fork's practically springing back.
What?!
Impossible! There's no way they could have braised it long enough!
Your team had an accident, did it not?
How did you manage to finish the assignment?
We used honey!
I kneaded it into the meat before braising it,
and I also used it in the seasoning.
Honey has proteases, which breaks down proteins.
The proteases went to work on the tough beef flank,
allowing you to tenderize it
in the short time you had left.
B-But how'd you know that
you could use honey this way?
I read this cookbook a long time ago.
It said you could use pineapple juice to tenderize meat.
I couldn't think of a reason why I'd get an entire pineapple just for that,
so I experimented with a bunch of different stuff to see if anything else had a similar effect.
Honey has a long shelf life.
It's also the most effective and easy to apply.
Well, you'll see once you have a bite, Tadokoro.
Here.
I'm melting.
Melting...
How marvelous!
Chapelle-sensei...
smiled!
Yukihira and Tadokoro.
I'll give you an A rating.
However...
I regret the fact that I do not have the authority
to grant you a higher rating.
Glad you liked it!
That transfer student's cooking...
...got a higher rating than ours?
H-Hey!
The sauce is burning!
Shit!
E rating!
That was an easy win, Bro.
Yeah, just as usual.
If only we'd been in the same
class as that transfer student,
we would've known how to crush him!
Souma-kun.
Hey, good work back there!
Um...
Thanks for today!
It's all thanks to you that I...
Don't worry about it!
I look forward to working with you
from now on, Tadokoro!
Same here!
Maybe I've gotten myself paired up
with someone really special.
By the way, want to try the new
recipe that I came up with,
to celebrate our teaming up?
Is that okay with you?
I'd like to try it!
Here!
Um...
It's squid dipped in honey.
The flavor of the squid had been
taken in the wrong direction,
making it as disgusting as it'd feel to be
groped all over by its tentacles.
No!
It's Erina-sama!
I wonder if she's testing new recipes again.
I wish I could try something of hers, just once.
Erina-sama!
Erina-sama, I have terrible news.
What is it? Pull yourself together.
He received the highest rating possible in Instructor Chapelle's class.
By "he," I mean him... Yukihira Souma!
I would prefer not to have that name uttered in my presence.
P-Please forgive me!
He is an abomination that has
invaded my sacred shrine.
I cannot let him have his way!
I will purge him...
and soon!
I have squid with peanut butter too. How about it?
I have so much more.
I don't like him after all!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the f-fourth dish:
The Madonna of the Polar Star.
Please enjoy.
Here, here, here, here, try this next.