Damn, what is it with this school?!
It's freakishly huge!
The sun's about to set.
I'm exhausted.
To top it off, it's freezing!
And I'm so hungry that the squid's
not cutting it any more.
Seriously, though...
Everywhere I look,
there's yet another pompous-looking building.
I have no idea what some of these
are supposed to be used for,
but there's no question that this school is rich.
I bet their facilities are all top-notch.
Hey, the dorm might be pretty swanky too.
Maybe I could get used to this place!
Are you kidding me?
Hello?
Smoke?
Is that a fire?
A-And now an earthquake?
Harietta!
Drake!
Stagley!
No! Don't leave me!
Hey, Room 116!
Don't you dare keep game animals in your room!
If you do that again, I'll flay you alive!
Sorry!
And Room 208!
You turned an empty room into a smoker without my permission again, didn't you?!
Want me to string you up
over some wood chips?!
Yeah, yeah.
I'm deeply sorry.
And Room 205!
If your room collapses,
I'll collapse you with a punch to the gut!
I-I'll try to be more careful!
You wanna fight?!
But there are two guys fighting in my room!
Bring it!
You must be Yukihira Souma, the transfer student who wants to live in this dorm.
I'm the caretaker, Daimidou Fumio.
But I'm better known as Fumio-san, the Madonna of the Polar Star.
As in, you'd better address me that way.
How'd I get involved in another freak show?
So what did you bring in the way of ingredients?
Huh?
What do you mean?
What else could I mean?!
Anyone who wishes to live here must pass our famous challenge!
First rule: dorm applicants must make one meal.
Only those whose cooking passes muster will be allowed to reside in the dorm.
Second rule: the caretaker will serve as the examiner.
Third rule: the applicant may bring any ingredients they wish to use.
This is news to me!
I haven't got any ingredients on me!
I guess that means you fail by default.
I won't let you cross the threshold
without first seeing what you're made of.
Huh?
Then that means tonight I'll have to...
Camp outside, of course.
No way!
You can't be serious!
Even in April, it's freezing at night!
I'm already half dead from exhaustion and hunger!
The challenge is mandatory.
Just forget about it.
The only things left in the kitchen
are scraps and leavings.
Consider today your unlucky day—
You mean I can use those leftovers?
What?
I'll take the challenge.
Where's the kitchen?
Oh, wow.
Considering what the place looks like from the outside, this is a really nice kitchen!
Listen up.
I hate know-it-all brats the most.
How many student-cooked meals
do you think I've tasted in my life?
Don't you dare think I'll give you a passing grade
for something you're going to slap together.
Onions and other produce odds and ends.
Eggs.
Panko bread crumbs.
The usual assortment of spices and seasonings.
And...
All right! This should be more than enough.
What on earth...
Polar Star Dormitory Caretaker
Daimidou Fumio-dono...
You better hang onto your seat!
There wasn't a speck of ground beef or pork left!
What is this magic?
How'd you make this meaty-looking hamburg steak?
I used canned mackerel.
It's a mackerel burger!
Canned mackerel?!
Once I prepped the eggs, onions, and panko,
I added them to the drained and shredded mackerel
and seasoned it with salt and pepper.
Throw that onto that stove,
and you get a fluffy mackerel burger.
Then I made a simple sauce from the mackerel juice
by adding ponzu and thickening it with potato starch.
I call it "Yukihira's Kitchen-Clearing
Mackerel Hamburg Set"!
Have a taste!
Don't be ridiculous.
A hamburg steak made with canned mackerel...
would be way too fishy.
DE!
LI!
CIOUS!
If he had told me that there was beef or pork in this, I might have believed him!
Yet it's still light and has an excellent mouthfeel.
But what about the egg drop soup?
What is this?
The soup base can make or break a soup.
Only a top-notch stock could have been used
to produce a soup with such a fragrant flavor.
But how'd you come up with this?!
There was neither kelp nor bonito
to prepare a soup base!
It turns out I did bring an ingredient with me.
Dried squid?!
You made a soup base with dried squid ?
Dried squid is basically umami in concentrated form.
If you reconstitute it in hot water and add salt,
you end up with a rich base
that can add a depth of flavor.
This kid's something special.
I can't believe he managed to concoct something this delicious from just those ingredients.
What a soothing flavor.
This meal warms both the body and soul.
Mackerel and squid...
This beautiful marine rhapsody of flavor...
It reminds me of my younger days.
A-Aren't you cold?
Fumio?
Hey, Kou-chan.
Do you know what I want you to do right now?
H-Huh?
Uh, well...
C'mon.
Don't make a girl say it out loud.
Come closer.
I want you to warm me up.
Please.
Take me!
Let go of me, old woman!
He made me try so many of his creations
that I'm exhausted from reacting to all of them.
You're an idiot, Souma-kun!
You treated me like your plaything.
Right, Ducky?
You'd be in a pickle too.
Very well!
I will allow you to live in this dorm!
Glad you liked it!
You'll be in Room 303.
Here.
All right!
He demonstrated an impressive flexibility with a limited array of ingredients.
Yukihira Souma will make
an interesting addition to this dorm.
This has been the only sanctuary
I've had since junior high.
Fumio-san's kind of scary,
but at least there are no strict
teachers or Souma-kun here.
A bath!
First I'll have a hot bath!
Oh, I guess I forgot to warn him.
It's the girls' turn to use the bath right now.
Waaaah
Ah, that hit the spot.
That's right. I've left my home
of 15 years for the first time.
Here's your liver and garlic chives.
Could I get the pork and tofu set?
I'll have today's special.
Got it.
One pork and tofu, one special!
It's so quiet.
Hey, transfer student!
C'mon, we're having a welcome party.
I told you already,
I'm busy studying for the written exam!
Go have your fun somewhere else!
Why do you guys always insist on partying here?!
What choice do we have?
You have the biggest room.
Who said you could sit on my bed?!
Your room's always clean too.
I just finished cleaning up!
Yeah, there were books scattered about earlier.
That's because you two were on a rampage!
Anyway, you should get some more chairs.
Like hell I should!
Whoops.
Not the books again!
Listen, Megumi.
A proper lady mustn't show
off her skin to just anyone...
Anyone...
Sorry, Mom.
I can't get married anymore.
Well, who knew we'd end up in the same dorm?
Uh-huh.
Wait, does that mean you passed the dorm entrance challenge on the first try?
I guess.
I'm glad I managed to figure something out.
That's amazing.
Almost no one makes it through
on their first attempt.
Really? How'd you do, then?
W-Well...
So-so, I guess.
I'd die before I tell him that it took me three months!
Here, Yukihira-kun.
Oh, thanks.
Huh?
Why is it cloudy?
A 1.8 liter bottle with a handwritten label on it.
Don't worry, it's just rice juice.
Oh?
Still, are you sure we're not going to get in trouble for partying this late at night?
It's fine.
The dorm's in the middle of a forest.
Well, but...
What about the dorm mother?
Hey, guys!
I have some buri daikon!
Someone come and get it!
Yeah!
I love that hag!
Seriously?
Just come back before Fumio-san
starts her spiel about the Elite Ten.
The Elite Ten?
How dare you!
Do you know who she is?!
Who is she?
She is the top of her junior high class
and the youngest member ever of the Elite Ten Council,
the highest decision-making body in the academy:
Nakiri Erina-sama!
The Elite Ten...
Hey, what's this "Elite Ten" thing?
Huh? Seriously, you don't know about it?
You really showed up here without a clue, huh?
Tell him, Marui.
Why me?
Quit whining.
It's for the newbie's sake.
Fine.
The Tohtsuki Elite Ten Council
is a committee composed of the ten
highest-ranking students within the academy.
Students are allowed to manage many of the academy's affairs,
so a wide variety of issues are settled by the Council.
They are, in effect, the academy's highest decision-making body.
In the academy's hierarchy, they are second only to the director himself,
and not even the instructors
can oppose their decisions.
Decades ago, back when this dorm was always full,
a bunch of Elite Ten members were from Polar Star.
There were even years when
all of the Ten were from Polar Star.
Once Fumio-san gets going about
those times, it's hard to get her to stop.
Huh.
So Nakiri Erina is currently one of the Elite Ten.
We're back!
Hi there, Yukihira Souma-kun.
Welcome to Polar Star Dormitory.
We're glad to have you.
I'm Isshiki, a second-year.
Call me Isshiki-senpai.
Hi.
I'm so happy to have you join us.
It means we have yet another comrade with whom to share our youth.
There's nothing better in life!
Listen, friends!
We all live under the same roof
and eat the same food.
That's youth right there!
The epitome of student life!
I joined the dorm because I aspired to that kind of life.
Now, let us savor our time together
in this wonderful dorm!
Well, that's nice and all,
but would you please quit coming through the attic whenever you want to see us?
Oh, I shouldn't do that?
Well, maybe I'll use this for the guys too.
Tadokoro-chan comes over whenever
I talk to her through this.
W-Well...
Tadokoro-chan, are you asleep?
I'm having a lot of fun.
Well, I'm all by myself,
but I have lots of wonderful food.
If you're still awake, come on over, okay?
If I don't go,
he keeps talking to me every couple of minutes.
He gives up eventually if you ignore him.
You're so conscientious.
It'd be annoying to have him
talking at us all the time.
Maybe the attic's better after all.
It seems like this dorm's full of weirdos.
You'll fit in right away, Souma-kun.
Everyone have their drinks?
Here's to the future of Yukihira Souma-kun
and the glory of Polar Star Dormitory.
Cheers!
Wow, this rice juice sure is awesome!
See, I told you.
Born again, right here and now!
Fly beyond the sky we only dreamed of!
Food!
We need more food!
Okay, how about something I smoked today?
Smoked cheese and three kinds of jerky.
Damn, check out this smoky savoriness!
Ibusaki always nails it!
But of course.
Here, eat up!
Fried mixed veggies, fresh from the garden out back!
There's no way this wouldn't be good!
It's tasty, right?
Of course it is!
Well, the fried shrimp I made last week was better.
Hey, wait a minute.
You must have the worst palate in all of Polar Star.
What did you say?
Hey, not again!
If you call yourself a chef,
talk through your cooking.
Fine! Give me eight minutes!
Hey!
This is why you keep making
too much food every time!
You two need to chill out!
Shut up, game animal bitch!
You stink of wild game!
That goes double for your room!
Now that you've said that,
I'll have to school you on
the charms of my wild beasties.
Be back in an hour.
Are you going to strangle a duck
or something at this hour?
Yuuki-chan, calm down!
Hey, hang on.
How about one of my own
new creations from today?
Oh, Yukihira, bring it on!
Oh, sorry.
That one was no good.
Disgusting!
Sorry, sorry.
He's going to die!
There we go!
It's Isshiki-senpai's impromptu naked apron getup!
Nice job!
Times may change, but two things remain constant:
the laughter of students...
and the gathering of stars beneath the moon.
Tonight was quite enjoyable.
Again, we're very happy
to have you here, Souma-kun.
Well, I...
Thank you.
Looks like we're all out of food.
I have some filleted Spanish mackerel.
I'll go make something.
You're really gonna cook dressed like that?
Okay, all done.
Dig in.
It's peppered mackerel, dressed with a spring cabbage purée.
Thanks!
It's heavenly!
This dish makes the most of
the seasonal ingredients of spring.
How could he put together such a delicate dish in so little time?
He's head and shoulders above all the other students in this dorm.
And he's just a second-year!
Is that enough time to learn how to
make something like this?
By the way, Souma-kun.
I heard you said some pretty interesting things at the opening ceremony.
Gunning for number one at Tohtsuki
may not be as easy as you think.
Allow me to re-introduce myself.
I am one of the Tohtsuki Elite Ten:
the seventh seat,
Isshiki Satoshi.
Now...
I'd like to try your cooking, Souma-kun.
Show me the story you'll create on your plate.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the fifth dish:
The Ice Queen and the Spring Storm.
Bon appétit.
Take me!