It's heavenly!
This dish makes the most of
the seasonal ingredients of spring.
How could he put together such a delicate dish in so little time?
He's head and shoulders above all the other students in this dorm!
Allow me to re-introduce myself.
I am one of the Tohtsuki Elite Ten:
the seventh seat,
Isshiki Satoshi.
You're one of the Elite Ten?
Now...
I'd like to try your cooking, Souma-kun.
What sort of dish will you make?
Show me the story you'll create on your plate.
I'm beginning to understand
why Dad sent me here.
Hang onto your seat!
Isshiki-senpai's dish:
peppered mackerel dressed
with a spring cabbage purée.
Does your family run a traditional
Japanese restaurant, by any chance?
What gave you that idea?
Spanish mackerel grilled with Sichuan pepper is a common Japanese dish,
but not just any establishment could produce such a fine example.
The mackerel is grilled to delicate perfection.
The accompanying purée of
spring cabbage surprised me.
But its mild, smooth sweetness is
a perfect complement to the mackerel.
Spring is the season for Spanish mackerel,
while the spring cabbage brings
out the mackerel's flavor.
It's so festive,
it's as if I'm basking in spring sunshine.
Spanish mackerel...
All right!
I'll base it on a dish from Yukihira's secret menu, item number 20.
Yukihira's?
It's the name of my family's diner.
Using the same ingredients as you did,
I'll make a variation on
one of our popular dishes.
It'll be on the same theme of spring.
Did I pass out?
Oops! I drank too much rice juice.
Huh?
Yukihira's cooking right now?
Is he still hungry?
They're having a cook-off.
Whoa, you were awake?
Wait!
A cook-off between those two?!
What happened?
No idea.
But it was Isshiki-senpai's idea.
Are we going to turn a blind eye to Senpai's attire?
We shouldn't interfere in a cook-off.
I guess.
All done!
Yukihira's secret menu item number 20, revised!
Tea over a mackerel rice ball!
Since I used mackerel
instead of the usual salmon,
I had to tweak the dish
to account for that change.
There's enough for everyone,
so you can all dig in!
Wow, thanks.
What'd you pour over the rice?
It's salted kelp tea.
Its mild savoriness and depth of flavor are a perfect way to wrap up our feast.
Aw, getting served something like this makes me hungry all over again!
Indeed.
This is all too pedestrian.
It practically screams diner food for the masses.
But perhaps...
All right, then!
I'm gonna dig in!
Thanks for the food!
Delicious!
The mackerel is really juicy,
and the skin's crispy texture is superb!
The umami gushes out with every bite.
You can't get this kind of mouthfeel by grilling the fish.
How did he...
Poêlé.
This mackerel was cooked using the poêlé method.
Po...
...ê...
...lé?
Wait, why are you acting all surprised?
I'm not, I just don't know what this poêlé thing is.
What?!
Poêlé is a cooking method in French cuisine.
It's similar to pan-frying.
You pour olive oil and the like over the ingredients in order to ensure even browning.
Tell me, Souma-kun.
How did you come to know this method of cooking?
I learned it from my dad.
He said it's the best way to make crispy fish.
You can eat it all crunchy with rice...
or enjoy a different texture altogether
by softening it a little in salted kelp tea.
And how did your father learn to cook French cuisine?
Oh, I'm not really sure.
I think he went around cooking in a lot of different countries.
I see.
I never imagined he'd use a French technique to prepare a rice ball.
His cooking isn't bound by culinary
traditions or genres. How liberated!
The poêlé method is well suited
to meats with a thick skin.
Spanish mackerel is a perfect replacement for salmon.
Souma-kun realized its potential
in an instant and changed the dish.
The radiant rice is like pristine white snow.
And the Spanish mackerel bursts forth,
as if to symbolize the vitality of spring itself.
In this dish he has captured
the very moment that spring begins.
S...
Sprouting!
Glad you liked it!
How beautiful.
It was a beautiful thaw, Souma-kun.
Yours was, too, Senpai.
I could feel a refreshing spring breeze.
Thank you for this match.
Huh?
What the hell's going on?
Marui?
Marui.
Marui!
He's out cold.
Yeah.
Okay!
Dismissed!
Next time we'll be sure to
clean up before leaving, Marui.
Yeah, next time.
We swear.
Still, I wonder why Isshiki-senpai challenged Souma-kun to a cook-off.
Who knows? He's temperamental.
He's a weirdo. You shouldn't waste time on wondering what he might be thinking.
I'm tired.
Well, g'night, Megumi.
Good night.
Souma-kun, with this welcome party,
you're now officially a member of Polar Star.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask me.
Okay.
How do I get into the Elite Ten?
That's right.
You're gunning for the top spot
in this academy, aren't you?
Is there a specific reason
why you're so determined?
Well, I'm kind of in the middle
of a fight with my dad.
I'll have to pull off something that major if I'm going to gain his respect.
Our match just now was a draw.
If I beat you,
will that make me the seventh best at Tohtsuki?
How wonderful!
I admire your ambition, Souma-kun!
O-Okay.
I'm super impressed by you right now!
It's how students who live at Polar Star should be!
R-Right.
But!
I'm going to call it a night.
It's getting late.
Let's get some rest, Souma-kun.
Well, I g-guess.
You said you'd become number one at Tohtsuki.
Soon you'll realize just how heavy those words can be.
Uh, I'm Yukihira Souma.
To be honest,
this academy's just a stepping stone to me.
The number one spot is mine!
You'll come to understand
that at this academy,
cooking is literally everything.
The main ingredient will be eggs.
Make one dish.
Only those whose creations impress my palate will be allowed to transfer into this academy.
Hand over the dish!
Disgusting!
I'll say one thing!
I haven't accepted you.
Neither you nor your cooking.
The number one spot is yours?
Don't make me laugh.
Every student here has been studying
cutting-edge gastronomy for all of junior high!
An underdog transfer student like you...
doesn't stand a chance against them!
It's going to ferment!
Oh, Usako...
Heavy!
Morning, everyone.
They trashed my room yet again!
I'll be sure to tell them off
even more than I usually do!
'Sup.
Mornin'.
What is it?
What's wrong?
I had to table this last night,
but now it's time to put the Elite Ten's
seventh seat on the line!
It's time for a cook-off, Isshiki-senpai!
Huh?
Food! Food!
I'm starving.
Where's breakfast, Fumio-san?
Shut your traps!
Sit your butts down and wait!
Sorry, Souma-kun.
I never explained it to you.
Huh?
About how challenges work at Tohtsuki Academy.
Erina-sama!
Good luck!
Do your best!
Prepare yourself!
Our Chanko Hot Pot Research Society
has existed since the founding of this academy.
It has a long and glorious history.
What do you propose to build after razing our club room, Nakiri-kun?
A kitchen wing for my personal use.
The fifth wing has become cramped, so a sixth—
Unacceptable!
That building is chock full of not only history
but also the passion our predecessors
put into their food!
You seek to trample that into the mud?
How dare you call yourself a chef?!
Yeah!
Don't let this atrocity happen!
Erina-sama.
This so-called passion you speak of...
Is it in your copies of your predecessors' recipes, or the squandering of your budget?
Over the past few years,
your group has accomplished little.
A research society that only sings the praises of their past glories
is of no value to Tohtsuki.
You abuse your power.
I can no longer turn a blind eye!
If I win, I demand that you leave the Elite Ten!
Come and face me, Nakiri Erina!
Then if I win, I will proceed with the construction as planned.
I accept your challenge, Goudabayashi-senpai.
There is an established policy to settle disputes among students at this academy.
There are several rules.
Because you wish to challenge me for my seventh seat,
you must wager something of equal value.
Something of equal value?
If we're talking about the seventh seat...
Not even your expulsion would be enough.
What?
Seriously?!
Indeed, a spot in the Elite Ten
is worth more than that.
After all, they are the highest decision-making body in the entire academy.
Not even instructors can oppose
what the Elite Ten Council has decided.
In the past, this dorm used to produce several Elite Ten members every year.
It was the golden age of Polar Star.
In comparison, you lot are pathetic!
Not that talk again, Fumio-san.
Anyway, we could still go through with it if I chose to accept your wager,
but I don't want you to leave the academy.
So in conclusion, there can be no cook-off.
Seriously?
I even woke up at five today
to get myself revved up.
I can't believe you're going for the seventh seat.
You're too reckless.
I think he's just stupid.
Besides, you can't just do whatever you want.
There are three things you need
for an official cook-off.
First, official certification that you've made a formal challenge.
Second, an odd number of judges.
Third, an agreement between the contestants about the conditions of the challenge.
All must be met for the formal challenge to be valid.
I see.
Sounds like a huge pain.
But on the other hand,
if you satisfy those three requirements,
you can challenge anyone in the academy.
"All who oppose you...
shall be struck down through your cooking."
Tohtsuki's traditional cooking duel is called...
Cooking Battle.
The judges have cast their votes!
The winner of this Cooking Battle...
is Nakiri Erina!
I-Impossible.
It was unanimous.
But our Chanko Society...
Just how did my lobster fall short?!
There were 27 shortcomings in your dish.
First, the lobster.
You blanched it two seconds too long.
Second, the oysters produced a slight
off-flavor that tainted your entire hot pot.
Stop!
As for your vegetables...
How was your cooking?!
How could it be any better than mine when I spent days perfecting it?!
Ready!
How is it, Senpai?
How is my raviole de langoustine?
The steamed ravioli are light and bursting with the flavor of succulent freshwater prawns.
This supple elasticity...
It's reminiscent of being overwhelmed
by the strength of a Grand Champion.
Her cooking's flavor is of an entirely different league!
It's heavenly!
It's me.
Yes.
Please begin.
What are you—
N-No!
Please stop!
Cruel and diabolical...
This...
This is...
This is what it means to carry the blood of the Demon Lord of Food!
Good day.
"Cooking Battle," huh?
Man, and here I wanted to challenge Nakiri too.
Th-There's no way you could ever win!
I'm looking forward to your future.
You're sure to rack up a good cook-off record.
After all, you scored a draw against me.
Me, the seventh seat.
Wouldn't you agree, Ibusaki-kun?
Yeah, right.
I know you were pulling your punches.
That wasn't even your specialty.
You were playing it way too safe with that dish.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I believe I gave it my very best effort.
Heh.
How devious, Senpai.
Souma-kun.
When I ate your cooking, I realized
that you're the kind of rookie who will cause
a whole new era of cooking battles
to bloom at this academy.
That was most impressive, Erina-sama.
Defeating an opponent like him
is hardly praiseworthy.
He was far below my expectations.
Anyone who falls short of perfection has no place at Tohtsuki.
Show me the list of our next targets.
What?
Um, yes.
Here it is.
Erina-sama.
May I take on the next target?
I do not believe it necessary for you to personally deal with trash.
Please allow me the honor.
You're right.
That may be interesting.
However, I'm sure you understand the consequences if you fail.
I am called the Meat Master.
I will secure a perfect victory worthy of that name.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma...
Oh, it's already the sixth dish:
The Meat Invader.
Wonderful!
Do you want it?
I do.