So? You gonna do it with me or what?
Hm?
Let's do it.
A Cooking Battle.
Good morning, Souma-kun.
I'd like your help with something.
Can you get dressed and come outside?
I'm dead tired because I was up all night.
Please ask someone else.
Oh, don't be like that.
That's where you were?!
He woke you up too, Yukihira?
Yup, same as you.
So what did he drag us out of bed for?
We're harvesting veggies from the garden out back.
Wow, you guys even grow your own produce?
"The road to good food is paved
with good ingredients."
That's our dorm's motto!
Ibusaki prepares all of the wood
that he uses for smoking.
Ryouko, who specializes in dishes using rice malt,
has her own work space for fermentation.
I want to create a special Polar Star chicken, like the Bresse chicken from France,
so I'm breeding cage-free chickens out here.
Really?
Last but not least...
There's a plot that we take care of,
overseen by Isshiki-senpai.
Here it is!
We grow over ten kinds of vegetables in this field!
Good morning, Souma-kun and Yoshino-kun!
Morning labor is good for the spirit!
Let's sweat together!
It fits him to a T!
Knowing how food grows
is part of our training.
You could call this the Polar Star Farm,
or perhaps even the Isshiki Farm.
Uh, sure.
Oh, Souma-kun!
You're here too, Tadokoro?
Look!
Isshiki-senpai grew these vegetables.
Don't they look delicious?
Y'know, seeing you here in normal
clothing is very soothing.
Yeah, Megumi's a breath of
fresh air at Polar Star.
Here.
Why don't you try one?
Oh, thanks.
Delicious!
It's plump and super sweet.
I'd love to have these for our restaurant.
How'd you grow something of this caliber?
Oh, I spend all my time here.
I've been missing a lot of my classes lately.
Don't you have your priorities backwards?
Sorry to keep you guys waiting!
Whoa!
This is delicious too!
C'mon, Souma-kun, all you're doing is eating!
Aw, come on.
Breakfast time, everyone!
My back's killing me.
I'm starving!
Tadokoro, you made these?
Yeah. You must be hungry.
Dig right in.
Wow.
I see.
It's the Tadokoro-chan Special, the Rice Ball Trio.
Awesome, rice balls would hit the spot after all that fieldwork!
Thanks for the food!
So delicious!
There's green onions and salt in this, right?
You seasoned cooked chicken tenderloin with it
and also brushed some onto the rice ball!
The saltiness really excites your appetite!
Salty foods are so appealing
after doing manual labor.
This must be kelp.
It's a classic rice ball ingredient.
Kelp simmered in soy sauce and cheese?
Right!
The strong sweet flavor of the kelp pairs surprisingly well with the cheese.
So what's the last one?!
Delicious!
The garlic flavor rocks!
This one's pork marinated with garlic.
Wow!
After seeing you use honey in class the other day,
I decided to try something based on that.
I marinated boiled boneless pork rib in a mixture of garlic, miso, sake, and honey.
It goes really well with rice,
so I chopped it up and made rice balls with it!
Huh.
Oh, there's barley and roasted green tea as well.
Please have whichever you'd like.
This is the appeal of Tadokoro-chan's cooking.
It's comfort food that soothes everyone's souls.
The chicken is moist,
and the pork's nice and tender too.
Both bear the hallmarks of careful preparation.
So why can't you cook like this in class?
I've always had issues with stage fright.
When I get nervous, I blank out,
and then I fail at everything.
Oh, that's tough.
You should try to be more relaxed when you cook, Tadokoro-chan.
Yeah, Megumi.
You'd make a good cook and a good wife.
You think so?
Huh?
Research societies?
Yeah. Tohtsuki has lots of groups
that study various foods and cuisines.
For instance, some groups
develop new recipes after school.
Or they can compete in cooking
contests outside of the academy.
You could say it's Tohtsuki's
version of school clubs.
I'm in the Regional Cooking Research Society.
Huh.
You weren't kidding.
Asian and Western cuisine.
Imperial court and Buddhist cuisines.
Fermentation and preservation.
Oh, this one's for train bentos!
Huh?
The Donburi Research Society?
Maybe I'll find inspiration for our restaurant's menu.
All right, guess I'll go take a look.
Let's go, Tadokoro!
Huh?
I'm coming with you?
This is...
Sorry, but you should probably go.
Don RS is about to become history.
What?!
You said you're Yukihira and Tadokoro?
I'm Konishi, the leader of this research society.
You okay, Senpai?
You look pretty down.
Mock me all you want.
I couldn't save Don RS.
Are these recipe collections?
It's full of recipes created by Don RS.
Let's take a look.
From more mainstream items to offbeat ones,
these dishes are jazzed up with a spark of creativity.
These recipes are all interesting!
Why are you shutting down?
You understand?
Yukihira!
He's crying!
The don has a functional beauty that obeys the laws of speed, taste, and affordability!
It's so manly you can eat it completely with one arm!
It's food for men who fight!
I...
As a man...
I cannot die until I've created the ultimate don!
He really is something.
He's kind of oppressive.
My Don RS!
If only Nakiri Erina didn't exist!
Nakiri?
Right, this is how she works.
First, she'll propose that the council slash the budget or allotted space
for any group she doesn't like.
She coerces them into voting her way.
Once a group is cornered,
it's left with only one choice:
the last-ditch Cooking Battle!
In exchange for accepting the challenge,
Nakiri will make even more extreme demands.
In the end, she'll get what she wants.
That is how she expands her sphere of influence.
Once my members learned that our opponent is one of Nakiri's lackeys,
they all fled.
He couldn't inspire a loyal following, huh?
So are you facing off against Nakiri?
It's—
Hey!
Rather than renovating,
it'd be faster to raze this place
and rebuild from scratch.
Yeah?
Then let's do that.
Who do you think you are, Mito?!
What? I'm just checking this place out.
I already know the outcome, after all.
Like Erina-sama said,
no matter how much effort you put into a don,
it's a low-class dish relegated to class B gourmet fare.
"Tohtsuki has no need for such a dish," she said.
Well, it's a different story
if you think you can beat me.
Get it now, Mr. RS leader?
A club like this doesn't belong here.
Damn you, Nikumi.
My name isn't Nikumi.
If you ever call me that again...
Wait, she's your Cooking Battle opponent?
Who the hell's she?
She's Mito Ikumi-san,
also known as the Meat Master.
Ever since junior high,
she's always received high ratings.
And she's never received anything below an A rating for meat dishes.
Her knowledge of all things meat is said to be top-notch, even within the academy.
All ingredients must bow before worthy meat!
No matter what dish you may try to create,
you will never beat my super high-quality meat!
I think you give cooking a bad name if all you care about is the price of your ingredients.
Senpai...
would you let me handle this Cooking Battle?
Who the hell are you?
Outsiders should butt out.
Wait, you're that transfer student from the opening ceremony.
I've been wanting to talk to you.
You must have a lot of confidence in your skills
if you're butting into someone else's Cooking Battle.
Why don't we compete on your turf with a meat dish?
I'll win, though.
Then if I win, asshole,
are you willing to leave Tohtsuki?
If you don't have the balls
to do that, don't talk so big.
Sure, fine!
What?!
In return, if I win...
Yeah, you'll have to join Don RS.
Huh?
Huh?!
Join Don RS and contribute
to advancing donburi culture.
Call it penance for bothering us.
You really think you can beat me?
It's quitting time for all you contractors!
I'll cut you some slack with the theme.
The main ingredient will be meat,
and the dish will be the don.
The cook-off will be in three days!
Why'd you do that, Yukihira?
Oh.
She kept going on about how
pricey meat is everything,
and I couldn't let that pass
because I'm a diner brat.
Besides, I think this club's
too good to let it go to waste.
Yukihira!
But how are you going to beat her, Souma-kun?
I'll think of something.
I knew it!
I'm grateful to Erina-sama
for letting me handle this.
I'll teach that uppity transfer student
the pleasure of the flesh.
A bit more to the right. Just a bit more.
A little bit more.
What was Yukihira thinking?!
Everyone in the academy's talking about it!
Calm down, Yuuki!
I'll do my best to help,
but there's just too little time!
So what will you do, Souma-kun?
Since last night,
I've been giving this a lot of thought.
Nikumi's a specialist in meat,
beef in particular.
So, I don't think we should use beef.
For example, maybe we could
do a chicken-and-egg don.
Chicken still fits the theme.
We should differentiate ourselves from Nikumi as much as possible.
I see. An offbeat choice.
What kind of don do you like, Tadokoro?
Well, it's not a traditional don,
and it's not meat-based,
but I like taking scallops that've been lightly grilled in the shell
and seasoning them with a bit of butter and soy sauce.
They're godly on piping hot rice!
You're right.
We could've gone with a seafood don,
but you just had to go ahead
and say we'd do meat.
It's a done deal. Quit complaining!
You don't know how strong Nikumi is!
If we get slammed with
her A5 beef, we're done for!
"Eigo"?
English?
By A5 you mean the grade of beef, right?
Yeah, that's right.
The "A" is the yield grade, which is based on how much of a carcass is actually beef!
That ranges from A to C!
Then the firmness and texture of the meat,
the luster of the fat, and so on
determine the quality grade,
which ranges from 1 to 5!
Only beef that meets the highest qualifications for both grades
receives the A5 rating!
I've eaten one of Nikumi's steaks at an academy event.
At... At that level...
you can drink the meat!
Drink it?!
That's right!
The moment you bite into it,
the beef transforms into a mass of umami that glides down your throat.
If you were to order that
kind of meat at any store,
you'd have to throw down several Benjamins.
And there's something else
that you have to keep in mind.
Any ingredient you use in a Cooking Battle...
you must prepare yourself.
Procuring ingredients is considered an essential skill for chefs!
The Mito family operates a large-scale meat wholesale business.
They have the market cornered
when it comes to premium beef.
They have the finances,
the facilities, and the distribution.
All of this lies behind Nikumi's
premium-quality cooking...
He's bringing himself down with his own talk.
Can we really beat meat like that?
Y'know...
You know what?
Don RS should go with beef too.
Huh?!
Look here, Yukihira.
Were you even listening to me?
We don't have a snowball's chance in—
You said it yourself, Konishi-senpai.
The don is about speed, taste, and affordability.
Nikumi's making fun of that maxim.
If we're to make her respect the don,
we have to win with a fast and easy beef dish!
Also, we can't use super premium ingredients.
That's not where the don shines.
A-At times, men must compromise their principles in order to win.
Okay.
Let's go shopping.
How much do you have left in Don RS's budget?
W-Well...
Huh?
That's it?
I'll just have to chip in from my personal funds!
This is all I have?!
Thank you for your business.
I'll send you some money to live on.
This is what "some" meant?
That's what you meant?
This is rough.
I might be in trouble.
These are Don RS's recipe
collections from the past.
You might find something useful in there.
Senpai, I found some more of them.
Oh, thanks!
Put that stack over there.
All right!
Let's do this!
All done!
Have a taste, please!
A cutlet don, subbing in beef for pork!
I changed the Don RS recipe by using a mix of chicken and quail eggs,
so it should have a richer taste.
It's not bad, but it's still not enough!
There isn't enough impact in the first bite.
Nikumi's dishes always deliver
a punch in the mouth.
A punch, huh?
Then we're talking fat!
How about a sukiyaki don made with sugar and beef fat, all finished off with a chicken egg?
This won't work, either.
The flavor's not refined enough!
Okay, we can decrease the amount
of beef fat, and instead...
Um, how about this recipe?
Senpai's gone deathly pale again!
Splash water on him to get him back!
We've followed all the promising leads in Don RS's recipe collection.
We've tried every single variation we could think of.
Souma-kun, why don't you
go and get some rest?
Maybe you'll come up with something if you take a break,
just like that day in class.
Maybe.
Oh, like how I used honey
to tenderize the meat.
S-Souma-kun?
I owe you one, Tadokoro!
I've got an idea.
I think I know how to make
affordable meat sing!
Konishi-san!
It can be sirloin or even the rump!
Do you have any steaks left?
Steaks?
Slice a grid pattern into a steak,
then pound it out flat.
Spread minced onions on both sides of the meat, then let it rest.
Remove the onions,
then season the meat with salt and pepper.
Cook the steak in butter,
then sauté the onions in the drippings.
Onions...
Sprinkle the cooked onions on top of the meat, and it's done.
It's a Chaliapin steak!
When the opera singer
Fyodor Chaliapin came to Japan,
he was suffering from a toothache.
"May I have a tender steak?"
That request inspired this dish.
It's an offbeat dish that can only be found in Japan!
All right, both of you try it.
O-Okay!
A'ight.
So light!
It's so tender!
You can easily cut it with chopsticks!
And every time you bite into it...
...it dissolves in your mouth.
Onions have enzymes that tenderize proteins,
just like pineapples and honey.
That's why the meat is so tender.
I wouldn't have guessed
that this was a cheap cut of beef.
My mouth's full of its flavor.
And it goes without saying that it pairs well with rice.
But...
will this really be enough...
to surpass Nikumi's A5 meat?
I'll use Japanese Black wagyu fillet.
A5 grade, of course. Not only that,
it'll have been aged over a month to be at its peak flavor the day it's served.
In other words, it'll be an A5 to top all A5 beef.
I'll cook it in a way that optimizes its taste,
and I'll crush the Don RS.
I have high hopes.
Excuse me.
I didn't think an opportunity would come so soon.
Yukihira Souma.
I will take this chance to purge you from Tohtsuki.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the seventh dish:
The Quiet Don, the Eloquent Don.
Enjoy.
What a demanding body you have!