Too boring.
This one's no good.
Not this either.
I have to put my game face on today.
Let's go with this one!
Did you all hear about the Cooking Battle today?
Yeah, it's between Nikumi and the Don RS, right?
I feel bad for the Don RS, getting into Nakiri Erina's crosshairs like that.
Hey, did you read today's Tohtsuki Sports News?
They've changed the matchup.
See, Nikumi's facing off against
that cocky transfer student,
Yukihira Souma!
Here are the ingredients and tools for the match.
I got everything you asked for.
Yup. Thanks, Konishi-san!
Did you get any sleep at all, Yukihira?
I spent some more time tweaking the sauce.
I think I maybe got about two hours.
So many people!
S-Souma-kun, d-don't get too nervous!
D-Don't get nervous, okay?!
A-At times like this,
you write the character for "person" like so.
Okay, sure.
On your palm, okay?
Why don't you take care of that for me, Tadokoro?
On your palm, got it?!
On your palm-
Huh?
Aren't you nervous at all?
You're going to be cooking
in front of that huge crowd.
Nope.
This isn't scary in the least.
It's nothing like cooking in front of customers,
placing our restaurant's reputation on the line.
If I beat you,
will that make me the seventh best at Tohtsuki?
Ladies and gentlemen!
The Council has certified this match as an official Cooking Battle!
I am Kawashima Urara,
a first-year in the high school division.
I'll be your host for this event!
Super cute!
Urara-chan!
Hi!
Cute!
The contestants will now be making their entrances from those corners!
The first one to enter is...
the Meat Master, Mito Ikumi!
Hmph! Quit flaunting your giant melons,
you Holstein cow!
I'm the only one here who should have fanboys!
All right!
Here comes the other contestant!
Die, dipshit!
Eat it!
Die, transfer student!
I still remember the shit you pulled at the opening ceremony!
The transfer student who's already gained widespread notoriety,
Yukihira Souma-kun!
Between him and Mito,
it's obvious who'll win.
Yeah, I can't wait to see him get expelled!
Hey, what's with this massive crowd?
I'll never forget it.
When I had a Cooking Battle with the
Stand-up Dining Soba Research Society,
there wasn't a host, much less an audience.
The only witnesses were stray dogs attracted by the smell of food.
And what's with this hostility?
Didn't you just transfer in this spring?
Why do you already have so many haters?
Dunno. I haven't done anything weird.
And now, here are the terms of this match!
There will be three judges.
The theme is the don.
The main ingredient is meat!
If Mito-san wins,
the Donburi Research Society will be shut down,
and Yukihira-kun will be expelled.
If Yukihira-kun wins,
the Don RS's budget will be increased,
and their cooking facilities will be renovated.
Finally,
Mito-san will join the Don RS!
Hey, transfer student.
Today'll be the last day that you can talk to me.
If you've got any last words, now's the time.
Really?
I don't see why we can't talk anytime we want
when we're in the Don RS club room.
Hey, look!
It's Nakiri Erina.
Erina-sama...
Erina-sama!
Wow, seriously?!
Why?
Why would one of the Elite Ten bother to attend
a small-time Cooking Battle
involving the Don RS?
It's because Mito is part of
Nakiri Erina's faction, isn't it?
Really?
Is that the only reason?
All right, Yukihira-kun.
Show me how you lose in utter disgrace.
Erina-sama has come all this way to watch us?
Let us proceed!
Contestants, to your stations!
Everything is at stake
in this battle of the palates!
Let the Cooking Battle...
begin!
Transfer student!
Let me show you something that a low-life like you could never hope to touch in his whole sorry life!
Behold, the ultimate meat!
I told you that's what she would use!
It's A5 beef!
That's a cleaver for butchering meat.
She's wielding that big knife with precision
to sever the tendons.
Her strength is incredible!
I've never seen marbling that fine!
The glistening of the fat and muscle is unbelievable!
Attaboy.
There's a faint sweetness that tickles the nose.
As meat ages,
the quantity of umami factors
like glutamic acid increases,
which results in a sweet smell.
I'm going to prepare the finest meat
with the finest skills!
First, I'll sear the meat...
while basting it with butter!
The rich scent of butter is permeating the arena!
Just a whiff of it is enough
to whet your appetite!
I've now built a wall around
the meat to trap the juices inside.
Next...
Put the meat in the oven,
and cook it all the way through.
Well, then.
How's the transfer student doing?
As for Yukihira-kun,
it seems he has just finished mincing a large number of onions.
Just what could he be planning to do with them?
Oh!
Looks like he's finally taking out his meat!
Let's see how his meat measures up to Mito-san's A5-grade wagyu beef!
What?
"Cheap."
"Half off"?
I lucked out! It happened to be on sale!
This is bullshit!
Oh, please stop!
Please stop throwing things!
Yukihira, are you sure you know what you're doing?
I've seen enough.
You can just use the rest of your time to pack up.
Can you tell what the foundation of her cooking is?
Could it be her sheer strength,
which allows her to carve up a carcass with ease?
That's certainly one of her talents.
But her true strength lies in the opposite direction.
It's her delicate sensibility.
64—
No, 65 degrees Celsius.
Okay.
The lips are among the most
temperature-sensitive body parts we have.
Even so,
her ability to precisely determine
the temperature of meat is unique.
Mito Ikumi's sensibility shines brightest when she handles meat.
You're right.
Look at her fingertips,
the depth of her affection toward the meat.
It's like watching a piano soloist
in a flowing performance.
Can't you hear the heavenly melody?
The sonata of meat?
I will present this victory to Erina-sama!
What, you're still here?
Why have you grown quiet all
of a sudden, transfer student?
What happened to that bravado
from three days ago?
Say something, you pathetic wretch.
I don't need to say a word.
Soon my don will be telling an eloquent tale.
Huh?
Besides...
it's common knowledge that any chef who talks too much in the kitchen
can't be trusted to have any actual talent.
Are you mocking me?!
What?
What's he trying to pull?
Time's running out!
Time's up!
I love reading fairy tales!
I love romance movies too!
My dream is to become a bride!
The judging will now commence.
Mito-san's dish will go first.
Mine's a "Rôti" Don made with A5 wagyu beef!
Rôti is French for "roast."
It's often used to denote
dishes cooked in the oven!
The sliced meat is like a flower.
I'm honored to be presented with such a beautiful don.
Thank you for the food!
It's so delicious that it's paralyzing!
This is it!
This profound umami is the A5's true strength!
And this meat...
She even accounted for the angle at which the heat was applied.
When heat is applied perpendicular to the grain of the meat,
that energy is spread evenly,
and more juices are released.
The best chefs take even the grain
of the meat into account!
And note what's beneath the "petals"!
The garlic rice sautéed in beef fat and butter is exquisite!
I could eat three bowls of this rice alone!
This dish is fantastic, even seductive!
It's superb!
Do you get it now, transfer student?
This is the pleasure of meat!
It's a blowout.
Just let us see the transfer student's face when he loses already.
We're in trouble.
The crowd seems to think Mito-san's won.
Let's have the judges evaluate Yukihira-kun's dish now!
What would you call your don?
Well, how about the Yukihira-style
Chaliapin Steak Don?
Chaliapin steak, huh?
So you used onions to tenderize cheap meat.
But how could it measure up
to what we've just tasted?
Indeed, I'd just rather go home while
savoring the lingering flavor of A5 beef.
W-Well, it looks more promising
than I'd initially thought.
Guess we'll give it a try.
There's no way he could turn that
cheap meat into anything decent—
How can this be?
I can't... I can't stop eating!
The meat is most tender, but—
This sauce!
This fantastic minced onion sauce is an excellent spur to the appetite!
What is this?!
This full-bodied flavor must be from the red wine he added to the pan after the steak was done!
He deglazed the pan with it,
then sautéed the onion in the pan!
Thickened with potato starch,
the creaminess of the sauce,
coating the meat and rice, is irresistible!
Not to mention, the flavors are
rounded off by the burnt soy sauce!
He leveraged the burnt soy
sauce to enhance the flavor!
Yukihira!
Seems like he tweaked the onions,
a key ingredient in the Chaliapin steak,
and the sauce to boot.
But is that all?
In the end, sauce is just sauce.
It's got nothing on my premium meat!
Even though the meat and sauce
are both strong in flavor,
I only get hungrier with every bite.
It sure does feel like I could eat this forever!
This hint of acidity...
Could it be?
Yes, the trick's in the rice.
The rice?
I mixed handmade pickled plum
paste into the don's rice.
It's Refreshing Plum-Flavored Rice!
I knew it!
Pickled plums were behind
this refreshing aftertaste!
The texture of this steak is so light, yet the flavors are so fragrant!
The superb sauce with its signature creaminess!
And the refreshing pickled plum-flavored rice!
Each component builds upon the others' flavor!
You can't stop shoveling it all in!
Pickled plum? That's it?
He may have used a few gimmicks,
but it doesn't change the fact
that each ingredient is cheap!
Man, I'm already done!
How about seconds?
Can we have seconds?
The Rôti Don was fantastic as well,
but this don is better at
making you want to eat more.
What?
Wh-What about my garlic rice?
None of you finished it!
Oh, yeah.
I was wondering what you
were going to do about the rice,
ever since Konishi-san said you'd be using marbled wagyu beef.
If you beef up the rice after amplifying the wagyu beef's umami,
of course the two would clash.
Your dish may look like a don,
but it's not a real don.
The Don RS's leader said that the don has to be a complete package in one bowl.
Shut up.
I'm not interested in your twisted logic.
There's no way you could defeat my premium meat—
If you're not convinced,
why not try it yourself?
Listen to the story my don tells.
Dig in.
Yeah, he's right.
This don talks to you.
"Shovel in as much of me as you want."
Happy ninth birthday, Ikumi.
Thank you very much, Mother!
Darling, please stop!
Shut up!
The Mito clan has no need for
an heir with a ladylike demeanor!
Listen, Ikumi.
Be strong.
That's what you need to focus on.
Understand?
Shit. Why am I remembering that now?
It's because of this don.
This don's whispering to me
that I can just be myself,
be who I really am.
Damn it!
What an upset! The victor is Yukihira Souma!
Glad you liked it!
Souma-kun's amazing!
He did it!
Yukihira!
What?
I lost.
Erina-sama!
Evict her from the kitchen we provided to her.
As you wish.
Hey, Nikumi.
Let me try some of your don too.
Who the hell do you think you are?!
Don't you dare call me that!
Why not?
It's pretty cute when you write it out in hiragana.
H-Huh?
I'm looking forward to working with you,
Nikumi-chan.
Wh-What did you say?
You idiot!
Don't forget to come to the club room!
Yukihira.
You're really something, man.
You're the only one who can
lead the Don RS going forward.
You'll be the next "don" of the Don RS,
Yukihira!
It's pretty cute.
I-I'm coming in!
Oh, hey, Mito!
So you came.
Y-Yeah.
G-Guess Yukihira's not here yet.
I'm only here because he told me I had to come.
Oh, well...
Huh?
But I'm not joining the Don RS.
What?!
Huh?
I just wanted to check it out.
But hey, thanks to the Don RS,
I came up with a new don menu that
I could serve at our restaurant someday.
Well, good luck with everything.
I'll drop by sometimes.
That's what he said.
But because our budget was increased,
let's work together to build up the Don RS!
You're the only one who can lead
the Don RS going forward.
You'll be the next "don" of the Don RS,
Nikumi!
Shut up!
Don't you dare call me Nikumi!
It's said that from that day forward,
Mito Ikumi-san became even more violent.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the eighth dish:
The Concerto of Inspiration and Imagination.
Looks delicious!
Cute!
What a demanding body you have.
I'm moe-moe-ed out.