That time has come once more.
Have the students been informed?
They will all be notified by day's end.
At the academy, some will rise and some will fall.
This is where their paths begin to diverge.
Training camp?
It's that time of year again, huh?
What's this about?
You had something like this in middle school, didn't you?
We're going to a camp and staying there for a few nights.
Really? I had no idea the academy did stuff like that.
Why are you trembling, Tadokoro?
This camp represents the first circle of hell
for new high school students.
All first-years will be tasked with
grueling cooking projects every day,
in a remote location in the mountains.
If we don't earn a passing score,
we face immediate expulsion.
They claim it's an opportunity to strengthen our bonds,
it's a merciless gauntlet for
weeding out the weak!
This is what they mean by
education through competition.
The director spoke of the one percent.
This is where the selection process really begins.
Isshiki-senpai, you went to
this camp last year, right?
Yes, of course.
When I attended last year's training camp,
dozens were expelled and sent home each day.
Expelled?
After one camp some years ago,
half of the participating students
were shown the door.
Half?
Megumi?!
I'm grateful for the time
we've had together, everyone.
Megumi!
Okay, so we can bring playing cards and shogi sets,
but video games aren't allowed.
What, they don't give us any time for taking baths?
Hey, Yukihira!
How can you be so carefree and be planning your trip already?
Megumi's practically on her deathbed here!
Half the class will make it, right?
All we have to do is be in that half.
I'm also quite certain
that everyone in Polar Star
will come back smiling.
I'll make it back here!
I sure will!
Of course.
You're right.
We're all so determined!
We Polar Stars strike fear into the hearts of men!
We do?
Let's dominate this camp!
That's the spirit.
Fumio-san and I will hold the fort.
Give it your best shot!
Yeah!
Okay!
Got it!
I'm on fire!
That concludes the overview.
Please don't forget anything.
You'll depart in three days.
Everyone is to assemble at 6:00 AM.
I see.
Thank you, Hisako.
My stomach hurts!
I'm kind of getting jaded.
A'ight!
Let's go!
Off to the friendship and
team-building camp from hell!
Nothing's gonna surprise me any more!
Wow!
Th-This is our "camp" site?
Guess this school is full of rich guys for a reason.
They even run a big-ass hotel.
All of the hotels and inns around
here belong to Tohtsuki.
Heh, doesn't surprise me one bit!
They manage a dozen or so accommodations under the Tohtsuki Resorts brand,
and graduates often end up working in the resorts' culinary division.
I've heard it costs upwards of 80,000 yen
per night at these places.
That's like a month's rent!
I'm definitely not surprised at all!
You're totally surprised, Souma-kun.
Wait, so we're staying here tonight?
Wow, this is super exciting!
If we can survive today's task.
Boo!
Ibusaki, you're such a downer.
I'm just being realistic.
See?
There's an assembly as soon as we drop off our bags.
Okay.
It's too quiet.
It's hard to believe that nearly
a thousand students are here.
That's right.
What's about to start is the training camp from hell.
How many of us will survive?
Look, it's Nikumi!
Y-Yukihira!
Been a while, Nikumi!
You're not nervous at all, huh?
Hey, Yukihira-kun!
Why are you calling her by a nickname?
Huh? But she's fine with it.
Right, Nikumi?
Of course not!
See?
It's the transfer student.
She likes it.
Yukihira Souma.
Be careful, Yukihira.
Huh? About what?
Good morning, students!
I will now provide an overview of this camp.
You're scheduled to stay here
for five nights and six days.
During this time, you'll split off into several groups
and take on a new assignment each day.
Students whose instructors' evaluations fall below a certain baseline will be failed,
sent back to the academy,
and expelled.
To evaluate your tasks,
we have invited some guest lecturers.
Guests?
They're Tohtsuki alumni who have graciously agreed to join us,
in spite of their busy schedules.
Tohtsuki alumni?
That means...
they're all geniuses who managed to remain in the 90th percentile!
Hm, you over there.
Nine rows back,
the boy with a scar on his eyebrow.
Oh, sorry.
I mean the one to your right.
Yeah, you.
You're expelled.
You may leave now.
What?!
Your hair product has a citrus scent.
It interferes with the aroma of the food.
We do need to pay attention
to our sense of style.
If chefs have no sense of style,
their dishes will have no appeal.
But you should choose an unscented hair product from now on.
Wait!
I'm getting expelled just for that?!
Just that can be enough to lose your customers.
Are you trying to destroy my restaurant?
Farewell, student.
Who's that?
It's Chef Shinomiya!
He's the first Japanese national to win the French Pluspol award!
Not to mention...
Onstage are also Chef Mizuhara from F,
and Head Chef Sekimori from the sushi restaurant Ginza Hinowa!
Wow!
They're all people featured
in magazines every month!
You, girl who is innocent like a white clover!
That's Donato Gotoda of the auberge Tesoro!
You may be the reason for my existence.
Why don't we talk through the night till dawn at my auberge?
Um, what?
Um, excuse me!
Let go of her hand, Chef Gotoda.
Hinako.
It's Inui Hinako of the Japanese restaurant Kirinoya!
I'm sorry that you had such a frightening experience.
You're very cute, by the way.
I'm sure you'd be very good to eat.
Hinako.
Chapelle-sensei's glaring at us.
Let's go.
Oh.
Please come by my restaurant sometime!
Pssssh...
Oh! That's...
That's the man who graduated first in his class
after getting the highest score ever on the graduation exam!
He turned down over 800 offers from
high-caliber restaurants around the world.
Instead, he took the position of Executive Chef and Company Director of Tohtsuki Resorts!
Doujima Gin!
This is incredible.
All the star chefs leading Japan's culinary world
are lined up in front of me!
Welcome to my Tohtsuki Resort.
Each of the alumni who have gathered here today is a chef who owns his or her own restaurant.
For the next six days of the training camp,
we will treat you as we would our own staff.
Do you understand what that entails?
Those who cannot perform to our expectations...
will be fired!
Or in your case, expelled.
As you have already seen, at their discretion,
you may be dismissed at the drop of a hat.
I wish you all the best of luck.
Now, proceed to your groups!
We're all split up, but I wish you all the best!
I'm with you again?!
What's it to you?!
Later!
Yeah!
Oh, don't forget we're having
a card game in Marui's room later!
You don't all have to come
to my room even during camp!
Wanna drink?
Sure.
It seems you're all here.
In my class, you'll be working in pairs.
You'll be in the same pairs as in your first practicum of the semester.
Please go to your workstations.
Thank goodness! I'm with you again, Souma-kun!
Yup, let's give this a whirl.
Yukihira Souma, is it?
Yeah, so?
You've been grinding your foot
into mine for the last ten seconds,
so I guess I can assume it's intentional?
Of course.
I was wondering when I'd get to mess with you during camp,
but I didn't think I'd be lucky enough
to get close to you in our first task.
I'll crush you, just like I did your shoe.
Huh?
U-Um, we already know it's going
to be an intense camp.
W-We shouldn't be fighting on top of that.
I can finally put you in your place.
That makes me happy, Yukihira Souma!
I see.
Well, good for you.
I get the picture already, so move your foot!
Okay, everyone!
I'll be sitting right here,
so feel free to ask me any
questions you might have.
Excuse me, Chef Inui,
but we weren't given any instructions.
Oh, is that right?
Let me see.
Hm, my task for you is this.
Use the ingredients there to make a dish
that could serve as a main course in Japanese cuisine.
Ingredients? But...
There's nothing there.
Of course there is!
We're amid glorious nature,
right next to a clear stream.
There are ingredients galore.
We also have spices, condiments, and oil,
not to mention cooking utensils.
You are welcome to use other tools,
such as fishing poles.
We're on private property that is encircled by a fence.
If you cross that fence, you will be disqualified.
Obtain your ingredients from this limited space and prepare them.
You will pass if you create a dish
that I find satisfactory.
This session is two hours long,
so you should probably get to it.
Huh? You mean we should've already started?!
Why didn't you say so?!
We have to figure out what we can fish up first!
Sweetfish!
We can just grill it with salt!
But are they even in season right now?!
Whatever! We have less than two hours!
Hurry!
It's face-off time, Yukihira!
What do you mean?
Let's decide who's the better chef.
Chef Inui, I'd like you to make the call.
Please use your rigorous judgment and decide whose cooking tastes better!
Um, what?
That has nothing to do with my task,
so I would prefer not to.
Oh. I suppose you're right.
Hey, what're you gonna do?
Because you got on your high horse,
you're making everyone uncomfortable.
That was really lame, bro!
Shut up! Don't you laugh at me too!
"Bro"?! They're brothers?!
They look nothing alike!
I-In any case, I cannot lose to you!
I'll make a dish that tops yours!
Got it, Yukihira?!
C'mon, let's go!
What's up with him?
Oh, Souma-kun!
We should get going too!
Good luck!
Everyone develops tunnel vision
when placed in an unfamiliar situation.
Damn it! I'm not getting any bites!
Quiet, idiot! You're scaring the fish away!
Okay! I can make this into a meunière.
But we don't have any flour!
I told you to look for something like bamboo shoots!
I did look, but I couldn't find anything!
Bamboo Shoot
m 847.5 577.5 l 1099.5 577.5 1099.5 663 847.5 663
Their thinking slows to a crawl,
and they misjudge their options.
This task is merely a warm-up exercise.
Any chef who's daunted by something
like this isn't needed at Tohtsuki.
We need to finish fishing ASAP and get cooking!
What should we cook, Souma-kun?
If we get char or rainbow trout, maybe we can grill it with salt?
Or maybe braise it?
We have to think of the accompaniments too!
Maybe there are mountain
vegetables or something!
But everyone else will be thinking
the same way, y'know?
I want to go for a bit of a twist.
We don't have time for that!
We have to finish our dish!
Sure, but...
You caught it!
Yay!
We managed to get the fish, at least.
Yup.
We just have to figure out how to prepare 'em.
Please use your rigorous judgment!
Shut up!
Shut up, okay?
You guys are using fish too?
This is ridiculous.
Everyone's going with fish because of the theme.
Isn't that awfully narrow-minded?
Get off your high horse.
You got something better?
Can't you tell?
It's duck!
What?! Duck?!
We didn't just find duck.
There were chickens and rabbits too.
We were wondering why
no one else was around.
Damn it!
I had no idea there were
ingredients other than river fish.
But it's not like we've ever
dressed that kind of meat.
Out of my way.
Step aside, Yukihira.
Isami!
Okay!
He's separating the breast and
thigh meat with such precision.
But despite that speed,
he's not damaging the innards at all.
What agile knife work.
Yes? Did you want to ask me something?
N-No, I was just admiring your skills.
Really?
But my brother can finish this
three times faster than me.
There's no break in the work flow between any steps.
His moves are smooth and efficient.
Just who is he?
Well, I had no doubt that he'd be at least this good.
He has hands that look like
they'd been tested in an actual kitchen.
Forno accendere.
Forgive my belated introduction.
My name is Takumi Aldini.
This is my younger twin.
Isami Aldini.
We previously worked in
our family's trattoria in Italy.
"Trattoria"?
In Italian, it means a restaurant for the masses.
I'm the same as you, Yukihira.
I too am a chef who's been protecting his restaurant on the front lines.
I remember what you said
at the opening ceremony.
I don't plan on losing to folks
who've never served a single customer.
You identified yourself as a professional.
As a fellow professional, I cannot lose to you.
Let's show the world who's the better chef, Aldini or Yukihira!
Great!
Come at me!
What?!
Very well.
What's that?!
A mezzaluna.
A double-handed knife used in Italy whose name means "half-moon."
Let's go!
Tritare!
He has complete mastery over that strange knife!
The ingredients are rapidly turning into a paste!
The duck's almost done.
We'll finish the salsa at the same time.
Got it.
I'm ready.
All right!
What?!
Tre...
Due...
Uno...
Fine!
You're the first to finish!
Nimbleness is one of Italian
cuisine's charms, after all.
They're way too fast!
They had to dress the duck too!
I can't believe they didn't even take an hour!
Grilled duck with herbs
and a green sauce.
Buon appetito!
Well then,
I'll have a taste.
The fragrant, wild flavor of the duck
is heightened by the astringent sauce!
The masculinity and class of this dish is like a heavy bass resounding in the recesses of my stomach.
It is as if...
the duck were singing an aria.
I wouldn't mind being embraced
by a duck like this!
Hey!
That green sauce.
Isn't it salsa verde?
Isn't that a staple in Italian cuisine, made from chopped anchovies and flat-leaf parsley?
What are they thinking?!
The theme's Japanese cuisine!
They're gonna get failed for sure!
No, this sauce was not prepared with anchovies
but with uruka, salted sweetfish offal.
Uruka is traditionally made over the course of a week or more,
but this one is instant, isn't it?
Yes.
We boiled the rinsed sweetfish guts in sake,
then seasoned it with mirin, soy sauce, and salt.
We were able to quickly make a rich uruka,
with just the right amount of bitterness.
How is that possible?
That wasn't their only ingenious idea.
Instead of parsley, they chopped perilla and chives,
producing the vibrant green
color and astringent flavor.
They also subbed in yuzu pepper
paste instead of garlic,
which is rarely used in Japanese cuisine,
in order to bring the dish closer to the theme.
That's right!
This is Japanese-style salsa verde,
using instant uruka as the base!
They created a Japanese version of an Italian sauce?
Damn it!
I'm getting hungry just listening to them talk.
How'd they manage to combine that many ingredients out here in the mountains?
Unlike Japan,
Italy has a long tradition of meat-based cuisine.
In their homeland of Tuscany,
meats such as duck, rabbit, and boar are served when in season.
They must've learned how to
dress duck while living there.
The breast has been basted with a sauce made from soy sauce, mustard, black pepper, and honey,
then grilled to aromatic perfection.
It pairs well with the sauce.
You've introduced core elements of Japanese cuisine into both the duck and the salsa verde,
and you've pulled it all together into an exquisite Japanese dish.
Takumi Aldini and Isami Aldini,
you have passed my test.
Grazie!
He used his wits to create an exceptional dish,
despite the limitations imposed upon us.
He reminds me...
of Souma-kun.
Ah! Merveilleuse!
Nakiri Erina, you have passed my test!
Good day.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the ninth dish:
The Batter to Adorn the Mountains.
Grazie!
Grazie.
I'm gonna step on you!
Bro, you're being lame.