3 Years Ago in Florence, Tuscany, Italy
Buon appetito.
You've become even better than before, Takumi.
With Isami at your side, Aldini is in good hands.
Takumi, will you go out with me?
Looking good as usual, Takumi.
Why don't we have some fun?
Takumi, want to learn how to have a good time?
Si, grazie.
I appreciate the thought,
but there's something I have to do.
Are you sure you can afford
to let both of them go, Bro?
Yes. Even as their father,
I can see that they're great chefs,
but there is a certain something that Takumi lacks.
A culinary school in Japan?
I don't get it, Uncle.
What's the point in us attending a place like that?
We've been working here at Aldini
for eight years already.
Well, there's no harm in giving it a try.
The school's top-notch and world-famous.
You can leave the restaurant in my brother's-
I mean, your father's hands.
Focus on being the best chefs you can be.
We'd be transferring into
the second year of junior high.
What do you think, Isami?
I'll go if you do.
Takumi will surpass me in a few years.
But he doesn't have a goal beyond that.
What he needs right now is a worthy rival.
There's no way I can lose to any chef my age.
I'm a professional who has fought on the front lines.
I wasn't expecting to transfer here,
but I don't plan on losing to folks
who've never served a single customer.
Anyway, what I'm getting at is...
I just want to make it clear that
the number one spot is mine!
Mezzaluna.
Tritare!
Tre...
Duo...
Uno...
Fine!
You've introduced core elements of Japanese cuisine
into both the duck and the salsa verde,
pulling it all together into
an exquisite Japanese dish.
Takumi Aldini and Isami Aldini,
you have passed my test.
Grazie!
They're way too fast!
They had to dress the duck too.
I can't believe they didn't even take an hour!
Well, Yukihira Souma?
You don't seem to have made much headway.
What are you going to prepare for us?
I see.
You said you were competing with each other.
Very well.
If I can expect a dish that will be on par with what I just tasted,
I will make an exception and judge which of your dishes is better.
Did you hear that, Yukihira?
Sure! Let's do this!
Good. Whoever loses must kneel.
Huh?
Kneel before the victor,
and say "I am a loser" three times.
If you're staking the reputation of your restaurants,
then the penalty for losing
must be at least that heavy.
Oh, but you don't have to kneel,
Tadokoro Megumi-san.
You have such beautiful hands.
Sh-She really scares me!
Anyway, I dare you to make
a dish that surpasses ours!
These two made no assumptions coming into this.
They decided on a duck dish
and assembled an impressive list
of ingredients that would enhance it.
Think.
What's the best possible dish
I can make, here and now?
Use the ingredients there
to make a dish that could serve as
a main course in Japanese cuisine.
There were chickens and rabbits too.
Tadokoro.
Yes?
I'd like to use these ingredients
for the accompaniment.
I want you to gather them.
Think you can find all of this?
Um, yeah.
I think I can do it!
I often foraged for mountain
vegetables back home.
Great.
I'm counting on you, Tadokoro!
But what will you be doing, Souma-kun?
There's something else I need to track down,
so I'm heading out again.
Oh, but before I do...
Inui-senpai.
You said we can use anything we find, right?
What?
Oh, yes.
As long as it's within the fenced-off area.
Then the key ingredient for our dish will be...
this!
Huh?
Wha—
That's—
No!
The snack I'm having with my tea!
K-Kaki rice crackers?
So anyway, we're going outside again.
Oh, can you hang onto this for me?
Huh?
Why me?
All right! Let's go, Tadokoro!
O-Okay!
Wait!
My kaki rice crackers!
Yukihira...
What do you have up your sleeve?
And that's the last thing on this list!
Ow!
Damn you!
If there are chickens running around, that means...
There!
Yeah!
Freshly laid eggs!
This tastes terrible.
Try again.
Are we ever gonna pass?
So many have tried already,
but only a few pairs have passed.
What should we do?
Inui Hinako.
An alumna of Tohtsuki's 80th graduating class.
In her student days, she was known
as the Empress of Mist.
Everyone feared her.
The Empress of Mist?
I have no idea what that means,
but it sounds impressive.
Who gave her that nickname?
In any event, I must say...
There's been so many grilled fish.
Everything has the same texture.
I'm in the mood for something with more bite.
That's easy for her to say.
We're in the middle of nowhere!
What are we supposed to make?
Oh, you're all welcome to keep
making new dishes until time's up.
Sh-Shit! Let's try again!
It's hopeless!
There's no time!
I sure am glad we passed, Bro.
Why isn't Yukihira back yet?
He'll run out of time!
You should calm down.
If he doesn't finish in time, you'll win by default. What's the problem?
I want a heated battle!
A win by default is worthless to me!
Besides,
this thing he just handed to me...
Just how does he intend to use it in his dish?
Yukihira!
You're late.
You only have 15 minutes left!
Are you trying to get disqualified so you won't have to face me?!
Bro, you crushed it.
Ah, sorry!
I-It's not what it looks like, Yukihira!
Don't worry about it.
You saved me some time.
Thanks.
Speaking of time, we have a whole 15 minutes.
What?
If I made my customers wait 15 minutes,
they'd all leave.
Let's do this, Tadokoro!
Okay!
I saved him time?
Prepare the mountain vegetables.
First, trim the Devil's walking sticks.
Be thorough...
Thorough...
Once you're done, separate
the egg yolks from the egg whites.
Okay.
Huh?
We're making a deep-fried dish?
Yup, fried river fish.
But we don't have flour or potato starch.
There's nothing to use as batter.
You're not going to cook
without batter, are you?
The moisture content of river fish is too high.
Frying them won't work well.
Don't you worry. We have the perfect breading.
River fish.
Chicken eggs.
Rice crackers.
I get it now!
So that's how Yukihira's going
to use the rice crackers!
He's going to crush them
and use them as breading!
All right!
It's done!
Here you go, Inui-senpai.
Please try it before it grows cold.
All right, I'll have a taste.
Oh, my.
My kaki rice crackers have become part of
such a lovely deep-fried dish!
What a wonderful texture!
So crunchy.
Yet inside, the fish is very tender.
Protected by the breading,
the fish's umami has been concentrated within.
And thanks to the flavor
of the kaki rice crackers,
the breading has its own assertive taste.
The accompanying sauce is light as air,
made from Japanese mayonnaise and kinome.
Japanese mayonnaise?
That's made by beating together
vegetable oil and egg yolks, right?
And then they made a sauce with it?
He mixed chopped kinome, which are shoots of the Japanese pepper tree,
into the mayonnaise, along with some salt.
He created a refreshing flavor that cuts the oiliness of the fish,
making the dish more refined.
The creaminess that you can taste
between the crunchiness of the breading whets the appetite.
The fried mountain vegetables
are excellent as well.
The visual contrast with the char is superb.
I've assigned this task many times in the past.
I've seen some decent fried dishes without breading,
but this is the first successful attempt with breading.
The kaki rice crackers are embracing the char at the peak of its season.
It's like a passionate embrace
with an elegant mermaid.
No, I can't...
I'm drowning in my love of kaki rice crackers!
Where'd you come up with this idea, Souma-kun?
Have you heard of something called okaki-age?
You deep-fry ingredients in a breading of crushed okaki crackers.
The crumbs are used to improve
the texture or introduce a novel flavor.
I've made it at home before.
And that inspired you to try it
with kaki rice crackers instead?
That's right.
I call it, Yukihira-style Char Okaki-A—
No, I call it, Yukihira-style Char O-Kaki-Age!
You came up with that right now, didn't you?!
I had that in mind all along!
You're just making things up as you go!
I haven't strayed from my path!
Aldini-kun kept an open mind
That was just chance.
It was blind luck!
and did not overlook duck as a possible ingredient.
You were just damn lucky!
It's actually a menu item that's pretty common at Yukihira too.
On the other hand, Yukihira-kun
drew upon his unusual creativity
to make a dish no one here could've expected.
Despite the constraints of time and circumstance, they both rose to the occasion
and made a dish that they could call their own.
That is the mindset of a true professional.
Yukihira Souma and Tadokoro Megumi,
you have passed my test.
Glad you liked it!
Uh... Napolitan?
Wrong!
Okay, time's up!
The session is now complete.
Thank goodness.
I'm finished!
Shit!
Chef Inui.
Please make your decision.
Very well.
I will announce the victor.
The one who crafted a splendid texture for the char,
using an idea no one else had.
Wait, please give me a moment.
All right, I've made my decision.
The one who did not overlook duck as a possibility,
despite being thrown into an unfamiliar situation,
and surpassed others with his choice of ingredients.
Well, on the other hand...
What are they doing?
A comedy skit?
Ugh!
What is it now?
I'm in the middle of something important—
What're you up to, Hinako?!
Your group of students should've been back a long time ago.
Just get your ass back here, idiot.
S-Sorry, Shinomiya-senpai!
E-Everyone, we should hurry back to the hotel!
Hey!
What's your decision, Inui-senpai?!
Eek!
Oh, right!
I'll...
have to revisit that.
All right, everyone on the bus!
She kept us in suspense for so long!
She ducked out of making a choice!
I'm not letting this go!
Listen up, Yukihira!
We'll settle this someday!
Sure, but how?
Sooner or later, I will challenge
you to a Cooking Battle.
Don't you dare run away.
You'll have to accept.
And that's when I will crush you!
You'd do well to hone your skills before then as best you can.
Until we meet again, Yukihira Souma.
Seat yourselves as far back as you can!
Let's go!
So we meet again!
Shut up!
Don't talk to me!
What's the matter?
Aren't you gonna crush me?
I told you, don't talk to me!
That test allowed me to take full advantage
of the knowledge and techniques I've cultivated over the years.
When I had the inspiration for my dish,
I was convinced that I would win.
But he held his own.
Shit.
She didn't say which dish
she thought was better.
So why do I feel like I've lost?
This isn't over.
I will defeat you.
Takumi of Trattoria Aldini, huh?
There's someone my age who's that good.
If I had stayed holed up in Yukihira,
I never would've known about him.
Megumi!
Yukihira!
You made it!
Yuuki-chan, Ryouko-chan!
What about the others?
Ibusaki-kun's checking on them right now.
Got it. Well done.
All the Polar Star members
made it through the first day.
Whew!
Are you sure Marui made it?
He was running around in the mountains the whole time, apparently.
Oh, guess his test was similar to ours, then.
Man, I'm tired.
I can barely move.
Don't be ridiculous, ladies.
We're about to reap our rewards!
Rewards?
Dinner, bath, and hotel room!
I bet they'll all be extravagant and sumptuous!
And I'm going to enjoy all of it
to the absolute fullest!
Those of you who finish serving them
dinner will be allowed to have free time.
Who are all these people?!
The Jouwan University bodybuilder
club is staying nearby.
The American football and wrestling clubs will be arriving soon.
Our dinner today consists of a steak set.
Each of you will prepare fifty servings.
Fifty servings each?!
Now?!
You've got to be kidding me!
But, Sekimori-senpai!
What about our dinner?
Once you've finished preparing
fifty servings, you can make your own.
Make our own?
But what about...
What about our extravagant dinners?
There will be no such thing.
You should also know that
during your training camp,
you will be preparing your
own breakfasts and dinners.
Oh...
I can hear Yuuki's heart breaking.
Lastly,
if you cannot finish serving our guests' dinner within the next sixty minutes,
you will be expelled on the spot.
Begin!
Hey, don't cut in line!
You're taking too long!
This, this, and this.
The portions aren't large enough. Start over.
Seconds.
Seconds!
Not full yet.
Ten more bowls!
I can't lift my arms.
I still have thirty servings left.
I can't take it anymore!
I'm not done yet!
Not done!
Hey, Marui.
Are you okay?
This camp is hell after all.
Food!
Food! Food!
It's hell on Earth, all right!
Yukihira Souma, fifty servings complete!
You pass the test!
Glad you liked it!
He's so fast!
Shit!
He finished before me!
But just wait, Yukihira!
Mine will taste better!
I think.
You, there!
Move your hands, not your mouth!
Yes, sir.
Well, I'll be in Marui's room.
Don't you dare!
I want to go to bed early tonight!
Hey!
Hurry up, four-eyes!
He still wants to play?
Yukihira sure has a lot of stamina.
I said I'd wait in Marui's room,
but I really can't do anything on my own.
I wonder if there's something on TV.
That's right!
I'll just take my bath before everyone else!
Maybe I'll have the bath all to myself!
I gotta go get my yukata and underwear!
Oops, sorry.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the tenth dish:
The Heavenly Recette.
It's delicious!
Fate is the spice of life.