If you cannot finish serving our guests' dinners within the next sixty minutes,
you will be expelled on the spot.
I'm not done yet! Not done!
Fifty's nothing to sneeze at.
Fifty!
Here you go!
Finally, girl!
Wow, it's delicious!
I could eat this all day!
Thank goodness. I'm glad they're eating a lot.
It's not greasy at all!
It's not overcooked, either!
Great! Delicious!
I want seconds and thirds!
All right!
I'm going to try even harder!
Oops, sorry.
Y-Yukihira Souma!
You all right, Nakiri?
Did you twist your ankle or anything?
Don't touch me!
I can get up without your help!
What a blunder!
I let my guard down because I thought I was alone.
And he saw me like this, of all people!
I hope he didn't hear me.
You seem to be in a really good mood, what with the humming and all.
Humming?! Who, me?!
What are you talking about?!
So he did hear me!
Well, I do get why you're so cheerful.
Here we are, staying a few nights at a hot spring.
I even brought cards and other stuff to play with.
I'm not cheerful at all!
I'm not like you.
I'd been told this is supposed
to be a camp straight out of hell,
but I find it to be a boring, pointless excursion.
On the other hand, getting to see you expelled
may prove to have some entertainment value.
Sure, whatever.
You were totally enjoying yourself just now.
Erina-sama!
I'm sorry I took so long!
It was more work than I'd anticipated—
Y-Yukihira Souma!
What are you doing here?!
Oh, I pushed Nakiri down on the floor.
Oh, no!
What?!
Don't make it sound like something it wasn't!
But I did, didn't I?
I made you go all "boing" and stuff.
Boing?!
Th-That's not true, Hisako!
God! Just get out of my sight already!
Fine, fine.
Bathy bath, plungy plunge.
Is everything all right?
Yes!
Go take your bath.
Okay.
Oh, I managed to borrow them
from the front desk.
Cards!
I would never waste my time
on something so frivolous!
Uh, what?
But Erina-sama, earlier...
Say, Hisako.
Do you think they have cards here?
What?
Cards. Playing cards.
Cards? You want to play cards?
We can play together, can't we?
You're right.
I'll try asking the front desk.
Isn't that what you said?
I absolutely did not !
Is something the matter?
No, there is not!
Man, what's with her?
I still don't get what her deal is.
Oh, well.
Gonna take my sweet time in the bath.
First one in, here I come!
Uh...
Oh?
The first student's here already?
Sorry. Stretching in the bath
is part of my daily routine.
At that moment, a thought formed in Souma's mind.
He's freakin' scary!
A thought that rarely occurred to him.
But it was only for a moment.
Man, and I was all revved up thinking I'd be the first one here.
What a letdown!
Sorry about that.
You'll have to settle for being the first student here.
I have to say, between last year and this year,
the academy has some very
good students in the pipeline.
Last year?
The task of preparing fifty servings has been
assigned simultaneously at multiple locations.
It's obvious who completed that task the fastest.
Every year, I try to finish my bath
and leave before students show up.
But last year, there was a student
who finished and showed up early too.
Oh?
He's now the seventh seat in the Elite Ten.
Someone I'm quite familiar with.
He seemed promising as well.
That sounds like Isshiki-senpai all right.
Hm?
Wait, she finished even earlier than I did?
Speed isn't everything, of course,
but it does say something about one's skills.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Oh, Hisako.
Actually...
I even brought cards and other stuff to play with.
I don't need them after all.
Okay.
Nakiri Erina,
granddaughter of the academy's director.
The God Tongue.
All of the academy's senior lecturers
have been at her disposal since her infancy.
So-so.
She would refuse to eat anything except the most exquisitely made baby food.
Once when she was a child, she was made to taste several varieties of salt while blindfolded.
Shoudo Island, Kagawa Prefecture.
Noto Peninsula, Ishikawa Prefecture.
Kuroshio City, Kouchi Prefecture.
She correctly identified each salt's origin.
There are more stories than I can count about her God Tongue.
However, her ascendance as the youngest member
of the Elite Ten is founded on true talent.
If she continues at that level,
she will become Tohtsuki's greatest masterpiece, a true monster.
But she's still a diamond in the rough.
Tohtsuki is a hellish place,
where those with talent throng
and devour one another.
Its depths are unfathomable.
Sharpen your fangs, boy!
Yes, sir.
Yukihira!
You may have finished before me this time,
but I won't let that happen—
Chef Doujima?!
Ah, it seems I've soaked for too long.
I should get going.
At any event,
the camp is just beginning.
Be sure to take care of yourself physically.
Good luck.
Thanks, Doujima-senpai.
D-D...
Do you know who he is?!
Yeah, he's Doujima-senpai.
You're right, but— Wait, that's not what I mean!
How could you nonchalantly
shake hands with him, Yukihira?!
Hm?
Yukihira?
I've heard that name before.
Man, preparing fifty servings was exhausting!
I'm glad we all made it.
This is what the next four days will be like.
They didn't call it the camp from hell for nothing.
But when you're soaking in a hot bath,
you find the energy to fight another day.
You brought that with you?
I thought I should let him see the world.
Phew.
Still...
Wh-What?
You're as audacious as ever,
aren't you, Sakaki-dono?
Maybe the rice malt's working some magic.
Don't you start in on my bust too, Megumi.
Look, it's seeing the world.
Aw, silly boy.
Well, then.
Time to get going!
Let's see the room that'd normally cost us 80,000 yen per night!
Wow!
Yeah!
Why don't you try it out too, Megumi?
It's so fancy that I feel like
I'd jinx myself if I touched anything.
Fancy-schmancy!
Yuuki, you're embarrassing yourself.
I know you're happy, but...
U-Um...
Oh, Marui-kun.
You look a little wasted.
Do I?
Then why don't you hear what I have to say?
Let's call it a day and get some rest for tomorrow.
We're here!
Let's play!
Why do you guys keep coming to my room?!
All right!
What should we do?
Daihinmin! 100 games!
F-Fine. It's on!
Two minutes and fifteen seconds.
Their exhaustion overwhelmed them the moment they eased up.
Well, we can let them be till lights out.
You're not sleepy, Megumi?
That's not like you.
You usually go to sleep early.
Yeah, it's weird.
I'm tired, but I'm still wide awake.
Well, you've been super focused the whole day.
That's true.
But that's probably not the only reason.
I'm always so nervous in class.
I'm anxious the whole time,
worrying about messing up.
But today, I managed to back
Souma-kun up just fine.
Glad you liked it!
So just a bit, just a tiny bit,
I'm starting to believe in myself.
And I'm kind of excited about that.
But, you know, it's because Souma-kun gave me such good instructions!
I really didn't do anything special!
That's not true.
I couldn't have made that dish if you
hadn't gathered the right ingredients,
and you cooked everything just fine.
He's right.
You're totally capable of rising to the occasion.
Be more confident, okay?
Sixteen cups!
Wow!
Amazing!
Ultra fast rotation!
Let me try too!
Here it comes! Here it comes!
Let me try!
I want to continue to be with them.
I want to improve my cooking.
I'm going to try my best.
You're fired.
Good morning.
I'm Shinomiya, an alumnus
of the 79th graduating class.
This task involves preparing a dish of my choosing.
You all have the recette, I hope?
Shit, it's Chef Shinomiya.
I heard he expelled over thirty students yesterday.
And he's assigned a recipe
that he came up with.
Terrine of Nine Vegetables.
Though visually arresting with its nine vibrant vegetables,
each vegetable requires its own
specific preparation and cooking time,
and none must overwhelm or
underwhelm its counterparts.
It is a herculean task to bring
all nine flavors together.
I chose one of my easier recettes.
Would you prefer something
more challenging instead?
Damn him.
I want to punch him.
"Recette"?
It's the French word for recipe.
Oh.
Also,
you will not be working in teams for this task.
Each of you must prepare the dish individually.
You may not share information
or help each other during this task.
You will each choose your ingredients from the piles at the back of the kitchen.
Lastly, a word of advice.
You would do well to think of
everyone else as your enemies.
You have three hours.
Now...
begin.
Ow! Get out of my way!
Screw that! I'll kill you!
Outta the way!
Everyone's wild-eyed.
The tension's even worse than yesterday.
But I can't be scared.
I'm not going to let this get to me!
Okay!
All right!
Um...
This one!
I'm lagging behind everyone else,
but all I need now is some cauliflower.
Not this one, this one, or this one!
This slight discoloration...
All the ones that are left are in early stages of oxidization!
If I cook them as is,
the discoloration will become more pronounced,
and the terrine's appearance,
a critical element of the dish, will suffer!
Wh-What should I do?
Souma-kun—
You may not share information nor help each other during this task.
I can't.
I can't rely on Souma-kun all the time.
I have to figure this out on my own!
How can I preserve the cauliflower's color?
I've got it!
Hey, that's not what the recette says, is it?
Huh?
Oh, you're right.
You two, over there.
I told you before.
Sharing information or
helping each other is not allowed.
Did you miss what I said?
I-I didn't do anything like that!
He's right.
All he did was point out my small mistake.
So he did help you.
You've failed.
Both of you are fired.
Start over!
You're fired.
Good job.
P-Please!
I'll...
I'll make it over!
Do you have any ingredients?
You do not.
And time's almost up.
If you can remake the dish, you're a greater magician than I could ever hope to be.
Fired!
Fired.
Yukihira Souma.
Oh?
You pass.
I'm done!
The Terrine of Nine Vegetables!
I'm almost out of time!
You're the last one.
T-Tadokoro Megumi.
Thank you for having me!
Tadokoro Megumi.
You're fired.
That concludes our session.
Those who passed should
prepare for the afternoon—
E-Excuse me!
Why?
Why was my dish unacceptable?
Ah.
You used wine vinegar when you boiled the oxidized cauliflower, didn't you?
You maintained its pristine color by using vinegar, which has a whitening effect.
Using vinegar in the seasoning also
enhanced the cauliflower's sweetness.
The sweetness of the vegetables and the vinegar's mild acidity
are in perfect harmony.
Th-Then why?
Who said you could change the recette?
This dish is intended to display the harmony created by the sweetness of each vegetable.
Nowhere in the recette did it say
to make use of acidity.
The dish you made is an entirely different beast.
Presenting a dish that does not align with the task
merits a fail as a matter of course.
I hope that answer suffices.
It doesn't.
It was what you'd call an unavoidable accident.
There were ingredients that weren't fresh.
Besides, aren't we being treated as our senpais' employees during this time?
As our boss, managing the ingredients is your responsibility, Shinomiya-senpai.
Wouldn't that make this your fault as the chef?
You brat.
Who do you think you're talking to?
You don't seem to get it,
so I'll explain it to you.
I added poor-quality cauliflowers on purpose
to limit the number of people who would pass!
Cauliflower is an ingredient that oxidizes quickly,
is easily damaged, and is difficult to prepare.
Any idiot who lost their cool and made a poor selection would fail.
That includes any laggards who fell behind
and couldn't secure a better one.
That's why Tadokoro tried to
compensate by being creative!
I am the chef here.
Underlings like you have no right to make changes to my recette!
Listen up, underling.
If you refuse to back down,
I can fire you too, on my authority as a chef.
What?!
Souma-kun, it's okay!
I'm fine.
You'll get expelled too.
Okay?
So stop.
Huh?!
I don't care about that crap right now!
Really, it's okay.
Don't... Don't worry about me, so...
Shinomiya-senpai, I'm sorry to bother you,
but there's one more thing.
What now, Monsieur Yukihira?
Do you have another complaint?
No, it's a question, not a complaint.
Does that Tohtsuki rule apply to alumni too?
What are you talking about?
Cooking Battles.
If I beat you in a Cooking Battle,
will you rescind Tadokoro's expulsion?
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the eleventh dish.
Are you okay, Marui?
The Magician from the East.
Ibusaki's never off.
Nope.