I am the chef here.
Underlings like you have no right to make changes to my recette!
Tadokoro Megumi.
You're fired.
Cooking Battle.
If I beat you in a Cooking Battle,
will you rescind Tadokoro's expulsion?
A Cooking Battle?
Now that brings back memories!
What the hell is the transfer student thinking?
He'll be up against an alumnus,
a former first seat of the Elite Ten at that!
Plus, Chef Shinomiya is a seasoned veteran from the front lines of the culinary world!
A Cooking Battle with an opponent who's not currently a student is not without precedent.
But it does require the consent
of both parties, doesn't it?
I'm afraid that I have no intention
of accepting your challenge.
There is nothing you can do.
Tadokoro Megumi's expulsion is final—
Well, let's not be too hasty.
Looks like you have quite an interesting situation developing here, Shinomiya.
Doujima-san?
Hm, I see.
Tadokoro Megumi-san's dish is delicious!
Why not just let her pass?
You're so stubborn, Shinomiya-senpai!
How mule-headed!
Narcissist!
Poser!
Shut up, Hinako.
S-Sorry.
It hurts.
Doujima-san, I believe I was given full discretion for this task.
Of course, Shinomiya.
I have no complaints about the nature of the task or your evaluation criteria.
However, she did try to deal
with the situation at hand.
Don't you think her courage might merit a certain degree of consideration?
I don't.
Not in the least.
I do! Give her another chance!
Wow, it seems that we have a tie.
We are at an impasse.
You guys...
I'm left with no choice.
I'll oversee the unofficial Cooking Battle.
Think of it as a street brawl.
However, we cannot let it interfere with the training camp.
Once all the afternoon tasks are complete,
the two of you will face Shinomiya.
Hold on a minute, Doujima-san!
Why do I have to participate in this farce—
Just play along, Shinomiya.
Fine, fine.
I'll accede to Monsieur Doujima's whims.
Okay, Yukihira.
If you win, I'll rescind her expulsion.
But if you lose, you'll be expelled
right along with her.
So there you have it.
Come to the annex's basement
when you're done.
Let's see your mettle.
Well, looks like we're still here
by the skin of our teeth.
For now, let's do our best and get through the afternoon session, Tadokoro.
Souma-kun, how could you be so stupid?!
How could you make an insane challenge like that?!
You passed!
So you...
You shoulda just lemme be!
Tadokoro.
So your dialect slips out sometimes, huh?
Why are you bringing that up now?!
Come on, on your feet.
We'd better not be late to the afternoon session.
You're always helping me out,
and now I've dragged you into this mess.
I don't know how I'll ever make it up to you.
You don't need to.
It was my own decision,
so you don't need to apologize.
Besides, the reason
I challenged him should be obvious.
It's because you're not meant to drop out here.
Well?
Nope, she wasn't in our room either.
I can't reach her cell.
That's really weird.
I wonder if something happened to Megumi.
Everyone should be done
with the afternoon session.
Maybe she...
I didn't see her name
on the list of people who failed.
Why don't we ask people who were in the same sessions as her?
Oh, right!
Wasn't Yukihira with her?
So where's Yukihira?
Come to think of it, I haven't seen him.
Hm....
Those two managed to get themselves
into a Cooking Battle over Don RS.
Well, that was mostly Yukihira-kun's fault.
I have a really bad feeling about this!
There are no plans to use this hotel's annex for the training camp.
You're in the basement kitchen.
No one will interfere.
Wh-Why are all the alumni here?
I asked them to serve as judges.
I suspect Inui might be biased.
An unofficial Cooking Battle
in the middle of a training camp?
Not to mention, one between
an alumnus and a current student.
What would Chappelle-sensei do if he found out?
I bet he'd bite our heads off.
If he finds out about this, I'm going to run.
I'll say it's all Shinomiya's fault.
I heard that, Mizuhara!
We will now have an unofficial
match, two against one.
Use the vegetables and other ingredients
left over from today's sessions to make the dish.
You may make anything you like,
but try to use vegetables as the main ingredient.
The time limit is two hours.
I am the reason for this Cooking Battle.
I can't let Souma-kun get expelled over this.
I'll do my best not to drag him down—
There's one more condition.
Tadokoro Megumi.
You will be the master chef.
What?
You will decide the recipe on your own.
Yukihira, you'll be the sous-chef supporting her.
What?!
Very well!
Let the Cooking Battle...
begin!
Doujima-senpai!
I'm the one who issued the challenge!
So why that condition?
You had no basis for issuing your challenge, yet I made it happen anyway.
There's no room to negotiate.
But—
Yukihira! Suppose you win
this match with your cooking,
and Tadokoro's expulsion is rescinded.
But then what?
She'll still be your sidekick.
Soon enough she'll find herself
kicked out of another session.
Will you save her next time, Yukihira? And the time after that?
At Tohtsuki, everyone must demonstrate their worth through their own skills.
Whether you deserve to stay is up to you to prove.
So tonight,
at this time,
and at this workstation,
Tadokoro-kun,
you're the chef.
Doujima-san.
I already know what I'm going to make.
May I begin?
Go ahead.
Heh! I feel for you, Yukihira.
What do you mean?
It's only natural to be in despair.
Your fate is riding on that half-wit's skills.
Did you hear that?!
He is so rude!
Shinomiya has a really nasty personality.
That's why your relationships
never last, Shinomiya-san.
Quiet in the peanut gallery!
Wait, when did you slip out of those ropes?!
Good luck, my Megumi-chan!
Don't lose to that spiteful man!
Shut up!
Chef Shinomiya Kojirou.
After graduating from Tohtsuki,
he went to France and opened a restaurant in Paris,
the crucible for gourmet restaurants.
I'm facing someone like that with my recipe?!
I... I have to calm down.
I need to calm down!
I'm blanking out.
I can't stop shaking.
Tadokoro!
I doubt that you need the reminder,
but you're not allowed to alter her recipe.
You are a sous-chef, nothing more.
The assistant, understand?
You felt Tadokoro was good enough
to merit survival, didn't you?
If you can't trust her cooking,
remove yourself from this match now.
No way.
I'm a chef.
No chef would ever run away from a kitchen!
A failure.
I'm a failure, after all.
I only made it this far because of Souma-kun.
Hey, Tadokoro.
I'm just...
Put your hands together.
I'm just a...
Do it.
Ow...
It's a trick I learned long ago.
When you're nervous,
doing that can help you relax.
The only problem is that
you can't do it by yourself.
That hurt, but...
I've stopped shaking.
The first thing you need to do is calm down.
Then, take as much time as you need
to figure out what to cook.
B-But...
Chef Shinomiya's dish will be French cuisine that was tempered in France.
If I can't make a dish that can surpass his,
you'll be expelled.
My dad used to say,
"Cooking is about putting all you've got out there on one plate."
Forget about what the other
guy'll be making for now.
But my cooking isn't...
The rice balls you made for us back at
the dorm's garden were really great.
Don't think about stuff that doesn't matter.
Just make your own food, Tadokoro.
That's enough.
My own food...
Well, this is a surprise.
You two still haven't started cooking?
Your chef seems to be a real half-wit.
Why don't you wait till after you taste
her cooking before you bitch at her?
Souma-kun.
Um, I think I...
may have decided on a dish.
What're you doing, Shinomiya-senpai?!
How violent!
Untie me—
If you don't shut up right
this second, I'll put a gag on you.
Guess that got your attention.
A Cooking Battle with an alumnus?!
Yeah, a guy who was in the same session as Tadokoro told me.
But why?
How'd that even happen?
Sounds like Tadokoro was about to get expelled.
So then Yukihira—
Megumi's expelled?!
Ugh, no!
This can't be!
Yuuki, calm down!
That's what I'm thinking of making.
How interesting!
Really?
Seriously?
Yay!
Oh, b-but this recipe would require a lot
of prep work with different ingredients,
so I'm not sure we can manage.
Who do you think I am?
I was holding the fort as the number two chef at Yukihira Diner!
Well, it was only the two of us,
just my dad and me.
I'll give you everything I've got,
experience and all, to support you.
Just for today, we'll open Tadokoro Diner!
O-Okay!
Great!
Let's do this,
Chef Tadokoro!
Okay!
I'll prep the tomatoes.
Souma-kun, please get the other ingredients ready.
Got it!
Shinomiya-senpai!
What, Hinako?
The "dokoro" in "restaurant" and
the "dokoro" in "Tadokoro" overlap.
It makes the name really catchy!
Take her somewhere far away!
Seriously?!
Why?!
I'll only get more nervous
if I focus on beating Chef Shinomiya.
Just focus on my own cooking.
I'm the chef right now.
Oh, no!
I was supposed to prepare the shoulder cut first!
Now the order's all wrong—
The shoulder's done.
I removed all the tendons too.
Which do you want me to do next,
the chicken liver or the fatback?
U-Um, the liver, please!
Got it!
Souma-kun!
Is the mold ready?
Yup!
Just gotta get the pâté ready.
By the way, I'll be done sauteeing
the vegetables in twelve seconds.
Th-Thanks.
He's amazing!
He's delivering all the prepped ingredients to me right when I need them!
Is this how finely you wanted it chopped?
Yeah!
He's the only one helping me,
but I feel like I'm able to cook several times
faster than I'd be able to by myself.
What's going on?
He's staying several steps ahead of her and
providing support without neglecting his own tasks.
Yet he doesn't rush ahead and
go beyond what's necessary.
He's monitoring her very carefully
to avoid getting in her way.
Hm, Yukihira Souma.
He's the sole transfer student this year.
His family runs a diner.
It seems he was trained there.
I find it hard to believe he gained
that much skill from helping out at home.
His skill clearly surpasses that of any student.
Both contestants should begin finishing up!
We'll start plating the dish!
Got it!
We will now begin the judging.
Shinomiya's dish will be presented first.
Serve your dish.
A dish made by a Tohtsuki alumnus...
I wonder how amazing it'll be.
Well, I can't help but feel anticipation!
Indeed.
Hm?
Chou farci!
This is rather unexpected.
It's from the regional cuisine of Auvergne.
A filling of finely chopped meat and vegetables
is wrapped in cabbage leaves, then steamed.
It resembles the more familiar
cabbage roll found in Western cuisine.
It's a dish often made in French homes.
I'm taken aback.
I thought Shinomiya-senpai only
knew how to make fancy dishes—
Wait, where's my share?
I didn't make any for you.
Ask Mizuhara to share.
Well, then.
Ah!
The aroma of herbs whets the appetite.
M... Me...
Meraviglioso!
Th-This stuffing is different from the typical
pork and onion stuffing used in chou farci!
It's a farce of Jidori chicken breast meat!
First, he butterflied the chicken breasts.
Farce
m 1632 135 l 1792.5 135 1792.5 670.5 1632 670.5
Then he prepared a stuffing of morels, asparagus,
and fois gras sauteed in beef fat,
along with a smooth mousse-like paste made from
the chicken breast, butter, eggs, and heavy cream.
The chou farci was then steamed.
This mousse coats the tongue,
then dissolves instantly into a rich burst of flavor in your mouth.
And the most fearsome ingredient of all
is the cabbage that envelops the filling.
The Savoy cabbage.
In Japan, it's called the crepe cabbage.
It has a strong grassy smell when raw,
but it develops a delicate,
sweet flavor once cooked.
Blanchir... blanching.
Vapeur... steaming.
At each step,
he cooked the dish at its optimal temperature.
That resulted in a delicate sweetness
that elevates the flavor of the entire dish.
It's as if he cast a spell over the whole dish.
Immediately following graduation,
he went to France by himself.
He opened a restaurant in Paris
after several years of training
and became an owner-chef.
While most dishes in French cuisine use meat,
Shinomiya shone a fresh spotlight
on légumes, or vegetables,
shocking gourmands throughout the nation.
Eventually, the chef from Japan gained the respect of the residents of the capital of gourmet cooking.
He was honored with the name,
"The Magician of Légumes."
I hate to admit it...
I hate to admit it, but it's delicious!
He took a common regional dish and
reinterpreted it with his sharpened senses...
...and elevated it to something that could be served at a high-end restaurant.
The light chicken mousse that melts in your mouth,
and the fresh sweetness of the cabbage
envelops your mouth and beyond!
It's as if the power of this dish's flavor is coursing through your body!
This...
...is magic!
Indeed.
Yes!
It is a spell cast by a magician from the East!
Légume Magic!
Cabbage Red.
Ca...
Cabbage Blue.
Cabbage Pink!
Yes!
Magical Cabbage!
Magic, magic!
That was fantastic.
Well done, Shinomiya-san.
It is no wonder that you are called
the Magician of Légumes.
So, how did it taste, Mizuhara?
It was perfect once I wiped
all my memories of you.
Well, how unfortunate for you.
Still, I wasn't expecting this, Shinomiya.
I thought I'd be able to try the specialty
of your restaurant, Shino.
That's a joke in poor taste, Doujima-san.
My opponent's only a student.
Would I be so cruel as to serve my signature dish?
You would.
You would crush them,
so that they'd never be able to cook again.
An up-and-coming chef who's opened a restaurant in a prime location in Paris,
the battleground of gourmet food.
He believes he can't possibly lose to a student,
an arrogance that may well be justified.
If he has an Achilles's heel, it'd be...
All right. Tadokoro, Yukihira, serve your dish.
'Kay.
O-Okay.
Our dish will finally be judged.
Let's go, Tadokoro!
Tadokoro?
I poured everything I had into this dish.
I didn't think that having
someone judge it would be so...
so terrifying.
I wonder what they'll say.
What if they say it's disgusting?
I even had Souma-kun's help!
It'll be fine.
Go!
Hm?
Hm!
This is...
It's a terrine!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the twelfth dish.
You're fired.
Yes!
Magical Cabbage!
Yeah!