Tadokoro Megumi.
You will be the master chef.
Yukihira, you'll be the sous-chef supporting her.
What?!
Let the Cooking Battle...
begin!
Chou farci.
The Magician of Légumes!
All right. Tadokoro,
Yukihira, serve your dish.
'Kay.
O-Okay.
Hm!
This is...
It's a terrine!
This is a Rainbow Terrine,
featuring seven vegetables.
Ah, seven patés, each of a different color.
The vibrant stripes come
together to form a rainbow.
Didn't Shinomiya assign a terrine
during his sessions?
Fascinating.
Is this supposed to be some sort of commentary on my recette for the Terrine of Nine Vegetables?
N-Not at all!
I just wanted people to see my own recette, so...
That aside, let's see how it turned out.
Yes.
Tadokoro Megumi.
E rating!
Why is she still here?
She's dragging Tohtsuki's name through the mud.
She's always ranked at the bottom.
She has no talent to speak of.
Go back to the boonies already.
Tadokoro Megumi.
You're fired.
Yukihira,
if you lose, you'll be expelled right along with her.
Delicious!
Indeed!
Yeah!
She incorporated potatoes, carrots, zucchinis,
and other vegetables to create seven colorful layers.
Each vegetable was prepared in a way that would best bring out its flavor.
I'm impressed she managed to pull off
something so labor-intensive in so little time.
There are two kinds of sauce.
One is a sweet-and-sour sudachi gelée.
The other is an astringent green sauce made from a paste of several different herbs,
with perilla as the main component.
Pairing a terrine with sudachi and perilla—
now that's innovative.
Mmm!
The combination of sautéed zucchini with this herb sauce is so refreshing. It's fantastic!
And the sudachi complements the
lingering sweetness of the tomatoes.
I see!
With seven patés and two kinds of sauce,
you can enjoy fourteen different flavors!
This is very exciting.
Indeed.
These vibrant stripes contribute not only to the
visual appeal but also to the overall taste of the dish.
Tadokoro-kun, you used
sun-dried tomatoes, didn't you?
Y-Yes!
Back home, we dry vegetables
harvested during the summer
so that we can eat them in the winter.
I learned how to use the oven to dry them from Mo—
I mean, my mother while helping out.
When you sprinkle rock salt
on halved cherry tomatoes
and slow-roast them in an oven
at a low temperature,
they become sweeter,
and their flavor is greatly enhanced.
I thought they'd accent the terrine quite nicely.
Indeed.
Tomatoes contain glutamic acid, an umami compound.
The glutamic acid is concentrated as the tomatoes dry,
intensifying the savoriness perceived by the tongue.
Shinomiya's Terrine of Nine Vegetables is a dish that showcases the essence of fresh vegetables.
In contrast, this recette focuses on flavors unique to vegetables prepared for preservation.
While they are both vegetable terrines,
one highlights the taste of freshness,
and the other the umami born of maturation.
They approach the nature of vegetables from completely different angles.
The taste just sinks into your heart.
This dish is full of Megumi-chan's kindness.
Yes.
If Shinomiya-san is the Magician of Légumes,
Megumi-chan would be someone who
sneakily provides us with nature's bounty,
a Koropokkur of Légumes.
No way, that's wrong!
Megumi-chan is someone
who brings me happiness!
She's the Household Guardian of Légumes!
Stare...
Rather than that,
she is someone who has come from the snow country to deliver us this bounty.
A Snow Child of Légumes.
Here!
It's not even winter right now!
That doesn't suit her at all!
Koropokkur should be fine.
She's definitely a Household Guardian!
I still think she's a Snow Child.
Why did you all pick some kind
of supernatural creature?
Koropokkur!
Household Guardian!
Snow Child!
We're doing ghost stories now?
It can't be.
After all of my failures,
I had no confidence in myself.
I was the loser of the academy.
But these alumni, people whom I've looked up to for forever, say my cooking is delicious!
All right, let's move on to judging.
This coin represents one vote.
Each of the three judges have one coin.
Shinomiya or Tadokoro-kun.
Cast your vote for the dish
that you felt tasted the best.
Well, I'll go first.
For the longest time, the only thing I could think about was not getting kicked out.
But now I find myself wanting to do more than that, to stay at this school.
I feel I've finally discovered my own cooking.
Please...
I don't want things to end just yet.
Nice to meet you.
Well, who knew we'd end up in the same dorm?
A'ight! Let's go, Tadokoro!
I want to stay in this academy.
Souma-kun, why don't you go and get some rest?
Souma-kun's amazing!
Thank goodness! I'm with you again, Souma-kun!
Glad you enjoyed it!
I want to cook a whole lot more.
With everyone... With Souma-kun!
So please, God!
My condolences.
The gap between the two of you was obvious.
Shinomiya won by a landslide.
I... failed.
I'm sorry, Tadokoro.
I couldn't help you.
But you can stand up straight and proud.
You made a really good dish.
No! You're wrong.
It wasn't your fault.
Don't worry about it!
I look forward to working
with you from now on, Tadokoro!
I'm counting on you, Tadokoro!
Let's do this, Tadokoro!
Who do you think I am?
I was holding the fort as the number two chef at Yukihira Diner!
And now, because of me,
even Souma-kun is...
I'm sorry!
It was my own decision,
so you don't need to apologize.
The only problem is that
you can't do it by yourself.
I'll give you everything I've got,
experience and all, to support you.
I'm so sorry!
There's no need to be depressed.
It was inevitable.
Anyway, I have an early start tomorrow,
so please excuse me.
A good night to you all.
I believe the outcome has been decided.
What is the meaning of this?
Oh, it's nothing.
I simply wished to acknowledge this dish,
and so I cast my vote accordingly.
What?
You're not even one of the judges.
What're you trying to pull?
And why would you want to "acknowledge" that dish of hers in the first place?
I don't get you, Doujima-san.
Really? You don't?
The dish Tadokoro-kun made...
That's where you'll find your answer.
Shinomiya.
You're in a rut, aren't you?
What?
Shinomiya-senpai, you're so cool!
Hinako, I know how you feel,
but please stop crying.
We have to see him off with a smile.
But...
I can't believe he's going straight
to France after graduation.
He didn't tell me.
Yeah, I was surprised too.
But you're serious about this.
Yeah.
My cooking won't be perfected until
I hone it where French cuisine was born.
I'll train in France, open my own restaurant,
and win the Pluspol award!
The Pluspol award?
If you pull it off, you'd be the first
Japanese person to succeed.
I bet you can do it.
But, Senpai!
You won't make any friends
because you're so aloof!
You'll definitely get into fights with the staff—
I agree with her.
You guys!
A Japanese native,
opening a restaurant in France.
It is a thorny path full of unimaginable challenges.
I used the money I'd won in various cooking contests as a student
to go to France.
And after six years of training,
I opened my own restaurant, SHINO'S, in the 8th arrondissement of Paris,
where countless famous restaurants battle for survival.
I'm impressed that you're an owner-chef at your age.
Your cooking was magnificent.
Thank you.
I may have gotten cocky because of the restaurant.
That Japonais...
I overlooked a minor flaw.
Hey!
Who changed my recette for the sauce?!
This is more to Parisians' tastes.
Monsieur Shinomiya's flavors
are a bit too Oriental.
Well, not that someone who's
Japanese would understand.
Hey, he heard that.
Rebellion sprang up against the outsider.
Jealousy toward a chef they thought was too young.
Want to eat at SHINO'S?
I haven't heard anything good about this place.
Let's go somewhere else.
My restaurant's business became a shambles as more and more fissures emerged.
If you can't pay up soon,
we'll have to terminate our contract!
Is my ambition going to end here, of all places?
I don't need half-wits in my kitchen.
Get out of my sight!
The only one I can trust is myself.
I must think of even the staff as my enemy.
Throw it out.
Follow the recette to the letter and use the miroir glaze at the end.
I won't tolerate any deviations.
Pardon me for saying so, Chef,
but this step would be more than adequate.
We'd save on costs and increase efficiency—
I am the chef.
If you're dissatisfied, leave.
O-Oui, Chef.
I was on a knife's edge.
Delicious!
A knife's edge.
I feel the handling of the vegetables
presents certain Japanese elements.
Yet the dishes don't stray from
the traditions of French cuisine!
It is sheer magic!
He's a magician!
The Magician of Légumes!
I stayed balanced on the knife's edge.
That's how I got here.
You must have realized it yourself.
After you earned the Pluspol award,
you had no more goals to aim for,
nothing else to strive for.
You made you way to the pinnacle,
but you haven't taken a step forward since.
For chefs, stagnation is akin to regression.
You didn't cook your specialty in this match
because you didn't want us to find out that your cooking has hit a wall.
Shut up!
What would you know about any of this?!
You're a hired chef for the Tohtsuki Group!
You know nothing!
Try it.
Try Tadokoro-kun's dish.
Why would I do that?
Just do it.
The heating was insufficient.
The plating and the patés' textures
are subpar as well.
Doujima-san, you've lost your touch.
And yet...
And yet, why does
this dish speaks to the heart so much?
Yes, it's clumsy.
But each detail speaks
to the chef's care for the customer.
It's as though the dish unravels
your tightly wound heart.
This taste, it's as though...
Kojirou.
You got yourself in another fight?
You and those friends of yours
got into another tiff, didn'tcha?
Hmph! Whatever!
I'm fine bein' by myself!
Don't care no how if no one gets me!
I know, I know.
You've got a strong set of beliefs, don'tcha, boy?
You're easily misunderstood.
Momma knows you're a gentle boy at heart.
M-Momma...
Tell you what. I'll make you
your favorite for supper.
Let's get home and start it.
'Kay.
Look, a rainbow.
Ain't it pretty, Kojirou?
Yup.
I'm glad!
Yeah.
This taste is like a mother's love.
Hey, half-wit.
Y-Yes?!
The spice you used in the paté...
It's allspice, isn't it?
U-Um, yes.
I believe she used it to neutralize
the pungent odor of the chicken liver.
Allspice possesses hints of cinnamon,
clove, and nutmeg in its flavor profile.
But there was another reason
you used it, wasn't there?
Um, well...
Y-Yes.
You've all been eating a lot of food from all the judging you've been doing since yesterday.
That's why, well...
Allspice aids in digestion, so...
I-I wanted to serve you something that'd be gentle on your stomach.
I knew Megumi-chan was great!
Yes, it seems we have a good eye for people.
You only say that because she's your type.
That's not true, Mizuhara-senpai!
It may be clumsy, but it speaks to you.
That's the kind of dish it is.
Even in a competition,
Tadokoro-kun tried to be considerate toward the people who'd be eating her dish.
That's something to keep in mind while you're searching for the path beyond the pinnacle.
So this was all part of Doujima-san's plan.
I see.
For a very long time,
I've been turning a blind eye
to my customers and my staff
and cooking by myself.
Boom!
There.
Now the number of votes is equal.
That means it's a tie!
I'll take charge of this match.
Hm.
If it's a draw, it means Tadokoro-kun's standing
is the same as before the Cooking Battle, meaning...
This has all been very irregular.
What a farce.
Well, work hard so you can survive
to see the next day.
That's how a half-wit can get by.
Yukihira Souma, huh.
What a poor sport!
S-Sorry!
Huh?
Um...
Uh...
Tadokoro-kun.
Your cooking reflects your stance toward providing a warm welcome to your guests— your hospitality!
Continue to hone that valuable
edge while at Tohtsuki.
Consider these three coins to be an investment towards your future.
I guess we made it out alive.
Congrats, Tadokoro.
So Shinomiya hit a wall
because of his overly keen wit.
Yes.
He was so focused on getting to the top
that he cast off everything
he felt was extraneous.
He reached the top before he had matured as an owner-chef.
But for a chef to keep striving
for higher achievement,
it is imperative that they possess
a hunger to learn everything they can.
Now Shinomiya will regain that hunger.
In the end, this Cooking Battle saved two chefs.
You're quite the educator, Doujima-san.
You give me too much credit.
Hey, it's totally dark out.
I've so many missed calls
from Yuuki-chan and everyone!
There wasn't any signal in the basement.
Hurry back and show them you're okay.
I'll take my sweet time, though.
Okay!
Oh, Souma-kun!
Thank you so much.
I'll never forget this!
Everyone's worried about you.
Just go.
Okay.
I lost.
I lost...
Dammit.
Yukihira Souma was the only one there who was fighting for a win.
That is another quality a chef needs.
Just like what Shinomiya had
in his younger days when he left,
vowing to win the award.
I'm back—
Yukihira!
You're so reckless!
We were so worried!
We heard you'd challenged an alumnus
and thought both of you would get expelled!
Calm down, Yuuki!
If Souma-kun hadn't been there
for me, I would've failed.
Oh, right.
Um...
Ryouko!
Don't wipe your tears and snot on me!
But I'm really glad that you're both okay.
Don't leave us hanging like that.
We get exhausted worrying about you.
Yukihira, what happened to your right hand?
Are you okay?
Oh...
It's nothing.
Yukihira!
You're alive!
You bastard!
Yeah!
Let's start a card game tournament tonight!
Huh?! Right now?!
Why're you guys always in my room?
Yeah!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the thirteenth dish:
Try them.
Go for a complete collection.