Isshiki-senpai, we're back!
Welcome back, everyone!
I see that all of you survived the camp from hell.
Good job-
We are back.
Souma-kun?!
You look so much more manly.
The tasks must've been very challenging!
Chew, chew, chew.
Tadokoro-chan?!
Is that really you, Tadokoro-chan?
You're all kinds of rough around the edges!
Shut your trap!
Huh?!
Boss!
Whaddya say we beat the crap out of him?
Let's do it!
Hey! All of you better respect your elders,
or there's gonna be hell to pay!
Ibusaki-kun, your charming hairstyle's been ruined.
Scruff.
Come to think of it, where's Marui-kun?
I don't see him with you.
This was all that we could find of him.
Th-This can't be...
Marui-kun!
It was only a dream.
Today is the third day of camp.
I hope you're all okay.
No good!
Start over!
Good, you pass the test.
You may clean up now, Tadokoro Megumi.
Thank you!
Watch where you're going!
S-Sorry!
Nice work, Tadokoro.
You've still got some rough patches, but...
Not enough.
Still not enough.
Perfect!
I have to do better.
I have to!
You'd best relieve yourself of the notion that you can stay the queen bee forever.
Thank you for the advice.
I'll do my best to keep what you said in mind...
as the prattle of the unwashed masses.
Today was another tough one!
I want to pass out in my room already.
We only have two more days of this.
We might scrape by.
Strange.
I don't see a time listed for lights out.
You're right.
Maybe it got left out by mistake?
Students of Tohtsuki Academy!
One hour from now, at ten o'clock,
assemble in the banquet hall in your uniforms.
What?!
What the hell?
What a drag.
Wow, the herd's really thinned out.
Everyone's exhausted, of course.
What could they have planned
at this time of night?
Yukihira!
Hey!
Don't go pulling ridiculous stunts like challenging an alumnus to a Cooking Battle, idiot!
How dare you risk getting kicked out of Tohtsuki without first settling your score with me?!
Who the hell are you?
That's my line.
How did you guys know
about the Cooking Battle?
Everyone's been talking about it!
Hang on. If Yukihira's here right now,
wouldn't that mean...
No way! You beat Chef Shinomiya?!
Did you really?!
Nah, I blew it.
Huh?!
Is that so?
Can we please stop talking about this?
No way! Explain yourself!
What happened?!
Hey!
Look!
Erina-sama!
It's Erina-sama.
All eyes up front!
We've gathered all of you here for one reason and one reason only:
to explain to you what tomorrow's task will be.
Tomorrow?
Why bother telling us that the night before?
Your assignment will be to create a new breakfast menu worthy of being served to the guests of Tohtsuki Resort.
Breakfasts are the face of the hotel.
It is an important meal because it is what starts the guests' day.
I'd like you all to come up with an innovative dish that will make a vibrant contribution to the breakfast table.
The main ingredient will be eggs.
Your dish may be of whatever cuisine you'd like,
but it must be capable of being served buffet style.
The judging will begin at 6 o'clock tomorrow morning.
Make sure that your dish is ready by then.
Did I hear that right?
He meant six in the evening, right?
No, he definitely said "morning."
W-Wait!
We have no time to waste on sleep!
You're free to decide how to spend your time.
You can work on your recipe
in one of the many kitchens,
or go and get some rest in your room.
I'll see you all again in the morning.
Dismissed!
No way.
I'm already in pieces.
My brain's barely working as it is!
Finally, a task worth competing over.
Just you wait, Yukihira.
Hm?
I'll deliver the ultimate breakfast:
a traditional Italian egg dish that's been prepared with the Aldinis' expertise!
What's in this traditional Italian egg dish of yours?
Well, aside from the eggs, you take
some cheese and vegetables and—
What are you doing, Isami?!
Stop giving away our secrets!
C'mon, let's get out of here!
Fine, fine.
Come to think of it,
my transfer exam also featured eggs.
The main ingredient will be eggs.
Make one dish.
Here you go!
Doesn't this bring back memories, Nakiri?
D-Don't you dare act so familiar with me!
A word of advice.
Don't make a low-class dish like last time.
If you want to avoid embarrassing yourself in front of the judges, that is.
But it seemed like you enjoyed it, didn't you—
Huh? What are you talking about?!
I told you that it was disgusting!
Erina-sama!
I've secured a kitchen.
Very well.
Let us be on our way, then.
Well, good luck racking your
nonexistent brains over this one.
Good day.
Um, are you guys all right?
Fine, I'll show them what I've got!
Hey, Marui! Stand up!
We're all going back to the dorm together!
Polar Star!
Fight!
Yeah!
Y-Yeah!
What a quiet night.
It's very different from the typical scene during a task,
what with all the yelling.
Indeed.
But all things considered,
I would expect the students to be more frustrated than they'd usually be.
I wonder if this'll work.
Maybe I'll try another seasoning.
This assignment is more cruel than I thought.
You're right.
Unless you're extremely confident in what you've
come up with, there's no way you'd go to bed early.
I'm retiring to bed.
Will you continue to test recipes?
Y-Yes.
I'm still only halfway done.
I see.
Don't stay up too late.
Erina-sama is impressive.
Pressure doesn't exist in her world!
Her royal bearing...
How worthy of admiration!
Oh, one more thing.
Tomorrow night, we'll play Sevens!
In the game of Old Maid yesterday...
I wasn't... feeling my best, exactly.
Got it?
Y-Yes.
Erina-sama is impressive!
She's determined to be the victor
in anything and everything.
How worthy of admiration!
Yukihira Souma...
I will teach you your place with my cooking.
I will show you what an egg dish worthy of Tohtsuki is made of.
Is a buffet like one of those all-you-can-eat places?
I have no idea what breakfast
at a luxury hotel looks like.
Guess I'll give this a shot.
If you're talking egg dishes...
In Japanese cuisine, it'd be dashimaki eggs.
With Western cuisine,
scrambled eggs sounds about right!
Yum!
Self-Praise
It's delicious.
No doubt about that,
but it's not enough.
Something new for the menu, huh?
That was quite interesting...
but I'm vetoing it.
Huh?!
Why, Dad?!
You thought it was good!
Listen up, Souma.
We're a diner.
Our customers come to Yukihira
because they're looking for diner food.
Making off-the-wall dishes simply because you can won't win anyone over.
Trying to dazzle them with something novel isn't going to work.
I need to make something that's both classic and classy enough to be served here. But also...
An innovative dish that will make a vibrant contribution to the breakfast table.
There's got to be some kind of twist to
the dish, something fresh and unexpected.
I've got it!
I'm done!
This breakfast is a culmination
of the Aldinis' expertise!
Just you wait, Yukihira!
Wait till you see my ultimate dish!
Just go to sleep if you're done, Bro.
What should I do?
What should I do?!
I have to decide on a menu!
Just make your own food, Tadokoro.
That's enough.
Your cooking reflects your hospitality.
Hm...
Not everyone can stand to eat
a lot of food during breakfast,
so maybe I should go with something on the lighter side.
Something lighter...
Right! I get it now!
Hey, you!
What?!
Okay, I think I have a clear idea
of what I want to do now.
Better start testing right away—
Whoa!
Who are you?
Hm...
Looks like you'll make a pretty good dish.
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
Thanks.
Who is she?
Her skin and hair are snow white.
Tomorrow morning will be quite the show.
Good evening—
Ow!
Come on!
Don't just stand there! Get out of the way!
But you told me to stand here, Miss.
I also told you to only do that when I'm trying to intimidate someone!
When you stand off to the side looking like you're ready to pounce,
my intimidation factor goes way, way up!
Hey!
Where'd they go?
Where are your balls?
I forgot them somewhere.
I can't believe this!
They add a lot to the intimidation factor too!
You're so absentminded!
Oh, I'm sorry.
What were we talking about?
Oh, we weren't really talking at all.
So you know what you're making already?
Pretty much.
Good luck on your recipe testing.
Later.
What was that about?
That was Yukihira Souma-kun.
Despite all the rumors,
he doesn't seem to be anything special.
I can't believe he's planning to make that.
He must really want to fail this test.
Whoa!
This place is huge!
Hey, wake up!
Sorry.
Oh, Tadokoro's here.
She's writing the "man" character again.
Takumi's here too?
Yukihira!
Looks like he's saying something,
but I can't make it out from this distance.
I'll win this time for sure!
Okay, so this is my spot.
Oh.
Hm?
Nakiri! Guess we're right next to each other.
Y-Yukihira-kun?!
We sure run into each other a lot!
Why does he keep popping up everywhere?!
It's bad for my heart.
This will be the first time I get to see you cook.
Well, it's a golden opportunity to show him how superior I am to him.
Yes, feel free to savor the gap
between my cooking and yours.
Huh?
You want to compare our dishes?
Sure, but after the test's over, okay?
N-No!
That's not what I meant!
My sarcasm went right over his head!
Well, let's do our best.
It looks like you're planning to
make some kind of soufflé.
Yup!
It's going to be a kind of omelette.
I'll whip the egg whites into a
meringue before cooking the dish,
so the omelette will have a unique texture.
That's the soufflé omelette.
An novel texture is one of the surprises a dish can spring, y'know?
What?
No, nothing.
Texture, huh.
Each of you is ready to present your dish, I assume?
I will now explain the conditions for passing the test.
First, let me introduce the judges.
K-Kids?!
These are the people who grow and produce ingredients for Tohtsuki Resort Hotels.
Their families are present as well.
Every year, they serve as judges at this camp.
I've informed them that the theme is an inspired egg dish.
S-So many.
Their judging is quite accurate.
A hearty thanks to all!
You may assume that I won't even touch anything poorly made.
These guys know their shit!
They're way too intimidating!
So scary!
Tohtsuki Resort's kitchen and service staff will also join the judging team.
The steward of the service department!
Even Chef Doujima's right-hand chef is here!
There are two judging criteria.
One is whether your dish displays inspiration worthy of acknowledgment by professional producers and staff.
The other is to have 200 servings of your dish consumed in the next two hours.
200 servings, huh?
I see.
There is a wide range of diners:
men and women, young and old.
They intend to simulate an actual hotel breakfast.
This challenge closely mirrors a real-life situation.
Those who fulfill those two criteria will pass the test!
Very well, honored judges, please enjoy the breakfast in all of the exam halls.
May the judging begin!
Here it is!
Welcome!
Here you go!
Please enjoy!
Oh, how fragrant.
What is this?
It's a frittata.
I see, an Italian egg dish.
It's made with cheese.
As far as breakfast goes,
it might be a bit boring.
Not at all.
I'll be serving my frittata to you as a salad.
I'll break the frittata into pieces,
and toss them with vegetables!
Then I sprinkle some balsamic vinaigrette and Parmesan cheese on top.
And it's done.
I present to you the insalata frittata.
"Insalata"?
That's Italian for "salad", right?
Wow! It's delicious!
The texture of the fluffy eggs
and the crisp raw vegetables!
And the light balsamic vinaigrette
ties it all together!
Amazing!
I've never eaten a salad like this!
Grazie!
U-Um...
P-Please have some if you'd like.
It's single-bite breakfast oden!
What? Oden for breakfast?
Hm...
And on top of that, this is
a quail egg on the skewer!
Hm, I see.
Chicken eggs aren't the only eggs available.
That's her angle.
What a comforting taste!
The mild broth fills your mouth with every bite.
The vegetables were cut
to match the quail egg's size.
They're so colorful that you
can't resist picking them up!
Will you...
marry my grandson?
What?!
Uh, um...
This is cool.
A loco moco donburi at a buffet, huh.
Hm...
Loco moco is typically topped with gravy,
but here you've used a vinaigrette sauce!
The light acidity of the white wine vinegar
heightens the creamy texture of the yolk and the juiciness of the meat!
This is a very fortifying dish.
Well done!
Yeah!
I was able to leverage the recipe
I came up with in the Don RS.
And it'll be a piece of cake
to make 200 servings of this.
Have we met before?
Huh?!
You?!
Oh!
You were one of Erina's lackeys.
Funny, I haven't seen you around recently.
Oh, I get it.
Did Erina decide you weren't worthy of her?
Shut up!
I'm gonna beat the crap out of you!
My apologies!
Hm?
What's with her dish?
A boiled egg, another unshelled egg,
and a raw egg on a small plate?
That's supposed to be a dish?
None of the guests are going near her booth.
What's she thinking?
Here you go.
It's Eggs Benedict.
What beauty!
They're like brilliant jewels!
Eggs Benedict...
The dish consists of an English muffin
topped with poached eggs and bacon,
then finished with a slightly
acidic hollandaise sauce.
It's a mainstay on American breakfast menus
and certainly nothing one would consider new.
What's innovative about this item?
The poached egg melts on your tongue
and is perfection itself.
The hollandaise sauce has such a refined acidity.
The bacon is crisp,
and the muffin has a subtle sweetness.
The perfect harmony of all these
flavors envelops the tongue.
No, that's not the only thing.
What is this brilliant golden powder?!
Dried mullet roe?!
She sprinkled dried mullet roe powder on the muffins?
I see. Fish roe is also a type of egg!
The refined saltiness of the roe
meshed with the chicken egg yolk
to produce this deep flavor!
A particular restaurant in New York
that serves Eggs Benedict
has been praised as the "queen of breakfast."
And this dish is truly worthy of a queen.
The taste is enough to make you kneel!
But of course.
Wonderful.
I'm melting.
Erina-sama...
Eggs Benedict-sama!
Nakiri Erina!
200 servings, complete!
She's fast!
But I'm right behind her!
What about Yukihira?!
I'm halfway there!
What about Souma-kun?!
What's wrong?!
Yukihira?
No way!
He's still at fewer than ten servings!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the fourteenth dish.
It's hell!
Metamorphosis.
I'm going to ferment.
I won't let anyone take
my No. 1 spot at Polar Star!