All right!
Another batch of fluffy soufflé omelettes!
All done!
I can't believe nobody's taken even a single plate!
The soufflés have collapsed?
Of course!
At a buffet, the food won't get eaten right away!
It's not like Yukihira,
where I can serve each dish to the customer at the right time and temperature!
At a buffet,
customers decide when they'll come for a dish.
But a soufflé's texture can only be enjoyed the moment it's finished.
You can't appreciate the dish otherwise.
Crap!
No matter how many plates I set out,
the soufflés will fall before
the customers come up to take one.
Shit!
Not to mention...
Nakiri's dish is luring away
all of my potential customers.
Nakiri Erina! 200 servings, complete!
I suppose you understand by now.
In a buffet,
the stability and aesthetic appeal of a dish are of utmost importance.
Long story short,
you couldn't possibly have chosen a dish that was more ill-suited for this task.
It seems I'll be finally bidding you farewell.
I hope you can appreciate the beauty of my dish in the little time you have left.
The main ingredient will be eggs.
Your dish must be worthy of acknowledgment by professional producers and staff.
And 200 servings of your dish must be consumed within two hours.
The criteria for passing this test are not trivial.
Now is the moment of truth.
This will be a true battle for survival.
Shit!
I've had no takers after the 150th bowl!
I've set out some more servings!
Please don't push!
What's going on?
I hear she made some more!
After just one customer tried her dish,
there was so much uproar that
she drew away everyone near me.
So those weren't just any normal eggs.
I had no idea her dish held such a secret.
This isn't a raw egg!
What looks like egg white is a gelée made from diluted seawater!
And the yolk is actually salmon roe held together with gelatin!
What?!
At first glance, this appears to be a boiled egg.
But the egg white is really a mousse of white asparagus,
while in place of the yolk,
there's a rich, yolky hollandaise sauce!
The creamy egg flavor strikes the perfect balance
with the slight tinge of bitterness
from the white asparagus!
So what's with this egg that's still in its shell?
Oh, this? Well...
She stabbed it?!
It's a milkshake you drink with a straw.
I took an empty egg shell and filled it with a milkshake that I made from eggs, milk, and caramel.
I-It's delicious!
Its mildness and refreshing aftertaste are a perfect complement to a morning meal!
In ensemble,
I call this set the "Egg Plate in Three Forms."
It's a staggering masterpiece!
Each "egg" contains an entire
world of surprising flavor.
On this single plate,
the flavors of the sea,
the forest,
and grassland have been combined!
Wow!
I want more!
Another!
Me too!
Me, me!
Please let me have one!
You've got to be kidding me!
At that rate, she'll totally serve over 300!
Takumi Aldini! 200 servings, complete!
All right!
Yukihira!
What is he doing?
Tadokoro Megumi! 200 servings, complete!
Phew.
Souma-kun?
The all-nighter I pulled is catching up to me.
Erina-sama snagged all of my customers,
so no one's taking any more of my dish.
I'm done for!
Calm down.
Two new customers!
Souma, set out some hand towels and appetizers!
Hurry up and clear Table 3!
Table 4 needs their check!
I can't do all of that at the same time!
Appetizers, right?
Appetizers... uh...
And... huh?
What am I supposed to do?
It's all jumbled up in my head.
I don't know what I'm supposed to do anymore.
Ow!
Ow...
Listen up, Souma.
If you find yourself panicking in the kitchen, stop and analyze the situation.
Visualize each task you have to do,
and take things from there.
My condolences.
But this is the gap between your skill and mine.
Now do you understand?
Uh, what?
He didn't fall asleep, did he?
I have a little over thirty minutes left.
First, attract customers.
I need just under a minute to cook
the omelette on one side,
How many burners do I have?
Prepare the ingredients.
What's he muttering about?
This is gonna be close.
He can't possibly think that he can serve 200 people in the time left!
How on earth does he plan on doing that?
All right!
There's very little time remaining.
His chances are slim to none.
What are you going to do, Yukihira Souma?
Get the first one!
Win over the first customer!
That's step one!
What's this? Wow!
I know what this is!
It's called Eggs Benedict!
Ow!
C'mere!
Watch closely, little miss.
I'm gonna cast a magic spell on this egg!
There.
Wow!
Wow, it smells so good!
Here you go!
It's jiggling.
Wow, so delicious!
It dissolved like bubbles
in my mouth and vanished.
I told you it was magic!
Huh? What's going on?
Isn't it just an omelette?
So what if he gets one or two at this point?
It won't change anything.
Here you go!
What?
What is this?
It tastes like an omelette,
but its texture is like a sweet soufflé!
Wow!
Hey, look!
The surface is cooked,
but the inside has all these bubbles,
so it's really springy when
you press on it with a spoon.
It's really bouncy!
What's going on over here?
Hey, let's check this out.
Here you go!
Another!
Okay! I'm starting to draw a crowd.
I can't let this chance pass me by!
He still needs to serve well over a hundred.
How's he going to do that in thirty minutes?
It's impossible.
The battle's only just begun!
There!
200 servings, complete!
Oh, how disappointing.
I've run out of ingredients.
I didn't think so many people
would want to eat what I made.
Very well.
You may wrap things up.
Thank you!
Bye, bye!
I can't believe that bitch!
She managed 380 servings!
I'm bored.
Maybe I'll go check in on Erina.
Oh, come to think of it...
I wonder what happened to that guy.
Yukihira Souma-kun.
Put the lids on,
and while they steam,
prep the ingredients for the next batch.
He's so fast!
His hands are a blur!
All right!
Beat the egg whites,
then add egg yolks and heavy cream.
Add salt and pepper.
Seasoning? Good.
This batch is just about done.
Plate...
with the special tomato sauce and parsley.
Thanks for waiting!
Hey!
The booth next to this one looks pretty amazing!
You're right!
He stole my customers!
Despite the significant workload,
he's actually ratcheting up the pace as he goes.
Every time he finishes one batch,
he's further optimizing his preparation.
Delicious!
It's melting.
Wow! It's so fluffy!
They're going fast,
and the crowd's only getting bigger.
The more people there are, the more come.
There's something called live cooking,
where food is prepared right in front of customers
instead of taking prepared food to their table.
Doing that heightens their
expectations for the dish,
and watching ingredients turn into a finished dish is exhilarating.
Wow!
He's churning them out!
He's so fast!
So cool.
Yukihira is attracting his customers
by putting on a fantastic show.
He's entrancing them
with his skills and his cooking.
That's how he's turned things
around to his advantage.
Sakaki Ryouko! 200 servings, complete!
Yoshino Yuuki! 200 servings, complete!
Finally!
Yeah!
I passed!
I wonder how Bro's doing.
Five minutes remaining!
Yukihira...
Souma-kun!
Wow.
Yukihira Souma! 200 servings, complete!
Time's up!
Stop!
What's with that smug look?!
Barely scraping by is nothing to be proud—
I'm so surprised!
I thought you'd only manage
eight servings at most!
But you managed to pull through by putting on that circus act.
Huh?
Talk about a final push.
Indeed.
What this task requires is the ability to envision the situation.
A hotel breakfast and a buffet at that.
The key is the ability to imagine in great detail
what kind of dish such a situation would require.
And one more thing.
Given that unexpected emergencies constantly arise in kitchens,
there is one thing that is absolutely essential.
He gave himself a huge handicap
with his menu choice,
but his adaptability allowed him to
overcome that with impressive flair.
What an interesting diamond in the rough.
But still,
the student who served 407 people sure was something.
Nakiri Erina was the only student to crack 400.
And there was that other student, who used up all her ingredients and served 380.
Still, you'll never win the top spot
if your cooking relies on a circus act like that.
What you need is workmanship rooted in cutting-edge theory.
Something like my own cooking, for example. Right?
I believe I haven't introduced myself yet.
I am Nakiri Alice.
I'm the one who'll stand above all of you.
Remember that.
Nakiri Alice?
Nakiri?
Yes, Erina and I are cousins.
I lived with her until I was five.
There you are, Miss.
Oh, what good timing!
Come!
Explain my upbringing to Yukihira Souma-kun.
Oh...
Well...
Miss Alice is Miss Erina's cousin, and—
I already said that!
Never mind! I'll continue!
My father chose Denmark, my mother's homeland,
as his base of operations when he founded Nakiri International.
It's a facility dedicated to researching molecular gastronomy.
They come up with cutting-edge food preparation techniques
based on how they affect not only the senses of taste and smell
but also cerebral psychology.
I was there until I was fourteen,
then came to Tohtsuki...
to crush Erina and become
number one at Tohtsuki.
My cooking will never lose to a chef who only values modern spectacle.
How mean!
You've always been this way!
When I was three, you stole my toys.
When I was four, you said
the cake I made for you was...
Disgusting.
And I'll never forget how, when I was five—
Wh-What's that have to do with anything now?
Not to mention you, Yukihira Souma-kun.
You talked big at the entrance ceremony,
but performance art in cooking
belongs to a bygone era.
As proof of that,
you barely scraped by a task requiring 200 servings.
Yeah, I was sweating bullets there!
Being ignorant is scary!
I really messed that one up.
But...
I did learn something from my mistake.
You're a shrewd one.
In any case, I won't lose to you two!
I look forward to when I get
to defeat you head-to-head.
Sounds like fun.
I'll take you on when that happens.
Good!
Well, until then.
Yukihira!
Souma-kun!
Jeez! I was so worried!
How can you be so reckless?!
Huh?
Oh, sorry.
The following concerns those
who completed 200 servings!
The next task will begin in four hours.
You are free to rest until then.
You've got to be kidding!
We only get three or so hours of sleep?!
That's right.
The camp...
...isn't over!
I'm done for.
I can barely move my legs.
I want to lie down.
I'm totally spent.
Huh?
Wh-Why have we been summoned to the lobby?
There's nothing listed on the schedule.
Huh? Wait, the last time that happened...
Don't tell me there's another task like that coming up.
Good.
It seems all of you are here.
Not again!
Before we begin, I'd like to say a few words.
At this point in time,
352 students have dropped out,
and only 628 students remain.
This may seem cruel,
but this camp is a microcosm of what
it means to choose cooking as your career.
You'll need to stay calm
when facing the unknown
and commune with your ingredients.
If you become a chef,
there will be great pressure.
You'll endure countless nights
of anxiety and indecision,
adapt to a wide range of situations,
and overcome those challenges.
This life is akin to wandering alone
through a barren, wind-torn wasteland.
The farther you walk, the more you will stumble,
and the hazier your goal becomes.
You may reach a standstill
after making it to the pinnacle
and lose sight of how to return.
But I want you to remember one thing!
Here at Tohtsuki, you're with others who would tread the same wasteland.
This fact will sustain you once
you sally forth and go on alone.
I wish all of you the best of luck from the bottom of my heart!
Now then,
let us begin the final program of this camp.
I knew it!
Welcome!
The final program consists of a modest banquet
to celebrate the conclusion of the training camp.
You will be enjoying a full course meal prepared by the alumni.
Let me now say to all 628 of you who survived:
Congratulations for passing the training camp!
Enjoy it to your heart's content!
All right!
Seriously?!
I can't believe it!
This isn't "modest" by a long stretch!
We're probably the only people in the whole wide world who can eat something like this.
I'm glad to be alive—
Marui's finally kicked the bucket!
Thank you.
So good!
Don't cry, Yoshino.
Cooking school?
Why do I have to go to a school like this now?
Paying to learn how to cook is so stupid.
Is something wrong, Souma-kun?
Oh, nah.
I think this school might be more
interesting than I expected, after all.
Huh? What do you mean?
Nothing, just thinking out loud.
C'mon, let's eat.
Okay!
This year is shaping up to be very interesting with regard to that upcoming event.
Yes. It's something to look forward to.
These diamonds in the rough will be facing off against each other in a major event:
the Autumn Selection.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the fifteenth dish:
Huh?!
What?!
The Man They Called the Demon.
So yummy!
I'm going to meet a better chef than me!
Rawr.