Now then,
let us begin the final program of this camp.
You will be enjoying a full course meal prepared by the alumni.
All right!
All students, please gather your belongings
and prepare to board your designated bus.
Please return your room keys to the front desk.
Please check your surroundings to avoid leaving anything behind.
Oh, man!
We're done. We're finally done!
Everyone in Polar Star made it.
Yup.
Yeah.
It all passed by in a flash.
It was pretty challenging, though!
No kidding!
You didn't all need to barge into
my room on the last night!
Didn't you enjoy yourself
the last time we came over?
Yeah, last night too.
C'mon, draw the old maid!
Let's finish the game back at the dorm!
What?!
Maybe Isshiki-senpai can join in.
We can play Presidents and Assholes too.
Shinomiya-senpai!
So the two of you survived.
Yeah, we managed to get by somehow.
A suitcase?
Are you going back to France already?
Yes.
I can't keep my restaurant closed for too long.
Besides, I've decided what my goal is going to be.
I'm going to make SHINO'S the number one
three-star restaurant in all of Paris.
There's so much more I want to do.
Getting the Pluspol award was just the beginning.
A three salt plum restaurant?
Wow!
No Japanese chef in France has ever received three Michelin stars!
I don't suppose—
Stop right there!
You're not going to steal a march
on us, Shinomiya-senpai!
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Yukihira Souma,
are you interested in Italian cuisine, by any chance?
Huh?
Tadokoro-kun, your talent would flourish at a sushi restaurant—
No way!
To ensure Megumi-chan's safety, I'd better take her with me!
Uh, what?!
I see you two have already been approached.
Ch-Chef Doujima, wh-what's going on?
The chefs have been sizing you up.
Sizing us up?
This camp also serves as an opportunity for chefs to offer students a position after graduation.
In order to come here, alumni temporarily close their restaurants,
or even let their sous chefs take over for them.
It's partly so they can recruit future staff.
Finding promising chefs is a challenging task.
Huh, okay.
I had no idea there was another purpose to the training camp.
Megumi probably doesn't realize
what it means to get recruited by that lot.
Uh-huh.
Yukihira-kun, you would shine
here at Tohtsuki Resort.
You're welcome to join us.
I appreciate the offer,
but I already have Yukihira.
That's right,
your family ran a restaurant, didn't it?
Yes, my father and I kept the
place running by ourselves.
I don't know where he is or what he's doing,
but I want him to recognize my skills one day...
and to deem me worthy of taking over Yukihira.
Senpai, you're really going to try for those stars?
You heard?
How about I come and help you out?
Sure, I was thinking that I could use a servant.
Are you kidding me?!
Doujima-san?
Is something wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Okay, Souma-kun, this is our bus.
All right, see you later.
Crap, my headband!
Huh, you left something behind?
It's almost departure time.
Let me go—
I-It's all right!
I can go get it myself!
I'll go back in a different vehicle,
so you should go on ahead.
Take my luggage with you.
O-Okay!
Whew.
It's a good thing I found it!
Well, that was a thoroughly enjoyable resort, wasn't it?
Shoot, wrong bus.
I'm already looking forward to next year's camp!
When there is a cluster of tour buses,
it is easy to mistake another bus for yours.
We strongly suggest that you confirm the parking spot
and bus number if you need to step outside.
Oh, you're the boy who made the souffle omelette.
Hey, the chicken egg guy.
That wasn't bad at all.
Um...
I'm sorry I wasted so many of your eggs!
Hm, I guess you did do that.
But I'll forgive you if you'll give my eggs preference
in your own restaurant someday. Okay?
I sure will!
I hope you'll use my beans too, boy!
My cheese too.
Hey, would you like some rice crackers?
Take these cough drops.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks! Thank you!
Wait, I need to get going!
Where's my bus?
Um...
Uh...
I got left behind!
Seriously?
I made it through training camp,
only to have a major crisis now?
Wh-Why are you still here?!
Why?
Well, it's a long story.
Lady Erina!
We've made arrangements
for a car to take you home.
There happened to be one available.
Did he miss his bus as well?
Want some rice crackers?
No thank you.
Cough drops?
No need.
By the way,
I remember you saying that you'd enjoy seeing me get expelled.
I survived, though.
So how about them apples?
I don't even have to look to know he has a smug grin on his face.
You'd do well to flounder
at the very bottom of the barrel.
I doubt you'll get through the Selection.
The Selection?
You don't know about it?
The Autumn Selection is a long-held Tohtsuki tradition.
It's a gourmet festival where select first-years are allowed to display their skills and compete.
The academy's board of directors and investors,
all heavyweights of the food industry, will be present.
It'll be the first opportunity for students to demonstrate their skills to those outside of the academy.
The selection process has already begun.
Didn't you notice that Selection Committee members were at the camp?
Oh, so that's who they were.
It was those suits, right?
In other words, this camp isn't just for weeding out the weak.
It's also meant to discreetly identify
those who will ascend above the rest.
A gourmet festival, huh.
Sounds like fun!
I can't help but get revved up
just thinking about it!
Like I said, there's no way someone
like you would be selected!
What was all that about earlier, anyway?
I did learn something from my mistake.
Learn from your mistake?
That's what a loser says to cover up his failure.
Failure is not an option for chefs!
Is that so?
It is!
Only perfection can be served at the table.
That is the only way you can achieve the ultimate gourmet experience.
Just like his cooking.
Huh?
What was that?
Nothing.
By the way, why'd you end up missing the bus?
There's no need for me to tell you.
Oh, okay.
I guess this is what you'd call an awkward situation.
Guess I'll go to sleep.
Found it!
Thank goodness.
I see.
So Yukihira Souma is your son, Jouichirou.
Camp's finally over.
It's going to get noisy around here again.
That was awfully quick.
Well, my goodness.
If you were coming back,
you should've called ahead!
You're still every bit as rude as you were.
I just happened to be passing through the area.
I'm back.
I'm back!
We're back!
Souma-kun, I hear you came back
in one of the hotel's cars?
I'm so jealous!
That makes you a VIP! A VIP!
It wasn't anything that fancy.
In any event, I'm glad everyone came back safely.
You must all be tired.
I'll give you guys a good meal tonight.
Yay!
We haven't had Fumio-san's cooking in forever!
Well, I won't be the one cooking.
Hey, Souma.
You're back.
Help me out with this.
Sure.
I'd like you to prep this.
I've already made the stock.
Sure, got it.
Wait, I reacted like we're back home out of habit,
but what the hell are you doing here?!
What, you know each other?
Wh-Who is he?
He's an alumnus of Tohtsuki Academy and a former resident of Polar Star Dormitory.
A Tohtsuki alumnus?!
Must be the generation gap.
You don't know the former
second seat of the Elite Ten,
Saiba Jouichirou?
The former second seat of the Elite Ten?!
"Saiba"?
Hey, the rice is almost done, Souma.
Forget the rice!
Just tell me what's going on, Dad!
You're family?!
Hm, I see now.
So Dad's an alumnus of Tohtsuki,
lived at Polar Star Dormitory,
and was in the Elite Ten.
Even for me, it's hard to take this all in.
Whoa, I've never seen Souma flustered before.
I guess it's not that unusual.
He's Yukihira-kun's father, after all.
So you are Jouichirou Saiba.
Oh, you've heard of me?
Yes, I've come across your name in past documents.
You were described as a nomadic chef who worked his magic in famous restaurants around the world.
But after a time,
you vanished from the front lines.
You became a legend known only to a select few.
I am the current seventh seat of the Elite Ten,
Isshiki Satoshi.
I'm honored to meet you, Chef Saiba.
Oh, I go by Yukihira now.
You can just call me Jouichirou.
H-He's not disturbed by Isshiki-senpai's appearance in the least.
He's not a former Elite Ten for nothing.
What's that have to do with anything?
I didn't know Dad was so famous.
You really had no idea?!
Well, I only learned recently that he'd worked overseas before.
We used to get calls in languages
I didn't understand,
and I'd come across tons of
photos of him with foreigners.
I thought that every family
experienced those sorts of things.
They don't!
You should've noticed!
Who knew Souma-kun's father
was such a great man?
Well, let's have a toast!
This is to celebrate all of you surviving the camp.
Don't hold back tonight!
Thanks for the food!
Cheers!
F-Food made by a former Elite Ten member...
I wonder what it tastes like.
Somehow... I'm really nervous.
Please, try some.
O-Okay!
I can see it!
Places I've never been...
Vistas of foreign lands...
It's all coming to life in my mind!
This is the essence of Arabia!
It's delicious!
What's this paste spread on the lamb?
That's harissa.
It's an all-purpose chili pepper spice blend from North Africa.
Using traditional Middle Eastern cooking as a base,
I tried adding parsley and
garam masala this time around.
J-Jouichirou-san, what's this?
That's zuppa di pesce.
It's a Ligurian seafood soup with stocca fisso.
What about this one, Jouichirou-san?!
P-Please tell us about this too!
Oh, that's...
Jouichirou-san's such a hunk.
Yeah, he gives off this manly aura.
Even the guys are all over him.
Will Yukihira...
...turn out that way too?
Huh? What now?
They were all wound up tight
when they first met him,
but a single bite has opened their hearts.
This dish is bursting with its creator's personality!
Whoa! This dish is awesome too!
Wow! They're all super delicious!
What about this one?
Disgusting!
Oh, that one!
I tried to recreate a snake dish I had last month.
It's so disgusting!
They chop the snake up with the skin still on,
and then they boil the pieces
without any further prep work.
Dad, this sucks big time!
Right?
It's easily in the top ten best disgusting dishes.
Yukihira Family
Isolation Ward
Wouldn't that make it the ten worst dishes, then?
Are you sure it's not in the top four?
Heck, maybe the top two.
Oh, I get it now.
This is Yukihira's father we're talking about.
I think the top two were those, y'know...
Well, the one quirk aside... Jouichirou.
They used to called you "The Demon."
But you're cooking really gentle dishes these days.
Yeah.
You ought to let Gin try
a dish of yours sometime.
I guess you're right.
You don't mean—
That's right.
He was acting all high and
mighty at camp, wasn't he?
Doujima Gin, the head chef of Tohtsuki Resort.
Here, this is Gin,
and this is Jouichirou.
They were second-year high schoolers at the time.
They're both so young!
Fumio-san, please don't show them things like that.
Why not?
So Chef Doujima was also from Polar Star.
Seriously?
Doujima Gin, the first seat of the Elite Ten.
Saiba Jouichirou, the second seat.
When these two became the core,
Polar Star entered a golden age.
We won victory after victory in Cooking Battles,
seized acre after acre and expanded the dorm,
invested in ever larger kitchen facilities,
and secured procurement routes for ingredients.
We were fully self-sufficient.
More like, we were a nation unto ourselves!
Those fields you're using out back,
the fermentation workshop,
and the large hen house—
all of those were built back when
Gin and Jouichirou's crew were around.
Still, while Gin never fails to send a New Year's greeting card and mid-year gift...
Jouichirou!
Why don't you ever write a letter once in a while?
I do come by to see you sometimes, don't I?
As if!
You just wander in and wander out!
Talk about the legendary graduate.
Strictly speaking, I never actually graduated.
What? You didn't?
But you were the second seat.
A lot of things happened.
Is Gin doing well?
Y-Yeah.
Dad.
Yeah?
What was...
Polar Star Dormitory like back then?
It was fun.
Everyone worked on perfecting their craft however they could.
Dad, want to sleep in my room tonight?
I guess.
Souma, you're in 303?
Yeah, why?
In the middle of the room...
there's a scorch mark from
when a pot fell on the floor.
It used to be my room.
Fumio-san, let me stay in one of the empty rooms!
Sure!
This was Dad's room.
Saiba Jouichirou, huh?
Really now,
just how much do I actually know...
about that man?
Souma!
Are you up?
Yeah.
I'm in the kitchen right now.
Bring your knives and come join me.
Maybe he's prepping breakfast?
Come to think of it, why did
Dad come back to Japan?
I wonder if it has something to do with a job.
Oh, there you are.
You've sharpened your knives, right?
Of course.
I did it last night so the smell of the whetstone—
Okay, good.
Well, sorry to spring this on you,
but I need you to show me
how much you've grown...
or how much you haven't.
Let's have our first cooking
contest in a long time...
Souma.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the sixteenth dish.
Thanks for waiting!
The Chef Who's Crossed a Thousand Leagues.
Do have a taste.