Well, sorry to spring this on you,
but I need you to show me
how much you've grown...
or how much you haven't.
Let's have our first cooking
contest in a long time...
Souma.
I was wondering why you'd
showed up out of the blue.
That's what you're here for, old man?
Well? Are you in, or are you out?
As if you needed to ask!
Who would've guessed that Souma-kun
was the son of a former Elite Ten member?
I don't blame you for being surprised.
The only cooking techniques I taught Souma
were ones that'd be useful in a diner.
Next to all the elites at this academy,
he must stick out like a sore thumb.
You're certainly right about that.
But from the very first time
I faced off against Souma-kun,
I understood that he would
stir things up around here.
Really?
Well then, for the theme...
Hey, Judge.
What do you have a hankering for?
Judge?
I see that the competitive streak runs in the family.
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree, now does it?
Fumio-san?
Jouichirou asked me last night
to oversee this match.
Well, this will be quite the spectacle.
Don't scare me like that!
Why are you even here, Isshiki?
I caught a whiff of an interesting match
on the way back from my morning fieldwork.
Unfortunately for you, you may only observe.
After all, we can't have an even number of judges.
Hm?
T-Tadokoro?
Oh, Souma-kun.
Morning.
Whoa, what happened?
What's with the huge dark circles under your eyes?
Oh, those? Yeah, I'm really tired,
but whenever I try to fall asleep,
I end up thinking about camp.
We need to finish fishing ASAP and get cooking!
Watch where you're going!
What should I do? What should I do?!
I'm so sorry!
I'm kind of amazed that I survived all that.
Well, it's all over now, so you should relax and get a good night's rest.
Oh, but this is perfect timing.
Come here, Megumi.
Huh?
With her here, we have three judges.
No objections, right?
Yeah.
Yup.
You know, I'm no spring chicken.
I can't eat anything heavy in the morning,
and the girl pulled an all-nighter.
With that in mind, the theme should be...
Serve us a dish that'll give us a boost
and get us ready to start the day!
You may use anything you can find in this kitchen.
You have one hour.
Now, begin!
It has to be light and easy to eat,
and yeah, it has to be nutritious of course.
Okay!
Huh?
Uh...
Why are they competing against each other?
G'morning, Tadokoro-chan.
I guess you're finally awake.
Huh?
What?
Why?
S-Souma-kun, your father was a member of the Elite Ten, right?
How can you possibly win?
Hey, it's not like this is
the first time we've done this.
I think the first time I had a face-off with him was in sixth grade.
An elementary school student versus an adult?
I guess I can see Souma-kun doing that, but...
Hold on, have you ever beat him?
Oh, I can't really remember.
Not even once.
Quit pretending.
I think you're on over 500 losses by now.
No way! I've only lost 489 times!
So you do remember.
A cooking match?
Yes. And I'd like you to be the judge.
Well, I'll get to see you in a match for the first time in a very long while,
so I'm fine with adjudicating.
But you'd better not take it easy on your opponent just because he's your son.
You needn't worry about that.
When it comes to Souma,
I've never pulled any punches.
Huh? An apple?
Souma-kun...
He may be your father, but we're talking about the former second seat of the Elite Ten.
So why do you look so confident?
I see.
This is how he got started.
Souma-kun never backs down from a challenge,
no matter how insurmountable it may seem.
And now I know why.
He's been trying to surpass his father,
someone who far exceeds his own abilities,
even after 489 losses.
Who'll be the first to finish?
Thank you for waiting!
That looks like...
An apple risotto.
Go on, have a taste!
A risotto?!
It's true!
I can see the finely diced apples.
Fruit in a risotto?
He sure likes surprising us, doesn't he?
A refreshing aroma that's both sweet and tart.
Did he also use lemons in this dish?
He did.
The dish's fragrance is invigorating.
Just a whiff of it is enough to shake my leaden stomach awake and rouse my appetite.
It's enough to banish any fatigue.
An apple risotto, huh?
Well, why don't we see how it tastes?
The apples lend a crisp texture
and a mellow sweetness.
The simmered onions impart
a silky texture to the risotto.
Meanwhile, the crunchy bacon accents the gentle apple flavor that permeates the entire dish.
It's as though it's...
gently waking me up from a long sleep.
Such a gentle kiss...
from the prince of apples!
Apple...
It's delicious!
Now try seasoning it with black pepper.
It makes for a novel flavor that's just as good!
Let's see.
The subtle sweetness of the apples and onions...
...contrasts with the peppery
bite of the black pepper!
The black specks on the white dish...
...create a contrast in both taste and appearance.
It's like a waltz in black and white!
I think I'm going to melt!
It feels like it's sinking into my sleep-deprived body!
You're getting vitamins, fats, and carbohydrates.
The rice is on the soft side,
so it's gentle on your stomach.
It's perfect for eating right after you wake up.
But there's something I find puzzling.
What is it?
The rice and onions have been infused with the flavor of apples,
but if the apples had been cooked that long,
they should've become mush.
Instead, they still have a crisp texture.
You're right.
How's that possible?
About that...
I used this!
Apple juice?!
While I was simmering the sauteed rice and onions,
I added the juice bit by bit as the dish was reduced.
The diced apples were added later, and they were cooked just long enough to warm them.
That's why they retain their raw texture.
I see.
What an innovative idea.
The flavor of apples permeates the dish,
and it was the apple juice that was behind it!
Even though he was presented with the theme right before he started,
he was able to produce a dish
on the fly that was spot-on.
Is there any limit to his talent?
The apple risotto was an excellent
response to the assignment!
I can hardly imagine a better dish.
What a terrifying man.
I can sense how he might be able to surpass
this near-perfect dish by Yukihira Souma with ease!
Thank you for waiting.
Now, please eat.
This is revolting!
It's as if 50,000 blue crabs had run rampant through idyllic farmland!
Absolutely horrid!
The dishes he prepared yesterday
were all meticulous and polished.
What would he make for a contest?
I'm honored to witness a dish made by a predecessor of the Elite Ten.
During his time here, Jouichirou was well-known for his inventive dishes.
Take a long, hard look!
Have a taste.
It's Jouichirou's Special Rich Ramen.
R...
Ramen?!
Ramen for breakfast?!
Wow. The broth looks really rich.
I've heard of places where ramen
is eaten in the morning,
but this appears to be made
with a thick seafood-based broth.
This dish is too much for the sleep-deprived
Tadokoro-chan and the elderly Fumio-san.
Jouichirou!
Your obsession with novelty has gone too far!
I've warned you about this before!
You would serve up untested
recipes with bizarre ingredients
at a Cooking Battle without any hesitation!
And that's why you would lose
Cooking Battles from time to time!
I was pretty ornery back then.
As if you've changed at all!
Hm?
Fumio-san, the broth may look rich,
but it has a surprisingly light and mellow scent.
You're right.
Well anyway, let's see how this dish fares.
It's... not bad.
Yuzu citrus was kneaded into these noodles.
Despite how rich the ramen is, I can keep eating.
Or, rather, I...
...I...
...just...
...can't stop!
The broth is a combination of
soy milk and scorched miso.
But how would that alone be enough to produce such depth of flavor?
The ebi-imo taro I grated into the soy milk
and miso has an elastic texture and a rich taste.
Doing so imparted a creamy depth to the broth.
I feel like I'm being warmed from within.
It must be the effect of the chili oil,
grated ginger, and garlic.
The mild soy milk masks
the bite of those ingredients,
letting them gradually warm you up.
A lot of work and attention to detail went into these toppings too.
Lotus and burdock roots were thinly sliced and fried to a golden color.
Carrots and turnips were grilled over charcoal until lightly scorched,
then seasoned with rock salt to bring out their natural sweetness!
Just like in French cuisine,
each ingredient was prepared using a method uniquely suited to it,
in order to bring out its flavor.
And to top it off, he used tempeh!
Tempeh?
A fermented soy-based food product originating in Indonesia.
It's made by fermenting soybeans with tempeh mold,
which is found on hibiscus and banana leaves.
Tempeh is a traditional food that's been made for over 400 years.
It's light, but at the same time very filling.
It's almost like char siu pork!
The texture of tempeh is close to that of meat,
so it's often part of vegetarian and macrobiotic diets.
People who don't eat meat or dairy products can still enjoy tempeh.
For this dish, I prepared the tempeh by cooking it in soy sauce and sake.
Could this be... a vegetarian broth?
That's right.
It's made with kelp and shiitake mushrooms. No meat involved!
When I was traveling overseas a long time ago,
I met a priest who was lamenting
that he had to abstain from meat and fish
for several weeks for religious reasons.
I want to eat something filling!
This ramen is based on what I learned through trial and error while making dishes for him.
I see.
The umami components of kelp and shiitake mushrooms have a synergistic effect when used in combination.
It makes it possible to attain a rich broth without using bonito fish.
Wait, Jouichirou!
If that's the case, then this ramen...
You achieved this much complexity in flavor without using any meat or fish?
It's easy to use animal products to create umami and depth of flavor.
But this is a rich ramen
that uses neither meat nor fish!
Isn't that more interesting?
What a guy!
By combining the flavor of soy and other vegetables,
he created a dish that is deeply satisfying.
How many ideas are crammed into this single dish?
It contains the knowledge of a man
who's spent a lifetime traveling the world.
Even though every bite leaves quite an impression,
you never get overwhelmed!
What a pleasant, perfect spiciness!
I can just feel the energy coursing through my veins!
Ah, I feel so warm inside!
My cells are rejuvenating!
Rejuvenating!
Thank you for the food!
The clock's been turned too far back!
Let's get down to the judging!
Thank God, I was just seeing things!
But you do look somewhat younger.
In fact, you're kind of glowing.
Yukihira Souma or Jouichirou.
Set forth the dish that was
more delicious in front of you!
It's unanimous.
The victor is Jouichirou!
Glad you liked it!
Both demonstrated more than sufficient surprises,
innovation, and consideration
of the diner in the morning.
But after tasting that ramen so full of vitality,
Yukihira's dish feels lacking in comparison.
It's a complete victory for Jouichirou!
Souma-kun, your dish was certainly delicious,
but it seemed a bit lackluster to me.
It is morning,
but I'd just finished fieldwork.
I guess I wanted something more substantial.
Jouichirou-san's dish hit the spot.
I see.
When I made that dish, all I thought about was
how to minimize discomfort and meet their needs.
Minimize
On the other hand, Dad aimed to maximize their enjoyment by fulfilling their desires.
Maximize
But it's good to see you've grown up a little bit.
Apple risotto, huh? Not bad.
Listen up, Souma.
While you're at Tohtsuki, you'll find
yourself with plenty of battles to fight.
Until the next time you lose to me,
you'd better not lose to anyone else.
So they communicate through their cooking, huh?
What a pair those two make.
But all that aside...
Yeah?
This is your 490th loss, huh, Souma?
Hey!
Another win for me.
It's not as satisfying when I don't have a single defeat to my name.
Shut up!
I'll show you next time!
Th-They're taking notes?!
Have they been recording every single win and loss since the beginning?
They're oddly meticulous about things like that.
So you've been facing him over
and over again, Souma-kun.
You've been up against this amazing father
and experienced frustration many times over.
Souma-kun, I'm going to keep trying too!
Huh?
Uh, okay.
Your father's amazing.
I guess that's the power of the second seat!
I guess.
It's not like my goal's changed, though.
I want to see what it's like up at the top,
where not even Dad's been.
This has only made me even more fired up!
Souma-kun...
All right!
Let's aim for the Elite Ten together, Tadokoro.
Huh?
What?!
That's impossible for me!
Don't be silly!
What, leaving already?
Do you ever relax?
You should give him some more advice.
I'm pretty laissez-faire about parenting.
He'll figure it out.
Yeah, right.
That match was meant to encourage him, wasn't it?
Since the Autumn Selection is coming up.
Hm?
I just wanted to see my son's crestfallen face again.
You could be more honest, you know.
Well, I'll leave it at that.
Besides, I had an errand to take care of at Tohtsuki.
An errand?
Oh, it's nothing important.
Well, later, Fumio-san.
I'll come by sometime to cook for you.
My goodness.
No matter how old you get,
you'll never shake off your wanderlust.
My apologies, Erina-sama.
I'm sure you're tired from the training camp,
but here is the schedule for today.
The owner and head chef of Kishoan will be arriving shortly to give you their regards.
They'd like you to taste their new menu.
Following that will be a group luncheon with Food Executive Company board members...
Stop the car!
Erina-sama?
Ah, no, it's nothing.
What?!
Jouichirou-san already left?
Wh-When did he leave?
Just now.
I have no idea where he's off to, though.
He's too footloose.
He should've at least let us say goodbye.
Aw, I wanted to let him try some eggs from my Polar Star chickens.
I wanted his advice.
And I wanted to thank him for the breakfast ramen.
Ramen?
Yeah...
Souma-kun and Jouichirou-san had a cooking face-off this morning.
What?!
How could you?!
You should've called us!
Sorry! Please forgive me!
We're not going to forgive you!
By the way, Yukihira.
Jouichirou had a message for you.
A message?
Yeah.
"Air out the restaurant once in a while."
The restaurant?
Why don't you go home for a bit
during the next holiday?
Holiday, huh.
I wonder what's going to happen
to this shopping district.
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the seventeenth dish:
The Sensuous Karaage.
It's only planned for now.
Crap. I haven't seen even
a single car come this way.