Hey, you hungry?
What are you thinking, ice cream maybe?
Nah, I want something more filling.
Definitely!
I want something filling too.
So what do you want to eat?
Kurase Mayumi
First-Year, High School
Meat!
Hey, good idea!
What do you want?
Meat!
Would you like some?
Grilled squid tentacles in a peanut butter dressing.
Here, dig in.
Every single day,
when we pass by this place,
you stop and stare.
Huh?
Th-That's not—
Don't lie!
You were thinking about Yukihira again.
That's why, back in junior high,
I told you to ask him out
when you learned that you'd be going to different high schools!
Oh man, sorry!
I'm sorry, Mayu!
Well, it might not be too late, y'know?
Maybe try to win him over by calling or texting him.
No way.
I'm a very plain girl.
Something like that would never work.
Oh, hey, Kurase.
Been a while.
Yukihira?!
Long time no see, you guys.
You should've told us you were coming back!
Are you going to reopen the diner?
Nah, I just came by to air the place out.
Whoa!
Yukihira's open again!
What?!
It's true!
Souma-chan, make me something!
Me too!
For me too!
Me too, please!
I miss your diner's cooking so much.
All right!
I'll have to make a supply run first.
Diner Yukihira's gonna be open once again for a limited time!
Your Chicken-and-Egg Rice Bowl
and Ma Po Tofu Sets!
Yahoo!
I've waited so long for this!
Say, where's your dad?
You're not with him?
Oh, I ran into him the other day.
I guess he's off globetrotting again.
Souma-chan, can I add sauteed snow pea sprouts to my order?
Sure thing!
Yukihira-kun...
A cooking contest?
He's going to face off against his dad and needs a judge.
You've never been over to his place, right?
You can eat really yummy food!
Better not pass this up!
I've been in the same school as
Yukihira-kun since kindergarten,
but we've never really talked.
Dig in!
Thank you!
I don't have any special skills or hobbies.
I'm pretty ordinary. So to me...
you're really amazing.
It's only been two months since we graduated from junior high,
but you already look a bit more mature.
It feels like you're even more out of reach now.
Thanks for the food!
Thanks!
Thanks for coming.
Huh. Is it me or are there a lot fewer people around than normal?
This street should be busier at this time of day.
You guys run this shopping district.
What's going on?
Are mega-investors really that great?!
Calm down, Tomi-chan!
What happened here, Chairman?
It's pretty simple.
About a month ago,
the station's commercial complex completed its renovations.
Oh, yeah, it's a lot nicer now.
Well, it's another one of those
train station shopping malls.
They have a bunch of stores selling clothes, books, and other goods.
And there's this pretty popular shop that sells karaage.
It's supposed to be really good.
Huh.
Have you guys tried it?
Yeah, my parents brought some home the other day.
Mine too.
It was good, yeah.
They showed it on TV the other day.
It's crisp on the outside and juicy on the inside!
Well, that's a 10 out of 10 from me!
All the customers are going to the in-station mall for the karaage.
Commuters don't pass through
this street any more.
My bento store's sales have plummeted.
I'm not sure how much longer we can stay open.
Seriously?
Maybe you shouldn't be
wasting time chowing down.
Seconds.
Hey.
I guess it's a sign of the times.
This shopping district may be on its last legs.
Well, I'll figure something out.
Figure what out, exactly?
Their main attraction is the karaage, right?
So let's cook up a new karaage here
that'll knock their socks off.
What?
That's impossible, Souma-chan!
They have us beat in everything.
Money, marketing, you name it.
You don't want to pick a fight with them!
It's better than sitting around and doing nothing.
Customers are insatiable, y'know?
Yukihira's open!
Souma-chan, make me something!
If you make something really good,
they'll track it down.
I'm one of you guys.
I can't let this place become a ghost town.
Let's steal our customers back with a new karaage recipe and revive the shopping district!
Well said, Souma-chan!
You're not the future owner of Yukihira for nothing!
We can count on you!
All right, I'm gonna use my vacation
to come up with a great dish!
This is going to take a lot of prep work.
Okay, first off...
Guess I'll get back to work.
Not that there's much to do.
Thanks, Souma-chan.
Your face is saying,
"I'd like to help Yukihira-kun too,
but I doubt I can be of any help, ugh."
You're an open book.
Hey, Yukihira.
You need a taste-tester, don't you?
Huh?
She's not in any clubs,
and I bet she's got good taste!
Oh...
What?!
Wh-Why me?!
I don't know anything about cooking!
Now, now.
You never know, input from
a layperson might be important.
But why my opinion—
"I'll try my best!"
Oh, okay.
Thanks for helping me out, Kurase.
We'd better check out their karaage first.
Then we'll brainstorm our menu.
Okay!
I'll see you tomorrow morning!
Are you sure about this?
I'm not discerning enough to be a taste-tester.
You've been a judge for a cooking contest.
This is totally different.
We have to come up with a brand new dish.
Listen, Mayu.
This is your chance!
Huh?
A guy and a girl sharing the same goal,
in a room by themselves...
Of course you're gonna get close!
G-Get close...
Time to get your game face on, Mayu!
Aki-chan, you're scaring me!
Hm...
Karaage, huh?
We've made that here plenty of times,
but maybe I need some special insights
into take-out dishes like I did for the buffet assignment at camp.
Who do I know that might have
that kind of knowledge?
Karaage...
Chicken...
Meat...
Man, who's bugging me now?
I'm trying to enjoy my break here.
Huh?
Who is this?
I don't recognize this number at all.
Hello?
Hey, Nikumi?
It's Yukihira.
Wh-Why do you have my number?!
Oh, sorry 'bout that.
I asked Konishi-san for it.
S-So why are you calling me?
I have to come up with
a new karaage dish pronto.
I'm back home right now.
Do you think you can come over and help?
Come over? To your home?
Did you already have vacation plans?
W-Well, I guess I gotta bail you out, don't I?
I'm super busy, but I'll come!
I'm busy, but I guess I can make it!
It's not like I have any choice here, do I?
Hey, if you're busy, I can ask someone else.
I said I'd come, didn't I?!
What's this run-down place?
Okay, so Diner Yukihira...
Maybe I should've picked out a more normal outfit.
Nah, I'm fine being me!
Sorry, Kurase,
can you hang on for a second?
S-Sure, I'm fine!
I'm so nervous.
I hope I'll be able to help him.
Get close!
Get close, okay, Mayu?!
Aki-chan, don't pressure me!
Hey!
What?!
This is Yukihira Souma's place, right?
Y-Yes!
Oh, hey, Nikumi!
Thanks for coming!
Right, this is Kurase. She's one of
my old classmates from junior high.
I asked her to be a taste-tester.
Huh?
This is one of my classmates from high school.
She's a meat expert.
You can call her Nikumi.
"Nikumi"?
D-Don't spread that nickname around!
I'll punch you!
Anyway, now that everyone's here,
let's go check out enemy territory!
Welcome!
Come try the karaage
that's the talk of the town!
Crap, what should I wear?
Should I try to be more refined?
What about just being myself?
Or is that no good?
Dammit!
Bah!
Wow!
This place is so huge now!
It looks pretty trendy too.
It's no surprise that our shopping
district's on the ropes!
Th-This is no laughing matter, Yukihira-kun.
Whatever! It's not like I expected to be all alone with Yukihira in his home!
The reason I'm here is to think up a new dish!
She said her name's Mito-san.
She's like an actress, or a model.
I've never met anyone this sexy before.
High school students are amazing.
I'm nothing like her.
That's right.
It's nothing out of the ordinary
to have someone else around.
So why am I so irritated?
He said this girl's his childhood
friend or whatever,
but is she his type?
Is that it?!
Oh, could Mito-san be Yukihira-kun's girlfriend?!
What're you staring at, huh?!
S-Sorry!
Hey, don't be mean to Kurase, Nikumi.
Quit calling me that!
Are you upset that I called you on vacation?
Not really.
Sorry, Kurase.
It's okay.
Well, they're meeting each other for the first time.
I should try to smooth things over by putting myself between them!
Hey!
Isn't that it?
The karaage place.
The line starts here!
Thank you for waiting.
You can get a discount on a box of twelve!
Welcome!
Come to Mozuya for karaage!
This is Mozuya!
So Mozuya's the karaage place
you were talking about.
You know of it?
They're a really famous chain in Kansai.
That's Nakamozu Kinu.
She's the owner of the Mozuya chain.
They started out in Kyoto and now have branches all across Kansai.
They've won the National Karaage Competition
three years in a row, a historic feat,
and everyone says they'll win this year as well.
I see.
A lot of the customers are housewives.
Yeah, and there'll be even
more people in the evening.
The packaging is stylish,
so it's really popular with the ladies.
A lot of people even take the train here just to buy it.
So they have a nice storefront with a bunch of staff.
The business looks good.
Huh?
Chairman?
Whoa!
Souma-chan?
What're you doing here?
O-Oh, I was thinking maybe I could do something to help out.
What's with the getup?
We're behind enemy lines.
It'll be dangerous if they realize who I am.
How so?
You should be more careful, Souma-chan.
There's no need to skulk about.
Why not line up with pride, Chairman?
Are you folks from the shopping district?
Would you like to try some?
Really?
Don't mind if I do.
Inside the crisp, light batter,
there's fat bursting out of the plump chicken
and making war inside your mouth with umami!
It's like umami arrows are raining down on you!
Wow!
How do you make this taste so good?
Let me tell you!
We're using Omi local chicken.
They're a premium breed fed only on herbs.
The finishing touch is Mozuya's proprietary
super secret soy sauce marinade!
Along with grated apples, we use more than a dozen ingredients in the marinade to dress up the chicken.
We then fry up the chicken nice and crispy by exposing it to air as it cooks!
There are those who call our chicken "The World's Greatest Karaage."
Are you sure you want to tell us all this?
After all, we're here to spy on you.
Oh, I don't mind at all!
I doubt you'd ever manage to duplicate our recipe.
Still, what a pathetic loser of a man you are,
relying on women and children to save you.
You just stood by and watched
as the customers left one by one.
Don't you have any self-respect?
Oh, but I'd be worried about my business too
if someone depressing like you were on my storefront!
This weakling reminds me of someone I know.
The next don of the Don RS is you!
I guess you're really confident, huh?
So if our shopping district were to come up
with karaage that's better than yours,
it'd be a huge embarrassment
to Mozuya-san, huh?
You talk big, boy,
but don't you kid yourself for a moment!
What could a mere child like you possibly do?
Hm? Well?
Well, a wimpy shopping district that has no competitive streak or shred of imagination
deserves to wither away and die, no?
I hope you'll continue your
patronage of Mozuya at the station!
Please come again.
Th-That was scary.
I felt like I was in a yakuza film.
Do you want to try and see how far we can get
by doing what the competition's doing?
Yeah, let's give it a shot.
Neither of them are discouraged in the least.
They sure are tough!
All right!
Operation Defeat Mozuya!
On with the trials!
Knead the marinade into chunks of breast meat.
Like Mozuya, we'll add ingredients like grated apples and onions,
and modify it with ginger for added measure.
This'll form the base of the karaage's flavor.
Make sure the marinade coats
each piece, and let it sit.
This is just a test, so we'll fry it right away,
but I bet Mozuya lets their chicken rest
in the marinade for about ten hours.
Ten hours? That long?
Then dredge the pieces in katakuri starch.
Dusting off the excess starch is key to frying the chicken up nice and crisp.
I see.
And here I thought it would taste better
with more of it left on.
Okay, the temperature's perfect.
Let's go!
Test number 1, complete!
Kurase, try it.
Okay.
It's delicious!
It's great, Yukihira-kun!
But it doesn't pack the same punch as Mozuya's.
That high-quality marinade contains soy sauce,
garlic, and many different spices.
All of them combine to create a complex flavor.
I bet it took them years to perfect that recipe.
We're going up against something like that?
Hey, is there some reason it has to be chicken?
Even if we stick to meat, there's beef, pork—
really, there's all sorts of options.
Huh, you're right.
How about A-5 beef?
In terms of quality and brand name recognition,
we'd totally win.
But isn't it really expensive?
I'll give you the special Mito
conglomerate discount,
since you're a classmate and all.
I'll get you the best ingredients,
and to hell with the profits!
Hold on, let me figure out the price.
Thanks a ton, Nikumi!
If we can keep the price down to about 1,000 yen per 100 grams—
That'll be 3,500 yen per 100 grams!
You know what? Never mind.
Huh?
Don't hold back just because it's so cheap!
Uh, no, I'm not worried about it being too cheap.
How about you, Kurase? Any ideas?
Huh?
Um, well...
C-Can you capitalize somehow on the fact
that we're a shopping district?
Oh... Um...
I don't really have any specific ideas.
I'm sorry.
Customers use the station as a hub to catch trains and buses.
And customers come to the station building for other reasons.
This location gives us a twofold
advantage in terms of customer draw.
It was the right decision to choose this spot.
Of course, it's only to be expected,
given that we contracted your consulting services for our Kanto expansion.
Don't let your guard down.
You haven't established your brand in Kanto yet.
Let me know if you catch the slightest whiff of any potential issues.
For someone so young, you're such a worrywart!
We're making steady progress.
Observing the market and reacting optimally as soon as possible is a basic rule of business.
Well, if anything,
there's this brat from the shopping district who's trying to pull something.
Brat?
Oh, it's nothing to worry about.
At any rate, the store's getting a constant stream of customers!
It's only a matter of time before
Mozuya takes over this entire city!
Just in case,
keep an eye on what he's up to.
Don't forget to follow up with me, got it?
Sure, sure.
Kids these days are all so uppity.
None of these are bad per se,
but they're not great either.
We've tried changing the marinade and the batter...
...but none of them have stood out so far.
What should I do?
What kind of karaage will let
us take back our customers?
If we don't succeed, the Sumire
Avenue Shopping District will...
Huh.
It's a holiday, but students are passing through.
There're quite a few of them, actually.
Must be junior high students on their way home from club practice.
There are a lot of schools around here.
Junior highs, high schools, and universities too.
C-Can you capitalize somehow on the fact that we're a shopping district?
That's it!
Y-Yukihira-kun?
That's right!
I spent all this time thinking inside the box!
We don't need to fight them on their turf!
So we're going with A-5 beef, then!
Nah, we'll be doing chicken karaage.
Huh?
But you just said we won't fight them on their turf.
We won't.
We just have to think about doing
what the other side can't.
Doing what only we can,
because we're a shopping district.
We're going to come up with the best way for people to enjoy karaage.
We're going to set the stage for our victory.
My word is law.
That's the condition for my consulting services.
Fine. I accept.
Mozuya isn't the only one who wants my magic.
It's almost time.
Shut up. I know.
What's on the agenda today?
You didn't read the message?
It's the Autumn Selection.
We're going to start narrowing down
which first-years will get to compete.
What a waste of time.
Why do we have to do that during break?
What choice do we have?
It's one of our important responsibilities...
as the Elite Ten of Tohtsuki!
End
Next time, we'll talk about karaage in a train station!
Mozuya, Mozuya, Mozuya!
The Karaage of Youth.
Have one!
Please continue your patronage!