Karaage.
The wafting steam,
the nose-tingling spices,
the plump chicken and the hot juices that course along your lips.
One of the cornerstones of the Japanese dinner table is about to become a weapon
in the ultimate fight for supremacy:
the Sumire Avenue Shopping District Summer Karaage Campaign.
Let's go check out enemy territory!
I doubt you'd ever manage to duplicate our recipe.
So if our shopping district were to come up
with karaage that's better than yours,
it'd be a huge embarrassment
to Mozuya-san, huh?
You talk big, boy,
but don't you kid yourself for a moment!
What could a mere child like you possibly do?
What's the best way to enjoy karaage?
Well, of course you'd want to eat it
right after it's been fried.
Right?
But that's simply not possible
with Mozuya's karaage.
Huh?
What do you mean?
They sell their karaage in sealed plastic packaging,
so that customers taking the train won't bother other passengers with the smell.
They assume their product won't be eaten right away,
but rather when the customers get home.
You can't eat karaage while you're walking around that nice mall at the station.
I see.
It's not like there's a food court there,
so they only have takeout.
But a shopping district doesn't
have that kind of constraint.
Some shopping districts specifically capitalize on being able to eat while walking around.
Biting into piping hot karaage,
straight out of the fryer.
That's how karaage should be eaten.
Not to mention, there are
tons of schools around here,
from elementary schools to universities.
You're right. There's no reason for us to go head to head with them in the take-home food arena!
We should take advantage of our location instead!
That's exactly what we'll do!
Our keywords are...
Walk-n-Eat Karaage!
We'll have a fighting chance this way, won't we?
Yup!
I'm feeling it!
Souma-chan, I'll do my best
to improve my recipes too!
I own a bento store, after all!
Let's defeat Mozuya together!
All right!
Let's do this!
S-Sure. Good luck with that.
We're Mozuya, the famous
three-time consecutive champion
of the National Karaage Competition!
Come buy our special karaage today!
President Kinu, we've just received
the consultant's invoice.
Hmph.
I think that brat has outlived his usefulness.
There's no reason to keep paying
his high consulting fees.
Ma'am?
Oh, it's nothing.
All Mozuya needs is our secret marinade.
We do owe the consultant for getting us a spot in this impregnable fortress of a station,
but this castle belongs to me now.
We'll just keep sittin' pretty and
scarf down this town's money!
Packaging to let people eat the goods right away...
Maybe toothpicks.
Kind of like this?
Reusing milk cartons?
Huh.
I went with karaage that elementary school students might like.
This one is seasoned with curry powder,
and this one is topped with
powdered cheese that'll melt.
How are they?
They're delicious!
Both the curry and the cheese one!
But...
I think Mozuya's karaage was more satisfying.
So... I'm not sure this measures up.
I see.
The pieces have to be small if you want to fit them into a small carton or eat them with a toothpick.
It can't compete with Mozuya's meaty pieces.
The seasoning is pretty superficial too.
You have to capitalize on
the quality of the ingredients.
Say, what if you put the pieces on a skewer?
That'd let people eat it using only one hand.
Well, karaage skewers are a dime a dozen,
so it might not have much visual impact.
That's true.
The packaging needs to be novel and eye-catching,
and the flavor of the karaage needs more work.
To make us competitive with Mozuya,
we need something that'll tick both boxes.
I know!
I have a notebook containing
all the recipes I tried as a kid.
Let me go get it from my room!
Yukihira-kun's room?
Yukihira's room.
Ah! He left us all by ourselves!
I-Is there anything we can talk about?!
Um... Um...
U-Um, Mito-san!
Yeah?
Um, uh, h-how...
How is high school going?
Huh?
Oh, no! That's not what I meant to ask!
I wanted to ask what
Yukihira-kun's like in high school,
but I blurted out something that sounds like what a junior high school teacher would ask in a letter!
Um, um...
She knew Yukihira back in junior high, huh?
You see, what I really meant to ask was...
Um... well...
I guess that makes them childhood friends.
So... uh...
Um... uh...
Wait, why am I so irritated all of a sudden?!
Recover, Mayu! Recover!
M-Mito-san, you're really amazing.
You're in the most rigorous
culinary school in Japan.
I don't have any special talents.
It's no big deal.
Most people are just hopeless.
I know a real deadbeat too!
Man, just thinking about him
gets my blood boiling!
What a useless waste of oxygen!
Become the don of the Don RS!
I... I see.
Well... still...
I guess Yukihira's not so bad, though.
Does Mito-san have feelings for Yukihira-kun?
U-Um—
Oh, sorry.
You okay, Nikumi?
What the hell do you think
you're doing, Yukihira?!
Sorry, I didn't mean...
Huh?!
Maybe that was just my imagination.
Wow, it's so much juicier than before!
Right?
Mozuya's karaage is made from breast meat,
which is very lean and low in calories.
That'll be more popular with women, sure,
but if you want a rich flavor
right out of the fryer,
you gotta go with thigh meat.
Yeah!
It's got volume and taste.
At joints that serve fried chicken,
thigh meat's really popular among children.
This'll be a great crowd-pleaser for students.
Nice! Good job, Meat Master!
No big deal.
"Miito" Master?
Oh, it's a pun on Mito-san's name.
Okay, next up is the marinade.
We'll use soy sauce and
cayenne pepper as the base.
Oh, let's try using cornstarch this time.
Crap! I don't have any.
Oh, I'll go buy some!
Thanks.
We started from scratch,
but now we're just full of ideas.
Those two are amazing!
All right!
I'd say we have the seasoning figured out.
Yup!
We just have to decide how
to serve it to our customers.
Souma-chan!
Chairman?
I snuck in from the back door.
Snuck in?
I've finished it!
I created the perfect dish
for eating while walking!
It's a revolutionary idea that represents all the knowledge Tomitaya can offer!
Look!
This... is the karaage rice ball!
You can already buy this everywhere.
I've seen it in convenience stores.
I'm so embarrassed!
What a blockhead!
And I was so confident this would be a success.
I mean, karaage and rice are a match made in heaven, y'know?
A way of serving karaage that's
innovative, memorable, portable,
and able to enhance its taste.
That's it, Chairman!
Huh?
This?
No, not that.
What you just said!
That'll work!
It'll be the key to our karaage!
The battle will begin tomorrow at sundown!
Hey!
Open up!
We need you to print a bunch of these ASAP!
Yes, chicken thigh meat.
I need it, and I need it bad!
Have it delivered to Toudou Butcher Shop in the Sumire Avenue Shopping District tomorrow at 5AM!
Sis, what're you doing?
Oh, Hiro-kun! Please help me with this!
It'll be a sneak attack.
Right before dinnertime,
when the war for selling side dishes is at its peak,
we'll strike right at the enemy's heart
without giving them any chance
to launch a counterattack!
From the time we were in kindergarten,
Yukihira-kun would make disgusting bentos,
force them on his friends, and make them cry.
All right!
It's evening! Time to rake in the big bucks!
Training was tough today too.
I was already starving during practice.
What's that?
Are those brats holding karaage?
Nah, I must be mistaken.
There's no karaage more enticing
to customers than ours.
Our business is safe.
Welcome!
Would you like to buy Mozuya's karaage?
What the hell's going on?!
There're a whole bunch of people in the station holding that thing with a mark!
How are our sales looking?!
I emailed the information to you, as usual.
They're holding steady, aren't they?
Well, receipts have been down
twenty percent over the past two days.
No way!
You lot had better be providing
proper customer service!
I'll beat you up if you're slacking in any way!
Excuse me.
Yes, yes, welcome!
Is this where you can get
the Sumire Mark Karaage?
I... I believe that'd be in the shopping district in front of the station.
Oh, really?
The shopping district, huh?
Thank you for the information.
Want to get something for dinner at Mozuya?
What? I want the Sumire Mark karaage.
Hm, okay. Let's go!
Yay!
Customers are passing us by?!
How humiliating!
Um, perhaps we should call him
and tell him what's—
We can't rely on that brat, idiot!
I'm going to see for myself
what's happening on Sumire Avenue!
This place was a ghost town just three days ago!
How can this be possible?!
One, please!
I want one too!
Me too!
I'd also like one!
I'll have three!
Thank you!
Please wait a moment!
Need a re-up here!
Got it!
Coming right up!
We left large pieces of thigh meat to soak in our original marinade based on soy sauce and cayenne pepper.
Breaded and ready!
Thanks!
Man, the anticipation is killing me!
I can't wait to dig in.
And...
after frying it once to cook the meat,
we fry it a second time to crisp up the surface.
Then we put it in a special wrap
along with herbs and leaf lettuce.
Add an extra hit of flavor
with our special chili fish sauce,
as well as a dash of black pepper.
Here you go!
Enjoy the Sumire Mark Karaage Roll!
Wow, it looks really filling!
It's still sizzling!
It looks delicious!
The chicken's really plump and juicy!
The fried chicken is crispy in parts and tender where the sauce has soaked in.
The way all the different flavors mingle between the juicy meat,
the black pepper, and the vegetables...
Yummy!
Delicious.
I want one!
Give me two, boy!
I want three!
Mommy, I want to try it.
Sure!
Oh.
Tomita-san, cover the fryer for a sec!
Wha—
What?!
Hey, Souma-chan!
What's it being wrapped in?
A crepe?
Or a tortilla like they use for tacos?
I have no idea.
Well, well! If it isn't Mozuya-san!
There's no need to skulk about.
Why not line up with pride?
H-How long have you been at this?
Huh?
About three days.
What?!
The hardware store provided
the kitchen equipment.
The sheet metal store crafted the Sumire Mark branding iron.
The grocer and butcher supplied
us with the ingredients.
And the printer made the flyers and the packaging.
Everything was made here in the shopping district.
In a single night.
Who'd like ice-cold beer to go
with that karaage roll?!
We're selling taiyaki at a discount right now!
We have cold ramune here!
Try our new dish!
Free dessert with each meal!
Beer with this karaage? How sinful!
It's like a festival!
Mister, please give me one of those.
I'll have a beer.
What in the world?
With the karaage....
No, with this brat at the center,
the entire shopping district
is coming back to life!
I underestimated him.
This brat's an extraordinary tactician!
He laid siege to Mozuya in an instant,
just like Sunomata Castle that
Hideyoshi built in a single night!
Remember what you said, Mozuya-san?
A place with no competitiveness or
creativity deserves to die out, right?
Well, this place has it.
Our shopping district has what it takes!
Quit your yapping!
Who gives a shit about your karaage?!
Mozuya will crush you soon enough—
Come on, what's with that kind of talk?
Try it for yourself, Auntie!
It's really good, seriously!
This is none of your business!
And don't call me "Auntie"!
They're right, you know.
You let us try your karaage last time.
Why don't you give ours a shot?
Here's one. Dig in!
This wrap...
is made from rice flour!
I see. This is similar to bánh xèo!
Bánh xèo is a Vietnamese dish.
A thin batter made of ingredients such as
rice flour, water, and coconut milk is cooked,
then stuffed with ingredients such as pork, shrimp, and bean sprouts.
I get it now.
This is based on the idea
that piping hot rice and juicy karaage are a match made in heaven.
The pairing was reimagined,
then further strengthened by improving its portability, taste, and visual impact!
Students on their way home from club practice...
Mothers rushing home to get dinner on the table...
Commuters enjoying a break...
The hustle and bustle of
the city are strangely relaxing.
This karaage...
This ambiance...
They invoke something far more brilliant than profits and returns.
In this final match, it's the bottom of the ninth,
with two outs and bases loaded.
The pitcher winds up! Here's the pitch!
This... is the taste of youth!
Glad you liked it!
Nikumi, you're really awesome!
That marinade was super helpful.
I hope you'll teach me
a lot more from now on!
S-Sure, if I'm free.
I envy Mito-san.
After tonight, I won't get to spend any more time with Yukihira-kun.
Kurase!
Um, it's up to you, but...
Y-Yes?
Can you help Tomitaya out part-time?
What?!
We just have to hang on till
the karaage rolls stick, y'know?
But it'll be a little shaky if we
just rely on Tomita-san,
and I can't be around most of the time.
B-But I've never worked a job.
There must be someone better suited to—
Is there?
I thought I could depend on you,
because I know you're a responsible person.
What?
In junior high, you'd work really late doing class council stuff.
Even in elementary school,
you never skipped watering
the flowers when it was your turn.
I'd feel a lot better if you were here.
I always thought that he was out of reach...
but he was paying attention to me?
Well, I won't force you—
I'll... give it a try!
Really?
You're a lifesaver!
I'll come by sometimes to air out Yukihira,
so you should drop by.
I'll cook for you.
O-Okay!
Yay!
Huh?
What's the matter, Nikumi?
Nothing...
It's great to be young.
One here too.
Me too.
I've never felt so satisfied before!
I want to try it.
So that's the Sumire Mark Karaage Roll.
What's the verdict?
Here!
I give it twenty...
out of ten!
Sales have plummeted three days in a row.
Well, Mozuya-san?
What do you have to say for yourself?
Well, so much for vacation.
It was over in a flash.
Who the hell are you guys?
Yukihira Souma, right?
You're coming with us.
There you are.
And who're you?
The Sumire Mark Karaage Roll wasn't a bad idea.
I'm the one who orchestrated
Mozuya's Tokyo expansion.
And not just Mozuya.
Since junior high,
I've offered consulting services to over 500 businesses
in the food industry and led each of them to success.
I heard about how you revived
the shopping district.
Thanks to you, my record has been spoiled.
So you want to beat me up now, is that it?
No.
Come work for me.
I'll make sure you never go hungry.
I already have a goal:
to carry on my family restaurant.
I have no plans to work for anyone else.
To be honest, I didn't think
you'd accept my offer.
You're like everyone else.
Huh?
You're trapped in your own little world.
As long as you can pretend to be a professional, you're satisfied.
Your restaurant's small-time, isn't it?
Is your ambition so limited because you were born into that kind of place?
Well?
You talk big,
but you're a chef too, aren't you?
I am not.
What I am is the one whom all the chefs obey.
I've set my sights on an entirely different stage.
Yukihira Souma,
allow me to inform you that you've been chosen for the Autumn Selection.
But don't rejoice just yet.
The Selection will mark the end
of your upward trajectory.
I'll make you pay for staining my career.
Those who know of me call me...
the Alchemist!
I'm the ninth seat of the Tohtsuki Elite Ten,
Eizan Etsuya.
I'll crush you on the best stage possible.
Next time, at Bento Shop Tomitaya... No, wait!
...on Shokugeki no Souma,
the nineteenth dish:
The Chosen One.
It's so delicious, Yukihira-kun!
I'll do my best at work today!