I object!
We should re-evaluate whether this student should be chosen for the Autumn Selection.
His record hardly merits his inclusion in a time-honored gourmet festival.
Nakiri-kun.
On matters concerning food,
your judgment has been indisputable.
However, when it comes to Souma-kun,
your views border on the irrational.
Perhaps something happened between you two?
Something personal?
C-Certainly not.
I simply believe this man to be unworthy!
Isshiki-san,
perhaps you are biased in his favor because he's from your dorm.
Of course not!
Yukihira Souma...
He seems like an interesting guy.
I say we let him take part.
It's true that he has accomplished little of note at the academy.
He hasn't been here long.
Nice to meet you!
But at the camp, he made a last-minute comeback to serve 200 dishes.
He received commendations
for the first day's task as well.
A maverick like him would surely
make the festival more entertaining, don't you think?
I don't get why you're so against the idea.
No further objections, I suppose?
Then let this be the final decision.
Hey, hurry up!
They finally posted the results!
Yeah!
I didn't make it!
So these are the Autumn Selection contestants.
Oh?
Heck yeah!
Wh-What do I do now?
Hey!
So all three of you were selected too?
Souma-kun!
Good job, guys.
It seems we'll get to face off
before we'll ever have a Cooking Battle, Yukihira!
Hey, Nikumi!
Looks like you made it in.
Y-Yeah.
What about you?
Yup!
Good luck to you too, Takumi!
D-Don't treat me like a sidekick!
Isami, quit laughing!
But of course.
Um... Oh, I'm on the list too.
As if you wouldn't be!
It'd be embarrassing if my close
aide failed to be selected.
Failure is not an option during the prelims, got it?
Don't worry.
Even if I were to end up facing you,
I'm invested enough to still try to win.
Why are you upset?
What's with you?
It looks like you don't respect me very much!
I'm always trying to show you how much I respect you.
More!
I want you to show me more respect!
You should emulate Erina's secretary!
Oh, hey! You're Nakiri's cousin!
Well, well, if it isn't Yukihira Souma-kun.
How have you been?
Hey, why are all these famous
people flocking to Yukihira?
When did he even meet them?
Oh, yeah!
I'd better tell Fumio-san about this!
I bet she'll be so happy that
the "golden age" has returned!
Hello, everyone!
I have the honor of being your host for the Autumn Selection!
My name is Kawashima Urara!
Smile!
Urara-chan!
Glower...
My heartfelt congratulations to those of you who have been selected!
As I'm sure you're already aware
from the announcement,
the sixty contestants have been
split into Groups A and B.
Each group will undergo
the preliminaries separately.
Only those who attain a high enough rank within each group will advance to the actual tournament!
Let's see.
I have a message from Eizan-senpai,
a member of the Executive Committee.
"Many VIPs and heavyweights of the food industry will attend the preliminaries.
This is the perfect opportunity for you to demonstrate your talents."
"However...
...should you have the misfortune of presenting an unworthy dish,
any hope of pursuing a career in the food industry will be forfeit."
"Well, best of luck preparing for it...
...over your summer break."
That's all, everyone!
We have no choice!
I'll make it into the tournament!
Congratulations on being selected.
It was only to be expected, given your talent.
Thank you.
As your aide, I will not disappoint you, Erina-sama.
And please rest assured that
I will punish Yukihira Souma!
Oh, my deepest apologies!
I shouldn't have mentioned him!
You'd do well to flounder at
the very bottom of the barrel.
I doubt you'll be chosen for the Selection.
Selection?
Like I said, there's no way someone
like you would be chosen!
Don't get too ahead of yourself, Yukihira-kun.
Nakiri Erina stands far above you.
Nakiri's not participating?
Right.
The Autumn Selection is overseen by the Tohtsuki Elite Ten every year,
so Erina will be on the other side of the table running things.
Oh, well. I suppose it'll be a while before I can face off with Erina.
I was afraid of this.
Everyone's so talented that I feel out of place!
Why'd that dropout get picked when we didn't?
I have higher scores than her in classes and labs.
It doesn't make any sense.
What's going on?
Shut up!
You're all so pathetic.
Listen up!
The selection isn't based solely on grades.
Candidates are assessed based on a range of factors,
including their individuality and potential.
Anyone satisfied by mere grades
would never be chosen.
Look at that deep footprint!
U-Um, thank you!
Um, who are...
I'm Houjou Miyoko.
You're Tadokoro Megumi, aren't you?
I'm very interested in you.
Shinomiya Kojirou was one of the Elite Ten.
I heard you had a Cooking Battle
with him. Is that true?
And on top of that, I heard it was a draw.
Oh! But, um...
But I didn't officially get a draw!
No way!
You mean you won?
N-No, not at all! I mean—
What is it?! Speak up!
Well...
S-Souma-kun, he...
It was all th-thanks to him.
I wasn't any good by myself, so...
Yukihira Souma. You mean the transfer student?
What the hell? So it was only
because you had help from a guy?
Sorry to waste your time.
I misjudged you.
Did you know, Yukihira-kun?
Most of the current Elite Ten have fought in the main tournament.
In other words, the next Elite Ten will emerge from those who survive the preliminaries.
Ah, Erina-sama...
She's as beautiful as always.
I want her noble eyes and words to despise me!
That bitch!
Oh, how I hate her!
I am more worthy of Erina-sama!
The groups should be getting
announced right about now.
Yes.
Marui-kun.
You'll have to win this if you're going to have any chance at all.
I hope the day will come when Erina, you,
and I can all compete over the Elite Ten seats!
In the middle of the room, there's a scorch mark.
It used to be my room.
Until the next time you lose to me,
you'd better not lose to anyone else.
I'll crush you.
I'm getting hyped up.
Well! What a beautiful morning!
It's the perfect way to start off summer break!
Hey!
Look, everybody, look!
It's here!
It's from the Autumn Selection office!
C'mon, let's open it.
Curry...
dish?
So we just have to make curry rice?
It says "dish," so it doesn't have to be curry rice.
I guess it can be any dish
that uses curry in some form.
Right, Isshiki-senpai?
Well, I wonder.
Aw, you're avoiding the question!
Curry....
It's such a broad theme that
I don't know where to begin.
Sakaki-kun, you make good tea.
May I have seconds?
Hm?
What was Polar Star Dormitory like back then?
It was fun.
Everyone worked on perfecting
their craft however they could.
Oh, there was one student who always made curry.
Her name was Shiomi.
I think she became an instructor at Tohtsuki.
If you ever meet her, mention my name.
I looked after her a lot back then.
I think she'll look after you.
That's what my dad told me.
I guess that's the place up ahead.
Huh?
It's more run-down than I expected.
Maybe she's scary, like Chappelle-sensei.
Hello!
Shiomi, Shiomi...
Excuse me!
Huh?
No one's here?
Holy crap!
Um...
A visitor?!
Um, um...
Sorry!
I'll put on some tea!
She's so short.
Oh, sorry for being so inconsiderate!
Is she in junior high?
I'm sorry, please don't mind us!
Sorry, I'm always spacing out!
I'm sorry for barging in like this!
Oh, don't worry about it!
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
They're apologizing for making
the other one apologize.
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry.
So, uh, is the instructor in charge of this lab around?
If you could tell her that Saiba
Jouichirou's son came by to see—
You're Saiba Jouichirou's son?
Please get the hell out!
What?
Um, he's unconscious right now,
so that might be difficult.
I don't even want to think about Saiba-senpai!
Hey, Jun. I got you what you wanted—
Oh, sorry for the intrusion!
Hey, c'mon!
Are you even trying?
Find the best angle!
But you're beautiful from every angle.
You don't have to tell me that!
Okay.
Nice to meet you.
M-My name is Shiomi Jun.
Welcome to Polar Star Dormitory.
I heard you passed Fumio-san's
entrance test on your first try.
You sound quite promising.
Th-Thank you!
Mornin'!
Jouichirou, go get dressed.
Huh? Fresh meat?
Okay, it's time for a welcome.
Want to try a new recipe of mine?
S-Sure, I'd love to!
And so it came to pass that, as the most junior resident of Polar Star Dormitory,
I was subjected to Saiba-senpai's experiments at every turn and tortured like you wouldn't believe.
No!
That was how I became scarred for life.
Hey, you haven't changed one bit!
Well, that's perhaps because I've always been partial to spices.
Many spices are good for your looks.
There's no way that's the whole story!
Man, my dad really treated
his underclassmen poorly,
Stare...
didn't he, Tadokoro?
Um, so, the two of us are from Polar Star,
and we wanted to learn more about curry.
That's right.
The Autumn Selection—
I don't mind teaching the girl what I know.
But I'll never speak with Saiba-senpai or any of his family members.
Sorry. As our guests, she should be
treating you two with more respect.
I'm Hayama. I'm a first-year in high school, just like you guys.
I'm an assistant here.
Really?
I thought you could only join a lab
once you're a second-year.
Well, it's because this woman needs me.
She's incapable of anything besides fiddling around with spices.
Isn't that so, Jun?
Don't call me Jun!
Call me Professor Shiomi!
Hayama-kun, you're my assistant!
You should show me some respect—
Jun, you were supposed to water the plants today.
You forgot.
I did it in your stead.
Yes, sorry.
You forgot last week too,
and the spice plants almost died.
Yes. That was my fault.
And who took care of the guests
that you ignored entirely last month?
It was you, Hayama-kun.
She's getting even tinier.
Look, Souma-kun.
Yeah, there are a ton of spices.
Oh, this smells a lot like curry!
It's a spice called kadi patta.
It also goes by the name "curry leaf."
Huh?
Is this fresh?
You know this, Tadokoro?
Yeah.
The tree is very susceptible to cold weather.
It will die in the winter.
So in Japan, you usually only see dried curry leaf.
It's very difficult to get fresh leaves.
It's one of Jun's research projects.
She's devised a way to reliably
cultivate tropical spices in Japan.
Aside from pioneering new freezing
techniques for long-term storage,
she's managed to extract many
never-before-seen flavor compounds.
Wow, you're more accomplished
than you look, Sensei!
Y-Your flattery doesn't make me happy.
Still, yes.
That shows how much potential
is locked inside the spices.
To start with, spices speak to these three factors:
fragrance, spiciness, and color.
Blending spices creates synergy.
The more spices you blend,
the less their own attributes stick out.
But if you are not mindful in selecting your spices,
blending may combine to produce off-flavors.
Twenty different spices is the limit!
In addition, fat is indispensable for making the most of spices!
By heating spices in oil,
you can amplify their fragrance.
What, we're being subjected
to a full-on lecture now?
The flavor is best enhanced
through emulsification!
Ugh, she'll be stuck like this for a while.
Hey, maybe it'll be faster for you
to learn by experiencing it firsthand.
Come have a taste.
I'll show you how deep the spice world goes.
Here's the first dish.
Kozhi vartha curry.
It's a traditional south Indian dish.
I used the curry leaf you saw earlier to flavor it.
Wow, it looks really good!
What's this?
First, the strong fragrance of
the curry leaf pierces your nose.
Then the spicy umami of chili peppers and onions follow, filling your mouth!
That's the power of fresh curry leaf.
It's ten times as potent
as the dried version.
All right.
Here's the next dish.
Goan fish curry, which uses whitefish such as marlin and salmon.
Huh?
Two servings of the same curry?
They both use the same ingredients and spices.
Compare how they taste.
The second one I ate... tastes much better?
That's right.
For the second dish,
I toasted red peppers and
coriander in a frying pan.
Dry-roasting is the key to that difference.
What?
Just doing that changed the dish this much?
The fragrance in this one
is worlds above the other!
I understand what she was talking about now.
All the ingredients' flavors are grounded
and unified by the dry-roasted spices!
Here's the last one.
It looks just like the kozhi vartha curry we first tried.
Right, but it's totally different.
The curry leaf flavor is stronger
in this one, several times over!
The burst of spiciness in your mouth
is much stronger in this one too!
The flavor is much more distinct!
Note that I haven't added any
new ingredients for this curry.
I simply simmered the ingredients
in water instead of stock.
Water?!
I applied what Jun said earlier.
The more flavors you blend together,
the less pronounced each flavor becomes.
This is the other side of the same coin.
By removing the flavor of the stock,
I magnified the flavor of
the spices in this curry.
But that usually means
the taste will lack depth.
And yet, this fragrance is really assertive.
It's piercing me!
I wouldn't have imagined a dish
could undergo such a dramatic change
just by handling the spices a little differently!
He didn't look into the pot
even once while cooking.
The fennel's fragrance is starting to come through.
Five seconds until the fennel's been heated through.
Forty seconds until the coconut paste's flavors are melded with the rest.
He monitored what he was cooking
just through the fragrance
of the ingredients and spices
wafting up from the pot!
I told you.
She needs me.
I transform her principles into actual cooking.
Huh?
Everyone's gone!
That's the role I play here.
A scientist who generates theory,
and a chef who puts it into practice!
I must admit, I laughed when I saw what the preliminaries' topic was.
Who knew it'd be a curry dish?
You're in the Autumn Selection too?
And in the same group as you, Yukihira Souma.
Huh?
Did I tell you my name earlier?
Come now, everyone knows your name.
Or at the very least, any first-year
who attended the opening ceremony.
Your cooking's quite interesting.
Even when faced with all kinds of obstacles,
you use inspiration to overcome them.
But that's not enough to climb
to the top of Tohtsuki.
There's something that reaches the diner long before flavor and appearance.
And it lingers on long after
the diner chews and swallows.
That's fragrance.
The one who dominates the field of cooking
is the one who dominates its fragrance.
In other words, the one who'll
take the top spot at Tohtsuki...
is me, Hayama Akira!
Well, thanks for the food.
Your curry was seriously good.
I'll repay you for that next time.
Next time?
I'll let you taste curry
that's even better than yours...
at the preliminaries.
You think you can defeat me at curry?
You still don't get it after eating my curry?
Oh, I get it all right.
It was scary.
Huh?
Here's a guy who can make something I can't.
Of course I'm super envious.
Thanks for teaching me a lot!
I'll see you again at the prelims—
Hey!
I was still in the middle of my lecture!
The doorknob stabbed me in the gut.
I'm so sorry!
Yukihira Souma.
Facing curry means facing the spice head-on.
You have to face the fragrance.
My sense of smell is unparalleled.
You don't have a snowball's
chance in hell of beating me.
Oh, sorry, I spaced out!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the twentieth dish:
The Dragon Lies Down
and Ascends the Skies.
Oh, I'm sorry. What am I supposed to say?
Um, um, um...
Summer break!
S-Summer break!
Summer break...