Hm?
What's wrong, Tadokoro?
After seeing Hayama-kun
with all his different curries...
I guess I'm feeling a little down.
All right.
There's just a little over a month till the Selection.
How am I supposed to come up with a dish
that'll stand up to the likes of Hayama-kun?
At my family's diner,
whenever I'd get a good look
at my dad working away,
I could tell, y'know?
That I still had so much more to learn.
But Dad still made me come up
with new menu items.
I was so nervous.
After all, I was only in sixth grade.
I'd never be able to deal with that much pressure!
The thing is...
if I let that sorta stuff get to me,
I'd never come up with anything.
I don't have the time to be thinking about how I might fail to measure up.
I couldn't run away from
my family's diner back then,
and I can't run away from the Selection.
I just have to deal with it and push on, you know?
Okay! Yeah!
Also, about the topic...
Spices are important, sure,
but I don't think they're
the only thing that matters.
With only six weeks until the Autumn Selection,
thus began the scorching summer we spent facing curry head-on.
There are roughly forty varieties of spices that might be found in a typical curry.
So you have to pick out between ten and twenty of them to make a blend. Okay.
Some spices may cancel each other out,
so you can't just randomly throw some together.
You have to figure out whether to use whole, ground, or fresh spices,
which oils and cooking methods
will maximize their flavor,
which roasting and maturation methods will work,
and whether they'll pair well with the ingredients.
Huh?
Come back!
Megumi!
Spices are important, sure,
but they're not the only thing.
Wow, what a great honor!
To think that one of our Don RS members would be selected as a candidate!
Use your super-high-quality meat to score a spot in the main tournament, Nikumi!
Then we'll rake in gobs of club funds and perks.
We'll attract scores of members!
The Don RS's future will be secured!
It's not that simple.
Simply serving good meat won't cut it.
I have to figure out the best combination of spices and the right meat to go with them.
My greatest weapon is meat dishes.
I'll create a curry that'll best
take advantage of that.
You'd go so far for the Don RS?
Nikumi—
Shut up about the Don RS already!
Are you sure you don't want
to go back to Italy yet?
Yeah.
Mom and Dad will be sad.
There are plenty of regulars
waiting for your cooking too.
I'm only pushing back my flight by a few days.
I want to think about this
a bit longer on my own.
All right.
Then give it all you've got.
Try to beat me!
Okay.
But you better not cry if I win, Bro.
You always cried when you lost at some game.
Hey, that was when we were in elementary school!
Ugh, I'm leaving!
Hey, Bro!
Huh?
Do you have your passport?
Can you check in and board the plane on your own?
Use the restroom before you board.
Quit making fun of your brother!
Have a safe trip!
Heh. I won't stand for any of that bullshit!
So what if she's the daughter of Chef Houjou?
I won't stand for no woman heading the kitchen!
The moment she sets foot in here,
I'll bully her right outta here!
Delicious!
It's hard to believe that a third-year
junior high schooler could make this.
Yeah.
She's already as good as the chief, if not better.
Chief!
When I graduate from Tohtsuki in three years time, I'll be joining your kitchen.
I look forward to it, Senpai.
I'll be entering a battlefield full of formidable men.
I need prestige!
I need overwhelming prestige so that they
won't dare look down on me for being a girl!
First, I'll win the Autumn Selection,
and then I'll win the first seat on the Elite Ten!
You can count on Houjou Miyoko to do just that!
Once August arrived,
Polar Star members began
going home to visit their families.
And...
You're going back today?
Yeah.
It's Obon season.
I also want to see how spices pair up
with the local ingredients back home.
I see.
Good luck.
Thanks. You too!
You'll be the only first-year
here for a while, but...
Well, it's not like I'll be bored.
See you soon.
Okay!
Bring back presents!
I will!
Three weeks until the prelims.
This is it.
With this flavor, I will triumph.
I'll get you this time!
For sure!
I can feel it!
Just you wait, Arato Hisako.
What's wrong, Hisako?
Oh, it's nothing.
I just felt a slight chill.
Oh, that's not good!
Should I turn down the air conditioner?
E-Erina-sama, you don't need to worry about me.
Then do you need anything else?
No, it's enough that you're
allowing me to use your kitchen.
What about tea?
Should I make you some tea?
No, um...
Really, please don't worry about me.
Oh my, Erina's bored out of her skull
because she's not competing in the prelims.
Looks that way.
Well, I've basically figured out what I'll make,
so I'm bored too.
Um, Miss.
I'd like to work on my curry too.
No way! You have to entertain me!
Hey!
It's you, Megumi!
Hi, everyone!
It's been a while!
We heard all about it!
You got picked for a super-big contest!
You're our pride and joy for sure!
O-Oh, stop it, you guys.
Megumi!
Welcome home.
Mom!
I'm home!
It's been a long time since I've
had your help in the kitchen.
I think you're better than ever.
Oh, I still have a ways to go.
I'm always making mistakes.
Even during camp, Souma-kun...
What the hell? So it was only
because you had help from a guy?
I misjudged you.
It's just like Houjou-san said.
I've always had someone helping me.
But in the prelims, I have to fight on my own.
Even I have to wonder what exactly I'm capable of.
Souma-kun, did you pull an all-nighter?
Oh, Isshiki-senpai, morning.
That's a lot of trials you've got there.
This one's interesting.
Yes, really interesting, Souma-kun!
Oh? But I'm just getting started.
I'll make it even better...
Hayama-kun?
Did you pull another all-nighter?
Yeah.
It's almost done.
My secret weapon of a spice mix.
You shouldn't!
If you work yourself to the bone, you'll get sick!
Look who's talking.
You often pull all-nighters yourself, Jun.
Quit calling me Jun!
It's Professor Shiomi!
Oh, and do try to stop passing out on the floor.
You're pretty heavy for a runt.
A-And here I was all worried about you!
I hope you lose, Hayama-kun!
I won't lose.
I'll prove to everyone that you
and I make an unbeatable team.
Sorry, Hayama-kun.
I forgot to water them again.
Are you mad?
I'm not mad.
I'm so, so sorry.
You must be mad.
I'm not mad.
Ah, I knew it! You really are mad!
This place is huge.
Are we really going to cook here?
Souma-kun!
Tadokoro!
How did your summer go?
It was good. I think I trained
hard for this in my own way—
Megumi!
Long time no see!
You look well.
You too, Yukihira!
How've you been?
Well, so-so, I guess.
Oh, Nikumi.
H-Hey.
We're in the same group.
Let's get through this together.
To...
Together?!
Y-You idiot, we're rivals!
I'm not g-gonna lose to you this time!
S-Sure.
I'm disappointed I'm not in the same group as you.
Oh.
But Ryou-kun is. Have fun, you two.
Ryou-kun, say hello.
'Sup.
'S-'Sup.
The lingering scent of spices
is coming from your fingers.
Hayama!
I guess you've been hard at work.
Yup.
I want to let you taste some really great curry.
Heh.
Yukihira!
Oh, Takumi.
It's been a while.
I'll... I'll say this to you now.
Your true rival is me right here—
Hey, who's the guy standing next to you?
Who, him?
It's Isami, of course.
Huh?
You're lying!
Wh-What's with you?
Isami loses some weight every year
when the summer heat gets to him.
This is because of the summer heat?!
I feel more comfortable this way, but don't worry.
I'll be back to my old self come fall and winter.
S-So this happens every year?
I'm amazed you're still alive.
A-Anyway, now you know.
This is Isami.
Okay, let's start from the top.
Yukihira?!
Thank you for your patience, everyone!
Eyes on the front stage, please.
Hey, what's going on?
Oh, sorry, can this wait?
Huh? Hey, wait!
We'll be starting with a speech
by the director of Tohtsuki Academy,
Nakiri Senzaemon.
Nakiri Senzaemon...
He's the old guy who made that
speech at the opening ceremony.
D-Director?!
D-Don't mind me.
I just choked on something.
When I breathe in the air here,
I can feel the energy coursing
through me, body and soul.
He was coughing just now, though.
Shh!
This is the Hall of the Moon Gods.
Ordinarily, only the Elite Ten may use this space to challenge each other in Cooking Battles.
To show our respect to those
who have won the first seat,
it is traditional to display their portraits.
Whoa!
He's right.
There's Doujima-senpai over there.
Shinomiya-senpai too! He was a first seat?
Countless unforgettable battles
have been fought here,
and countless specialties have been born here.
That is why the memories of
the battles fought here
linger in the air like a thick fog!
And this is also where the main tournament
for the Autumn Selection will be held.
In other words, only students who pass the prelims...
Right. Only they may fight on that stage.
You will all make your marks on history today!
Let us meet here again,
chefs of the 92nd class of Tohtsuki Academy!
Oh right, Takumi.
What was it that you wanted to say earlier?
Forget it.
We'll now explain the rules for the preliminaries.
As indicated in our written notice,
the theme of this stage is curry.
You will have three hours.
Out of the sixty candidates in the preliminaries,
eight will advance to the main tournament.
In other words, there will be four from each group.
Only that many?!
They'll be weeding us out real fast.
Candidates should proceed to their group's designated workspaces.
The preliminaries will begin at eleven o'clock.
Let's go!
Let's do this!
There's no point in getting scared!
Yeah.
Right!
Yukihira!
Let's meet again back in here...
at the main tournament!
Yup.
Begin cooking!
Welcome.
Surely you were informed that
we would begin promptly at eleven?
What is the point of such questions when you know just how difficult it is
to free up even a minute of my schedule?
Well, Eizan-kun?
S-Sendawara Natsume!
She controls the curry business in Japan.
She's the Queen of Curry!
Eizan-kun talked me into coming,
but can mere students hope to be anything but a waste of my time?
Heh, just keep shelling out the big bucks to me.
What was that?
Oh, nothing.
Please enjoy the Autumn Selection
to your heart's content,
Natsume-sama.
Eizan-senpai's amazing.
Only he could bring in a superstar like her.
Yeah. If we're getting Sendawara Natsume,
I bet Group B's getting...
Yeah, her twin, Sendawara Orie!
Say, Isshiki-kun,
when will you join our company?
I can't wait for you to be mine already.
But I'm still just a student.
That's no problem at all.
Go ahead and drop out right now.
You'll be set for life if you stick with me.
C'mon, hurry up!
I can't wait any longer!
Well, for today, please enjoy the dishes
prepared by the cute first-years.
Hm, oh, very well.
Takumi Aldini... Is he from Italy?
It looks like he's making stock from beef shank and chicken bones.
How boring.
His younger brother is next to him.
Isami Aldini.
He's covered the bottom of his pot with tomatoes.
Tomatoes are a staple vegetable of Italian cuisine.
I'm sure he knows all about them.
Oh, this peculiar, insistent fragrance!
It must be from spices being sautéed in duck fat!
Keep it up!
Yoshino!
Oh, look over there. What is she making?
By all accounts, she should have
sautéed those spices in fat,
but instead she poured them
straight into water!
Look!
Nakiri Alice's doing something totally different from the rest!
What the hell are those giant machines?
A flash freezer and a centrifuge?
I can't imagine what kind of
dish you'd make with those!
Well, the same goes for Sadatsuka Nao.
Her roux's pitch black!
That's not cooking. That's black magic!
Miyoko-sama!
Sister!
I feel like someone's getting
all the attention from the guys!
That's the heir to Houjou-rou,
a famous restaurant in Yokohama's Chinatown.
Many of the spices used in Chinese cuisine can also be used in curry.
It'll be interesting to see
the twist she puts on her dish!
It's true there are a few students who look interesting.
Fine, I've made up my mind.
Give me all the students over there.
G-Give?
You don't hold back, do you?
Oh, but...
I don't need the girl with the braids.
She has no flair.
I don't think she has much potential.
Oh, I wouldn't be so sure about that.
That girl is using Sichuan peppercorns.
It's a spice that can remove gaminess from meat.
Not to mention, she ground it coarsely, so it retains its rich fragrance.
Well done.
Nikumi...
You've grown so much.
Hey, Nikumi!
I'm cheering you on!
He's like a dad watching
his daughter at a sports festival!
J-Just ignore him!
How's everyone else doing?
Nakiri Alice's aide...
Most of the prep work's done.
Okay.
The hell?!
He's like a totally different guy!
What extravagant movements.
Indeed.
In comparison, however, that one's quite dull.
Is that... udon?
That'd be the one who specializes in fermented goods,
Sakaki Ryouko.
It's black?
And what on earth is that sticky substance?!
This prelim's strongest contender should be him.
Fish head curry, hm.
By using the entire head of a whitefish,
you can enjoy the full flavor of the fish.
It's a curry dish originating in Singapore.
He's pairing it with naan, not rice.
It's less original than I'd expected.
That naan, could it be?
That's right, Jun.
My cooking's just getting started!
This fragrance...
This slight twinge of freshness amid the rich smell of coconut milk...
That freshness makes you hungry!
Despite all of the aromas in the air,
you can tell which one's coming from his pot.
It's evidence that he's blended
his spices to perfection.
This is a different kind of fragrance.
It's smoke!
I see!
Smoking is yet another method of adding fragrance to a dish.
The air in this hall has changed yet again!
Hm.
Well, it seems I'll be a bit entertained.
So, who's your pick, Eizan-kun?
Hm, let me think.
At this point it's hard to say,
but there is a man whose
abilities I wish to assess in full.
What?
Yukihira?
No way...
He's asleep!
I'm Natsume!
I'm Orie!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the twenty-first dish:
Menu
The Unknown Known
The Unknown Known.
Thrill me!
Be thrilled!
Why didn't you cut it into a bunny shape?!
Oh...
You good-for-nothing!