What?
He's asleep?
He dozed off while sitting on a chair like that?
Now!
Now's the time!
This fragrance...
Hm?
Hey, look!
Look at that pot!
It's rice!
He's simmering the rice
with vegetables and spices!
Your pot...
You've added a paste of
apples, bananas, and carrots.
The rice gains a creamy consistency,
similar to a risotto.
Nice one, Hayama.
You're spot on. I knew you'd figure it out.
You've got quite the nose!
No, there's another secret.
He hasn't used anything special
in his blend of spices,
so what's the key to this complex fragrance?
Man, I was up all night testing recipes.
I was so focused on working out the differing smells
that I didn't get any sleep. Whoopsie!
You've got balls of steel, man.
Well, you just wait and see.
My cooking's just getting started.
The dropout's going at it in such a boring manner.
Man, she's getting on my nerves.
Go back to the farm, you country bumpkin!
What did you two boys just say?
Say it again loud and clear, why don't ya?
Cut it out!
Just let them be.
C'mon, Fumio-san!
They were trying to get under Tadokoro's skin!
Never mind them. You've got
some girls to cheer on!
A'ight.
Yeah, yeah.
Tadokoro, Yoshino, hang in there!
Yeah!
You can do it!
I'm finally done with the prep work.
I'd better hurry up and start cooking.
Do you know who's the biggest
nuisance in a kitchen?
The klutz who's unaware of her surroundings!
Houjou-san, I'm so sorry!
I'll be more careful.
Hmph.
Houjou's finally adding in her spices!
She's letting the fragrance fully develop,
then stir-frying the eggs and rice!
Look over there!
There's something amazing going on!
He cut the pasta in a second.
What skill!
He took the mezzaluna, typically used for mincing,
and cut the dough into equal widths!
What's that dough his brother's holding?
You can't keep your eyes off either of them!
Tadokoro's not falling behind, either.
Yeah!
Watch her masterful work!
Wait, what?
Tadokoro...
Tadokoro Megumi.
When I heard about her
Cooking Battle with Shinomiya,
I thought she might be good
enough to go up against men,
but she turned out to be
as wimpy as she looks.
Look!
A monkfish?!
She's going to cut that up?!
What's that girl doing?
She's preparing to butcher a monkfish.
I can see that.
Monkfish are covered by a gelatinous slime,
so it's difficult to break them down on a cutting board.
Hanging them is the traditional way to do it.
But...
She'll be cutting into the fish
while it's free to move around.
which requires a high degree of skill.
She chose such a difficult fish to work with.
That's awfully risky of her at an event like this.
Dig in!
Souma-kun has always had a positive attitude, no matter the situation.
He's always helped me.
He's not with me right now,
but he's fighting on his own at this very moment.
I don't know if I can do this by myself,
but Souma-kun, please lend me
some of your courage today!
I learned that trick a long time ago.
When you're nervous,
doing that can help you relax.
The only problem is that
you can't do it by yourself.
All right!
I'm sorry.
I know butchering the monkfish has been a huge draw.
And I'd like to keep doing it for the customers,
but my body's just not what it used to be.
Don't push yourself too hard.
You've worked so hard for all this time.
We can just stop putting on that demonstration.
What the hell?!
You want to learn how
to butcher a hanging monkfish?
You've got to be kidding me!
Women and children couldn't possibly master it!
P-Please teach me!
I want to help at home!
Please!
I'm begging you!
Fine.
If you promise you won't ever cry, I'll teach you.
But if you say even once that
you're tired or want to rest,
that'll be the end of it, you hear?
No! You're doing it all wrong!
Don't make me repeat
the same thing every time!
Don't you think you've had enough?
Just give it up.
Is this...
good enough...
for us to keep on doing this?
Amazing.
Megumi...
The monkfish butchering demo!
Sh-She did it!
All by herself.
She broke down the monkfish!
Just what is that girl planning to make?
See?
This is her true ability!
It's about time you two head over to
Hall A to cheer Ryouko and Yuuki on.
We're on it!
You can count on us!
Yup, that's the spirit.
You're one of the Polar Star members that I, Daimidou Fumie, accepted.
All right! I'm gonna show
everyone how amazing I am too!
The time allotted for cooking is almost over!
Please put on the finishing touches, everyone!
Five!
Four!
Three!
Two!
One!
Time's up!
Soon...
Very soon.
Arato Hisako, the moment when I'll expose you
for the failure you are is near.
Erina-sama will finally smile upon me!
Become sinister!
We will now enter the judging phase!
Here again is your host...
Kawashima Urara!
Smile!
So freakin' cute, Urara-chan!
So annoyed!
There are five judges here today.
Each judge can award up to twenty points,
so a dish can be awarded a
maximum of a hundred points.
Only the top four scorers will
advance to the main tournament!
Only the top four...
Now let's ask our judges to
evaluate the first contestant!
Hm.
Mm, delicious!
Kita Osaji.
He hosts the Kitami Gastronomy Club, which only top-notch literati
and financial heavyweights can join.
He spends his fortune on bringing
all kinds of gourmet food to his table.
The man over there is Andou Shingo.
He is a writer and essayist specializing in food culture.
He has closed many businesses with a stroke of his pen.
This dish is based on achari murgh,
a traditional North Indian curry dish.
The special chaat masala has a strong acidity. It adds a wonderful fragrance.
On top of that, rather than the usual tandoori chicken,
you made it with chicken tikka instead.
It's boneless, so it's easy to eat with a spoon.
You've done your research,
and you've shown due consideration for the diner!
Not bad for a Tohtsuki student.
Thank you.
The scores, then, if you please!
What?
Each judge has twenty points
and not ten, right?
But they were praising him so much.
M-My dish only got 33 points?
What's the meaning—
Who exactly do you think we are?
We encounter dishes made by
countless professionals every day.
We may have said you did a good job,
but we meant a good job for a student.
I'd say a score of 50 points would be something to be proud of!
I see now.
It's not just the Sendawara sisters
who are to be feared.
All five of the judges have become jaded after
partaking in all the gourmet world has to offer.
They have vast experience in food tasting.
28 points!
31 points!
6 points!
Unbelievable.
All of the dishes have been very refined too!
No one's even gotten a score in the 40's!
The harsh scores continue to rock the arena!
Up next...
Wh-What's this stench?!
Where's this horrible smell coming from?!
Enjoy.
It's Sadatsuka Nao's special jet-black curry laksa!
Crap!
So nasty.
It's like concentrated sewage!
It's hell!
Hell on Earth is erupting right here in the arena!
It's difficult to imagine that a gourmet food festival is being held at this moment!
What a horrific scene!
I thought something like this might happen.
Good thing I came prepared with my cutting-edge gas mask.
Laksa...
A Southeast Asian dish known for its exceptionally slippery noodles.
The black color of the roux
may be from squid ink, but...
This overpowering stench...
It couldn't be!
It's kusaya.
I knew it!
How dare you use such a thing in curry, you idiot!
Kusaya...
It's a famous dried fish from the Izu Islands.
Kusaya is made with a fish-curing brine that has been used for decades.
The fermented liquid is used to flavor blue-black fish such as sardines.
The fish are then left to dry in the sun.
They are very smelly.
It's something I made myself,
using flying fish and mahi-mahi,
as well as my precious kusaya, which I've carefully fermented for a very long time.
Zero points! Zero!
I've eaten all kinds of delicacies, but this—
L-Lady Orie?
You can't be serious!
I am merely fulfilling my duties as the sponsor of the preliminaries.
Eww...
The bitter acidity and fishiness mingle to create an odor that's like an unscrubbed toilet!
I-It's delicious?
But it stinks!
It stinks to high heaven!
But still, it's somehow delicious!
But it stinks!
Wh-What's going on?
She's digging in, even while she says it stinks!
This is not so different from using fermented shrimp paste, kapi.
By using kusaya,
which is far more pungent than kapi,
she added depth to the flavor.
It also pairs very well with laksa,
which uses fish stock.
The umami of all the seafood coats my entire mouth. How delicious!
The more I eat, the more this
odor actually seems pleasant!
The use of coconut milk and spices like lemongrass has broadened its flavor!
By using kusaya as the main ingredient,
she has strengthened the umami many times over!
Sadatsuka Nao's specialty is stewed dishes.
She's also well versed in the use of ingredients with strong flavor profiles, such as dried fish.
Her kitchen emanates a malicious aura
that may well make children
cry and run for their lives.
And on several occasions,
she has caused evacuations.
It has earned her the nickname...
"The Boiling Witch."
True aesthetics won't be found in prim, pretentious cooking.
The essence of gourmet cooking can only be found in the pursuit of horror.
How innovative!
It's the beginning of a new era for curry!
I hate it!
It reeks!
But I can't stop!
I've become prisoner to this smell!
W-We have 84 points!
She's the first one to get over 50 points!
Sadatsuka did it!
She's in first place for now!
I hope I can serve this curry
to Erina-sama some day.
All right. Now that the ventilation systems are running at full blast, we'll proceed.
Will the next student please present their dish?
I've long awaited this day,
the day on which I get to crush you in public,
Arato Hisako.
This match has been confirmed by the
administration to be an official Cooking Battle!
Any objections to the conditions put forth?
Listen, Arato-san. If I win,
you will hand over your position as Erina-sama's secretary to me.
Of course, Sadatsuka-san.
And if I win,
you must never again come within 50 meters of Erina-sama!
Standing at Erina-sama's side...
and being verbally abused by her
is my ultimate dream!
Thinking of all these insults rolling off her God Tongue is enough to...
I believe that matter has long been settled.
I won the Cooking Battle.
Indeed.
It's true that ever since,
I have been limited to worshiping
Erina-sama's face through binoculars
and sending about 30 letters every day.
I should've included that stuff
in the restraining order!
But if I can best you in the Autumn Selection,
it's such a large venue that
Erina-sama might change her mind.
I'm sure she'll let me stay by her side.
Next up is Erina-sama's secretary.
I'm sure she'll serve something spectacular.
Please enjoy.
The roux isn't very thick,
and there's so much of it.
Is it something like a soup curry?
This meat is mutton.
Mutton has a stronger, gamier flavor than lamb.
I guess the spices have taken care of that gamey smell.
The smell!
My cooking has left its mark.
This is just like a curse!
A curse upon you, Arato-san!
Well, let's give this a try.
What is this?!
Andou-sensei, what's the matter?
Wh-What?!
Andou-sensei's normally such a dried-out stick of a weakling
that you can barely understand
what he's mumbling!
I don't understand what just happened, but he's become energized.
He could star in a kung fu movie now!
This distinct fragrance...
Chinese angelica, Sichuan lovage,
foxglove root, and peony root.
These four medicinal plants
form the basis of this dish.
The Four Substance Decoction!
The Four Substance Decoction?
This dish has its own legend.
Supposedly, a dying traveler recovered instantly upon tasting this dish!
I see now!
Earlier, she was steeping the spices!
Yes, that's her specialty.
Arato Hisako is an expert in medicinal cuisine.
It blends food, medicine, and pharmacology.
Based on Eastern medicine, it seeks to
provide holistic nourishment to the body
by using steeped herbs, as well
as other natural remedies.
In addition to the four herbs,
I added kyo'o, daiuikyo, and shouikyo,
to create an original medicinal spice mix.
I steeped these spices for approximately
an hour to extract their active ingredients.
Then I added vegetables and mutton and simmered them until tender.
Finally, I added Shaoxing wine and
coriander to heighten the fragrance.
Now that you mention it, the main components of medicinal cuisine aren't that different from curry.
Kyo'o is otherwise known as turmeric,
daiuikyo is star anise,
and shouikyo is fennel.
All three spices are essential in curry!
She decided to capitalize on it by
connecting medicinal cuisine with curry.
This is my medicinal dish:
the Four Substance Decoction Mutton Curry!
This is the real deal!
It's coursing through me!
The power of the medicinal herbs are coursing through my veins!
So delicious!
The strong flavor of the mutton has been enhanced by the spices
and mellowed by the sweetness of the vegetables cooked into the roux!
Thanks to the Four Substance Decoction,
I became all warmed up inside the moment I had a spoonful!
Yes.
Medicinal cuisine is said to warm
one's organs, hearten one's spirit,
and completely purify both body and soul!
The way you maximized the fragrance and balanced the umami is beyond reproach!
It surpasses what a normal student could make by far!
After eating this dish, the previous dish feels like a mere crude shock to the senses.
I-It can't be.
All of the judges should've been
bewitched by my curry.
This is for you.
Once you eat it,
you'll understand the difference
between you and me!
The murk...
The chaos...
That is the font of my cooking.
But now, it's all being washed away and purified!
No!
Stop!
The Arato family has practiced
Eastern medicine for generations.
I have converted all of that knowledge into cooking for Erina-sama,
who has endured a heavy
burden since childhood.
That is what my medicinal
cuisine is based upon.
The emperors of imperial China had
a special physician, a dietetic doctor,
who served them medicinal cuisine.
Erina-sama is my empress.
Sadatsuka Nao, your cooking
has always been self-centered.
You do not deserve to serve Erina-sama.
You are a blight. Begone.
Now, what will Arato Hisako's score be?
92 points!
Finally, a score in the 90's!
No surprise there! She's been
acknowledged by Erina-sama as a chef!
She surpassed Sadatsuka's score with ease!
Hisako-onee-sama!
It's time for the long-awaited
clash between brothers!
Bro...
I really want to beat you today.
I'll spar with you for a bit, little brother.
It's the Aldini brothers!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the twenty-second dish.
I'm gonna be number one!
The One Who Surpasses the Ordinary.
Doesn't it smell good?
Princess Erina, I will protect you!
Prince Hisako!