will emerge from those who survive the preliminaries.
Of the sixty participants in the preliminaries,
only the four highest-ranked candidates from
Groups A and B will advance to the main tournament!
That'll be just eight people in all!
28 points!
31 points!
6 points!
Unbelievable.
All the dishes have been very refined too!
Sadatsuka Nao, 84 points!
So what will Arato Hisako's score be?
92 points!
Finally, a score in the 90's!
No surprise there! She's been
acknowledged by Erina-sama as a chef!
Next up to present a dish is Houjou Miyoko!
How will the judges score her dish?
Here we go!
87 points!
She has pushed Sadatsuka Nao
aside to take second place!
Fragrant with both spices and pineapple,
her pineapple curry fried rice
is surely unforgettable!
The sweetness of the fruit and the savoriness of the stir-fried rice fill your mouth.
It's an experience not unlike sweet-and-sour pork,
another Chinese dish made with pineapple.
The dish was finished by placing the stir-fried rice into half a hollowed out pineapple,
capping it with the other half as a lid,
and then baking it in the oven.
She salted the interior of the pineapple to
control how sweet the rice would become.
That allowed her to impart just
the refreshing fragrance of the fruit
to the rice and also prevent
the dish from drying out.
This dish is an advancement in Chinese cuisine.
Invincible and indomitable.
She is like a kung fu master
cloaked in a dragon of flame!
She is the Iron Fire Dragon Girl!
Unsurprisingly, she's heir to the oldest dining establishment in Chinatown.
This dish is something that puts men to shame!
Or should I say blows them away?!
Wow, I had no idea you could turn curry into something like that.
Hurry! The judging's about to begin!
Yeah.
I bet there's a huge uproar in here too—
Huh?
What on earth just happened?
It's way too quiet.
Huh?!
Zero points?!
What the hell?!
How is that even possible?
86 points!
Talk about a dark horse candidate!
Candidate Yoshino Yuuki has
leapt into third place!
The current rankings have
Candidate Arato leading
by a wide margin at 92 points,
with Candidate Houjou in second place,
Candidate Yoshino in third place,
and Candidate Sadatsuka in fourth place.
Wow, I must say!
Your wild game curry was delicious beyond my wildest dreams!
Thank you!
Starting with the stock you made by sauteeing spices in duck fat,
your dish was saturated
with the essence of duck.
One would expect the dish
to be way too gamy,
but somehow you gave it a bright, clean taste!
Yet it retains a unique, wild flavor!
And to top it all off,
you literally topped it with a fried duck cutlet!
The gaminess was ameliorated by the flavors of turmeric and orange.
In French cuisine, it's traditional to pair duck with a sauce made from oranges.
Exactly!
I added orange pulp and zest
into the roux as well.
They pair well with my custom
garam masala mix!
I see.
Autumn is the season for game meat, that's for sure.
But acquiring such high-quality
game in time for these prelims
requires good connections with hunters.
Miss...
I'll invite you to my gourmet club next time!
Oh, really?
How generous of you!
Think nothing of it!
Is it her natural good cheer that changes people?
Yuuki, your cheerful, open
smile attracts everyone,
and your cooking pierces
right through people's hearts.
One might call you...
the Little Red Riding Hood
of the Forest of Wild Beasts!
And now, it's time!
The highly anticipated
sibling face-off in Group B!
The Aldini Brothers!
First up is the younger
Aldini, Candidate Isami!
I'll be going on ahead.
Yeah.
Please, do dig in before it gets cold.
Oh!
Is this a calzone?
A calzone is pizza dough folded in half and stuffed with a filling.
They can be baked or fried and can be found in a variety of forms throughout Italy.
They typically contain mozzarella cheese and other pizza toppings, don't they?
That means...
Ah!
There's curry inside!
So this is something like
an Italian version of curry bread?
It's rather different from the previous dishes we've had. Very interesting!
Well, let's dig in.
Splash!
T-Tomatoes?
The curry's overflowing with the rich,
juicy flavor of tomatoes!
Inside the calzone is a curry that was made primarily with tomatoes.
Oh, you didn't add stock or
any other liquids to the curry?
Right.
If you heat tightly packed tomatoes
at the bottom of a pot,
they release a surprising amount of liquid.
I added a special spice mix that pairs well with the tomatoes' acidity.
It resulted in a rich curry that's
full of the tomato's umami.
As for the dough,
I used the grape yeast our family makes.
The surface is so light and crisp!
Yet when you bite into it, it's chewy and sweet.
It's a perfect match for the rich curry.
Wonderful!
You re-imagined curry bread as Italian cuisine
and created something
completely new in the process!
"The pitiable younger brother, forever doomed to sit in the shadow cast by his older brother."
Many have thought of Isami Aldini that way.
But that's not the truth.
He too is an explorer in a foreign land,
pursuing new culinary horizons on his own.
This time I will defeat Bro for sure!
Isami's score is 87 points!
He's now in second place!
He got the same score as Houjou!
That means Sadatsuka Nao won't make it into the main tournament.
She's laughing for some strange reason.
Was falling to fifth place that big of a shock?
Hisako-onee-sama...
Such a tight race!
What passion! How fitting for
a gourmet food festival!
And now, it's Candidate Takumi Aldini's turn!
Buon appetito.
Oh?
So it's a pasta dish now?
I guess we're getting Italian cuisine twice in a row.
Bacon, green bell peppers, and mushrooms.
It looks like spaghetti Napolitan,
but he used curry as the sauce instead of ketchup.
The pasta's shaped like fettuccine.
Otherwise, nothing really stands out.
Hm...
Next to the novel calzone we just had,
this doesn't look very promising—
Wh-What?!
What is this rich depth of flavor?
It has struck me to the very core of my being!
The stock was made from beef flank and chicken
and seasoned with fennel and green cardamom.
The curry sauce tickles one's
nostrils in a delightful manner!
It coats the thick noodles well!
What?!
The secret ingredient is soy sauce?
No.
It's tamari soy sauce.
It's manufactured primarily in the Tokai region.
It has a more concentrated
umami than regular soy sauce,
while still retaining a sweet, mellow flavor.
But where is this mild cheese flavor coming from?
It's quite simple.
Please look more closely at the pasta.
Wh-What's this?
The pasta has three layers!
I incorporated turmeric in the outer layers,
and Parmesan cheese in the middle layer.
I see!
The tamari soy sauce and Parmesan
combine to create this much depth.
S-Still, with the cheese in the dough,
the heat from boiling the pasta would—
So that's why there are three layers!
By sandwiching the cheese between two layers,
he prevented the cheese from melting and leaking out!
The curry sauce's depth of flavor is enhanced by the tamari soy sauce.
And when you bite into it,
the rich flavor of the Parmesan cheese spreads in your mouth, delivering a final blow!
Marinating cream cheese in soy sauce is a well-known technique,
but who would've guessed that Parmesan and tamari soy sauce would pair so well?
Italian and Japanese cuisine have achieved a new harmony within the format of this curry dish!
Takumi Aldini...
He is yet another pioneer of the culinary world!
They're both skilled chefs,
but maybe Takumi is a tad more sophisticated.
I'd like my main course to be made by Takumi today. Is that all right?
I can do that too!
Isami!
Why did you alter a finished dish?!
What you did diluted its taste.
Do you want us to lose our customers' trust?!
Bro, I'm sorry.
I ruined your cooking.
I wanted to show them that I'm just as good.
I didn't want to become a burden to Takumi.
Mezzaluna...
The blade named for the half-moon.
Don't you think it's perfect for us?
When two halves of a whole come together,
perfection is born.
Aldini needs both of us, Isami!
I will move forward with every step you take.
One day, our restaurant will
become the best in all of Italy!
Buon giorno!
Welcome to Trattoria Aldini!
Ciao, Aldini brothers!
Let us have the best possible meal today too!
We're counting on you!
He's an everyday sort of guy you can always tease,
but he becomes a totally different person once he puts on his chef's coat.
Guess I couldn't catch up with him today, either.
My brother sure is amazing.
Takumi Aldini's score is 90 points!
Grazie!
Whoa!
Another score in the nineties!
He surpassed Houjou!
Group B is in the final stretch!
And with that, we only have—
Here you go!
She didn't wait for my announcement!
Hey, don't you dare ignore me, you bitch!
I just got tired of waiting!
Wh-What is this?!
You've got to be kidding.
Is that really food?
I put a lot of effort into this.
Please enjoy.
The twins on the box
are us two.
Nostalgic, isn't it?
That picture was
taken back in the 90's.
I think they can work
out how old we are.
Maybe we should
change the packaging?
Huh? J-Just what is this dish?
Is that really curry?
Is that amazing arch a garnish?
The sauce is a weird green color too.
I don't see the roux anywhere.
Oh, will you listen to yourself?
Everything on this dish is curry.
What's going on?
The judges had so much to say until now,
but now they're frozen in place!
U-Um...
How does it taste?
Um, I'm not sure how to describe this.
There's warmth... and something cold.
The veterans of gourmet are all tongue-tied.
Does that mean that dish is beyond even their comprehension?
The curry sauce is foamy and ever so slightly warm.
It melts in your mouth.
The tomato mousse is c-cold, and...
After I added the spices,
I solidified it with sodium alginate.
Huh?
Before you is a frozen mousse made from turmeric and powdered foie gras.
The white object in the center is a puree of potatoes and six types of cheese.
Its ingredients have been flash-frozen,
so it will melt in your mouth.
Once you feel its coldness inside your mouth, enjoy the flaky pie crust.
Flavored with coriander and other spices,
the pie crust will cleanse your palate.
"Thermal sense."
It's one of the themes of molecular gastronomy:
a dish composed of different elements at contrasting temperatures.
This dish embodies that theme.
S-So, then... does it taste good?
Of course it's delicious!
But I don't have the words to express how delicious it is in full!
Not even a gifted writer can describe how it tastes?
With spices at its core,
this dish manipulates texture and
temperature and makes them shine.
It revolutionizes the entire field of cooking!
Indeed, if I were to give her a title,
she would be a Global Innovator!
N-Ninety-five points?!
Nakiri Alice has received the highest
number of points and is now in the lead!
Oh, not 100 points?
How unexpected.
But, I suppose...
Look, I received higher marks than Secretary-chan.
Wh-Who are you calling Secretary-chan?!
Wow!
Every judge gave her 19 points!
That's almost a perfect score!
I can't believe those gourmands would do that.
I haven't seen such a high score in a long time.
Candidate Nakiri Alice is in first place,
followed by Candidate Arato,
then Candidate Takumi.
Candidates Houjou and Isami
are tied for fourth place!
Only four may advance from
Group B to the main tournament!
It's time for the judges to decide,
"Who will advance to the main tournament?"
Well!
That dish was quite interesting,
and certainly made for a fitting end!
Indeed.
Adjudicating the top dishes was a difficult task.
As usual, this year was a close contest.
And on that note, let's proceed with the voting.
Excuse me...
M-My curry... is still waiting.
She's the one who butchered the monkfish.
Huh?
She was still here?
Ugh, and here we were all
revved up for the finale.
I'm sorry!
So sorry!
Here it comes!
It's Megumi's turn!
Megumi!
Everyone?
What'cha doin' here?
We left fishin' to the young 'uns today.
We wanted to see you up on the big stage!
O-Oh, ya shouldn't have.
Hey, I guess those scary guys really like her.
Who is Tadokoro Megumi, really?
All right, Candidate Tadokoro,
hurry up and come forward.
Oh!
Go on, Megumi!
Show 'em what ya got!
Yeah!
Okay!
P-Please teach me!
I want to help at home!
Please!
I'm begging you!
It's monkfish dobu-jiru curry!
Dobu-jiru...
That's a hot pot dish with monkfish as the main ingredient, no?
Correct.
It's a dish that has been passed down by fishermen
of the Ibaraki and Fukushima prefectures for generations.
Monkfish in curry?
Just what is she thinking?
Whew...
I see. So this is why you used monkfish.
The main characteristic of dobu-jiru hot pot is that
monkfish liver is sauteed and rendered into a paste.
Miso and sake are added to the liver to form the base of the broth.
However, this girl also added spices to that mix,
effectively creating a liver curry miso paste.
The deliciousness just seeps
into you. How addictive!
The unctuous, deep flavor of the liver is
a surprisingly good complement to the spices!
Still, I must say,
after the previous dish, it's all the more apparent to me that...
How should I put it?
It's a very human dish.
The ingredients are monkfish meat, skin, fin, and...
Hm?
Kogiku kabocha squash, Tachikawa burdock root, and Akasuji daikon!
Y-Yes!
They're all ingredients that
are local to my hometown.
I wanted to highlight their strengths,
so I've been experimenting a lot.
Curry is very assertive,
so it was hard to blend it with the sweetness and bitterness of other vegetables.
But I realized I could use dobu-jiru with
monkfish liver to take advantage of the spices.
The broth could then bridge the gap between them and the flavor of the vegetables.
I wanted to make the kind of curry
where you can almost experience
how it feels to be in my hometown!
What?
Megumi really made this?
Yes!
No one here can beat her at cooking any more!
I've heard that there's a famous
culinary school in Tokyo.
Would you like to go?
What?
I hear many of their graduates go on to awe the world.
B-But Mom, I want to help out at this inn when I'm done with school.
If that's your final decision, that's fine.
I'd be happy to have you here.
But before you make that choice,
I want you to catch a glimpse
of a bigger world, at least once.
What?!
How can Megumi's dish only score in the teens?!
I told ya already!
The five judges' scores all add
up to a hundred, old man!
Good job!
That's our Megumi!
Here, a good luck charm to help you stay focused on your studies.
Tokyo, huh?
It'll get lonely around here.
However, we can't let Megumi's talent go to waste.
Good luck, Megumi!
Megumi might become the biggest fish to come outta these parts!
Megumi...
How's school?
Mom, um...
It's going fine.
I'm having a lot of fun in my classes!
Megumi, you're pretty amazing, y'know?
Do you want to come practice cooking again?
We'll keep you company.
Oh, it's okay!
Thanks for the offer.
But I think I'll practice on my own today.
Your time's finally come, Tadokoro-chan.
It's time for you to leave the
tiny world you started off in...
and soar into the sky.
Candidate Tadokoro Megumi has 88 points!
She's in fourth place!
She passed the preliminaries!
Houjou Miyoko didn't make it
out of the preliminaries!
This is a major upset!
Megumi! You did it!
Megumi!
I thought I'd have to overpower the men to succeed.
But with the way I am now...
is that just a pipe dream?
Okay, this is no good at all.
How could I possibly score a dish like this?
U-Um, wh-what is the score?
Didn't you hear me the first time?
I said it's no good.
Th-The total is 19 points.
Sendawara Natsume keeps awarding zero points to each dish.
She's already judged more than ten candidates,
and she's yet to give even a single point.
All the dishes looked pretty good too.
Wh-What the hell's going on here?
Maybe the judges for Group A
are way more strict.
V-Very well, n-next up is
Candidate Kurokiba Ryou!
Come on up, please!
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the twenty-third dish.
Ryou-kun, say something already!
The Competition of the Blossoming Individuals.
I will be the one at the top!
Isn't that a bit much?
No way.
It's how these things go.