Zero points!
Zero!
Another zero!
Does Sendawara Natsume
only give out zeros?
The scoring equipment isn't broken, is it?
That's Nakiri Alice's aide.
What dish will he present?
I heard he had quite the crowd lined up
at camp when we had to serve 200 people.
That's the boy who was preparing lobsters.
He was a completely different
person while he was cooking.
Ah, the contrast between the fiery red of the lobster
and the vibrant yellow of the saffron rice is beautiful.
The lobster shell is immaculate,
with no damage to the legs or antennae.
That is noteworthy.
This delicate and elegant plating is unexpected,
given his dynamic style of cooking.
Hmph. There are any number of
restaurants that serve lobster curry.
Mere seafood curry is hardly worth the attention you're lavishing on it.
A forest.
I'm deep in a forest.
What is this?
What's behind this fragrance?
Whoa, that's the first time today that Natsume-sama took a second bite!
How does it taste?
What's it like?!
This is... Group A.
Candidate Kurokiba's dish
is currently being judged.
Sauce américaine forms the base of the curry,
a French sauce made with the shells of crustaceans.
As for this deep forest fragrance,
it must originate from...
cognac!
That's high-quality brandy made in the area around Cognac, a town in western France.
Of course!
As the brandy ages, it takes on the scent of the wood used for the barrels!
That's why this curry has rich woody notes of cedar and sandalwood.
That's exactly right.
Please note that, in order
to impart a richer fragrance,
I used the highest grade of cognac, Napoléon cognac.
To think that the fragrance of cognac could enhance curry to this extent!
This is a fabulous French lobster curry!
He's the first one to get a positive reception from the judges!
I always knew he was really good!
It's been a while, Erina.
Allow me to introduce him to you.
Now I have an aide too.
This boy is your aide?
Yes.
I found him in Scandinavia.
You sound like you adopted a stray dog.
Come on, Ryou-kun. Say hello.
Hey.
I see.
So this is why Alice picked him up.
Finally, a dish worth judging has shown itself.
But still...
Is that really all there is to that dish?
W-Well, it wasn't horrible.
I suppose this may be worth a few points.
Let me think—
Ah.
Uh...
Oh, okay, here it was.
It's not over yet!
The tasting isn't over.
Do you really have to put that on every time?
Hm, eye droppers?
It seems there's more cognac inside.
There's a part of the lobster
you haven't tasted yet.
It's what's in the lobster's head, the tomalley.
Put a few drops of this inside the shell,
then slurp up the tomalley.
That's the best way to eat it.
Slurp?!
As if I could eat in such a crude manner!
At least crack the shell and
serve it on a plate or something.
What's with all the posturing?
You—
I can tell from the look in your eyes.
Why don't you show everyone your real face?
Admit it, you want to suck it down right this second, don't you?
After you slurp the cognac and tomalley,
stuff your mouth with roux and saffron rice again.
It'll be so much better than
what you had before.
So much better than before?!
The delicious flavor of seafood bursts in your mouth
and mingles with the deep fragrance of the forest!
I feel...
faint...
Candidate Kurokiba, 93 points!
Wow!
He's so far ahead!
I can't believe this!
93 points?!
I thought Hayama Akira would be
the one to win Group A by a landslide.
Talk about a dark horse candidate!
I've been continually thrown
into culinary fields of battle...
for as long as I can remember.
Compared to that, this is a walk in the park!
What an amazing score!
Is there anyone who can score higher than him?!
Well, that's that.
93 points, huh.
I must say, that was quite a surprise.
There have been years where the scores topped out in the 70's or 80's.
Th-That was a total ambush.
I never expected anything that impressive.
I need to calm down.
Very well, th-the next candidate, please!
Oh!
Wh-What's this?
Please enjoy. My curry dish is...
Dongpo pork curry!
Dongpo pork is a dish where pork belly is braised with soy sauce.
But never mind that. Look at
how beautiful this meat is!
It's glistening!
Because the alternating layers of meat
and fat appear to be stacked threefold,
pork belly is sometimes called "three-layer meat."
Even the slightest touch of the bowl sets the meat quivering.
Yet despite becoming so tender,
it has retained its shape!
It is proof that the cooking temperature was masterfully controlled.
This dish is sensuous in the extreme!
Even before my first bite,
my tongue is aflutter with anticipation.
Looks like Mito-san's dish is
faring well with the judges too.
Nice one, Nikumi.
Awesome job, Nikumi!
That thick cut of meat must've
soaked up a lot of the tasty broth!
I wonder what it'd be like
to take a huge bite out of that!
H-Hold on!
I'm still recovering from the
impact of that lobster curry,
and now I'm supposed
to judge a dish like this?!
What's the matter?
Savor and enjoy this ultimate meat in all its glory.
Meat!
It's so tender!
The moment you bite into it,
the meat's juices gush out in a flood!
The gamy taste associated with skin-on pork belly has been erased by the spices.
The only flavors left are the
sweet fat and the rich curry.
It's astounding!
After parboiling the pork belly,
I browned the meat,
then braised it with soy sauce, oyster sauce, and Shaoxing wine.
For spices, I used star anise, ginger, and Sichuan peppercorn.
But why is it that I can eat so much meat without feeling bloated?
Of course! It's the rice!
The rice has a small amount of
rock salt and peppercorn oil mixed in!
The oil's numbing tingle and refreshing overtones cut the oiliness of the meat.
But it also makes you crave the sweet flavor of the fat, creating a virtuous cycle.
She's created a feedback loop
of delectability in this bowl!
E-Excuse me! There are still
several dishes to be judged,
so please be mindful of how much you eat.
No way...
What?
We know there are more dishes, but there's no way we can stop!
Mito Ikumi...
From the day she entered the academy, her intuition and knowledge of meat exceeded anyone else's.
The problem was that she was prone to neglecting all of the other ingredients.
But it's as clear as day from this dish that her cooking has evolved.
The fat and the roux are melting into a wonderful harmony in my mouth.
What bliss.
This dish is so devastatingly good that it makes you believe this is the only way to cook pork belly.
Without question, she is the Meat Master.
No, she is far better than that.
Oh, meat!
She is the Meat General!
Meat!
Meat, oh!
Candidate Mito has scored 86 points!
What a high score!
That puts her solidly in second place!
Damn.
I didn't make it into the 90's.
Nikumi, that was amazing!
It looked super tasty.
It's what I learned from you, Yukihira.
A don should be complete in one bowl, right?
You really do understand, huh?
Nikumi, good job!
Wow, I'm so relieved.
This is finally starting to feel like a competition!
Let's keep this going!
Next up is Candidate Sakaki Ryouko.
Please enjoy.
It's everything I have to offer right now.
It looks pretty plain, doesn't it?
Compared to the previous dishes,
there isn't much visual impact.
Hm, it look to be dal, also called pulse curry.
It bears some resemblance to chana masala.
Wait, I know this sticky substance!
It's natto!
The viscosity and umami are coating my mouth.
I didn't think natto could be this delicious.
No, it's not just any natto.
It can't be...
It's natto made over a charcoal flame:
charcoal-fermented natto.
I maintained a charcoal fire in an underground chamber to assure optimal temperature and humidity,
while soybeans were fermented with the natto spore for several days.
I made use of my time over
summer break to make it.
Slowly fermenting soybeans over a charcoal fire allows you to create a more complex flavor.
Since the natto mold isn't killed during this process,
the odor of ammonia is considerably less.
But that's not the only thing!
What is it?!
What is this umami that hits your palate like a deep bass note?
My secret ingredient is soy sauce rice malt.
Soy sauce rice malt!
First you mix soy sauce into rice malt.
Then you let the mixture ferment for
several weeks at room temperature.
I get it.
The black substance I saw her using
was the soy sauce rice malt,
and the sticky substance was natto.
Soy sauce rice malt has over ten times the glutamic acid of salted rice malt.
That's how she could add more umami
without the strong curry flavor eclipsing it.
It's a great curry dish that takes full advantage of her mastery of fermentation.
The thick Japanese-style curry pairs well with the viscous natto.
The generous pile of finely sliced
green onion is irresistible as well.
She has used her mastery over the
power of soybeans to perfect this dish.
I'd be proud to call her a sister-in-arms...
or rather, Mistress!
Candidate Sakaki has scored 86 points!
That's the same score as Candidate Mito!
Good job, Sakaki!
She's in second place!
You make some really cool things, Sakaki.
Let me have some next time.
Sure. Of course!
This place is getting fired up!
Who's next?
Oh...
It's him.
I bet most of the people here don't have any expectations of me.
Mr. Marui.
Mr. Marui!
Good luck, Mr. Marui!
But just you watch. I'll stir things up.
Here, go ahead.
Oh, um... uh...
Calm down!
Okay, I'm Enomoto Madoka!
Like Mr. Marui, I'm part of the Miyazato research lab.
Mr. Marui and I...
Me and Mr. Marui...
Next is Candidate Marui!
Please show us your di-
It's so white.
The roux and ingredients are all white!
The noodles are udon.
They've been kneaded with cumin.
So this is your version of curry udon?
Yes. It's white potage curry udon.
Hm. It's quite beautiful.
If Kurokiba-kun's dish was
a tumult of color,
then this dish is
like a tranquil lake.
Let us begin.
Whatever, I doubt it'll get high marks.
The only thing I remember about Marui is that he was about to kick the bucket during camp.
E-Excuse me...
Could one of you please comment on the dish?
P-Please don't ignore me!
What?!
They're all chowing down like there's no tomorrow!
A plump poached egg, creamy mashed potatoes,
and a generous amount of piping hot, melted cheese.
The roux is like a vichyssoise!
Vichyssoise...
A dense soup made mainly from
potatoes and fresh cream.
It's a dish devised in 1917 by Louis Diat,
the head chef of the luxury hotel Ritz-Carlton.
Though it might appear to be thick and heavy, you can just keep on eating it.
It's coriander that makes the udon so light, isn't it?
Coriander is known for its mild overtones,
which is reminiscent of citrus, and its faint spiciness.
The synergy between it and the cumin in the noodles enhances the fragrance of both.
This is an unbelievably satisfying dish!
I have included dill, which is a
mainstay topping in vichyssoise.
By roasting the seeds of dill
and cumin together,
I have created a very fragrant soup.
He has taken the trendy dipping ramen concept and applied it to vichyssoise, a century-old dish!
How wonderful!
Mr. Marui!
Well done, Mr. Marui!
Well done.
It's the perfect showcase for your talents, Marui Zenji.
At my research lab, we research and analyze historic texts on food.
Despite being only a first-year,
Marui-kun is the star of our lab.
I don't have a keen sense for cooking.
I tire faster than most people.
That's all the more reason for me to study as hard as I do.
I am average, but I've set my sights
on reaching the geniuses.
We at the lab have a name for him:
the Professor of Taste!
Candidate Marui has scored 88 points!
He has second place all to himself!
Marui!
Good job!
Professor!
Look, Professor!
Mr. Marui is in second place!
Indeed.
We've seen one high score after the other!
Will this trend continue?
Next is Candidate Ibusa—
In terms of sheer power of fragrance...
this dish may be number one!
Please enjoy my special smoked curry.
The toppings are smoked bacon,
smoked potatoes,
and a smoked egg?!
You can't just smoke everything
and call it a day, Ibusaki!
But it does look really tasty.
D-Don't forget the theme is curry!
If you just smoke everything,
you'll overwhelm the spices.
The dish was finished with coarsely ground cinnamon, cumin, cardamon, and cloves.
Applewood wood chips were used
to cure these ingredients.
I see!
That's how he managed to enhance the spices rather than eclipsing them!
Yes.
Applewood is the best choice for
working with these spices.
These coarsely-ground spices
were also added to the saumure,
which is used to brine
ingredients prior to smoking.
This infused the ingredients
with the curry's flavor.
The toppings are wonderful.
This egg has been turned
into an umami bomb!
The half-congealed yolk just
melts in your mouth.
But wait.
How did he achieve cohesion between all the different ingredients?
How did he achieve such unity?
I see! I understand it now!
You used smoked salt in the spice mix!
He smoked the salt?
But how much difference could that make?
I'll have you know I didn't use just any salt.
It's seaweed salt, made by burning seaweed with high sodium content, dissolving it in water,
then boiling down the supernatant.
So that's why the flavor is so rounded and mild.
He achieved unity in this curry
by using smoked salt.
What an astounding boy.
He has a complete grasp of what
flavors curing can bring to a dish.
Despite his youth, he has the skills to manipulate smoke at will.
You are the...
Prince of Smoke!
88 points!
Candidate Ibusaki is now also in second place!
Whoa!
Good job, you two!
I've never seen the two of them like this.
So only now do you reveal your true colors.
Look who's talking.
Finally coming out from behind
that veil of smoke, are you?
I guess.
Natsume-sama looks like
she's reached her limits!
Wow!
There are three Polar Star
members in the top five!
Huh?
Wait a second.
Only four get to advance to
the main tournament, right?
What happens if there are too
many with the same score?
If these standings still persist
after the judging is over,
the five judges will vote to determine
who will proceed to the main tournament.
However...
There are still others.
Next up is Candidate Hayama Akira.
I made an extra portion just for you.
Oh? What a coincidence.
So did I.
Let's have fun comparing.
Sure thing.
Here you go.
Huh?
Um, isn't this...
You got what you came for, so scram!
I'm busy!
What? But...
I figure it's around 30 percent by weight.
You mixed in some poor quality spices, didn't you?
What would a slum rat like you know?
Just try and prove—
I can tell.
My nose is something special.
Are you Chinese?
No, you're Japanese.
Huh?
This is no place for a little girl to go sightseeing.
I'm 26 years old.
Huh?!
Candidate Hayama is considered one of the top contenders in these preliminaries!
It's finally his turn to be evaluated!
I believe his dish will be fish head curry.
It's a dynamic dish that uses
the entire fish's head in—
H-Huh?
Wh-What's this?
It's much more compact than I'd expected.
It's not fish head curry?
I believe what's serving as the "lid" is... naan.
Please crack the naan into the bowl with the spoon as you eat.
Do take care. It's hot.
It's an explosion... of fragrance!
On the next and final episode
of Shokugeki no Souma,
the twenty-fourth dish:
The Banquet of Warriors.
Enjoy!
Oh, um...
Glad you liked it.