Dad!
I'm gonna become a chef who can beat you!
Oh, is that so?
Well, good luck with that.
Okay, let's get right to it!
Let's have a cooking showdown!
Since that day, we've had 490 matches.
Listen up, Souma.
Until the next time you lose to me,
you'd better not lose to anyone else.
My creations are still far more
disgusting than yours, Souma.
She's in fourth place!
She's passed the preliminaries!
In third place is Candidate Takumi Aldini, 90 points!
In second place is Candidate Arato Hisako, 92 points!
And in first place is Candidate Nakiri Alice, 95 points!
These four from Group B will be
moving on to the main tournament!
Now, let's take a peek at
what's happening in Group A!
It's an explosion... of fragrance!
So this is Hayama's curry.
That dish packs a serious punch!
I can't believe we can smell
it all the way up here!
And it stings and prickles your nose!
It's such a rich smell!
Contained by the "lid"...
is a luxurious curry chock-full of
umami from the grilled fish collar!
Just the aroma by itself makes me so happy.
Man, I really want to try it!
Hayama-kun...
Scoop up a piece of naan along with the curry
and have a bite—
Mere words could not do this justice.
Topping soup with puff pastry was an innovation devised by Paul Bocuse,
one of the preeminent chefs of French cuisine.
Bocuse said he was inspired by the lidded
lacquer bowls used in traditional Japanese cuisine.
The fragrance of the dish is held back by the lid.
When the lid is broken, the fragrance is freed in an explosive burst .
Hayama's weapon is fragrance.
Using it to full effect, he scored
a direct hit on the judges!
I'm detecting fennel, lemongrass, and cinnamon.
Wait!
There's something else that unites them.
What lies at the center of this strong fragrance?!
Holy basil...
Not only that, it's fresh holy basil!
Holy basil?
It's a spice native to southern Asia that many consider to be sacred.
With one whiff, a most luscious
sensation courses through your body.
In the Ayurveda tradition, a traditional medicine practiced in India,
holy basil is considered to be the elixir of life.
But fresh, high-quality holy basil is all but impossible to find in Japan!
That's true.
Which is why we grow our own
year-round at Shiomi Lab.
What?
The method by which we cultivate it is a trade secret.
Shiomi...
He must mean Professor Shiomi Jun, a foremost authority on spices.
It's a strong fragrance that sinks
its claws into you and won't let go.
But that's not his only trick.
What keeps you coming back for more is...
Yogurt?!
That's right, Yukihira.
With a single misstep, holy basil can overwhelm other spices,
but the yogurt mellows it out.
Not to mention, the curcumin compound in spices
Roland Chapelle
Tohtsuki Academy Lecturer
French Cuisine Lead
Curcumin
aid the liver in its task of detoxification.
Lactobacillus
When ingested along with lactobacilli,
like those commonly found in yogurt,
curcumin is more easily absorbed.
He's even thought the nutritional aspects through!
I knew you could do it,
Hayama-kun! You're amazing!
I didn't expect to meet a chef in Japan who was capable of using holy basil.
Hayama-kun.
Why don't you become mine?
What salary would it take?
A hundred million?
Two hundred?
Name your price—
I fight for Jun.
That's all there is to it.
Mmm, what a manly candidate.
Now I must have you all the more.
With every bite,
the tingling umami pierces
right through my brain!
I've never encountered
such a sharp, delicious flavor.
This is perfection in a single dish:
the evolution of modern curry
reaching its ultimate form!
W-Well then, judges, if you would please present your scores.
Guys!
Hey, how was Group B?
I'll tell you later!
How's it going over here?
What about Yukihira?
Where'd Yukihira place?
Calm down, bro.
It doesn't look like he's been judged yet.
What's Candidate Hayama's score?
Here it is!
Candidate Hayama has jumped
into the lead with 94 points!
Hayama-kun!
Second place...
I think the princess will be angry.
Well, guess I just need to try
harder in the main tournament.
Crap, I'm out.
Nikumi!
You did great!
Well done!
Ryouko-chan.
Hey, look.
Two judges gave a full 20 points!
Hayama Akira's scary good.
Not even Nakiri Alice received
full marks from any of the judges.
It's the highlight of the tournament.
Isshiki-san?!
What are you doing here?
What's going on with Group B?!
The rest of the team is wrapping things up.
That was quite the heated battle, wasn't it?
Hold on!
This room is for Autumn Selection staff only—
From a certain point of view, dorm mothers could be counted as staff, no?
Absolutely not!
You're here because you want to see how Souma-kun does, don't you?
What?! As if!
Well, while the arena's still
feverish from excitement,
it's time for Candidate Yukihira
Souma to present his dish!
Please serve your dish to the judges!
Souma-kun, what kind of curry did you make?
Here.
This one's for you, Hayama.
What's with that smug look?
A month ago you didn't even
know about kari patta,
one of the most fundamental
spices used in curry.
So how can you still be smiling
after tasting my creation?
Oh, I was just thinking how
my idea wasn't so crazy after all.
What on earth...
An omelette?!
Huh?
Wasn't the transfer student making a risotto?
Dig in.
Fragrance explosion...
take two!
Wow, there's a risotto inside the omelette!
The fragrance that was trapped inside
has been released in an explosive burst!
Right after Hayama's dish...
...another fragrance bomb makes a direct hit!
You had the same idea as I did?
It seems that way, doesn't it?
It's hot, so be careful!
Curry Risotto Omelette Rice,
carefully made by Yukihira!
The rice enclosed by the egg is glistening
like the rice in a don bowl coated with the highest quality sauce.
Amazing.
What a rich fragrance.
You can't help but smile after a whiff of it.
I'm anticipating something as
great as Hayama-kun's curry.
Now, then...
What impact!
Strike after flavorful strike!
Yeah!
A rich bouillon made from
chicken bones and beef tendon.
Umami from the ground beef and onions, sauteed in butter, suffuses the rice.
The creamy risotto is in perfect harmony with the impeccably cooked egg.
I feel like I'm going to faint from pleasure!
It seems this sauce is the clincher.
Based on oyster sauce,
it's been accented with honey.
The mild acidity adds
more depth to the sauce.
The sauce and the risotto create two different layers of flavor!
I understand now.
Hayama-kun's curry was a massive
explosion that catches you off guard,
but this dish continues to send out shockwaves of fragrance.
The outer and inner fragrances are mingling intermittently to seduce you!
But that's not the only source
of the depth of this dish.
This fragrance and faint bitterness...
comes from cumin and cardamom.
There's cloves too, which cause
a faint tingle on the tongue.
I've sniffed out the edges of this mystery,
but I've only scratched the surface.
What's the secret that brings all these spices together to produce this depth of flavor?
So that's it. Mango.
Mango chutney.
Mango chutney?!
How can that create such a complex taste?
Chutney is something like a paste, right?
Yeah.
It's a condiment made by mashing up
spices with fruits and vegetables,
then simmering the mixture down.
There are countless chutneys across Asia,
differing in the ingredients used.
Some are sweet or spicy,
while others use mint.
This is my house blend mango chutney.
I added it while I was simmering the rice.
The mango harmonizes the
flavors of each individual spice
to create an even richer
depth of flavor in the dish.
You could call it an applied
technique for spicing dishes.
In India, chutney is served on the side.
It's just another condiment.
Adding chutney to the curry
itself is unique to Japan.
Huh.
I had no idea.
From a purist's perspective,
this breaks with tradition.
However, in doing so...
...he avoided going overboard with adding fats and animal products to the dish.
But he still elevated the dish's
flavor to another dimension!
In the recent past,
Yukihira-kun made a major error with an egg dish.
His training camp omelette almost cost him his spot at the academy.
And his risotto lost completely
to his father's dish.
Yet he chose to bring those two dishes together in this match.
His father?
He hasn't wasted a single failure,
not in any of the 490 defeats he's suffered.
Hmph.
It sounds so noble when you put it like that,
but maybe he just doesn't
know when to give up.
He isn't one to let a failure stay a failure.
Yukihira may look like he can keep his cool,
but he is the ultimate sore loser.
I did learn something from my mistake.
That's what a loser says to cover up his failure.
Failure is not an option for chefs!
This umami is weighty and rock solid.
Yet the aftertaste is surprisingly light!
Is this again due to the chutney?
But Hayama-kun's dish had a richer fragrance.
No, wait!
When you mix the sauce into the rice,
the force of the flavor is magnificent!
One might imagine Hayama-kun's curry
as a sharp poleaxe with holy basil as its shaft.
This curry emanates its attack in waves.
Its taste is a flurry of combo attacks!
Both of them are using their weapons of choice,
attacking each other in their
own way, with all their might!
This is a battle between those who aim for the pinnacle of Tohtsuki!
Hey, that was no faint praise there.
Will the transfer student actually
surpass Hayama Akira?
Well then, judges, your scores please!
18!
19!
19! 19!
The total score is...
93 points!
Candidate Yukihira is in second
place with 93 points!
Oh man, so close.
Off by just one point?!
93 points.
Yukihira...
Second place, huh.
A tie.
Yukihira... Souma.
Well, I guess a transfer student
couldn't have taken the top spot.
Hayama's like curry personified.
W-Wait, those scores...
Of the five judges,
three gave Yukihira more points than Hayama.
Hayama Akira 94 points
Yukihira Souma 93 points
That's three to two.
If this had followed the rules of a Cooking Battle...
Gentlemen, how can you fail to appreciate
the incredible work of art that is that curry?
How can you not appreciate
the advantage of holy basil?
But the matter at hand is the curry dish.
It's not merely about judging
their selection of spices.
What's important is how satisfying
the dish is as a whole.
Hayama-kun's curry was superior
in that respect as well!
But it was Candidate Yukihira's dish that I wanted more and more of—
Shut up! You're just an extra!
You're being too emotional.
One who lacks multidimensional perspective has no right to speak about gourmet food!
Why don't you resign as a judge?
What did you just say?!
Um, stop! Please calm down!
Intellectual poseurs are nothing but trouble!
Shut up, mustache!
Please! Please calm down!
They seem to be arguing,
but Hayama's in first place all the same, right?
I think so.
He survived for now.
I'm looking forward to the main
tournament, Yukihira Souma.
Hayama-kun!
You're amazing, Hayama-kun!
In the main tournament, there can only be two outcomes: win or lose.
If those two end up facing each other,
who will win?
The 92nd class...
A generation full of diamonds in the rough.
All right, let's celebrate...
the conclusion of the Autumn
Selection Preliminaries
with a party for a job well done!
So...
Cheers!
Megumi!
Well, now...
That was amazing, Megumi!
Maybe you'll win the whole kit and caboodle!
Wh-What're you talking about?
Tadokoro Megumi.
Houjou-san.
I had you all wrong.
I'll be cheering for you at the main tournament.
What?
If you need any help, just give me a holler.
Thank you, Houjou-san.
I knew you were awesome, Megumi!
Yuuki-chan.
I'll be your head cheerleader
at the main tournament!
Thanks.
Hey, Megumi!
Let's take a group photo!
Go on. They're calling for you.
Oh, okay.
Yuuki.
Fumio-san!
Thank you for cheering me on!
It's gonna get really busy!
We have to make a banner
for Megumi and stuff.
Please help us, Fumio-san!
I'll make your favorite tonight.
It was a good dish.
You did well.
Whoa!
That's really high-quality duck meat!
Good job!
You could tell just by looking?
Huh.
Rice malt has that effect too?
That's very interesting.
Isn't it deep?
Still, I didn't know Marui had
a cheerleading squad.
Yeah, my opinion of him
has completely changed.
But you guys still insist
on partying in my room.
Here!
Dig in, all of you.
O-Okay.
Thank you for inviting us, Isshiki-san.
Here!
There's a man wandering around
dressed only in an apron.
Why is no one saying anything?
Say, where's Ibusaki-kun?
I bet he's holed up in his room.
He won't show it,
but I think he was really frustrated.
I guess it's up to me to go
and drag him out here.
The main tournament is two weeks from now.
It'll decide which of the first-years,
minus Nakiri Erina,
is the best chef at the academy.
Listen up, Yukihira!
I'll never forgive you if you lose
before we get to face off!
Sure, fine by me.
Come at me!
Hey, Jun.
Getting all drunk by yourself and passing out...
This is even worse than usual.
Whatever.
Hayama-kun, you might change the world.
Jun, I'll win the main tournament too.
All for you...
the one who found me.
Hey!
Why can't you come play
with me for just one night?!
Your own cousin passed the prelims with the highest score, you know!
It's your responsibility to celebrate.
Ryou-kun, don't you agree?
I have no opinion.
Hey!
You're supposed to back me up here, Ryou-kun!
Oh, my apologies.
I still have some paperwork left to do tonight.
I'll have to take a rain check on the festivities.
Hmph.
Fine. I'll give up for tonight.
But I'll be back tomorrow.
Let's go, Ryou-kun.
'Kay.
Congratulations on passing.
That goes for you too, Kurokiba-kun.
Thanks.
My apologies.
I did inform them that you were busy.
It was unavoidable.
It's Alice, after all.
Hisako, congratulations to you too.
Though I of course expected you
to pass the preliminaries,
I'm still glad.
Do your best in the main tournament as well.
I will!
I'll hone my skills even further
and win without fail!
Hisako-onee-sama...
The fragrance that came wafting from that dish...
Here and now, I'm starting a new life
umarekawaru ima koko de
Fragrance...
I'll transcend the sky I used to look up at
aoide ita sora koete iku
Well, well? Well, well?
Hope turned out to be inside
nigirishimeta tenohira no
Don't come any closer!
Doesn't it look tasty?
The hand that was clenched so firmly
sono naka ni kibou ga attan da
Doesn't it look tasty?
It's disgusting!
I realized that the landscape spreading out
me no mae ni hirogaru keshiki zenbu ga
Yukihira Souma...
Before my eyes was just a tiny speck
jitsu wa chippoke datta to kizuita
After all, meeting you so easily
tatoeba kimi to deaeba kantan ni
Overturned my world
sekai wa hikkurikaeru
Souma-kun.
Hey, Tadokoro.
What's up?
There are so many things I don't know that I can't help but laugh
shiranai koto darake de waraete kuruna
Um...
I just thought you didn't
look yourself, that's all.
That means I can still grow much further
madamada saki ni ikeru akashi da
Yeah?
Anyway, I heard you used local ingredients
from your hometown in your curry.
Huh? Yeah.
I'm striding forward
oikaketeta haruka tooku
Nicely done!
But it still hasn't really sunk in.
Six months ago, I was about to get expelled.
Never surrendering my true feelings
yuzurenai omoi mo tsurete
Oh, that brings back memories.
Toward a faraway peak
daremo shiranai itadaki wo
My first class was when we first paired up, right?
It's all thanks to you, Souma-kun.
That no one knows about
mezashite iku
I was able to come this far because of you.
With everything on the line
subete kakete
Nah, you had it in you from the start.
I opened the way fearlessly
kirihiraita osorezu ni
Your cooking's good.
It warms you up inside, y'know?
Looking for a new scenery
atarashii keshiki motomete
I like your cooking.
I don't need to make up a meaning or rationalize
imizuke toka rikutsu nanka iranain da
Thanks. That makes me really happy.
What're they talking about?
Wait. Why am I hiding in the shadows?
I just do what comes naturally
omou mama ni
Oh?
They seem to be having a moment.
Whoa!
Souma-kun, you were amazing too.
You were Hayama-kun's equal,
even though he's a curry specialist.
But I was one point short.
I went in gunning to win.
I wanted to get 20 points from all five of them.
O-Oh, I see.
Hayama took advantage of a spice
I didn't even know about
Tasting so many of both sweet and bitter days
amai hi wo nigai hi wo abinagara
and made an amazing dish.
I want to learn a whole lot more about the culinary world.
We learn new things and go forward
bokura kizuite iku manande iku
I want to experience all sorts of
ingredients and cooking techniques,
experience real cooking, expand my repertoire,
and leverage all of it in my future dishes.
To do what no one else but us can do
bokura shika dekinai koto wo
I want to be better!
What I've been chasing far off in the distance
oikaketeta haruka tooku
Hey!
We're starting the second round!
The night's still young!
I'll transcend the sky I used to look up at
aoide ita sora koete iku
Hope turned out to be inside
nigirishimeta tenohira no
Boomerang!
Bam!
Isshiki-senpai's third form!
It's a Speedo!
The hand that was clenched so firmly
sono naka ni kibou ga attan da
What?!
Drink up, Ibusaki! It's rice juice!
You're laying it on real thick.
I realized that the landscape spreading out
me no mae ni hirogaru keshiki zenbu ga
Yukihira!
I'll defeat you for sure!
Before my eyes was just a tiny speck
jitsu wa chippoke datta to kizuita
He seems to be in a strange mood.
When he's shaking like that,
you should just leave him alone.
After all, meeting you so easily
tatoeba kimi to deaeba kantan ni
You're so cold to your own family!
Wow, this is super high quality meat!
Fumio-san went all out!
Overturned my world
sekai wa hikkurikaeru
Thanks for the food!
Hold up, you assholes!
Using sauce on that wagyu beef will destroy its delicate umami!
There are so many things I don't know that I can't help but laugh
shiranai koto darake de waraete kuruna
Don't you have any respect for meat?!
I-I'm so sorry, Nikumi-san!
That means I can still grow much further
madamada saki ni ikeru akashi da
Don't call me Nikumi!
The only one who can call me that is...
I'm striding forward
oikaketeta haruka tooku
You bastard, look at what you're making me say!
You asshole!
Never surrendering my true feelings
yuzurenai omoi mo tsurete
All right, let me make a dish
to cheer everyone up.
I don't like the look in his eyes!
Toward a faraway peak
daremo shiranai itadaki wo
Yukihira, stay put!
You don't have to make anything, Souma-kun!
That no one knows about
mezashite iku
But I've already made it, see?
With everything on the line
subete kakete
Dig in!
It's squid tentacles with yogurt.
Oh, God!
Not again!
Thank you for the food!