It wasn't a dream?
I really am in another world.
Honestly, I can't tell
if I'm inside the game,
or if this is just another world
that's similar to Cross Reverie.
I might need to try looking into some things.
What is this unfamiliar sensation?
Her boob?!
D-D-Don't panic!
A Demon Lord doesn't panic!
Gently remove your hand!
My hand is acting on its own?!
Left hand? Left hand?!
My mind is refusing to take my hand away?!
My left hand is out of control!
Help me, right hand!
Wait, this one, too?!
They're budding?!
This is a perfect harmony
of solidity and softness!
And this other one absorbs my
fingers like a bottomless swamp,
yet it's firm enough to press back!
Boobs are awesome!
Still, any longer and this'll be bad!
It'll be social death for me!
Diablo?
I don't think it's good to do things like this!
Y-You absolutely shouldn't
do things like this until
you choose me as your master, okay?!
You'll allow it if I choose you?!
What's going on? Mew two are so noisy...
Oh, no!
I'm a Demon Lord.
Roleplay the Demon Lord.
Act boldly, with dignity...
Rem, hold your chest out proudly.
Your budding breasts are valuable assets, too.
Episode 2
Strongest Newcomer
Rem, are you still mad about this morning?
I'm not mad.
Please drop the subject.
You're totally mad.
Dwarves, Grasswalkers, Pantherians...
Elves...
And Demons.
Although I thought Humans were
the most common race in-game.
I don't see any Humans here. Why is that?
This is the block where demihumans live.
Hardly any Humans come here.
So there's an even greater divide
between Humans and demihumans in
this world than there was in-game.
That guy last night seemed to
have a beef with me, too.
He even called out his level 30
or whatever Summon.
Does this world measure strength
with the concept of level?
Y-Yeah, by levels...
Though I don't have mine yet.
I'm a level 40 Summoner.
The Adventurer's Guild we're heading to
has a means of assessing your level.
Oh?
Oh, yeah! The reason I don't have a level is
because I haven't registered
as an adventurer yet,
so I could be 40 or 50 when they measure me!
Your level is probably around 10 or so.
It must be at least 10 below average.
That's not true!
It is.
Is not!
Is.
I said it's not!
This area was supposed to be
level 60 in-game, give or take.
I said it is.
Not! Not! Not! Not! Not!
I'm telling you, it's not!
Is this whole world operating
at a reduced level?
Once we're registered with the Adventurer's
Guild, we'll be able to accept quests.
Both of you are going to earn your lodging.
Hey, were you licking it?!
Like I'd lick it! That's gross!
What'd you say?!
S-S-Scary!
What is this savage place?!
I know it's a bit obnoxious,
but this happens all the time.
We register as adventurers
on the second floor.
Good.
Uh, I'm Shera L. Greenwood.
I was born in...
I can't read this writing!
Listen, I dislike such tedious work.
Fill mine out for me.
I can?!
Yes.
Yay!
It's kind of like I'm the master now!
Now then, to finish up,
please place your blood seal here.
Blood seal?
It's fine. Just a little prick.
I don't like this...
Hmph. You'll never succeed as an adventurer
if you balk at something like this.
It's not scary. It's fine.
It's just like a shot.
There!
I cut it too much!
So next...
What's this?
A mirror that measures the
strength of your magic power.
There's nothing reflected in it, though.
Touch it with your hand, and try
filling it with magic power.
L-Like this?
Wow, that's incredible!
Let's see...
It's clear enough to count your eyelashes
and goes all the way down to your chest,
so your level is...
How high? How high?
30!
No way!
I lost to Rem?
You were overreaching if you
thought you could surpass me.
I'll surpass you in no time, Rem!
You can spend your whole
life looking up at me.
If she's level 30 in this lower level world,
What?!
then that's a relatively high evaluation.
You'll never be able to catch up to me.
Uh, next person, please.
You're going to regret saying that!
Right.
How do I focus magic power into this?
What is that?!
That's scary!
This looks dangerous!
What was that wave just now?!
Guildmaster! U-Uh...
Guildmaster? Her?
I'm Sylvie, Guildmaster of the
Adventurer's Guild here in Faltra City.
Do all of you have a moment to spare?
It's the first time the mirror
has ever reacted that way.
Honestly, I don't think
we can handle you here.
Huh?
What do you mean?
I'm certain you're high level,
but I have no idea how high.
Frankly, you're beyond our knowledge.
So even if you registered,
I wouldn't be able to decide what
missions were acceptable for you.
So you won't accept me as an adventurer?
We're happy to register strong people.
But I'm weaker than you are.
Can you really accept being
ordered around by me?
I don't care about such trivial details
as long as you pay out the rewards.
You're an interesting guy.
All right. Glad to have you aboard, Diablo-san.
I-Indeed.
Though I imagine there aren't many quests
that fit your actual abilities...
Hmm, this is a new quest.
What's the matter?
A few things.
This one smells fishy, but care to try it?
A quest to defeat a Madara Snake
in the Man-Eating Woods?
They need the eyeballs of a Madara
Snake for their experiments.
The client is the Mage's Association.
The Man-Eating Woods is where incredibly
strong monsters show up, right?
Yes. Ordinarily, such a dangerous
quest would never come down to us.
If someone requested it anyway,
it must really be...
The Mage's Association?
Is that woman from yesterday involved?
Worry not.
You two can leave this one to me.
M-More importantly, we still
have some distance to go, right?
It would be more convenient
if we could use Teleport.
Is there no portal near the woods?
Portal?
What's "Teleport"?
A spell to return to the last town
you visited is basic magic, isn't it?
Items that send you back should be
easy to obtain, too, even early on.
If we had something like that,
everyone would use it!
I already hear enough
nonsense from the fat Elf.
That's mean! I'm not fat!
That's another difference from the game.
You are.
I'm not fat!
Whatever.
You're just jealous of them!
Guess we'll keep walking.
No, I'm not. Those things
would just get in the way.
Five hours spent traveling...
This game is total BS.
Where do you think we can
find a Madara Snake?
They're over twenty meters long,
and they usually lurk in the swamp,
where they attack prey that comes close.
Say that sooner!
These woods are even creepier than
they looked in the game's graphics.
There's no map displayed, either.
It'll be dangerous to walk around blindly.
We're doing this quest
all by ourselves, right?
Naturally.
Then do more people go in and out of
the Man-Eating Woods than I thought?
Those who fear for their
life don't go near it.
Why?
You can sense them, can't you? In the woods.
Is that true?
There are about ten people up in the branches.
They seem to be lying in wait for something.
Are you an idiot or a major idiot? I can't tell.
Why?!
So this is why Sylvie said it seemed fishy.
Huh? Huh?!
We've been caught in a trap.
They're going to ambush us.
What?!
Where are they?
There, there, and over there.
Burst Rain!
How's that?
Elemental Magic is...
capable of this?!
I didn't know your power was that great.
What is this?!
Elves?!
What's going on here?
That spell was suspicious!
Celsior?! Why are you here?!
Shera-sama!
I have hastened here to rescue you!
Slave trader, I'll have you
return the noble princess
of the Kingdom of Greenwood,
Shera L. Greenwood!
Princess? Shera is?!
Right, Greenwood!
That's the name of the Elven royal family!
That was written somewhere
in the game lore.
Why would Elves submit a quest under
the name of the Mage's Association?
I don't know who's tasked you
with this, but I am no slave trader.
Silence!
That Enslavement Collar is irrefutable proof!
Release Shera-sama from her collar!
Well, I can already think of
someone in the Mage's Association
who holds a grudge against me.
I don't care about the royal family!
Everyone in the royal family
is worried about you!
What Nii-san needs isn't me, it's an heir!
He just wants me to bear his child!
That's a very important duty.
I don't even love him!
It's not right for me to be forced to
marry someone when I don't even want to!
I refuse to return to our country!
I'll live on my own from now on!
But right now you're enslaved, aren't you?!
I'm not! I am no one's slave!
I belong to myself!
It sounds like your situation is complicated,
but you're too weak to live on your own.
We will bring you back,
even if we must do so by force.
Well said.
That was impressive, for you.
It takes determination to abandon your country and live on your own.
I have to say I like that.
Rem...
Then we have no choice, everyone.
You buffoons.
What?!
You have made three mistakes.
First, I am no slave trader. I am a Sorcerer.
Second, Shera is not powerless.
After all, I'm lending her my aid right now.
Diablo...
And your third mistake was
making an enemy of me!
Fire!
Diablo!
Wha?!
I thought you would be
a bit better than this.
This is like the graphic for the basic,
ordinary arrows sold in shops.
These arrows of yours will
be of no use in combat.
What do you even spend your time fighting?
Are you insulting us?!
I'm asking a question.
Are you not fighting monsters and Fallen?
O-Of course we aren't!
Now I understand.
That's why this world's levels are so low.
You monster!
Ah. Tempest Arrows, huh?
How do you know that?
I've seen them many times in-game.
If you use those, you might
be able to damage me.
Of course!
These are prized treasures
granted by His Highness!
They're supreme arrows that
can penetrate anything!
They'll pierce right through
you and your vile nature!
Run!
Those arrows are bad!
Pierce him!
Diablo!
Wha?!
Diablo...
Thank goodness!
Wh-What are you?!
Keep that fear etched in
your hearts along with this:
I am Diablo, the Demon Lord
from another world!
Freezia!
Hey!
Weren't you guys supposed
to be elite Elven troops?!
You're useless!
Hey.
So you were the one who put
them up to this, plebeian?
No, I, um...
I just told them that the Elf
princess had come here, that's all.
They seemed convinced I was
a slave trader, though.
That was their own misunderstanding!
All demihumans are stupid!
Don't involve yourself with me again.
The next time you defy me,
I'll eliminate you without mercy.
I wonder what Celes would have to say...
if she were to find out
you borrowed the name
of the Mage's Association
to lay a trap for us.
N-No...
I... I'm not in the wrong here!
Tell Nii-san something for me.
I'm never returning home.
I don't belong to him.
I'm staying with my companions,
Diablo and Rem, now.
Let's go home now!
I'm hungry!
Good grief. Since when did
you and I become companions?
Huh? We're not?
But you just said you liked me earlier!
I only said your determination
appealed to me.
Hey, are you blushing?
Are your cheeks red?
S-Stupid Shera!
Me... A companion?
Rem sure is late.
Yeah.
She went to tell Celes-san
about what happened...
But she should be back by now.
Yeah.
I can't keep a conversation going
when I'm alone with a girl!
Anyway, your magic is amazing, Diablo.
I've never seen anything like it.
There's one thing I've come
to understand about leveling.
The people of this world live their
lives as peacefully as possible,
trying to avoid death.
Isn't that normal?
There are no salvation mechanisms
or resets here, like in the game.
When you die, it's over.
Devoting time to leveling up
in the face of such danger
is too risky for the average person.
I come from a world where I prioritized
leveling up as efficiently as possible,
even if it meant risking death.
You don't value your own life?
Of course, I never thought about
throwing it away wastefully,
but I might not be able to defeat
the Demon Lord Krebskulm otherwise.
Diablo, are you choosing Rem?
Rem's really focused on Krebskulm, you know?
Even though we don't know where
or when she'll ever revive.
Yeah.
So if you're also thinking about
defeating the Demon Lord Krebskulm...
Then you're really choosing Rem?
Hey!
I need you too, Diablo!
Even today, if it weren't for you,
I would've been taken back!
Oh, uh...
I was so happy today.
But if you choose Rem, then I'll...
Wait!
N-No!
Now, you listen up!
I am the Demon Lord!
Which is why I have no companions!
I-I haven't chosen Rem!
Really?
O-O-Of course!
Don't start thinking a Demon Lord
will ever obey either of you!
Uh, and because I'm a Demon Lord...
I don't like this because it
makes me feel weird, but...
Feel weird?!
It feels like I'm yearning for something!
Sorry.
Did it hurt?
No...
Diablo, do you like breasts, by chance?
You're always looking at mine...
She's totally caught me!
They're bigger than Rem's, aren't they?
Well, yeah...
Wh-What's this suddenly erect,
hard peak among the softness?!
Hey, Diablo?
Wh-What?
Oh, it's Rem!
I already know mine are small!
You're going to release them both!
Right now, I feel like I can
beat even a Demon Lord!
I must right this world!
Episode 3
Fallen Assault