Episode Three
Fallen Assault
Sorry for making you all come out here.
I know you just completed a quest for us,
but we have a commission
specifically for Diablo-san.
Someone's specifically requesting Diablo?
This isn't another trap, is it?
This one's fine.
After all,
it's directly from the head of the
Mage's Association, Celestine Baudelaire,
and I personally received it from her.
From Celes?
Not to mention the reward's
high for how simple it is.
So it includes reparations
for the incident with Galluk?
Well, I imagine that's true.
I won't be going.
Huh?
I don't want to owe Celes any favors.
I wouldn't mind if it were a normal mission,
but I'm not taking on a quest from her
with an unnecessarily high reward.
She's strict on herself.
But honestly, this is a boon for us.
We don't have that much money.
It's a simple mission,
so I think you'll be fine even
if you're not all together.
What do you say, Diablo?
I guess I could split the reward
we earn from this mission by
paying Rem my lodging fee.
If you don't want to come,
then stay here in the city by yourself.
I will.
Great!
So you and Shera-chan will be going, then?
That settles it.
I'm counting on you!
Go to the Bridge of Ulug
and deliver refreshments...
So easy!
This really is a reparation...
Does Celes really think I'd accept this
and take the reward for such
an obviously simple quest?
I think Celes-san is a nice person, though.
Hold it, Demon.
You're the one, right?
The Demon that everyone's talking
about in town right now.
You look as evil as the rumors said.
Emile?!
Rumors?
What rumors?
I heard of an unfamiliar horned Demon
walking around with two
collared women in tow.
That's you, right, Demon?
They're really bad rumors!
The Distorted Crown
Makes the wearer appear
more like a Demon Lord.
Wait, this is just my headgear,
the Distorted Crown.
They think they're real?
Who is this?
He's said to be the strongest
Warrior in the Adventurer's Guild.
Exactly!
My name is Emile Bichel Berger!
I'm the Guild's greatest,
Level 50, Superhuman Warrior!
Love
Horned Demon, prepare yourself!
Emile Bichel Berger
This is like in a game!
This is it!
Emile Bichel Berger
It's not a real Demon Lord
roleplay without a challenger!
Emile Bichel Berger
Who gave you permission to
announce yourself, twerp?!
Diablo?!
And just who gave you permission
to lead those two around?
Listen well, Demon.
I love all women!
Huh?
As a defender of women,
I cannot allow you to enslave
Rem-chan and Shera-chan!
Emile, please listen!
These collars—
Fear not, you two!
I'll save you now!
He's an oddball,
but this is my first time fighting
a challenger here in this world.
He'll probably fight the same
way others did in the game.
Since he's Level 50, he should be
able to use some special techniques.
That stance...
Sword Smite?!
That's a Martial Art that allows one to
rush the enemy in an instant
and deliver a slashing blow.
It's a standard opening move.
Huh?
Am I actually getting excited
for the first time in a while?
A standard opening move like Sword Smite
is doomed to be seen through in PVP.
Skilled players will use the rushing
motion of Sword Smite, cancel the slash,
and chain it to their next attack.
Heh Heh Heh...
Isn't Diablo acting a little weird?
Here I go!
You'll be releasing those two!
Come!
You didn't cancel the slash?!
I'm shocked!
You can stop this blow?!
Hmph. I'm actually surprised
at how unbelievable that was.
Alps Fall!
Alps Fall?!
While that technique packs power,
the trade-off is the lengthy
time it takes to activate.
He's using it at a range this close?!
The power is building within me.
The moment I unleash this blow...
will be the moment of my victor—
Diablo?!
I-It's like I'm facing a beginner.
I thought the levels in this world
were lower than the game world,
but does that mean the skill
of the players is just as low?
Well, it's possible this guy's just an idiot.
I won't lose!
You have spirit, at least.
I can never fall before an enemy!
I won't be able to hold back next time.
I fight for the sake of oppressed women!
Very well.
Then come!
Stop!
Rem-chan? Shera-chan?
That's enough, Emile!
Don't abandon hope, Rem-chan!
I'm going to...
That's not the case.
You're misunderstanding this.
In other words, this Enslavement
Collar is on my neck
because of my own failure.
Diablo's actually working with
us to get these collars removed.
It's hard to say this when
you're sticking up for us,
but you're just jumping to conclusions.
I want to run away...
Oh, thank goodness!
So there are no women being forced
to wear Enslavement Collars!
That's some mental fortitude!
I'm sorry, Demon.
What was your name?
Diablo.
My name is Emile Bichel Berger.
A defender of women, and all women's ally.
If you ever have need of my strength,
you can call upon me anytime!
Though you were pretty good yourself.
Is that so?
Let's meet again, my friend!
Friend?
I'm sorry you had that
misunderstanding because of us.
Hmph! A man that weak isn't
even enough to entertain me.
Emile isn't a bad person.
His strength is true, as well.
But he seems like an idiot, huh?
She said it!
Errands, errands!
Off to the Bridge of Ulug!
The Bridge of Ulug, huh?
In the game's setting,
it was built as a fortress
to protect Faltra from the
monsters in the Man-Eating Woods.
What lovely weather!
But isn't a simple delivery kind of boring?
Yeah.
Hey, want to go for a dip in the water?
Huh?!
Let's do it, let's do it!
Please?
Bathing together with a w-w-woman?!
There's no way I can clear party events
like that with my poor social skills!
You fool!
How can you go b-b-bathing in
the middle of a quest?!
But I'm bored!
I want to do something fun!
It would be fun if we triggered an Invasion.
Invasion?
It refers to when high-level monsters
appear during a low-level quest.
Huh?!
No way! I don't want that!
I'm not strong like you, Diablo!
Y-Y-You fool!
What good comes from an
adventurer fearing danger?!
I don't want things to stay
like this forever, of course.
I want to grow strong like you and Rem
so I can actually make it on my own.
Hmph. Then continue working hard.
Thank you!
I might still cause trouble
for you until then, though,
so help me out, Diablo!
That way I can grow even more and more!
If they grow any more, I'll reach Heaven...
That man! Is he a Fallen?!
Why is he coming from Faltra?!
Who are you? I am—
Shut up, you suspicious man!
If you're not a Fallen,
then what are those horns?!
My horns again?!
Hold on, everyone!
This man's a Demon!
He's not a Fallen!
Boris?
He's probably the horned Demon
everyone in town is talking about.
The one with the collared women.
Saved by rumors...
We're on a quest to bring refreshments here!
It's wine!
Really, it's awful of you to mistake
me for the likes of a Fallen.
Has something happened here?
Actually...
We just received a report from our patrols
that a huge army of over a hundred
Fallen is heading this way.
Fallen?!
A hundred?!
I know it's hard to believe, but...
The Fallen were treated as boss monsters
in every scenario of Cross Reverie.
I've never heard of an event
where they attacked en masse.
Is this some large-scale Invasion
that was never possible in the game?
Hey! How's your end?!
Hurry into position!
Hurry!
What's going to happen, Diablo?
What'll happen?
It goes without saying.
This place will be wiped out.
It's clear that the people of this world have
lower levels and weaker skills than
the player characters in the game.
They'll be massacred before
they can even put up a fight.
Diablo?
That's not the real problem.
Huh?
Even if they break through the Bridge of Ulug,
the Fallen shouldn't be able to enter Faltra
with Celes's barrier protecting it.
So why engage in such a fruitless campaign?
They say the Fallen have been
active here and there lately,
hoping to revive the Demon Lord Krebskulm.
In which case, their target is Rem?
Have they realized that she secretly
houses the Demon Lord within her?
Guess we should return to the city...
Even with my power,
taking on a hundred Fallen
at once would be a bit tough.
Um,
here...
Our letter of gratitude.
Huh?
It should serve as proof
that we received the wine.
Should you really be discussing
this during an emergency?!
You might say I'm being too relaxed,
but if today happens to be my last day,
then I want to live it out properly.
Your group isn't retreating?
If we retreat,
then people working the fields and the
slower travelers will be in trouble.
It's our job to buy enough time for
everyone to flee into the city.
Diablo...
Sorry, twerp, but your resolve will be wasted.
Huh?
Because I'm not going to
let this be your last day.
Rem-chan!
Rem-chan, you have a visitor!
A visitor?
Diablo-san,
the final traveler has passed through.
We're now lowering the gates
to buy as much time as possible
for them to reach the city.
Then lower them quickly.
Please reconsider!
It's reckless to face them alone!
Diablo-san!
Here come the Fallen!
Fall back, all of you.
You'll make it harder for me
to use my magic if you're nearby.
But...
Let's do as he says.
Don't worry. Diablo is very strong!
Diablo...
What?
Be careful.
Be careful, huh?
That's the first time anyone has shown
consideration for me before a battle.
I'm afraid of facing a hundred Fallen...
But right now, I feel like I
can beat even a Demon Lord!
All of you!
Who gave you permission to
advance your army here?!
If you didn't know that I was in this land,
then be ashamed of your ignorance!
You're... tiny and weak.
Kill...
You still intend to face me?
Very well...
Then I'll exterminate you all!
I've discharged Galluk-san.
He arbitrarily used the Association's name
to place you all in danger, after all.
Besides, it seems like he was also
the one who caused that commotion
by bringing a Summon into town.
He needed to take responsibility.
I'm sorry he's caused
you all so much trouble.
It's fine...
By the way, Galluk-san said
something interesting.
Huh?
Apparently Diablo-san called
himself a Demon Lord.
Diablo is a Demon Lord from another world.
Truly?
What do you mean?
I understand that you're very
talented as a Summoner, Rem,
but I've never heard of a Demon
Lord existing in another world,
and even if one did, I doubt
they could be summoned here.
Perhaps...
There's a chance that he's a Fallen
who was drawn to you by the soul you possess?
That's not possible.
Diablo had plenty of opportunities
to kill me if he wished!
Yet instead...
I'll crush the soul of Krebskulm for you.
Huh?!
Of course, we'll need to spend some time
researching a way to extract it first.
Did I do something?!
That was the first time anyone
said they wouldn't leave me.
You underestimate me too much.
I'm not so weak as to leave
you over something that petty.
Yet instead?
Forget it.
I'm sorry, sir, but we're rented out right now.
Galluk-san?!
Celes-sama!
Would you please reconsider?!
Why do I need to leave
the Mage's Association?!
You did something that was wrong.
I've only done what's right!
Yet everyone keeps lying
about me being fired.
So I hurt them to try to get
them to tell me the truth.
Hurt them?
Are the others at the
Mage's Association safe?
Worry about me, please!
Settle down.
Let's talk about this calmly.
Everyone's crazy...
I've devoted myself to the Association,
yet in the end, no one
understands the real me.
Figures what that woman said was right.
That man?
Stop, Galluk!
Don't disgrace yourself any further!
Like I could ever accept this world...
What is that dagger?
I'm not sure, but I have a bad feeling...
I have to be the one to correct this world!
Stop him, Shadow Snake!
Galluk-san?!
Galluk?!
It can't be...
Don't get close to him!
No way...
It can't...
Is this a Fallen?
It's finally time for the
great Gregore's appearance.
That Human kept babbling on for damned ever...
Now,
are you prepared to die?
Incredible.
Diablo...
That makes about thirty?
If I don't hold off on
the big MP cost spells...
I'll be done in before they are.
Their commander's coming?
Why did you climb off your monster?
Because... he wouldn't move?
He's usually a good, obedient one, too.
But he wouldn't move after seeing you.
Hmph. Your monster understands
better than you do, then,
that one shouldn't just stroll up here.
He knows you can't defeat me.
I'm Edelgard, the strongest
lancer of the Fallen.
I'm not going to lose to some Demon Sorcerer.
If I defeat their commander,
there's a good chance the
others will withdraw.
This fight will decide it.
Very well!
I'll test you to see how strong you are, then!
Fight?
Or don't fight?
Fight!
It's over, Human.
If I take you down, we Fallen win.
You don't understand anything.
The true Demon Lord is none
other than me, Diablo!
Episode Four
Point-Blank War Dance