Move it!
Hurry!
The Fallen are coming!
We're all right now.
The city is protected
by Celes-sama's barrier.
The Fallen can't get in here.
So you're Celestine Baudelaire?
You can go ahead and die, for starters.
Episode Four
Point-Blank War Dance
It was easy to penetrate your barrier,
thanks to that stupid Human.
I guess even you can't
detect camouflaged Fallen.
No way...
I can't believe Galluk-san
would lead a Fallen here.
You tricked Galluk into this!
Rem-sama!
Please take care of Celes-sama!
I'm not letting you escape!
Everyone, run!
There's a Fallen!
Rem-san, that hurts!
Just hang in there!
No, not that way!
Your game of tag is over, shrimp!
Come forth, Asulau!
Oh, a Summon, huh?
In just one blow?!
Guess you can die first, then.
Rem-chan!
Who the hell are you?
My name is Emile Bichel Berger,
and I am an ally of all women!
Emile!
I can't believe a Fallen is
running loose in the city.
But more than that, I cannot
forgive you for targeting women!
Huh?
Celes-sama is the keystone of
the barrier protecting this city!
We'll protect her with our lives!
You're interesting, Humans!
Let's see you do your best to
entertain me, the great Gregore!
Hey, you're pretty strong for a Human.
Right now, I'm fighting to protect someone!
That means I'm invincible!
And you won't shut up! This is great!
What was that?
What did you just...
Magic, Human!
I'm the greatest Sorcerer
in the Man-Eating Woods!
What?!
My favorite thing to do
is plunge confident Humans
like you into despair!
I can't get enough of the face
you all make in that moment!
Sword Smite!
I forgot to mention it,
but I'm a strong Warrior, too.
Dark Bullet!
Emile!
Emile-san!
Emile, please run!
You're outmatched!
Don't say such silly things, Rem-chan.
I'll never turn my back on an enemy!
My name is Emile Bichel Berger!
I am the defender of all women!
It's over, Human.
She's rather strong.
About Level 80?
However...
It's foolish to believe you can
defeat me with so little strength.
Then I'll...
use this.
What's that?
Oh, she's using Sacrificial Charge?
It's a powerful skill that
consumes one's own hit points.
I might be able to use this
to break her will to fight.
Interesting!
I'll take that move of yours head-on!
Go ahead and try to damage me!
Yeah, I will.
Sacrificial...
...Charge!
Diablo!
I see.
This can't be.
I landed a solid hit...
Diablo!
Boris, bad news!
So this is how damage feels?
It's my first time really taking
any since I came to this world.
Have you finally realized the
difference in our abilities?
It seems your most powerful
blow was unable to injure me.
What is she hesitating for?
She should see that she
has no chance of winning.
Any further combat is pointless.
Why isn't she withdrawing her army?
Diablo-san!
A messenger came from the city!
Celestine-sama is being attacked by a Fallen!
They said a Pantherian woman was with her!
It has to be Rem!
So Gregore did his job well?
He's an idiot, but nicely done.
They snuck a soldier into
the city ahead of time?!
Are they planning to break
the barrier by killing Celes,
then push through here
and and storm the city?
So...
Once we finish you off,
we Fallen win.
Tch!
This is even worse if Rem is caught up in it!
I don't have time to be out here!
I'm using Grand Magic!
If you don't want to die,
curl up behind those stone walls!
I have no pity for the Fallen,
but I'll offer one last time.
If you withdraw now, I'll spare you.
I seek the revival of the Demon Lord.
That and exterminating Humanity
are my duties.
So, I will do my best.
Hmph, you dare say you
work for the Demon Lord?
I hate being laughed at.
You know nothing.
I am the true Demon Lord.
There are no others before Demon Lord Diablo!
True Demon Lord?
White Nova!
Impossible...
This cannot...
Demon Lord Diablo...
I'm shocked.
She's still alive after taking a White Nova?
Diablo, Let's hurry!
There's no time to walk back.
I'm trying Return Magic!
Please!
Let this work the same as it did in-game!
Return!
He vanished?
You're the only one left?
I won't be defeated.
For the sake of my fallen
comrades, I'll never...
Stop this already, Emile!
You'll wind up dead!
Don't worry.
I'll protect you no matter what.
Good grief, but you Humans are persistent.
Just die already.
Diablo...
It's hard to say I've made it in time,
but it seems you're still alive, Rem, Celes.
Rem!
I'm so glad you're alive!
Ow!
Are you all right?!
You're bleeding!
This is nothing.
More importantly, Emile's...
Twerp, you're still alive, right?
Yes, my friend.
I acknowledge the fight you've put up.
I'll take it from here.
Here's a healing potion.
Use it on Emile.
Are you really saying you'll fight a Fallen?
To protect us?
I'm just meting out a fitting punishment
to the insolent being who attacked my base.
Don't get the wrong idea.
So there are good Demon Lords, too.
That was quite the foolish
stunt for a mere Demon!
He's a Sorcerer who's developed
his abilities as a Warrior.
In Cross Reverie, he'd be a Brawler Sorcerer.
To think there was one among the Fallen.
No matter how you beg for your life,
I'm killing you!
And right after that, I'll destroy the barrier!
Even if you destroy the barrier,
Edelgard won't be coming.
I dealt quite a bit of damage to her.
I defeated most of the Fallen army, too.
Such bold-faced lies.
You'll understand once you fight me.
You'll see which one of us should
be begging for his life.
Of course, no matter how you beg for your life,
I won't spare you.
Dark Bullet!
What's that?
That's Diablo's...
Magic Reflection?!
What the hell have you done?!
Dark Bullet.
Quit whining.
I haven't used my real magic yet.
Wh-What is this power?!
There's no way a Fallen Sorcerer is only
capable of using Dark Bullet, right?
Dark Press!
Take this!
Wh-What the hell have you been doing?!
You still don't understand?
I suppose your brain is only a lizard's.
Dark Press.
I get it!
I'll leave the city,
so spare me!
P-Please!
Please!
I told you at the start, didn't I?
No matter how you beg for your life,
I won't spare you.
You'll pay for your crimes with your death.
You've killed too many.
N-No!
P-Please don't kill me!
Naraku.
I'm sealing you in a dimension of darkness.
For eternity.
This exhaustion really is awful.
I did end up using a lot of Magic Points.
Diablo!
I thought we were done for.
Thank you so much.
Truly, truly...
Huh? Y-Yeah...
You really might...
be able...
to save me.
Yes, I did promise that.
Shoot!
Shoot, shoot, shoot!
What would a Demon Lord say
next at a time like this?!
I've never seen a woman thank a
Demon Lord before, so I don't know!
Y-Your Enslavement Collar!
Huh?
In short,
it means that you belong to me,
so of course I'd protect my possessions!
I didn't fight for your sake!
W-Was that pushing it?
I belong to you?
Right...
So long as this Enslavement Collar lasts.
Why does she seem so happy about that?!
Hey! Only Rem?
I belong to you too, right?
Uh, I'm exhausted right now,
so if you press those against me...
They bounce!
Diablo!
H-Hard!
Diablo hit his head and passed out?!
What?!
Oh, no!
The casualties of the Fallen's assault
were buried three days later.
Nearly all of those lost in
this assault were Adventurers.
This world isn't like the game.
When someone dies, there are no salvation
mechanisms like resurrection,
and I was bitterly forced to accept that.
What surprised me the most
was that even after facing such tragedy,
many people still retained the light of hope.
They took each other's hands
and tried to return to their normal lives.
That was never in the game, either.
As for me...
Days
Later
Like this?
Diablo, are you awake?
I'm awake, but still sleepy.
Hey, let's go on a quest.
I'm bored.
It's already been ten days since then.
I consumed too much MP, though,
so I still can't shake the
melancholy mood hanging over me.
Maybe I'll just go ahead and
become mold on these sheets.
Come on, what are you saying?
Get up!
Wha?!
Wha... Huh?! Wha?!
Diablo, think you can perk up now?
Sylvie-san said doing this
would make a man perk up.
What are you teaching her,
you wicked Guildmaster?!
Hey, how about it?
Are you feeling better?
Shera!
Why are you dressed like that?!
Uh... I'm hot?
You're hot because you keep clinging to him!
Get away! Stay at least thirty
steps away from Diablo!
What?
But that puts me out of the room!
Why are you constantly pressing
your breasts against him?!
Because they hit him when I hug him!
Though in your case, your ribs might hit him.
That wouldn't happen!
She's right!
I think I can feel her ribs a bit.
But this is also...
Morning!
Getting along well, are we?
Sylvie-san, good morning!
Hey, Shera-chan.
Diablo-san, too.
Glad to see you're feeling well.
So, what did you need, Sylvie?
I've brought information I thought
you'd be interested in, Diablo-san.
Oh?
The Lord of Faltra City has received demands
from the Elven Kingdom for Shera
L. Greenwood to be handed over.
The deadline is ten days from now,
and they say they're not afraid to
wage war if their demands aren't met.
War?
Is he sane?
He'd have people fighting one another?
The lord just issued a request for us
to try and resolve this quietly.
Are you saying you accepted a quest
that requires turning Shera over?!
Hold on, hold on!
You know I wouldn't do that.
Do you really think I'd try to seize Shera
from the man who routed an army of Fallen?
Hmph. It seems you're not an idiot.
So, here's the quest from
me and our troubled lord.
Stop a war from breaking out
with the Elven Kingdom. Okay,
Diablo-san?
I am Lt. General Chester Ray Galford.
Let's work hard together
so everyone can be happy!
No, let go of me!
Episode Five
Imperial Knights
Shera!