Prevent a war?
Yup.
Assuming you don't want
to hand over Shera-chan.
The Lord of Faltra City has received
demands from the Elven Kingdom
for Shera L. Greenwood to be handed over.
The deadline is ten days from now,
and they say they're not afraid to
wage war if their demands aren't met.
No way...
What'll you do, Diablo-san?
Episode Five
Imperial Knight
You're kidding...
You're kidding, right?
Greenwood is going to war with
the Kingdom of Lyferia over me?
At this rate, yeah.
That's why the lord and
I are both in trouble.
Back then...
Shera made her feelings known and clearly
told them she didn't want to go home.
They still haven't given up?
So...
We'd like you to work out a way
to prevent this war, Diablo-san.
Okay?
I absolutely refuse!
How am I supposed to prevent a war?!
Rant
Negotiate?
Gripe
If had the communication
skills to do that,
Gripe
I wouldn't be struggling to keep
faking this Demon Lord persona!
That's something the people
in power should figure out!
But reality never works out that way.
What do I do to protect Shera?
What should I do?
By the way, Prince Keera from
the Kingdom of Greenwood
has put a huge bounty on Shera-chan.
What?!
Nii-san did?!
Absurd.
The reward is enough for a commoner
to goof off for the rest of their life.
From now on, you'll never know when or where
some imprudent adventurer will
try to go after Shera-chan.
You'd be better off not going outside at all.
That's...
That's just...
Shera...
Diablo?!
He placed a bounty on his own little sister?
Screw him!
If there's any fool out there blinded by greed,
I'll make them regret challenging me!
Diablo!
You belong to me.
I told you before, right?
Yeah.
So no matter who comes after you,
I won't let them lay a finger on you.
You can continue walking proudly
through the city, just like always.
What do we do about the
Kingdom of Greenwood?
The first step to clearing any
quest is gathering information.
So we're going to go
talk to the lord right now.
As if I'm gonna let him start some stupid war!
Thank you, Diablo!
I'll go with you, too!
I'll follow you anywhere, Diablo!
Ahem...
Go change your clothes first, stupid Shera.
The lord is the hero of this city.
Hero?
It happened thirty years ago.
When the Demon Lord was still around,
he fought on the front lines and
defeated several Fallen single-handedly.
Sounds like Diablo the other day.
What's his level?
We've never assessed him, so I wouldn't know.
He's not an adventurer, either.
He might have been measured long ago,
but he's not the kind of person
I could ask about that easily.
Do you mean the lord...
is hard to talk to?
People say he can be pretty rigid.
He's a little scary.
So Diablo-san...
Be careful how you speak to him, okay?
H-Hey, Galford-san!
Nice weather we're having, huh?
Can Diablo even use polite language?
Shh! Shut up, stupid Shera!
Diablo-san has accepted
the quest about that matter.
In that case,
he should resolve the problem quickly.
You can report to me after
the quest is complete.
Well, the difficulty of the quest
is pretty high, you know?
So he wanted to gather
some more information.
I believe I already told you
everything you need to know.
Well, true, but...
Oh, right!
Could you at least introduce
yourself to them?
Good grief...
Adventurers who don't even know
the name of their lord?
I am Lieutenant General Chester Ray Galford.
His Royal Majesty has entrusted the
fortified city, Faltra, to me.
I'm Rem Galleu, an adventurer.
I'm Shera L. Greenwood.
S-S-Scary!
What's with this tense atmosphere?!
Demon
Lord
Mode
Humble
Spirited
Mode
Introductions?!
Trying to do this without dropping my Demon
Lord act or provoking the other guy
sets the hurdle way too high!
Difficulty
This seems way more difficult
than preventing a war!
Y-Yeah...
I am Diablo.
I've come to hear you out.
I did it!
I managed a peaceful introduction
with my poor communication skills!
I can do it when I try!
According to my reports, you call yourself
the "Demon Lord from another world."
Is that true?
Shall I reduce you to ash to prove it?
Diablo!
W-Wait, please!
He's always like this!
He doesn't mean anything by it!
Hmph.
You adventurers truly are a strange lot.
Huh?
Look behind you.
Southeast of the city lies Seplia Lake,
and to the east of that is a forest
that currently conceals Elves.
We still don't know their exact number.
But considering the Kingdom's
forces, we estimate 100 at most.
A hundred?
That's not much for an army.
It's a number not worth considering.
However, their specialty is hiding
in trees to ambush enemies.
If I were to send troops into that
forest where the Elves lie in wait,
I would lose many men.
Having my men die needlessly
is the one thing I hate most.
And that's why you're using me?
If you'd just hand over the princess,
there'd be no need for that.
I refuse!
Princess Shera,
what do you seek so ardently that you
would abandon your life of luxury
and brave danger to disguise
yourself as an adventurer?
I...
I wanted a reason to be myself.
One that wasn't my bloodline.
I wanted to know what I'm worth on my own.
I don't think I could ever
find that in the Elven nation.
I see.
You understand?
I couldn't possibly empathize with that.
But I'll retain the knowledge of it.
I see...
We don't need empathy from others.
We face hardships as we please,
put forth our efforts where we please,
challenge our limits as we please,
and savor the successes we
achieve by our own strength.
When you're following a
path you chose yourself,
you mustn't be led astray,
no matter what others may say.
That's what it means to live free.
Then you won't be handing
Princess Shera over.
So you'll be taking measures to prevent
war with the Kingdom of Greenwood.
Do I understand you correctly?
Shera to belongs to me anyway.
There's no room for others to get involved.
Then I leave it to you.
Oh, right.
Someone was dispatched from
the royal capital about this matter.
Let me introduce you.
I am Alicia Cristela, an Imperial Knight.
I have received orders from His Royal
Majesty to address this matter.
An Imperial Knight?
It is an honor to meet you.
An Imperial Knight...
Alicia Cristela?
In Cross Reverie, only powerful people with
a lineage could become Imperial Knights.
They're supposed to be
the elite of the elite.
Was there a character like her in the game?
It's extremely rare to see an
Imperial Knight who's a woman.
I thought they were all men.
Fortunately for me, I serve as an
Imperial Knight despite being a woman.
That's wonderful.
No, I still have a long way to go.
What about you, Rem-sama?
You seem to be worrying
about something yourself.
What made you think that?
I'm sorry.
It was just a guess.
According to the reports,
you're a talented Summoner,
but you aren't working under anyone.
So I figured there must
be some reason for that.
I see.
If there's anything I can help you with,
please feel free to talk to me about it.
Thank you very much.
Sylvie-sama...
His Majesty sent this as reparations.
Reparations?
Since you lost many adventurers
in that incident the other day.
Oh...
Thanks.
Shera-sama!
I'm with you!
I'm sure we'll have a lot of
trouble due to this matter,
but I'll do my best alongside
you to make everyone happy!
Yeah!
She's crazy!!!
She's crazy!
Her overwhelming communication
skills let her converse perfectly
with someone she only just met!
As a person, her level is a whole
universe higher than scum like me!
Diablo-sama...
I cannot express enough gratitude
and respect to you for defending
the Bridge of Ulug and Faltra
from the Fallen's attack.
I'm sure you have no need of my aid,
but please permit me to
accompany you nonetheless!
C-C-C-C-C-C-Crap!
She's too perfect as a person!
If I'm not careful, she might see
through my Demon Lord act!
Frankly, I don't want her to talk to me!
Do as you please.
However!
If you don't want to die,
then don't speak to me frivolously.
Then I shall prepare myself for that.
Huh?
If that is enough to quell
your rage, Diablo-sama,
then I shall not begrudge you my life!
Sh-Sh-Sh-ShShShShSh...
She's so diligent!
Diablo-sama, where are we heading?
We're not heading straight for
the woods with the Elves, are we?
We're going to a weaponsmith before that.
A weaponsmith?
I don't think this city can offer a better
staff than the one you have, Diablo.
Don't judge my actions by your standards.
I have a plan.
This was true in our last battle, too,
but the residents of this world are just
too low-level compared to the game.
It's not going to end well
if I accidentally kill my opponents
in front of an Imperial Knight,
so I need to buy a weapon that makes
it easier for me to go easy on them.
Welcome!
Thank you so much!
You... bought a pretty incredible one.
I focused on its appearance
and ability to deal with small fry.
Since that's what I want!
It... suits you well.
What are we doing after this?
Well, next, I guess we'll buy ingredients
for potions at an item shop.
It would be nice if we didn't need to fight,
but it's always best to be
prepared for any outcome.
Hurry!
Shera-sama, if you run
around too much, you'll trip.
She's like a mom.
Wha...
What?!
No! Let go!
Shera-sama?!
Bounty hunters?!
You're not getting by us!
You can play with us for a bit.
What did you say?!
Move!
T-Too strong...
That wasn't lethal, was it?
Well?!
Huh?
Good, I can hold back on them.
I made the right choice with this weapon!
Why, you!
I won't allow you to get
in Diablo-sama's way!
Tsk...
I'm surprised.
I didn't think fools tempted by the
bounty would show up this soon.
Are you prepared for this?
Please leave them to me!
Right.
Shera!
No!
I hear something approaching us, Nii-san!
What is this sound, little brother?!
Help me!
Shera!
Wait for me, Shera!
I'm catching up now!
Diablo!
What?!
He's fast, Nii-san!
He is fast, little brother!
But we can't let ourselves get
captured after coming this far!
Double Smash!
I'll never allow wickedness to
befall women in this city!
You're...
It's been a while, friend.
My name is Emile Bichel Berger.
I am the ally of all women and allies of women!
Thanks, Emile.
You saved me.
Still, I'm surprised you were
passing through this back alley.
Well...
I've kept it quiet so far,
but I can smell the very scent
of a woman in trouble!
Just don't do anything
to get yourself arrested.
I kid, I kid!
I actually heard from the Adventurer's Guild
that Prince Keera put out a bounty.
So I was searching for
Shera-chan to protect her.
Makes sense.
As for me personally,
I'd like to repay you for
saving me the other day.
By the way,
what are you planning to do with them?
They may have failed,
but they're still kidnappers.
There's an Imperial Knight with us, too.
Leave these men to me.
I need to eliminate those who would
make women cry from this world.
Will you kill them?
Perish the thought.
I'll just pound the preciousness of women
into them until they understand it
from the bottoms of their hearts!
I'll turn them into honest people who would
never make the mistake of
trying to kidnap women!
Harsh!
Now then, I'll be heading off,
but this won't be the last of
those blinded by the bounty.
Please be careful.
Later, Emile!
You have my gratitude.
I nearly allowed my charge to be kidnapped.
You have my sincere gratitude.
My goodness! It seems I've
charmed another woman.
What a sinful man I am.
I think Emile's a good guy,
but I'm not charmed by him.
He's not a bad person,
but I'd rather avoid getting
too involved with him.
Shera...
What?
Don't stray from me.
Stay by my side.
Huh? I can?
It'd be a hassle if you got kidnapped again.
Can...
Can I... hold your hand?
Yes.
Listen...
Thanks for saving me.
Emile is the one who saved you.
But you're the one who took
out their companions, right?
I was really scared,
but when I saw you chasing after me,
I felt relieved.
Don't rest easy before you've been saved.
You're too optimistic.
That's too close!
But it's dangerous if I'm
away from you, right?
Still...
I'm surprised.
You're that strong even
without using your magic?
Impressive.
Th-That's only natural.
I'm no mere Sorcerer, after all.
I'm the Demon Lord.
Yes!
My apologies, Diablo-sama.
Shera-sama was endangered
due to my inattention.
How can I make it up to you?
That's not true!
I'm to blame for that!
You didn't do anything wrong, Alicia-san!
But...
You're misunderstanding.
I'm the Demon Lord Diablo.
I never desired your aid to begin with.
Th-Then how may I be of
service to you, Diablo-sama?
This girl is way too diligent.
Even if she is an Imperial Knight,
it'll be hard on her if
she doesn't relax more.
Are you one of those?
The type that thinks anyone
who isn't useful should die?
Huh? That's not...
That's not true at all!
Then forgive yourself for being useless.
If you want to accompany us,
do so as you please.
You don't need to insist
on producing results.
Yes.
I, Alicia Cristela, shall henceforth
turn my greatest effort
toward forgiving myself when I'm not useful!
That's all wrong!
Well, shall we head to the
forest with the Elves now?
Yeah, let's all do our best!
Good grief... You're so boorish.
That wasn't me!
It was Diablo, wasn't it?
Don't be foolish!
I'm not as gluttonous as you are!
Then who...
Shall we go grab a bite, Alicia-san?
I-I'm fine...
You know what they say about empty stomachs.
I-Is that so?
Hey, what should we eat?
Meat.
You always want that, Rem!
What would you like, Alicia-san?
I don't really...
Let's eat meat.
No!
I want fruit!
Don't fight, you fools!
You figured out a way
to release our collars?!
It looks good on you.
Send my magic power into Shera!
Diablo, wait!
Episode Six
Slave Market
This feels incredible!