You figured out a way
to release our collars?!
Don't be hasty.
We're not certain yet.
I'm only talking about a possibility.
A slave caravan came in yesterday and
set up a market in the central plaza.
The Enslavement Collars and slave collars
are fundamentally the same
on a magical level, so...
I see.
So we might be able to learn a way to release
our collars from someone
who's used to handling them.
Are you sure about this, though?
I think resolving the issue
with the Kingdom of Greenwood
is our highest priority right now.
That's definitely true,
but if we can remove the
Enslavement Collars,
I'd like to do it as soon as possible.
Diablo?
Hmph.
The issue with the Elven nation
will be quickly resolved once I head there.
Time spent stopping by the slave
market won't affect that result.
Shera-san,
I'm sorry this is all the
help I can offer you
when you're in trouble with your nation.
Not at all! Thank you very much!
Episode Six
Slave Market
We might finally be able
to get these collars off!
I bet my neck will feel breezy without it,
since I've gotten so used to having it on.
So this is a slave market...
Is something the matter, Diablo-sama?
No...
I lived in Japan, so I've only ever seen
slave markets in games and manga.
Master!
I'm not sure my heart can take this!
I need to be careful not to let it
affect my Demon Lord persona.
This is...
not quite what I expected.
Welcome to The Beloved Traveler.
My, my, what an entourage of customers.
Are you in charge here?
I'm the owner, Medios.
Oh?
Those are lovely girls.
If you're selling, I'll gladly buy
them for an exceptional sum.
These two are not slaves!
Well, pardon me, then.
I presumed you were here to sell one off.
You possess tremendous
magic power, don't you?
What?
What an incredible flow of magic power...
No amount of lives would save
any poor soul who angered you.
Flow of magic power?
What is she talking about?
I knew it!
You can tell that Diablo's strong right
away from his flow of magic power!
Huh?
Oh?
You can see the flow of magic power, too?
Yeah!
Is that true?
You never said a word about that to us!
Well, you never asked.
I understand.
So you want me to teach you how
to remove the Enslavement Collars.
Can you do it?
Well, now...
It's my first time dealing with a
magic spell being reflected, too.
But since Celestine has sent you to me,
I can give it a try.
Yay!
Please do!
By the way,
you also possess quite an interesting flow.
Huh?
Magic power is perpetually
pouring from you.
A very sinister power...
Do you recall anything
that might have caused you to
become pregnant with a Demon?
Huh?!
What?!
I-Is that true, Rem-sama?!
When did that happen?!
This isn't funny!
Ah! That night Diablo tortured you!
That night!
Huh?! Me?!
We didn't do anything like that!
But when you share a bed alone with someone,
you get pregnant, right?
Huh?!
But I'm sensing Fallen energy
from within a Pantherian...
That's enough idle chatter!
Tell us how to remove the collars at once!
Oh, I'll show you.
But it is a trade secret.
I'd like to show it to as few as possible.
I'll be standing by outside.
I'll hold off, as well...
I don't feel so good.
You don't look so good. Are you all right?
Could you see the magic power
coming out of me all along?
Huh?
Yeah!
That's why I thought you must
be a really strong adventurer.
I... see.
I'm glad you're such an idiot.
Hey, that was mean!
The soul of the Demon Lord
Krebskulm is sealed within me.
My ultimate goal is to defeat the Demon
Lord Krebskulm that lies within me
and extinguish her soul.
That was close.
We'd be facing all kinds
of trouble if she found out
about Krebskulm right now.
I guarantee that I'll save you someday!
So just wait until then, Rem!
Are you really feeling unwell?
No, I'm fine.
Medios-san, was it?
I felt like she was going to
see straight into my heart.
It was a little scary.
Even for an upstanding
Imperial Knight like you?
All the more because I'm an Imperial Knight.
The harder you try to be righteous,
the more your lies steadily increase.
Is that how it works?
That's a secret.
I was afraid my own secret
would be brought to light.
Everyone has some kind of secret.
Oh, right!
I know of a charm to help you
conceal secrets when they're
about to be exposed!
Though it's a little
childish and embarrassing.
What kind of charm is it?
Could you close your eyes
and hold one hand out for me?
In my hometown, we did this and said...
"There, all closed."
Everyone said that this would
help protect your secrets.
Is something wrong?
N-No, nothing!
That's all.
It felt like my hand grew
warmer for a moment.
It did?
It's my first time doing
this with a Sorcerer,
so maybe something is actually cast
when it's done with magic power.
I feel a little more relaxed
after talking to you.
Thank you, Alicia-san.
I'm glad I was able to be useful to you.
Now, are you ready?
Why am I...
I thought we were just removing the collar.
It looks great on you!
What kind of crazy outfit is
this damn hag making her wear?!
It's best to actually touch the
skin the first time you do this.
Skin?!
Now, lie down.
Okay...
I'm going to teach Diablo-san
how to see your flow of magic power.
Once he learns that,
he might be able to undo
the magic power imbued in your collars.
Okay, first, try touching Shera-chan's skin.
Sure.
Don't make weird sounds!
But...
Stop flirting and try
reading her magic power.
Uh...
If you can use magic,
you should be able to do it.
Even if you can't see it,
sensing it is normal. Completely normal.
This isn't working because I'm
thinking of it as a person's skin.
I need to handle this like I'm casting magic.
Yes...
This isn't Shera.
It's a wand!
Wand, wand, wand, wand, wand, wand...
Looks like you can see it.
Y-Yeah...
All right, next, why don't you try touching
where her flow of magic
power is concentrated?
Here I go, Shera.
Okay. This is kind of scary, though.
Just trust me!
Once I learn this,
I'll be sure to release the Enslavement
Collars placed on you two!
Do it!
This is a wand!
There!
Diablo, wait!
This feels incredible!
This is her flow of magic power?
How far does this go?
I can't see the end!
Don't be so rough there...
Incredible!
When I change how I'm touching it,
the range I can see changes, too!
It seems like you can see most of it now.
Why don't you try going a little lower?
Lower?
Yes, and this time you're going to
pour your own magic power into her.
Gently, gently...
Like you're embracing Shera-chan.
Ah, Diablo...
My belly button might be sensitive...
Find where her magic power is concentrated...
Here?
Not there!
Try to affect her magic power.
Slowly insert yours into her.
Insert my magic power into Shera...
You've broken past the surface
and started to reach her core
in such a short time!
Shera, listen! We're finishing now!
Yes! Give it to me!
Diablo's...
Diablo's pouring into me!
What?
So in the end,
you quit before you could figure
out how to release our collars?
It seemed like you were putting
a lot of effort into it.
Yeah...
I managed to learn how to see the
flow of magic power easily enough.
But we ran into trouble after that.
The flow of magic power pouring out
of these Enslavement Collars is...
It's like countless balls of yarn
strewn about an endless
room, all tangled together.
I need to unravel that
mess thread by thread,
but the room is so full of smoke
that I can't see them very well,
and I can only stay in the
room while holding my breath.
That's what it felt like.
I see...
You look energized, though.
Yeah!
All I had to do was lie down.
Then Diablo's hot essence poured into me,
so I'm actually full of energy!
Somehow, I'm really tired today.
I know it's a bit early,
but shall we go to bed?
I'm all for that.
I'm confident I could sleep like the dead.
By the way, where are you
planning to sleep, Alicia-san?
She couldn't possibly...
I'm getting the feeling the greatest
accident ever might happen!
I don't have the stamina
left for that tonight!
Though even if I had the stamina,
I couldn't do anything!
I've rented the room next to yours,
so you needn't worry.
I see.
Well, then, if you'll excuse me.
The sound of a flute?
It's a pretty timbre.
It can't be...
This sound...
An Elf?
No way...
Why are you here,
Nii-san?!
Nice to meet you.
I'm Shera's older brother,
First Prince of the Kingdom of Greenwood,
Keera L. Greenwood.
I've finally found you, Shera.
Now, come home with your brother.
So you're the stupid prince
who put a bounty on Shera?
Diablo?!
According to our reports,
the adventurers seeking the bounty
were defeated and captured.
I'm not about to let Shera get
kidnapped by such weaklings!
That's good.
Huh?
Actually, I said, "I'd like to show my gratitude
to the man safeguarding my little sister,"
and it seems that caused
a misunderstanding.
Misunderstanding?
I'm relieved to see that you are all well.
We heard that the Elves were prepared
to wage war if Princess Shera
wasn't handed over, though.
I have no intention of going
to war with the Humans.
My father is just so concerned
with Shera's well-being.
Please allow me to apologize on my father's
behalf for his inappropriate remarks.
This isn't exactly what we expected.
Sure, finding a peaceful resolution
would be the best outcome, but...
This isn't right!
You're not acting like yourself, Nii-san!
If you speak the truth, Prince Keera,
then we're happy to hear it,
but we're left questioning if
you're trying a different approach
now that your forceful measures have failed.
I'm so sorry, Shera!
I've been prioritizing our country
so much that I ignored your feelings.
I didn't realize what I should be
cherishing most until I'd lost you.
Can you ever find it in you to
forgive your foolish brother?
What...
I'm going to respect Shera's opinion on this.
I don't know if what you say
is true or not, Prince Keera,
but I agree with you that Shera's
feelings are what matters most here.
Whether she returns to her
nation or stays here with us
is for her to decide.
Rem...
I understand.
I'm not lying about Shera's
feelings mattering most.
I'll take my leave for today.
It seems that our sudden reunion
has made Shera emotional,
so I'll come again tomorrow.
At that time, please let me know
your true feelings once more.
Hmph.
And if Shera still says
she won't return home?
Then war?
Heavens, no!
I'll respect Shera's decision!
I swear to God that I'll accept her choice.
He was surprisingly decent.
But what about you...
if she says that she'll return home?
What a foolish question.
There's no chance of that at all.
Diablo...
If she truly were to decide to go home,
then she can do as she pleases.
Of course.
Diablo...
Can't sleep?
Rem...
You're awake?
Standing in the night air in your
nightgown isn't good for your health.
Sorry. I'll close the window.
I don't mind.
Huh?
Shall we talk for a bit?
What do you plan on doing tomorrow?
Huh?
I mean,
will you go with Prince Keera... or not?
I'm not going home.
I made that decision when I left.
Prince Keera was a surprisingly nice fellow.
I can't tell whether or
not Nii-san was lying.
Are you worried?
Not about that...
I recalled several things
about my homeland.
So you were feeling nostalgic?
Yes! That!
Shh! You'll wake Diablo.
Oh, sorry.
I'm already awake, actually.
What are you going to do from here?
From here?
You shouldn't be hunted down
by any Elves anymore.
I don't think you'd need to continue
adventuring and moving around all the time.
Hmm...
I want to continue adventuring, though.
Aside from that, I'd love
to try opening a café.
A café?
Doesn't it sound lovely?
Everyone could have fun drinking
coffee and eating snacks.
That's too vague for me to picture.
Well, I've never been to one before.
There was a new one that
opened recently in Faltra.
You're kidding! I want to go!
You know, I've thought about this a lot.
Once I open the café, I'll be its owner!
And you can be a waitress,
and Diablo can be in charge
of polishing the cups!
Cups...
Why are you involving us in your dream?
Huh?
That's obvious, isn't it?
Because you're the first friends I made
after leaving the Elven nation!
Your first friends, huh?
Wherever you and Diablo are
would definitely be the new place I call home.
You two have done so much for me,
and you're my precious friends.
You're more family than my real family now.
Unfortunately, I can't be part of
your plans for the future right now.
I'm burdened with a certain
problem at the moment.
Until that problem is resolved,
I don't have any leeway
to consider the future.
And this problem is not
only a very difficult one,
but it's so depressing, it makes me want
to give up sometimes.
Is there anything I can do?
I don't know.
Well, you have Diablo, then!
True...
Diablo might be able to
do something about it.
So...
If you'll still welcome me again
after that problem is resolved...
Then maybe I will join you at that café.
Rem!
Ah, hey!
Get off me!
No way!
Rem! Rem! Rem!
I love you, Rem!
I-I get it! Now get off of me!
Nope!
S-Stupid Shera!
Let go of my tail!
I've always wanted to try touching it!
S-Stop it!
Then...
Where are you touching me?!
Diablo did this to me today.
He poured his magic power into me like this.
Why are you recreating that with me?!
Yeah! It makes you cry out like that!
You stupid Shera!
I... I can't sleep now!
Shera...
By this time tomorrow,
you'll belong to me.
I can't wait.
You'll bear my child,
Shera!
You belong to me, Shera!
Because I'm Shera's friend.
Tell me...
Episode Seven
Change of Heart
how you really feel!