Takuma, you're strong!
A monster like this is nothing when
you fight it with three people.
Want me to share my equipment with you two?
I have a lot!
Really?!
We're friends, aren't we?
All right!
"We're friends, aren't we?"
He's such a weird kid.
It's cool, though, since he gives us items.
Man, this equipment's super strong!
It makes the monsters easy,
even with just us two!
I'm starting to think we'd
be fine without Takuma!
We'd be fine! Totally fine!
A dream?
Y-You guys are clinging way too close!
I-It's definitely nice, though...
Episode Seven
Change of Heart
Well,
I'm heading out now to
inform Sylvie and Celes
about what happened with
Prince Keera yesterday.
I'll go report to Lord Galford-sama.
Good.
Be careful, okay?
It's you who should be careful.
Since there's a risk of adventurers
targeting you again,
Prince Keera will be coming
here to hear your reply.
Please be sure not to let your guard down.
Fear not.
No matter who comes, I won't hand over Shera.
I'll give Nii-san a clear refusal,
and that'll be the end of all this!
There won't be any war!
We'll just grab our reward,
and this quest will be complete!
Farewell.
I'll be heading off.
Now, then...
What are you doing?
We managed to avert a war this time,
but nothing good ever comes from
slacking off on preparations.
I'm going to try recreating
the potions from my world.
Wow! Potions?!
You don't become a Demon Lord overnight.
The truly strong are those who never fail
to make basic preparations like these.
Still, how do I go about making them?
These don't look quite the same
as Cross Reverie's graphics.
Do I just mix them together?
Hey, can I watch? I'll be quiet!
The pressure!
What's the matter?
Nothing!
I'm so close to being able to
see this Elf's great treasures!
I don't want potions,
I want lotion!
I don't know what I'm saying anymore!
Superb!
Superb
Oversized
Oversized!
Orbs!
Orbs
What?!
Incredible!
You can make it that quickly?
It's done?!
I've seen professionals brew potions before,
but they never made them that quickly.
I did it...
in the time it took her boobs
to jiggle three times.
Which means if I focus on doing the task,
I do the work as my real self,
who has no knowledge of this.
But if I let my mind
focus on something else,
my body goes through the motions I
perfected as a master Combiner in-game,
allowing me to complete
the potions in an instant.
You're not making any more?
Oh, no, I will, but...
Shera!
You should pay close attention!
You're an adventurer, too,
so it's best if you can make potions, as well.
Now, watch only my hands!
Okay! I'm watching!
I'm watching, too!
They're so jiggly...
The tips!
Just a little more, and the tips...
Being a master Combiner is incredible!
Wow, amazing!
This is only to be expected of a Demon Lord.
I've never seen anything like this before!
You can do anything, Diablo!
That's incredible!
Huh?
Diablo, you're smiling?
Huh?!
As if!
But you usually have a much
scarier look on your face.
Damn it! I can't believe I did that!
I loved that look you just had.
Huh?!
Ah, there! That one!
Crap!
I haven't smiled at anyone
since I came to this world.
Maybe someday...
I'll be able to talk to people normally,
instead of acting like a Demon Lord.
Well, um...
You know...
I was thinking it'd be nice...
if moments like these could go on forever.
Huh?
Wait, why am I getting all sappy?!
A sappy Demon Lord
is no Demon Lord at all!
I can't believe you'd say
something like that.
Listen, Diablo... I...
He's here.
Shera, what's the matter?
Listen, Diablo.
I need to tell you something.
Oh?
I'm...
going home to the Kingdom of Greenwood.
Huh?!
W-Wait... Hey...
What brought this on?
I just kind of realized...
Things can't stay like this.
Greenwood is my home,
and instead of using my time like this,
I should use it for the royal family.
I'm going now, okay?
Wh-What about Rem?
You don't want to tell her goodbye?
It's more important that
I go to my brother quickly.
Shera?!
Welcome back, Shera.
I had faith that you would return to me.
We both promised to respect
Shera's decision, didn't we?
Well, then, we'll be going.
Shera...
Oh...
Diablo?
What's the matter?
You look kind of down.
Shera returned to Greenwood.
She went back?!
Why?!
I don't know.
Wait a minute!
So?
What are you going to do now?
Sleep.
How did this happen?
Shera didn't seem like the
kind of girl who'd lie to me.
Just yesterday, she was clear
about not going home.
Did I step on some kind of land mine?
I was thinking it'd be nice if moments
like these could go on forever.
Diablo...
How long do you plan to stay like this?
Are you not going to rescue her?
That stupid Elf isn't capable
of putting on an act.
If she were,
she would've had a much easier time in life.
She's slow, and she has
trouble learning things.
That girl cannot tell a lie.
And she told me about her
dream for the future last night.
It was unrealistic,
but it was a cute dream that suited her.
And both you and I were present in that dream.
I can't imagine that she
would ever leave us behind.
Don't you think there's a chance she's
under a spell that's controlling her mind?
I know that much.
When Keera came to visit,
he was playing his flute again.
That was when Shera started acting strange.
It's possible his flute
possesses some kind of power.
But that flute didn't exist in Cross Reverie,
and most of all, I don't have any proof.
In the end, it's the same as before...
I convinced myself that we were friends,
and enjoyed the convenient misinterpretation
that they liked me, too.
It was the pathetic delusion
of one cast aside.
The thought that this was
all my own misunderstanding
feels the most correct to me.
I...
believe in Shera.
Even if this wasn't caused by magic,
I'm sure she's just deluded.
I'm going to go get Shera back.
What are you going to do?
No!
Getting rejected and hurt again
is the last thing I want!
I don't want to feel the
pain of having my emotions
tossed around by others again!
You were the same yourself, Rem.
So why?
Why?
Why?!
Because I'm Shera's friend.
I'm staying with my companions,
Diablo and Rem, now.
Diablo? Be careful.
Hey! Only Rem?
I belong to you too, right?
Thanks for saving me.
Listen, Diablo...
I wish moments like these
could go on forever, too.
You should wait, Rem.
If you storm the Elven camp on your own,
there's no guaranteeing your safety.
I'm not giving up until I see Shera again.
How interesting.
You'd face such hardship
just to see someone who left you behind?
Rem Galleu!
You are one of the two who summoned me!
So I ask you this!
Do you desire this Demon Lord's power?!
Yes!
I want your power,
Demon Lord Diablo!
Very well!
Then, to fulfill your objective,
I shall show you a glimpse
of my substantial power!
I shall go, as well.
Alicia-san?
I can't accept what's happening
to Shera-sama, either.
This might mean casting aside your
status as an Imperial Knight.
What I strive to defend isn't my status.
It's people in trouble.
Besides...
I can't just leave Rem-sama alone, either.
Alicia-san...
Hmph.
I thought I told you that you don't
need to try to be useful.
You're the type that draws the short
straw surprisingly often, aren't you?
Yes!
All right! Let's go!
We're going to take Shera
back from that stupid prince!
Yes!
It's pointless to resist, Shera.
You know that this flute is the
secret art of our kind, right?
When I saw you yesterday,
I played a tune only Elves can
hear that was imbued with a spell.
It's already impossible for
you to defy this flute.
I can overwrite your will however I please.
It was truly a masterpiece!
The look that Demon had on his face
when you betrayed him after
he placed so much faith in you!
Now, Shera, I'm overwriting you.
You'll want to answer my questions now.
Yes.
You can ask me anything.
What did that Diablo demand of you?
What kind of orders did he give you?
Orders?
He's given you all kinds of orders
using that Enslavement Collar, right?
Tell me.
How did he make you serve him?
I'll do even more incredible things to you.
Orders?
He only ever ordered me once.
To shake hands with Rem, with a smile.
You fool!
That's not what I meant!
But he never gave me any other orders!
Seriously?
Whatever.
Either way, you can't run away anymore.
I'll teach your body thoroughly...
just who you belong to.
What was that sound?
Jeez, and I was just about to...
What's that?
You don't need to be scared.
It's just a Slime.
N-No!
It'll melt me and eat me!
If it were a carnivorous one.
This is a breed that only eats fabric.
Huh?
What are you going to do
after melting my clothes?
That's obvious, isn't it?
I'm preparing you to create my heir.
No!
No...
It burns!
It feels like I'm being
licked by a huge tongue!
So you like it behind your knee, huh?
What a dirty girl.
Wh-What are you saying?
This just feels gross!
No!
You sure are hanging in there, silly Shera!
Nii-san...
I hate you, Nii-san!
I know.
Don't irritate me too much, now.
You'll make me want to kill
you before I create my heir.
I'd rather die than let you do this to me!
I wonder how long you can
keep up that tough act.
No!
Help me...
Help me!
You're so annoying.
Fine, then. I'll overwrite you.
To make you want to offer
your entirety up to me!
Help me, Diablo!
Sorry I kept you waiting, Shera.
Diablo!
My, my. What's the meaning of barging
into a prince's camp while he's busy
attending to official duties?
You call this an official duty?
I can't believe you're such scum.
Even royalty can't get away with that!
It's just a bit of entertainment.
It's better when it's exciting, right?
For both the man and the woman.
I knew it. I was wrong.
I should have kept Shera from
going with you back then,
even if it meant turning the
city into a sea of flames.
Sorry I was late.
Diablo...
You really... really came for me.
Shera!
Shera-sama!
Tsk.
Look at you, pretending to be friends.
How did my guards fail to notice intruders?
What are they doing?!
You didn't hear all the noise outside?
What is this?!
What's going on?!
What happened to my guards?!
Keera-sama...
Quit screwing around!
Do you know what you've done?!
This is an international issue!
Do you want a war?!
I only came here to confirm one thing.
Whether or not Shera truly wanted to go home.
You manipulated Shera
with your vile methods.
Your proof!
Where's your proof?!
I don't need any proof.
I just need to ask Shera how
she truly feels one more time.
Hey, Shera! Tell him!
What is it that you need to do?!
I have to return to Greenwood.
Shera?!
Greenwood is my home,
so I need to stop using my time like
this and use it for my homeland.
Please get a hold of yourself!
Hear her? You satisfied now, Demon?!
So what about it?
Huh?
Shera!
As the owner of your Enslavement Collar,
I command you!
Express your true feelings as
they exist, unbound by any magic!
Shera?!
Shera-sama?!
Hey, Shera!
Don't be swayed by him!
Overwrite! Overwrite! Overwrite!
Shera-sama! Don't give in!
Tell us the real truth, Shera!
You belong to me, Shera!
Shera,
tell me...
how you really feel.
I...
I want to be free!
I want to be with Diablo
and Rem forever and ever!
My friends are what's most precious to me!
You deserve to face judgment, Keera.
Tsk!
Useless, useless, useless!
Everyone and everything keeps
pissing me the hell off!
None of this is any fun!
You're a damn commoner acting pretentious!
Nii-san! That Summon's dangerous!
You're all sentenced to death!
The secret art of the Elves
will destroy this entire world!
If there's nothing for me to enjoy in
this world, then it can just perish!
Very well.
If you dare to challenge me,
then I'll give you your just reward.
Come forth, Force Hydra!
It's huge!
No way!
Run, Diablo!
You can't beat that Summon!
It's the Elven nation's trump card!
It's too late! Now, regret your actions!
Die, Demon!
What the hell are you?!
Pay for your many mistakes with your death!
No!
Keera-sama!
It's not good for us if you
decide to spare him on your own.
Episode Eight
Hero's Charge