Simply wonderful!
Just as one would expect from a Summon
whose use is forbidden because
it will destroy the world!
Cross Reverie never had
a Summon like this...
Run, Diablo!
That Summon has been in the royal family
for generations! It's a guardian deity!
You'll never defeat it!
How interesting.
All of you, stand back.
I'm going to crush that thing!
Episode Eight
Hero's Charge
Get him, Force Hydra!
Kill him!
Well, you don't have any control
over it at all, do you?
Neither this powerful Summon
nor the flute that manipulated
Shera were in the game.
It's possible that every planned element of
Cross Reverie is already part of this world.
That's an exciting thought!
That's...
You idiot!
There's no way you can win!
Just disappear, you Demon!
Looks like his confidence
in this Summon is absolute.
Heaven's Fall!
It's weaker than I thought.
It should go down in
another four or five shots.
Regeneration?!
That's way too fast! Is this a bug?!
Diablo!
That's it, Force Hydra!
Did you see that, Demon?!
Dragon's Breath is a purely
elemental attack.
Magic Reflection and physical damage
reduction won't activate against it.
What worries me is its skills.
Summons are supposed to be
limited to a single skill.
Yet this one seems to have two skills?
Ice, Sand, Wind, and Fire?!
That's too many attack skills!
Are you saying this world is
nothing more than another world
that just resembles Cross Reverie?!
Yes, yes! This is my power!
I don't need anyone who'll get
in my way or drag me down!
There must be something...
What's its weakness?
Diablo!
I've heard that the Force Hydra possesses
a core somewhere in its body,
and destroying that returns it to its crystal!
So that's what it is?
How does an idiot like you know about that?
Still, its core moves
around within its body.
It won't be that easy for you to find!
Moving weak points are classic.
What?
I never planned to search for it at all!
Matoi Izuna!
Wh-What is this?!
I don't understand!
Way to go, Diablo!
I can't believe you beat
a Summon that powerful.
What the hell are you?!
I am Diablo.
A chaotic Demon Lord from another
world that no one can control.
Don't be ridiculous!
There's no way you're a Demon Lord!
You need to be punished.
Pay for your many mistakes with your death!
I'll end this in an instant.
Burst, Explos—
Wait! Spare him!
Shera?!
You're not still under his control, are you?
No, I'm not.
I still hate Nii-san.
I loathe him.
But he's still family.
We still laughed together.
Tch!
Are you sure, Shera?
Yes. Thank you, Diablo.
And sorry.
It's not good for us if you
just decide to spare him.
Shera...
Keera-sama!
Galford?
What do you think you're doing?
How dare you?!
This is war.
The war started the moment that Elf prince
sent his troops into another
nation's territory.
He has no right to complain
about being killed.
Exterminate the Elven troops
scattered in the forest!
Capture the princess!
You may eliminate any who interfere!
Were you planning to do this all along?!
Were you plotting to make me fight the Elves
so you would have a justification
for seizing Greenwood?!
If you intend to interfere,
I'll need to eliminate you, too.
What's this?!
This is a spell I don't know.
It's been nothing but
things like this all day!
It's Ritual Magic designed
to capture large monsters.
Even you won't be able to escape that easily.
Galford,
what is the meaning of this?
Please explain yourself.
I'm performing my duties as Lord of Faltra.
I'm crushing invaders and
protecting the people.
But you're going to kill
people who surrendered!
Am I?
It certainly doesn't look
like they've surrendered.
Do you, a lone Imperial Knight,
mean to question my military judgment?
I'm going to stop you.
How do you plan to stop me
when your sword has no blade?
What just happened?
He's fast!
Those movements were on a
completely different level
from other soldiers and adventurers!
He's surpassed Human limits!
He's definitely above level 100!
You can return to the imperial
capital and give your report.
But I believe His Majesty will
listen to the stronger person.
At this rate, it won't just be Shera.
Rem and Alicia are in danger, too.
Feel it. Sense the flow of magic power...
Don't panic.
This is nothing compared
to the Enslavement Collars.
Where's the magic power centered?
Begin the operation.
Capture the princess and
eliminate those who interfere!
Yes, sir!
I see it now!
That's the center of the magic power!
Hurry!
I'm surprised.
You unraveled the barrier?
Diablo...
Stand back.
I suppose I should have dealt with you first.
You were planning an Invasion after
I wore myself down fighting the Elves
right from the start, weren't you?
That's called strategy.
Though I doubt an adventurer
would understand.
Hmph. I don't want to understand it.
Insults from an opponent
are praise to a soldier.
I'll make you face such despair that
you won't even be able to insult me!
Explosion!
I need distance!
This guy...
He has the basic idea of never giving
a Sorcerer an opening down pat!
It looks like you're considerably worn down.
Your movements are rather slow for a Sorcerer
who turned back an army
of Fallen, aren't they?
Hmph. I just can't get motivated
because you're too weak!
What?!
There's nothing wasted.
But that only makes your movements
easier to read, Galford.
So you laid a trap for me?
Super Mine.
It's a spell planted in the ground that
explodes when one passes over it.
It's been thirty years since
anyone wounded me, Diablo.
Is that so?
The fact that you've never faced
better opponents is why you'll lose.
He made the call to keep me from
reading his path. That's impressive.
However!
The steps used to close in on a Sorcerer,
the spells used to prevent that...
He has no idea
how much time I've poured
into researching those alone!
That's the world I've come from, Galford!
The man standing before you is one
who's buried countless challengers,
the Demon Lord Diablo!
A slight opening!
Freeze Zone!
It's over, Galford!
What?!
Oh, no! I can't move because of my skill's recoil!
He created an opening on purpose
to draw a big move out of me!
You're not bad, Galford!
Omit.
Lightning Bullet.
That was close...
I didn't think Galford was capable of
using absolute defense Martial Arts
that offer a perfect
defense against attacks.
That last skill he used was Heat Sonic,
which is learned at level 120.
He's the most powerful opponent I've
faced since coming to this world.
So where's the killing blow?
I'm still alive here.
Is this old guy serious?
If he thinks it was a close match,
he might come after me again.
I don't want him getting fixated on me.
I guess I should intimidate him a bit.
You're so weak, I've lost interest!
Know that someone like you
will never be a match for me!
So you won't kill me?
It looked like you risked it all to strike
while I was frozen after a huge move.
Too bad it didn't work.
If I were a normal opponent,
you might have won.
But if you're too weak to realize that
I factored that pause into my distance,
then you're no threat to
me even if left alive.
I could still give a report
to His Royal Majesty
that would be disadvantageous to you.
Huh?
I will not allow that to happen!
Galford-sama, I'll report that you took
action with the intent of destroying
our peace with the surrounding nations.
I still think killing me would
be much more certain.
Enough!
If you want to die, do it on your own.
If you want to challenge me again,
I'll take you on at any time.
But if you move against me
or my possessions again,
know that I'll reduce both
you and your land to ashes!
All units, withdraw!
I can't believe you beat Galford.
You really are incredible.
Of course.
So, um, do you have any
spare healing potions?
Are you injured?
No, it's not for me.
I wanted to use them on the wounded Elves.
Oh. Here.
You really are kind.
Fool!
Keep spouting nonsense, and I'll
blast away this whole forest!
I can't let the forest be wiped out,
so I'll go heal the Elves.
Jeez.
Diablo...
Please take care of Shera.
It had to happen, right?
I don't understand international
matters that well,
but Nii-san did something bad, after all.
I hated Nii-san, but...
But...
I never thought we would part like this.
Three days have passed since we stopped
the war between the Elves and Faltra.
Time passes on as usual
for everyone in the city,
unaware that such danger
had drawn close to them.
Shera was silent for a long while,
but thanks to Rem, she's slowly
regaining her energy.
Shortly after that was over,
Alicia headed to the imperial
capital to report the events
to the emperor.
As for Greenwood,
Celsior is taking the initiative
to explain matters.
As for me...
I'm as unmotivated as ever.
When my Magic Points are near zero,
I can't find the drive to do anything.
It would be fine if I were just
unmotivated, but we're broke, too.
Damn that Galford...
I know we cleared the quest
to prevent war with the Elves,
but since he was our client,
and I beat him up,
our reward was left unsettled.
I'll kill that Galford!
Yes?
Good afternoon, Diablo-san.
Sylvie?
I heard you weren't feeling well,
so I brought you something nice.
An MP Potion?
Well, something similar.
It's an alcoholic spirit that has the
side effect of recovering Magic Points.
Such a thing exists?
It's not very effective,
so you can get it for cheap.
Above all, it tastes better than potions!
Well, care for a drink?
Cheers!
Yeah.
Alcohol...
Alcohol, huh?
I'm not that big a drinker...
Not drinking any?
Oh, uh...
Well...
I guess Diablo's body is sturdy,
and there wasn't any "Drunk"
status effect in Cross Reverie...
So it should be fine.
Diablo-san, you must hold
your liquor really well!
Of 'ourse I do.
'Ourse?
This's nothin'.
I'm a Demon Lord, af'er all!
Diablo... san?
Oh, a hug pfhillow, huh?
This'un's made with th' nices' fabric...
Diablo-san?!
This is... not something I should be doing...
This'd be worth goin' into debt for.
Hey, stop!
Sumthin's pokin' me, though...
Y-You can't take that off!
If you go any further than this, I'll be mad!
Mmm, so smooth.
How did this happen?
No!
Not there!
Don't do that there!
That's...
Jeez, Diablo-san...
You'd better take responsibility for this...
Diablo-san?
Jeez! At least let go of me
before you fall asleep!
Rem-san and Shera-chan are
going to come back to this!
Give me my clothes back!
Come on!
I sense the Demon Lord's soul.
That man...
That's man's true power...
You really can tell how much someone's
worth by the color of their innards.
Episode Nine
Holy Knight Tale