Help me!
Somebody help me!
How awful...
How can the mortal races be this awful?
The mortal races should just be wiped out.
So beautiful...
Everyone worshiping the Demon Lord
in this village has found salvation.
What a beautiful sight.
You truly can tell how much a person's
worth by the color of their innards.
Episode Nine
Holy Knight Tale
Imperial Capital Sevenwall
Castle Grandiose
Alicia-sama?
You have returned?
Yes. It's good to see you again.
I see you're as busy as ever,
but please don't push yourself too hard.
It's an Imperial Knight's duty to
devote themselves to the people.
P-Pardon me, then!
My, if it isn't Cristela-dono.
Have you finished reporting to
His Majesty about the Greenwood incident?
Yes, without issue.
Though it's hard to predict what will
come of the Kingdom of Greenwood,
His Majesty told me that matter is now closed.
That's good to hear.
Peace is best.
How about you, Saddler-sama?
I heard that you were headed
to a village in the south.
Every last one of the
villagers found salvation.
Saddler-sama...
Do you hate the mortal races?
Heavens, no!
I love them.
They're the descendants of
those blessed by the Gods.
Which is precisely why
I cannot forgive those who
worship the Demon Lord.
Pardon me.
Will you be heading back to Faltra?
There are still a few
matters I must attend to.
Actually, I'll be heading to Faltra, as well.
The Head Priest, Lumachina-sama,
revealed a prophecy.
A prophecy?
Yes. "There are omens of the Demon
Lord's revival in the western city."
I'm heading off to investigate
that, as a Paladin.
Signs of the Demon Lord's revival?
Look, look! I summoned it!
Of course you did. You have me teaching you.
It's so cute!
This is a Turkey Shot.
To be blunt, it's not a strong Summon.
Huh? It's not?
Its special ability is Synchro Sight.
It's a power that allows you to
see everything the Summon sees.
That's useful!
Using it consumes magic power,
so you can't use it very long.
It might be useful when you're lost, but...
That's lame.
There are all kinds of Summons,
but ultimately, the ones that are tough and
have powerful attacks are the strongest.
I see.
Well, how about it?
There isn't much need to perform the
Enslavement Ritual with this one, but...
Since I summoned it, I'll forge the pact.
What's that?
I don't know, but it's necessary.
It's a magic stone needed to forge
the pact in the Enslavement Ritual.
I'll give you one, too, Diablo.
These weren't in Cross Reverie.
I command you in the name
of Shera L. Greenwood...
Answer my call, become mine, and obey me.
I did it!
I'm glad the magic wasn't reflected.
I don't want to be enslaved to a Turkey Shot!
About that Turkey Shot...
It might actually be an
interesting match for you.
Huh?
There!
Well?
Can you see where the coin fell?
No...
Now, try sending your Summon out.
Uh, Turkey Shot, go find the coin.
Incredible!
I feel like I'm the one flying!
There it is!
Now shoot an arrow at it.
Sure!
I hit it!
Incredible!
As you can see, depending on how you use it,
you'll be able to shoot enemies in
locations you can't see yourself.
I never knew it could be used like that.
That's impressive, Diablo!
I just saw that on a guide site a while ago...
Thanks, Diablo!
I thought I'd gotten stuck with a bad draw,
but now I really like it!
What's the matter?
It's not coming from the bird...
Shera?
Why don't you take a bath?
What do you mean?!
Well, you think so too, right, Diablo?
That Rem smells!
Huh?! What?!
If you don't cut it out,
I'm going to get angry!
Oh, in that case...
Let's all bathe together!
B-By "bathing"... you meant without swimsuits?!
What's a "swimsuit"?
For real?!
It's only natural to take off
your clothes when bathing.
Even if you can see someone's body,
it's proper manners not to look.
Come on, Diablo, hurry up
and take yours off, too!
I don't care for this bathing activity of yours.
You two should get rid of
the smell by yourselves.
I don't smell!
I can't believe you.
You really are a thoughtless person.
Pantherians' sweat doesn't smell, you know.
Really?
It doesn't smell, and it's not salty, either!
What are you doing?!
Lick, lick, lick!
Hey... No! Stop!
You're right. It isn't salty.
I told you it wasn't!
Want to try licking my sweat?
I'm not into that!
Then I'll lick it.
Stop that, you fat elf!
That's not fat!
Their jiggling is annoying!
You're not allowed to pinch the tips!
Hey! Where are you licking me?!
I want to turn around!
I'm not brave enough to stare,
but I want to burn this scene into my eyes
and save it in my heart's
important documents folder!
Maybe...
Just a little peek...
I'm sorry!
Are you a Fallen?!
R-Rem?
You're Edelgard!
She still hasn't learned her lesson?
What have you come here for?!
I won't fight today.
I've come to talk.
Rem!
Talk?
A certain person informed me.
And now that I've touched her, I'm certain.
I sense the Demon Lord's soul.
She's able to sense Demon Lord
Krebskulm within Rem?
What?
Rem, what's she talking about?
I don't like being the
only one kept in the dark.
Please?
The...
The soul of Demon Lord Krebskulm
is sealed inside me.
Huh?
So that's what was going on.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you about it.
But I didn't want to make you bear
the weight of this secret, as well.
Shera?
I may be weak...
But I want to help you
when you're in trouble!
We're friends, after all!
It must have been tough
for you all this time.
I'm sorry I didn't realize it.
Thank you... so much.
You want to defeat the Demon Lord.
Is that true?
It's true.
Hmm...
I have a question for you, as well.
I always thought I would be
killed if a Fallen found out
where the Demon Lord's soul was...
The Demon Lord is... delicate?
You can't just break the vessel.
There's more missing.
So I won't kill you.
Do you know of a way to completely
revive the Demon Lord?
I do.
Oh?
The resurrection ritual
poses no risk to her life.
I won't kill her.
It's more like... she will be treasured
as the mother of the Demon Lord.
You don't believe what I've said.
Then I'll teach you the ritual.
You do it, and we Fallen won't touch you.
How's that?
Rem wants to release the seal
on the Demon Lord Krebskulm
and settle matters for good.
It's bad luck that Edelgard discovered us,
but our interests are the same as far as
wanting the Demon Lord's soul out of Rem.
The question is whether or not
I can beat Krebskulm afterward.
Diablo?
Hmph. Very well.
Teach me this ritual.
I'll help you revive this Demon Lord.
Then I'll turn around and pulverize
that Demon Lord impostor!
The Demon Lord is the real thing.
That would be impossible for you.
Have you forgotten my power?
I'll be waiting for you three days from now,
on the night of the full moon,
at Starfall Tower.
We'll conduct the ritual there.
Very well.
We've come to terms, Rem.
Now we'll be able to change
this cursed fate of yours.
Three days from now,
I'll settle things for you.
Are you really going tonight?
Alicia-san!
Everyone, I have just returned
from the imperial capital.
I'm glad to see you had a safe journey.
How did you know we'd be here?
We only entered this shop by chance.
Diablo-sama...
Please return to the inn at once.
Huh?
What's the meaning of this, Alicia?
Did something happen at the imperial capital?
A Paladin, Saddler, is here
in this town right now.
Is that person dangerous?
I believe his level as a Knight is over 100.
Oh?
If he's over 100, then he's
on par with Galford or better.
Paladins never came after
me for a battle in the game,
so I don't know their stats.
Also...
If Saddler believes that you
might be Demon Lord worshipers,
he'll put you through awful torture.
Torture?
Yes.
He'll drag it out until you confess
to worshiping the Demon Lord.
Forget worshiper... I've proclaimed
myself an actual Demon Lord!
We'll probably be on super bad terms!
So I'd like to have you all remain
indoors as much as possible
until Saddler leaves town.
Shutting myself in is my forte!
Still, I doubt Diablo would
lose to that Paladin.
Of course, I'm well aware
of Diablo-sama's abilities.
However, that man...
That man's true power is...
I've been looking for you, Cristela-dono.
I was wondering where you had gone off to.
I wanted to say hello to several
adventurers I worked with before.
Is that so?
Nice to meet you.
I'm Saddler, a Paladin of the
imperial capital's Orthodox Church.
Who might you be?
We have an important mission tonight.
We don't have time to
provoke him into a fight.
I need to act normal and keep
from saying anything I shouldn't.
I am Diablo, a Demon Lord from another world!
I acted too normal!
I've heard there were many funny
people among the rural adventurers,
but a Demon Lord?
That is priceless!
Diablo-sama truly loves to jest.
Even if it is a joke,
the fact that you're being friendly with
someone calling himself a Demon Lord
is a problem I can't overlook.
These are adventurers who helped me.
There's nothing about them to be ashamed of.
You say they have nothing to hide?
Are you planning to torture me?
I don't know.
This makes no sense.
Do you have a problem with us
seeing Alicia Cristela-dono?
Know your place, slave.
I am no slave!
If you're too rude,
you'll face divine judgment.
You should be apologizing
for your rudeness yourself.
Alicia-dono's...
Rem?
Rem?!
Rem-sama!
Rem!
That was the work of the Gods.
It's a power the Gods granted
me because of my faith.
Rem! Hang in there, Rem!
What's this? What's going on?
There were no works of the Gods in the game!
What am I supposed to do?!
No...
That thing wrapped around Rem...
That's...
magic power?!
That's quite the stupid stunt
you've pulled, small fry!
Small fry?
You call this divine punishment?
It's just a simple spell!
Rem!
Rem-sama?!
You, a mere Demon, would insult a Paladin?
Rem-sama! Please hang in there!
Alicia-san...
Thank goodness.
You question the power of the Gods?
Then you can pay through
divine punishment, as well.
You're still claiming that?
Stupid magic like that won't work on me.
You foolish unbeliever!
You can repent as a stone!
Wh-What?!
Hmph. Cement Lock, huh?
That's a negative status Earth spell.
This is Magic Reflection?
It truly was a spell, then.
Most likely, it was cast using Subtle Chant.
It's a skill you can learn
after reaching level 60 as a Sorcerer.
It lets you use magic without
speaking the spell's name.
Will the Petrification wear off?
It depends on the caster's level,
but eventually the magic power
will dissipate, and he'll be free.
Are you all right, Rem?
Yes.
You saved me again, though.
Are you truly sure it was
okay to let Saddler go?
Are you saying it would
have been better to kill him?
Huh? Seriously?
I have no interest in whether
small fry live or die.
If he challenges me again,
I won't show mercy on him.
You're right.
I guess I was worried over nothing.
It's almost time.
Yes.
Let's go to Starfall Tower.
What's the matter?
Maybe we ought to tell her.
Tell Alicia?
I think that's okay.
Alicia-san's a nice person,
so I'm sure she'll understand.
I'm against it.
Alicia is an Imperial Knight.
Given her position, she wouldn't
overlook the Demon Lord's revival.
I understand that, but...
Even so, I want to trust Alicia-san.
She's my friend now, just like you and Shera.
I see...
You must have suffered a long time.
It must have been hard
for you confess this to me.
I'll help you as much as I can.
So there's no need to bear
this burden all by yourself.
We're friends, after all.
Thank you, Alicia-san.
This feels kind of cheap.
Something's not right.
What is this uneasy feeling in my chest?
No, no!
My poor communication skills
and lack of friends
just make it seem that way
to me, that's all. Yeah.
The Demon Lord's resurrection
is nigh.
Are you the ones who woke
me from my slumber?
That's the Demon Lord?
This incomplete Demon Lord must perish!
Episode Ten
The Demon Lord's Resurrection
Please save me from this fate.