You're finally here.
Were you waiting long?
Not really.
This brings back memories.
It's where I was summoned.
I've already drawn the magic circle.
Preparations for the ritual are done.
Oh, this is Alicia.
I've allowed her to accompany
us for certain reasons,
but she won't interfere.
That's surprising.
I thought she'd be more opposed.
Is this ritual meant to fill
Krebskulm's soul with magic power?
Yes.
You'll pour strong magic power
into the Demon Lord's soul.
That should hasten her resurrection, I think.
Diablo,
I can't trust the Fallen.
Do you want to call this off?
No.
I want to defeat Krebskulm.
I believe in you, Diablo.
Please...
Save me from this fate.
Today is the day I fulfill
my promise to you, Rem!
Episode Ten
Demon Lord's Resurrection
Let's begin the ritual right away.
You'll pour your magic power into the soul
of the Demon Lord in her stomach.
That will resurrect the Demon Lord.
I never imagined there would come a day
when I entered a magic
circle drawn by a Fallen
to pour magic power into the Demon Lord.
Here I go.
Yes. Please start.
I see it!
So this is Krebskulm's magic power!
It's hot!
Diablo is... pouring into me!
Well?
You're not even close.
The Demon Lord is even deeper in.
You're not reaching her.
What?!
Make a hole in her stomach,
and do it from much closer.
If you do that, Rem will die!
There is a hole.
What?
Where?!
Here.
Huh?
Insert your fingers into that hole.
My fingers?!
No, no!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Hold on! That's not okay!
That is really not okay!
My mind isn't ready for that!
I mean, of course, I've steeled
myself for saving Rem.
But—really?!
Aren't there all kinds of
issues with that visual?!
All right.
What?!
Please do it...
If that's what it takes.
I'm not sure I understand,
but hang in there!
She's telling me to do it?!
Please save me, Diablo!
Diablo!
Diablo's entering me!
Focus!
I'm still a long way away from Krebskulm!
She's deeper inside!
I see it!
What incredible intensity...
There's no mistake.
This is the magic power
of Demon Lord Krebskulm!
Here I go!
Take my magic power inside you!
Please, Diablo!
The Demon Lord is reborn!
This is bad!
We can't let this thing be reborn!
Are you all right?
Hang in there!
Diablo...
Please win.
Of course I will!
And you have a responsibility
to bear witness to it!
So you're not allowed to die!
Incredible!
This...
This is the Demon Lord!
Huh?
Where's Krebskulm?
Are you the ones who woke
me from my slumber?
Demon Lord!
The Demon Lord?! That's her?!
That's Krebskulm?!
Who are you?
I am Edelgard.
I'm overjoyed by your resurrection!
I see, I see.
You should indeed commend
me on my resurrection!
Hey, are you really the Demon Lord Krebskulm?
Indeed.
I see.
You're not quite what I expected,
but that matters not.
My name is Diablo!
I am the Demon Lord from another world
and the one who shall bury you!
I see. So you're the one who woke me?
Good, good. As your reward,
I'll teach you what fear is!
I'll kill you in the most
brutal way possible!
Yes! The most...
Uh, I know there's supposed
to be a really brutal way...
What was it?
Huh?
Hey, you're kidding, right?!
Has she forgotten how to fight?
Argh, forget it!
I'll just burn everything to ash!
That's what a Demon Lord would do, right?
You can't do that!
I can't?
Huh?
Demon Lord!
You're listening to what these mortals say?!
That's wrong!
But if they say I can't, doesn't it mean I can't?
What's going on here?
Is she missing some of her
memories or something?
The Demon Lord is the one who
destroys the mortal races!
Is that not true?!
Yes, I believe that sounds right.
Wait a minute!
Why do you?
I've always thought it was strange.
Why does the Demon Lord
kill the mortal races?
I feel like there was some kind
of reason for it, but.. um...
If you're not doing it of your own volition,
then please don't kill anymore!
I'm asking you, too!
Killing isn't good!
Well...
I can't remember why I'd
kill them, so why not?
Okay, I won't kill them.
Seriously?!
Are you serious?!
You say the Demon Lord won't
kill the mortal races?!
Killing the mortal races won't
fill my stomach, anyway.
Edelgard!
Is this okay with you?!
The Demon Lord is all that matters to me.
If that's what the Demon Lord wants,
I'm fine with it.
More importantly, your Demon Lord is hungry!
Oh, I brought snacks.
Here.
What are these?
They're biscuits.
It's good!
I have more if you'd like.
These are so good!
I've never eaten anything this good before!
Thanks to these, I've remembered my mission!
To devour all the biscuits in this world!
That is the reason I have
been reborn into this world!
Like hell it is!
Hey, are there no more biscuits?
My name's Shera.
Sorry, but there won't be any more
until we return to the city.
Very well!
Then lead the way!
What?! You're going into the city?
You, the Demon Lord?!
Diablo, I can walk on my own now.
Please let me down.
You haven't regained your strength yet.
I refuse to slow down to match your pace.
I see.
Are you really able to accept this?
It's not easy to accept, no.
How many biscuits are there in the city?
Myself, my mother, my grandmother...
If you go into a store, there are lots!
We all suffered due to that Demon Lord,
More than you can eat!
Is that true?!
and spent our lives hoping
to defeat Krebskulm.
Can I truly eat them all?!
It's just...
There's no need to fight her if she
isn't going to kill the mortal races.
Assuming that's really true, anyway.
Diablo-sama! Above us!
Hmm? Above?
What's that?
Huh?
Demon Lord, congratulations
on your resurrection.
Who are you?
I am Eulerex, the one who has served
the Demon Lords for generations.
Eulerex?
He was in Cross Reverie, too.
Eulerex has been alive since the
Demon Lord before the previous one.
He's the oldest and strongest among us.
I have long awaited the
resurrection of our Demon Lord.
Allow me to offer a sacrifice to
celebrate this auspicious day.
Auspicious?
Yes.
I would like to slaughter all the mortals
being kept alive here in your presence,
and offer their lives in
celebration of your resurrection.
You can't!
If you kill the mortals,
I won't be able to eat biscuits!
Edelgard, the Demon Lord seems
opposed to killing the mortal races.
What is the meaning of this?
I don't understand, either.
The Demon Lord is the
ruler of all dark beings!
And dark beings kill the mortal races!
Which means...
I believe our incomplete Demon Lord
needs to reincarnate again!
Edelgard?!
You act on your own!
Nothing is more important
than our Demon Lord's will!
Even Fallen have a purpose in this world.
So I must correct this
incomplete resurrection
of our Demon Lord!
Alicia!
Protect the girls!
Diablo!
I don't intend to get too close,
but they said he's the strongest Fallen.
Don't worry. I'll end this quickly.
Foolish Edelgard.
Do you think a weakling like you can beat me?
It's not right
for Fallen to turn on the Demon Lord!
A Demon Lord's soul is limited.
So long as this Krebskulm exists,
the true Krebskulm cannot be resurrected!
Your foolish actions
have brought about this incomplete
resurrection of our Demon Lord!
You dodged that?
A mere Demon dares stand before a Fallen?
Hmph!
You may have lived a long life,
but it seems you're missing
some important information!
I am Diablo!
You are the fool who dares
stand before a true Demon Lord!
What?
Just kidding.
There's no way he could know.
I'm just a player, after all!
Flare Burst!
Yes!
Curse you!
Super Mine!
This guy's fast!
Quartz Lance!
Come!
Could that be...
Magic Reflection?
Oh? You figured out my
power on the first shot?
It can't be!
Magic Reflection was the unique power
of the Demon Lord of the Mind, Enkvaros.
Why do you...
Because I was the first person to
defeat Enkvaros in the game.
I received this ring as a
reward for doing that.
It looks like living through
two generations of Demon Lords
has left him with lots of knowledge.
Hmph. Haven't you realized it yet?
No matter how much you struggle,
there's no chance you'll win.
The incomplete Demon Lord must die!
Look out!
Lightning Bullet!
You tried to protect a Demon Lord?
Rem, are you all right?
Rem-sama!
No, I...
Good work!
You have my praise!
No, no.
At a time like this, you say, "Thank you."
Shera...
I see.
Thank you, then!
What immense magic power.
You're no ordinary mortal.
I told you, I'm the Demon Lord.
Have you gone senile on
top of being so ignorant?
It's inconceivable...
Yet your strength is abnormal.
I don't understand.
Are you sure it was wise to let him go?
I've lost interest.
I don't care about those who run from me.
I could pursue him,
but if he used some area of effect
attack that wasn't magical,
I wouldn't be able to
protect this many people.
I'd rather avoid putting everyone in danger.
That delayed us far too long.
Let's make haste home.
The Bridge of Ulug should
soon be coming into view.
Right!
Demon Lord...
If we're going to the Human city,
I can't get near it.
I'll wait in the forest.
Please call on me at any time.
Fine.
Good work.
Thank you.
It is my humble pleasure.
Um, about Krebskulm-sama...
I believe we'll face several problems if
we use her name within the city, won't we?
True, it could cause unwanted chaos.
I am the Demon Lord,
but how you refer to me is a trivial
matter when biscuits are at stake.
I'll permit something else.
In that case...
Oh, how about Klem-chan?
Are you okay?
What's the matter with him?
When Diablo uses his magic,
he gets tired and loses his energy.
Oh, yes. I've heard the mortal races
get worn out when using magic power.
You don't, Klem-chan?
Because I'm a Demon Lord!
Infinite magic power constantly
wells up from deep within me!
That's cheating.
What happened to Rem and Alicia?
Everyone couldn't sleep in here,
so they're both sleeping
in Alicia-san's room.
I see.
Shera, you...
Rem's not here,
so I thought I'd help you get active again.
Wha... Wait! Hey!
You mortals are interesting.
That's how you give each other magic power?
Would you like to try too, Klem-chan?
Doing this helps you get active, too!
What?!
Even the one granting it gains energy?!
Let me see.
Hmm... Like this?
Uh-huh!
When you press against him
like that, he gets active!
You're right!
This is fun for me, too!
What is happening right now?!
This is bad!
It's shocking me!
Klem's pouring a ton of magic power into me!
What's the matter?
Do you like this?
Diablo, how is it?
Are you feeling active?
Damn it! Damn it!
I want to ogle them!
Just how different would my life have been
if I could just act confident
in situations like this?!
This is kind of amazing!
Something's coming from deep within me!
It feels like it does when his
magic power's pouring into me!
My Magic Points are fully recovered.
The Demon Lord's incredible.
My, metal on a woman's face?
That's shameful. Take them off.
I saw you had books that were
inappropriate to your education.
So I threw them out.
It's for your own good.
When an emergency arises,
protect Humans first.
Demihumans can come afterward.
Sometimes sacrifices are necessary
for the prosperity of the nation.
Do you understand?
Alicia!
I need the Demon Lord to fulfill
the Demon Lord's duty.
She must rid this world
of the mortal races
in order to create a beautiful world.
Are you all right, Saddler-sama?
How are you feeling?
Obviously not good.
I feel awful.
The Gods would never enjoy the
existence of an insolent man
who doesn't believe in my power.
I'll never forgive
those damn demihumans!
You're saying the Demon Lord has revived?!
The ugly mortal races will perish.
Episode Eleven
The Young Girl Awakens
I'm sorry, Klem.