B is for Big surprise!
S is for Superb!
What is that?
The biscuit song!
C is for Cake!
That has nothing to do with biscuits...
T is for biscuiT!
Now, let's sing together!
Sing it with us!
Uh...
B is for Biscuit!
S is for Superb!
C is for Cake...
T is for biscuiT!
Now, let's sing together!
Episode Eleven
The Young Girl Awakens
So good!
These biscuits are so good!
Yum!
This muddy water's bitter!
Then have some of this.
It's cocoa.
Let's see...
This muddy water's sweet!
You've heard what's going on, right?
She's lost her memories,
but Klem is the Demon Lord.
So what do you think?
A Demon Lord who loves biscuits
and won't kill the mortal races
isn't the Demon Lord we all fear.
Oh?
I just heard about her and wanted
to see what she was like, that's all.
I'll just watch and wait for now.
You did well, Rem-san.
No...
I caused you a lot of worry, too.
That was very good!
We shall come again!
I'm glad Celes-san understood.
Klem-chan isn't that dangerous, after all.
Yeah.
Given that Celes is the cornerstone
of the barrier protecting Faltra,
she can never leave this city.
So maybe she didn't want anyone else
to lose their freedom without reason
and go through an experience
similar to her own.
Hear that, Rem?
Huh?
They were all just here.
Alicia-san, where are we going?
We left Diablo and Shera behind.
To be honest,
I was just planning to bring Klem-sama,
and then bring Shera-sama later.
But that's all right.
I can't be sure what might
serve as the key, anyway.
Key?
They're not back here...
I'll go look for them.
You wait here so we don't
miss them if they come back.
Okay.
What is this odd stirring in my chest?
Why are you missing your memories, Klem-sama?
Where's all this coming from?
One of the Fallen priests said it
takes more than just magic power
to resurrect a Demon Lord.
A Fallen did?
So what can we do restore the Demon Lord's
memories and completely awaken her?
Hold on a moment!
Alicia-san, are you saying you
want the Demon Lord to resurrect
and kill the mortal races?
Did I not just say that?
What's gotten into you?
Nothing.
I'm the same as I've always been.
It's just that...
I no longer need to pretend
we're all friends.
What are you saying?
I have resurrected.
I'm perfect, complete, and whole right now.
But you won't kill the mortal races, right?
Enough! Do you want me to burn you up?!
Yes!
If that will awaken you, Demon Lord!
Being the first to be burned to death
would be an utmost blessing if that meant
ridding this rotten world of the ugly
mortal races and making it beautiful!
No...
So "that woman" Galluk
mentioned back then...
Figures what that woman said was right.
That woman?
It was me.
I'm the one who encouraged that man
and handed him Gregore-sama
disguised as a sword.
He was such a pathetic man, too.
A truly ugly being,
teeming with envy and hatred,
just like the mortal races themselves.
So there you are.
I've been looking for you
for some time, Cristela-dono.
You're...
My apologies.
I was a bit held up...
by these Demon Lord worshipers.
You're the Demon Lord worshiper here!
Goodness, no!
My undercover investigation has revealed
that you all are Demon Lord worshipers,
so I just secured this young child that
you all brought from who knows where!
That's the story you're running with?
So you are all Demon Lord
worshipers, just as I suspected.
I see you're not a rock anymore.
That did surprise me.
I had never known such disgrace.
To think anyone would do
something so insolent
to me, one with power granted by the Gods.
He'll need to be punished.
Come forth, Asulau!
Asulau! Please, break through them!
Be my shield.
Why do you obey orders that
could get you killed?!
We only live because the Gods deem it proper.
Death simply means the Gods
have invited us to Heaven.
But above all, protecting me is
equivalent to protecting a God.
Cowards who would refuse
to obey my orders out of fear
could never become squires.
Now, bow down before the power of God,
you infidel who worships the Demon Lord!
H-Hey...
Hatred is what she needs.
Damn it!
I have a bad feeling about this!
Don't tell me that nagging
feeling I had was because...
You!
Hey, you!
Are you okay?
Klem! You're all right?!
Where are we?
Good grief!
You're pathetic, losing to someone like that.
Here.
Eat this.
Thank you.
It seems you've suffered because of me.
Alicia was talking about it.
She said you went through
many hardships because of me.
That your mother, and her mother,
all the way back...
That's...
But you tried to save me.
You did the same thing with Eulerex, too.
The loyalty you've shown me
is worthy of great praise.
It wasn't loyalty.
I don't understand it, either.
Why?
I thought I always hated
the Demon Lord Krebskulm.
I gave up many things,
kept my distance from others,
and lived my life in fear and isolation.
So then why,
when my enemy is right here before my eyes,
can't I bring myself to want you gone?
Because of me, you were never free.
It's only natural that you'd hate me.
Having no freedom is painful.
You were sealed and all alone
for the same amount of time
that my whole family spent
suffering, weren't you?
It's more like I was half-asleep
the whole time, really.
All because you were born a Demon Lord?
It's true, I was born a Demon Lord.
Maybe you're not that
different from me, then.
Rem?
That's exactly why I want to protect you.
I won't let Alicia have her way.
You said it!
I already told her I'm complete,
perfect, and whole as I am!
Let's get back to the others.
If it's okay to use my powers,
I can break this iron cage
and turn those armored goons
to ash with a single blow.
You can't do that.
Please stay the way you
have been, eating biscuits,
laughing with everyone,
and singing with Shera.
That's what I wish for you.
I don't want you to kill
any of the mortal races.
Please don't ever forget that.
I don't really understand,
but it's a promise!
Well, we're here.
This is where we'll save you.
I'm not a Demon Lord worshiper!
I won't give you a false confession,
even if you torture me!
That's good.
Everyone who's heard the rumors about me
starts spewing shallow vows of repentance
as soon as they see these tools.
Though, of course,
they don't fool me.
You are a true Demon Lord worshiper,
trying to deceive us holy men to the end.
You intend to torture me
no matter what, don't you?
This is your salvation.
I shall cleanse your tainted soul
and release you unto Heaven.
Do you think you've become
a God or something?
You're right.
The truth is...
It seems that I am a God.
I was born into a blessed family,
I was granted a blessed body,
and I boast a blessed intellect.
I received all of the blessings of Heaven,
so the only explanation is that I am a God
descended from Heaven to save this world.
There's no point in saying
anything to you, then!
Those ears of yours are evil.
That tail is bad, too.
As are those hands, which dared
to cast a Summon at me.
You're going to Hell!
Your mouth is evil, too.
Shall I extract your teeth, as well?
Alicia!
What made you want to
cooperate with this man?
And to betray us, no less?!
I have my own goal.
If you don't like pain,
why don't you try pleading for help?
Don't you need my help?
I don't need it!
Please, keep our promise.
R-Right...
Your goal of resurrecting the Demon
Lord to wipe out the mortal races?
That's why you need to do all this?!
What a funny thing for a
Demon Lord worshiper to say.
So was the understanding you showed me
and the fact that you went with us to
rescue Shera all a bunch of lies, as well?!
Saddler-sama, may I leave
the rest in your hands?
Yes, please leave it to me.
Alicia!
Now, shall we get started?
Damn it!
Seriously, where did they go?
I need something...
Any kind of clue...
You testing me, punk?!
Like taste-testing?! That's disgusting!
Oh, you think that's funny?!
Oh, right!
Then I was surrounded by
a hundred scoundrels, so I...
Diablo-san?
Is something the matter, friend?
You two!
Wait, how would a Demon Lord ask for a favor?
Ordering people around is easy...
But even with my poor communication
skills, I still know it's not good
to ask a favor with that attitude.
If I were in their shoes, I wouldn't
lend someone like that a hand.
I can't use my Demon Lord act here!
A-Actually...
Rem... and... K-Klem are...
Damn it!
Can I not even talk to these two
without using my Demon Lord act?!
Friend,
you're acting like a different person.
Guildmaster!
Big trouble!
My friend said he saw a Paladin
carrying Rem-san away!
What?!
Rem-chan?!
Was it only Rem?!
Huh?
Was there anyone else with her?!
He said there was one more, a little girl.
He said they went into the
church in the North District.
Thanks!
Did he just say "thanks"?
Our Diablo-san?
We can't stay here!
I'm going out to rescue Rem-chan, too!
All right!
I gotta make it in time!
What?!
Those are all Fallen, you say?!
Send a messenger to Lady Baudelaire at once!
Tell her to secure the barrier!
Yes, sir!
What is about to happen here?
We cannot let them enter Faltra.
I must protect the barrier, no matter what!
You can scream as much as you like.
No one will hear you.
Do you have no conscience at all?
I do.
My heart aches when I don't bring
salvation to Demon Lord worshipers.
Don't move!
Rem!
No!
You promised me, Klem!
Don't!
But... But...
Did you not understand that
you were told not to move?!
Rem!
Why are you just letting them hurt you?!
I'll kill them!
You don't mind, right?!
Don't...
You'll die!
If you interfere,
I'll show no mercy,
even if you are a child.
A F-Fallen!
I'll turn you all... into ash!
Tsk. Damn Fallen!
Pretending to be a Human child!
How repulsive!
You'll pay with your life for hurting Rem!
Damn Fallen brat!
Rem? Rem!
Rem?! Hey! Hang in there!
Run... away...
You, too! I'll take you with me!
I'll kill these men and save you!
You... promised...
I-I did, but...
Damn demihuman, getting in my way!
What?!
So that's... what she meant.
Hatred is what she needs.
So because of me...
I'm sorry, Klem.
Finally, the moment of resurrection.
Now the ugly mortal races will perish.
No...
Impossible!
The Demon Lord has resurrected?!
Even if you are the Demon Lord,
I'll wipe you out, leaving not a trace behind,
using the powers of the Gods that I command!
For I am a God myself!
Now, suffer!
And kneel before a God!
M-My eyes!
Saddler-sama?!
No...
It can't be!
Why?!
Am I... not a God?
What?!
Was I too late?!
Klem!
Diablo!
Shera?!
Why are you here?!
I used Turkey Shot to search for everyone,
and I saw Rem!
Rem...
Rem is...
What?! Rem is...
What happened to Alicia?!
I don't know!
I see.
Take these.
I'm going to hold Klem off.
You go save Rem.
All right.
Please don't get hurt.
And save Klem-chan!
Who do you think you're speaking to, Shera?
I am the true Demon Lord,
summoned from another world!
Leave this to me!
I'll take care of it all!
You can't die here, Rem!
This attack should wake you up, Klem!
Episode Twelve
Battle for Legitimacy
Let's go home, Klem.