The Demon Lord has been resurrected!
Wonderful!
Krebskulm-sama has resurrected
as a true Demon Lord!
A mortal? Why are they here?
She's the one who developed today's plan.
What?
Welcome back, Alicia.
As planned,
I made someone special to Krebskulm-sama,
then arranged for their destruction.
Such a difficult task...
Amazing.
Soon the mortal races will perish.
We'll finally end this ugly world.
I won't let the barrier be broken!
A horde of Fallen to the west,
and the Demon Lord to the north...
Galford-san.
So this is where you were.
We're at war now.
There's no place for adventurers here.
Just listen to me, okay?
I want you to leave the magic
circle in the north to us.
What?
Diablo-san's already heading there.
I want you to hold off from
interfering and getting in his way.
That adventurer?
Klem!
Final Episode
Battle for Legitimacy
Do you recognize me?
She's lost her sense of reason?
If she's forgotten who I am,
then I'll force her to remember!
I'm going to save both you and Rem!
Rem!
It's not too hard to dodge,
but her power's incredible.
What I should do is get farther away
and activate my powerful spells,
but the outer walls and the
barrier tower are too close.
If I want to protect the city,
I have to restrain my area of effect!
Eleven more...
Volcanic Wall!
That was close! Is that Darkness Breath?!
Magic Reflection.
I know I showed it to you
in the fight with Eulerex.
Her magic defense is way too high!
Rem!
You're finally free now!
You can't die here like this, Rem!
Please, answer me!
Gods, please don't take Rem away.
Shera?
Rem!
Ow, ow! Stupid Shera!
Sorry!
But I'm so glad.
How did this all happen?
Alicia betrayed us.
She wanted the Demon Lord to
be resurrected from the start.
Th-That would mean...
She was a Demon Lord worshiper.
She forced Klem to endure something very sad.
Being overwhelmed by hatred was probably
the key to the Demon Lord's awakening.
That's awful.
What are those?
Diablo gave them to me.
He said to use them on you
and gave me all he had on him.
Then Diablo's fighting the Demon
Lord without any way to recover?
Six left.
Is this even possible?!
If I wasn't Level 150,
I'd be dead right now!
Oh, I gave away all my potions, didn't I?
Back when I played solo,
I never used my items on other people, and
I definitely never ran out of them doing it!
Look out!
Emile?!
Anything goes here, doesn't it?!
But that's thirteen spots now!
Friend!
Emile?
I took Rem-chan and Shera-chan outside!
Get her!
That's good work, for you.
As a reward, I'll demonstrate my Grand Magic!
I had a hard time fighting while
keeping her within its effective range.
Now, this blow should wake you up, Klem!
Apocalypse Abyss!
Get over here!
You're kidding me!
It's still alive after that blow?!
You still want to fight?
Klem!
Klem, I'm okay.
Please come back to us!
Let's eat biscuits together again.
It must have hurt so much...
But it's okay now.
Let's go home, Klem.
It's over, then?
You're... alive?
Welcome back, Klem.
I need to apologize to you.
I broke my promise.
When I thought they had killed you,
my whole mind went red.
It doesn't matter now.
No matter who disapproves,
I'll be on your side.
That monster turned into a little girl?
Look, Emile, this whole thing...
Worry not.
I'm an ally of all women.
I don't know what's going on, but I'd never
do anything to make those girls cry.
I forgot you were that kind of man.
Hey, are you all right?
Yeah.
I can't let them see a Demon Lord
on the verge of collapsing!
The presence of the Demon
Lord has grown smaller?
Why?
What's the meaning of this?
Edelgard, this is the
second time you've failed.
Not only did you ally yourself with a Human,
but you've wasted the
time of countless Fallen.
You will take responsibility for this!
When I give the signal,
run for the city.
Hey, Diablo-san, nice work out there!
It's thanks to the information I got
from the Adventurer's Guild.
Be proud that you proved useful to me.
I'm glad you protected our city, too.
By the way, I'd like to ask this
while the graveyard is sealed off...
That girl is Demon Lord Krebskulm, isn't she?
Sorry, but I can't just
let her run around free.
I have to protect the
safety of the mortal races
as the master of the Adventurer's Guild.
Are you saying you'll fight me?
I trust you, Diablo-san,
but I can't trust the Demon Lord Krebskulm.
Please! This girl is...
If Diablo-san wasn't here,
this entire city would've
been destroyed by Krebskulm.
Did you know that a huge army of Fallen
was approaching us from the west?
I didn't summon them here!
We don't know that.
What do I do?
Sylvie's not wrong, but...
Klem.
Would you like to live in
this city with Rem and Shera?
Yeah.
Then let me tell you something.
There's a way for you to eat
biscuits here in this city
without adventurers coming after your life.
I don't think there's a way to—
That's...
A magic stone of a pact?
Klem, I can cast the
Enslavement Spell on you
and make you my servant!
What?!
Make me your servant?
Oh, right!
We have that option!
Once I do that, you'll belong to me.
You said you trust me, right?
Well, I do, but... What?!
Enslave me?
It's okay!
Both Rem and I are Diablo's slaves,
but it's really nothing!
Still, wouldn't being a slave
mean I'm not free anymore?
Diablo's not like that.
I guarantee it.
Very well. I permit it!
You may use your
Enslavement Spell or whatever!
Wha?! Wha?! Wha?!
I command you in the name
of the Demon Lord Diablo.
Heed my call, surrender to me, and obey me.
The Demon Lord hasn't resurrected,
and the Fallen have withdrawn.
Is this thanks to that Demon?
Yeah.
Is there anything you
need to discuss with me?
Hmm, is there?
I figure you already know.
You have such a splendid
information network, after all.
We'll just have to watch over
them quietly for a while.
Of course, we can't let
our guard down, though.
Later, Galford-san.
To think we'd be saved by that Demon...
Huh?
Why are you scowling again, Diablo?
Because I've peered into an abyss that
the likes of you couldn't imagine.
That sounds awesome!
What's an abyss?
The abyss!
An "abyss" can be a metaphor for
something deep and endless.
Diablo's exhausted.
Just leave him be, and let him rest.
You may say that, but you're
planning to sleep with him, too!
It's fine if I do.
What?!
Come on over here, Klem-chan.
Really? I can join you, too?
Why not?
I killed mortals, remember?
I even tried to kill you all!
Don't you think I'm dangerous?
Sylvie-san's the only one
who thinks you're dangerous.
But...
Don't make me laugh.
You tried to kill me?
Those weak attacks wouldn't work on me.
After all, I'm the true Demon Lord.
I see!
In truth, I'm more nervous
about sleeping with them
than I am about fighting a Demon Lord.
I still can't get used to it.
Oh, the light!
I'll turn it off.
Rem, get that one.
Now, we sleep!
Alicia?!
Rem-sama? You're still alive?!
How dare you appear before me again?
Unhand Shera so I can rip you to shreds.
I'll release Shera-sama once
my business here is done.
Please rip me to shreds or
whatever you want then.
Oh?
I've heard the Demon Lord is able
to heal the wounds of Fallen.
Of course I can.
Then could you come with me, please?
Edelgard!
The other Fallen punished her
after our plan to resurrect Krebskulm-sama
and exterminate the mortal races failed.
I see...
When we met up with Edelgard
at Starfall Tower,
she never asked who you were
after you suddenly showed up.
So you two were working
together from the beginning?
You are correct.
Please!
Please, save Edelgard-sama!
Do you think I'd listen to
someone who put Rem in danger?
Diablo, what do you think?
Help her.
Very well.
In an instant?!
Demon Lord?!
Yes.
Demon Lord!
I'm overcome with gratitude!
Demon Lord...
Why have you returned to your original form?
Because the people here with me risked
their lives to restore me to normal.
They did?
Are you dissatisfied?
I don't know.
Fallen are meant to kill mortals.
We're supposed to be enemies, so why?
I don't know, either.
That's why I've decided
to live in the human city.
There are biscuits here, too.
So stop doing such sad things already.
If you can't obey that order,
then you're no longer my follower.
I swear, I will not do such things anymore.
Thank you very much.
You may do with me as you wish now.
How did an Imperial Knight like you
become a Demon Lord worshiper?
Have you never wished humanity would perish?
Have you never shouted in your mind,
"I'll kill you, you bastard"?
All the time!
Maybe not to that extent, but of
course I've gotten angry at others.
What happened to you?
Perhaps I might have been
able to compartmentalize it
if there had been a specific incident.
I think I was just exposed
to too much of the dark side
of self-centered, greedy,
powerful, and entitled people
who pretended they were good people.
My parents, the other Imperial Knights,
nobles, and even the emperor
were all the same.
They forced their own nonsensical
righteousness on us all.
It was so ugly that I couldn't accept it.
I believed there was no
place for me in this world,
as I lived on alone with
only hatred in my heart.
She's the same as me.
I played solo all my life,
with nowhere to fit in,
and never wanted to see the world outside.
Even if we wanted to understand others,
we never wanted them to understand us.
I can really relate to how she feels.
Demon Lord,
Are you sure you won't
eradicate the mortal races?
Enough of that.
I don't hate the mortal races as much as
you do, and I haven't lost hope in them.
I see.
Then I have no other choice.
What are you planning to do?!
I don't expect to be
forgiven for my betrayal.
So I'll end it now.
Wait!
Don't stop me!
I know I'm not normal!
I don't expect anyone to understand me!
Either way...
Either way, I'm all alone!
Stop!
You really are stubborn.
I told you before that you should relax.
Why does that even matter here?!
I entrapped Rem-sama to further my own goals!
That's not a sin I can ever atone for!
Don't be naïve enough to call
death a means of atonement!
B-But I tried to wipe out the mortal races
while serving as an Imperial Knight!
So what?!
Who decided to put you in that position?
The emperor? The nobles? Your parents?
Why should you care about a position forced
on you by people that mean nothing to you?!
You should you just be yourself!
Be myself?
Quit getting hung up on nonsense,
and try living the life you want.
It doesn't matter what you think of yourself.
Just take the actions you need to take
when someone truly needs you.
Do that, and that'll be where you belong.
That's how it was for me.
Dying with some stupid idea that you're
all alone in this world is no atonement!
Just try and take that easy way out.
The moment you do,
I, the Demon Lord Diablo,
will show you what true fear is.
Do you really believe I'll
find somewhere to fit in?
Even someone as ugly as me?
You're not ugly.
If your heart truly was ugly,
would you have risked coming
to us for your partner's sake?
I, too, was all alone before
I met Diablo and Shera.
There was a moment when I hated you, too.
But now that I've heard how you truly feel,
I can forgive you.
You can't let yourself
lose to isolation, Alicia.
Rem-sama...
But how do I be myself?
Hell if I know!
Huh?!
You're the one who decides that!
Your life starts today, right now.
He's always been cool,
but this is the coolest Diablo's ever been.
Yes.
Diablo!
Are you all right?!
My magic points...
Then I'll give you magic power
like before and re-energize you!
Right!
Let's all help Diablo perk up together!
If that's the case, then...
I suppose I must, just for today.
If it'll help Diablo recover...
Edelgard, you strip, too!
M-Me, too!
I'll also lend a hand!
Diablo!
Diablo fainted!
Wake up, Diablo!
Come back again, okay?
Well, then... I, Alicia Cristela,
shall be heading off.
Be well.
Yes.
You should be okay now.
Thank you, miss!
I told you, we're having fruit tonight!
Meat!
Fruit!
Fruit doesn't give you strength!
They haven't changed.
It's meat!
What?
Which side are you on?
Th-This is pointless.
Okay.
Huh?
Then kiss the side you choose.
Huh?!
I mean, I know it was for the ritual,
but you kissed Klem-chan.
When you did that right in front of us,
I was honestly a bit jealous.
We've belonged to you longer
than she has, after all.
I won't be satisfied until
you've gone further with us.
So?
Which is it?
Don't bother me with such nonsense!
Aw, why not?
Because I am Diablo!
The one feared as the Demon Lord!