The Easton Magic Academy.
A historic and prestigious school
that has produced
numerous pillars of the magic realm.
Of course, its entrance examination
is notoriously difficult.
Not even 3% of the applicants
will be admitted.
Only those with superior magical powers
will be able to open the gates of Easton.
Only those
with superior magical powers...
Let's see,
among this year's applicants are...
A scion of established nobility, and then
the undersecretary's son from the Bureau of Magic.
All the bigwigs of society, so to speak.
Maintenance of wands
and reviewing of grimoires.
They're devoting themselves to the exam.
It's only proper to have ambitious candidates
for a school as prestigious as ours.
What the...
Huh? What's going on?
We're starting an entrance exam
for a magic school now.
Why is someone pumping iron?
No, calm down.
Maybe I'm imagining things.
This is a magic school.
Slackers like that would never be here.
He's doing the invisible chair
while reading a fitness book!
Does he even want to pass this exam?
At least read some books about magic!
Consumption of protein within 45 minutes
of training is the most basic of fundamentals.
And he's talking to himself!
Consumption of protein within 45 minutes
of training is the most basic of fundamentals.
And he's talking to himself!
And who are those guys behind him?
They're anything but inconspicuous!
Are you sure this will work?
Mash can't use magic.
You don't trust me and my plans?
I made his scar
indistinguishable from a real one.
I'm sure we'll get a kick outta this.
Oh, well.
Slackers like that
will fail the exam anyway.
I wonder what the exam is like.
I have to pass it, no matter
what it turns out to be.
Greetings!
Welcome to Easton Magic Academy.
I am overseeing today's entrance examination.
My name is Claude Lucci.
The pleasure's all mine.
C-Claude Lucci!
This year's seventh
best up-and-coming mage!
He's said to have mastered countless
advanced spells despite his youth!
How exhilarating.
Praise and worship me even more!
It must've been hot
coming out of the fire like that.
I'm definitely going to flunk him!
Now, let's start our first exam.
Take your seats.
Seats?
There are no seats!
What?
- Desks just appeared!
- Amazing!
- Wh-Whoa!
- I've never seen magic like this!
No wonder they have
high hopes for this professor!
You could've just taken us to a room
that was already set up.
I'll kill him.
No matter.
The acceptance rate
of this exam is three percent.
There's no way
slackers like him will pass.
You have 30 minutes!
Now, begin!
The test paper...
The questions are squirming around?
That's right, I have enchanted
the test papers with my magic.
Thus, to pass this exam you need to dispel
the magic and properly line up the questions.
He'll never pull this off.
Why'd I think
this would work the other day?
Could you kindly stop moving?
Kindly... stop moving.
What?
I finished.
That guy from earlier...
I'm sure it's just
some random scribbles...
It's aligned so perfectly.
He's making that boulder float so easily!
Whoa! He's running on water!
From that point on, Mash...
somehow found ways
to pass the tests.
How can a slacker like that
still be here?
That tasteless brat
who makes a mockery of me...
Then I guess I must...
This is the next test!
Hey, the ground again is...
In the next test, you will solve this maze.
Of course, this is no ordinary maze.
There are various traps set within.
You have 30 minutes!
Reach the goal by the time limit,
and you pass!
Now, begin!
So I have to get to the goal area?
Sounds pretty easy.
Excuse me!
Can I tag along with you?
Why?
Huh? Um...
I think it'd be more efficient
if we worked together.
Makes sense.
Th-Thank you very much!
I wonder what kind of traps
will be waiting for us?
It hurts!
This maze has imps!
Please save me!
Th-This ground is trying to grab us!
Don't leave me behind!
Please wait.
Please don't leave me behind!
What was that about efficiency?
We have to hurry.
Levios Cuffus!
What are these?
I'm sorry I deceived you
this whole time.
There's a certain reason
I have to keep you away from the goal.
What reason?
I-I don't want to tell you,
that's why it's a certain reason!
So I've been deceived?
That's useless.
Human strength can't break...
I'm sorry...
but I have my own certain reason, too.
Later.
Th-This is bad!
I have to chase and stop him.
Four legs in the morning.
Two legs in the afternoon,
and three legs at night.
What is this creature?
This is totally
one of the dangerous ones.
It's only a test.
I'll use my magic and...
Answer my riddle.
Oh no. My knees gave out.
Bad, really bad. This is a riddle?
What's the answer?
Four legs in the morning,
two at noon, three at night...
Oh, this sucks. I'm panicking
and I can't think straight!
Time's up. Thou shalt be punished.
Help...
That's not right.
This truly is punishment
for selfishly deceiving others.
I'm so terrible.
I'm sorry, Mushroom Head.
Such a creature...
can't possibly exist.
Wh-Why did you bother
to come back and save me?
Well...
If your reason was similar to mine,
I'd kinda feel sorry for you.
But it looks like
we won't make it in time from here.
How do you think
I came here in an instant?
Time is almost up.
Multiple traps
and the guardian of the labyrinth...
And the student I recruited to stop him.
Since I put in this much effort,
I'm sure he...
Hey, what's with that loud noise?
Sounds like something is breaking!
Th-There's no way.
These walls are one meter thick
and are impervious to all magic.
The walls!
H-He trudged straight outta there!
Quite a curious young man.
Is that allowed?
Can he really do that?
There's no way he can!
That's cheating!
Gimme a break!
Go home! Go home! Go home!
I want to go home.
That's absurd.
It's no longer a labyrinth!
Indeed.
You're supposed to get lost
in a maze before exiting!
Good point.
What is a maze for you?
Philosophy.
Go home! Go home! Go home!
P-Please stop! It wasn't his fault!
Stop it!
If you say anything, you'll regret it!
I can still reconsider that promise for now.
- I was...
- Hey!
I was intentionally getting in his way
so he wouldn't reach the goal.
Professor Lucci asked me to.
He told me he would pass me
if I got in his way.
My family is poor, and I desperately
wanted to be accepted for their sake.
But he still saved me,
and then said to me,
"Please marry me"!
No, I didn't say that.
I mean...
If you're injured, I can piggyback you.
Huh? Wait, that means...
I'm a burden, you know?
I don't really mind burdens at all.
Don't be so bashful.
I know how you really feel.
It was really great. Yeah.
No, I totally didn't say that.
That's right. What about it?
I'm the examiner.
What's bad about trying
to fail students I don't like?
A cheeky brat and a pauper girl.
I reached out thinking even scum can be
useful, but you bit the hand that fed you.
Is your stupidity
inherited from your parents?
No wonder you have a miserable life.
I'm failing you both.
If you want to complain,
then challenge the decision.
Challenge me,
a Magus Cum Laude Professor!
Of course, that's only if you dare!
That's going too far, Professor.
What?
Wow. He broke that wand.
That's just the type of kid he is, huh?
I kinda feel sorry for him.
Shut up! Why would I even—
Silence!
Headmaster Wahlberg.
We will now begin the final interviews.
From this point on,
I will take charge of the examination.
Headmaster, why are you here?
Lucci.
See me in my office after this.
A-As you wish.
Now, let's start with our first applicant.
We will now begin the final interview
for Mash Burnedead.
Thank you for having me.
First, let's hear
why you chose our academy.
To live in peace with my family.
That's not an answer.
What does that mean?
It's fine.
Next question.
Is it true that you saved a girl in the maze test,
although you didn't have time to?
I guess so.
What made you do so,
even by risking to fail the test?
I kinda felt like I would regret it.
You seem to be the type
who acts before thinking.
You never considered
that the sphinx might be stronger,
or that you may not be able
to break the walls?
Well, even if I considered,
it still had to be done.
Extremely amusing.
But you can only say that because
you don't understand the ways of the world yet.
Many creatures that are stronger
than you exist in this world.
If you were to face something
that overwhelmingly outpowers you,
would you still be able
to take the same course of action?
Even if you were...
facing me?
What immense magical power.
And this spell!
What is this?
This is an ancient spell that transfers the soul
of the target's most cherished one into a doll.
Gramps?
What's wrong? Gramps! Hey!
Of course, that's not all.
If I were to stab a knife
into the soulful doll...
that being would never return.
Didn't I already tell you?
I am immensely more powerful than you.
You can't do anything in your current state.
And in a situation like this,
what would you...
You can't keep something
this huge out forever.
This is an endurance contest, right?
Power can be used to harm or to help.
It all depends
on the wielder of that power.
That is the reason why I put emphasis...
on protecting the weak,
and regulating the strong.
Noblesse Oblige.
One's capacity as a powerful being.
And according to my observations,
you are a human who possesses that capacity.
My apologies.
I was literally testing you.
I had no intention of that nature.
Don't worry about it.
What is it?
What you asked earlier, Headmaster.
The answer to the question
"If I had to face the Headmaster..."
If it comes to that,
I'd knock the stuffing out of you...
with my fist.
What insolence!
Are you insane?
Welcome to Easton Magic Academy.
Are you okay, old man?
Be gentle with me.
And so, a lot of things happened.
But Mash Burnedead passed the entrance exam
for Easton Magic Academy.
Today, we will be learning one of the most
basic of spells, the lock-opening spell.
You must imagine opening the lock
as you infuse it with magic energy.
Opti Ars.
Now, let's actually try it.
Professor. I opened it.
Why you little, that's not...
That's not it at all, damn it!
This is a magic school, you know?
A place where you learn magic!
Well, I...
I'm not good with magic and the like.
Why are you even here?
Looks like I have a hard path ahead.
Why are you sounding like
it's not your business?
What kind of nerves do you have?
What's with this year's transfers?
There's someone who's clearly bad news!
God is dead.
Where the hell did that come from?
Seriously creepy!
I definitely don't want to be around him.
Where the hell did that come from?
Seriously creepy!
Where are you looking at now?
Listen! Listen to what others have to say!
Since this is a boarding school...
I really don't want to be roommates
with people like that.
Let's see, my room...
Huh, wait...
The door...
I'm Finn Ames.
Nice to be rooming with you.
I'm Mash Burnedead.
I don't really know a lot, so I might
cause trouble, but it's nice to room with you.
Huh? He's surprisingly normal?
And this is Kevin.
This one's Mike.
This guy names his muscles! Freaky!
And when did he change clothes?
W-Well, you can ask me
anything you don't know.
The dorm pairs up transfers and continuing
students together as roommates.
It's customary to help each other out.
I see.
Be nice for now.
Nice, and distant.
This is for a peaceful school life.
Can I ask you one thing?
Sure.
How do you get to be
the academy's "Divine Visionary"?
Oh, a Divine Visionary?
You have to collect gold coins.
Tests, coursework, extracurriculars, school life.
We're evaluated on everything.
Based on the evaluations, you're given
coins of gold, silver, or bronze.
Regardless of coins earned,
if you can't keep your grades up
each semester, you'll be expelled.
I had a vague feeling,
but this is really brutal.
Looks like he'll be expelled real quick.
So that's why we're all desperate.
Including me, of course.
Best of luck to you, too.
Finn made sure not to say,
"Let's do our best together."
You're a great guy.
And Mash was very simple.
You want a cream puff?
Huh? Where did you pull those out of?
I'll take one, though.
Will Mash with no magical powers
really be able to become the Divine Visionary?