Mash's life in a magic school to become
a Divine Visionary has begun.
Although he can't use magic.
Although he can't use magic!
Finn, can you lend me
a broom for tomorrow's class?
I actually brought a burdock,
thinking it was a broom.
Burdock? You thought
a burdock was a broom?
Accidentally.
Accidentally?
Okay. I'll lend you one.
I knew you were a great guy.
Today, you will learn how to ride a broom.
Channel magic energy into the broom
and command it with the word "fly."
Then straddle it and regulate the magic
to keep it afloat.
Now, begin.
- Fly.
- Fly!
Pops. I'll become number one
and restore our peaceful life.
Okay.
Fly.
Fl...
Fair enough.
Come on now,
you can't even get a broom to float?
Looks like one of us needs the remedial class.
You're slowing the rest of us down.
Fly.
Th-That's cheating, you worm.
Quit acting innocent.
It flew up before you commanded it.
Why you...
Now, how fast can your broom go?
We will now begin the timed trials.
Perfect timing. How about a little race?
Loser has to obey the winner
for as long as we're here. Up for it?
Sure.
Idiot.
Unlike transfers, I've been riding brooms
since middle school.
There's no way I'd lose
to someone like you.
Prepare to get swept.
That student...
It's the class clown from yesterday.
Can he even ride a broom?
All right, on your marks.
Ready... go.
What the...
What the heck did I just witness?
No!
What incredible speed! A new world record
has been set! A world record!
What just happened?
Didja see that?
I have no clue.
I got a good look.
As soon as she said "start,"
he chucked the broom.
Then he immediately
jumped out towards the broom.
He used air resistance to decrease
his speed, closed the gap to it,
and mounted it in midair.
How is that even possible?
You must have cheated.
There's no way that happened!
Can't face the facts, huh?
I feel kinda bad for you.
Why you...
It's okay. I'll drop the bet, too.
I feel sorry for you.
You mocking m...
Hey, now. Let's not make a scene.
Sorry. My apologies for his rudeness.
This guy here is my friend.
Huh. Well, okay.
Uh-oh. Cavill's talking to him?
He's totally the target now.
We'd better stay out of it.
He's the first victim in high school.
Anyway, what you did earlier
really caught my attention.
Would you like to be friends with me?
Huh.
I'm Lloyd Cavill. Nice to meet you.
Spud Cabbage?
Excuse me, what are you all doing?
We're in the middle of class.
Oh, whoops.
You're pretty funny. You should
come here again after school.
I'll be waiting.
Huh.
Middle of class...
As for you... Why'd you have to go
and lose like that?
That was pretty pathetic, you know?
You got made fun of instead.
What a loser you are.
You just couldn't follow simple orders.
I simply told you
to go mess with him.
Oh, well.
At least I found a good toy.
Who was that guy?
Cavill is a continuing student
from the middle school division, like me.
So why is everyone afraid of him?
That's because...
Because he's the son of a high-ranking member
at the Bureau of Magic.
Even you must know that the Bureau of Magic
is absolute in this realm.
O-Of course, I know that.
Well, simply put, if you
stand against him, you get expelled.
The vice principal seems to have
close ties with his family.
Get on their bad side,
and they'll force you to drop out.
As a continuing student, I saw it happen
too many times since middle school.
For some, the torment
doesn't end after dropping out either.
That's why everyone obeys him.
They're scared.
It's after school.
It's fun to make some
on your own every so often.
I wish Pops could taste
these cream puffs, too.
Well, the choice is yours.
Spend the rest of your life
being hunted down,
or brace yourself to die
and try turning the tables.
I have to become the top student
in this academy no matter what.
I feel like I'm forgetting something.
Oh, well.
Mash ticked off someone
who you really shouldn't cross.
The next day.
The next class is Potions, so...
Oh no.
My textbook is falling apart.
Hello.
You didn't show up yesterday.
What were you doing?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I was making some cream puffs.
Anyway, I heard you're aiming
to be the Divine Visionary.
I'm good friends with the vice principal,
so I have some connections.
If you do what I tell you, I could put in
a good word for you. What do you say?
Really? Whoopee. I'll do it.
But why so suddenly?
Well, you seem like a fun person,
and I want to help out.
But it'd be weird to have
no strings attached, right?
Good point.
So, for starters, carry these for us.
'Kay.
Ugh, my shoes are dirty. Wipe them for me.
- Gimme a drink.
- 'Kay.
- Massage my shoulders.
- Do something funny.
- ‘Kay.
'Kay.
Next class is, let's see...
Another textbook torn up.
Finn, can you show me your textbook?
S-Sorry. Ask someone else to...
Thanks.
Um, I said no...
You're a real lifesaver.
And thanks for the broom yesterday.
These cream puffs are my thanks.
Uh, okay.
But I really am glad.
To have a great guy like you for a friend.
Yeah.
Wow, you're such a great guy.
I'm totally in your debt. You're a lifesaver.
Don't even mention it.
You've been a big help.
Sorry, sorry. I spilled some.
Clean it up, will you?
Hm? What's wrong?
You will do it, won't you?
So Potions is up next.
I really don't like that teacher.
Maybe I'll have
the vice principal have them fired.
Ain't that a little extreme?
It's so clean it sparkles.
Oh.
I can't believe he does whatever we say.
Maybe he'll catch on soon?
I'm getting bored of textbooks.
Next, I want you to burn his clothes.
Got that, Finn?
If you go that far,
maybe he'll quit school on his own?
I can't do this anymore.
What was that?
I didn't quite hear you. Say it again.
I said...
I can't do this anymore.
I see.
You've made a mistake.
When you make a mistake,
you drop down and beg for forgiveness.
Where did Finn go?
I accidentally
took his textbook with me.
What's that sound?
M-Mash.
If it isn't Mash.
What are you doing?
Getting an apology.
Because he got a bit ahead of himself.
Are you okay, Finn?
Yeah.
But you're bleeding.
That doesn't matter right now, Mash.
I-It was me.
The one who ruined your textbooks...
It was me.
I was ordered to.
I was too scared to disobey.
But you kept saying I was a great guy.
You called me your friend, but...
Still, I did horrible things to you.
So I just... I needed to apologize to you.
I'm so very sorry. Sorry.
If only you'd honestly
apologized to me like that...
Oh, by the way, I'm about
to dine with the vice principal.
Care to join us, Mash?
You can leave that dirty little lackey here.
I've been dying to introduce you.
You might never get a chance like this again.
Especially if you keep company
with someone who only apologizes, like him.
You're the one who should apologize.
Wut?
Double wut?
Th-That'll get you expelled.
Is that a big deal?
Mash.
Oh.
Maybe it is a big deal.
I might've done something bad.
Yes, that's right.
You have done something bad.
V-Vice Principal Farman.
What are you doing here?
This young boy's father
entrusted me with his son.
I witnessed the entire incident.
If you witnessed the whole thing, then—
This was a violent attack on a student.
Finn Ames and Mash Burnedead.
We will hold a school conference
regarding your roles in this incident.
Huh?
Surely you can see why
if you think about it.
You two and he are of different status.
Different social status
means different treatment.
Are you too ignorant
to figure that out, you idiot?
Then, I will enlighten you idiots.
This is how the world operates.
The vice principal.
Not him too.
He didn't seem that open to reason,
so I couldn't help it.
But really, after one, what's one more?
That's serial killer logic!
You assaulted me.
I can expel ordinary students
like you at any time.
Lepios Oga.
What is this?
Dirt?
Wha...
What... Sto...
What do you think you're doing?
Burying you.
And you think you can get away with this?
- I can have you—
- Just like...
you can expel me at any time,
I can bury you at any time.
Throw me in prison. Or cut my body in two.
Even if I have to crawl over, I will bury you.
Wait... Stop... Cut it out!
I'm serious! Stop!
Stop it. No!
I assume you know why
you were summoned here?
Because I made cream puffs
in the dorm kitchen without asking.
Completely wrong.
You punched young Cavill,
and buried the vice principal.
This issue was seen as a problem
over at the Bureau of Magic.
Here. I have a notice from the Bureau of Magic
to expel you immediately.
The Bureau of Magic
is this country's highest legal authority.
It's no stretch to say they control this country.
At the core of their organization
are the Divine Visionaries.
This academy furnishes the Bureau
with those qualified to become Divine Visionaries.
As I'm sure you're aware, young Cavill
is a high-ranking member's son of the Bureau.
In other words...
You have done something unforgivable.
However...
What is even more unforgivable is a world
where the caring are at a disadvantage.
I've been concerned
by the current state of things in this world.
Which is why I took
this position several years ago.
Currently the world turns with authority,
power, and the self-serving at its center.
We have frighteningly few people like you,
who sacrifice themselves and act.
The Divine Visionaries who lead
the Bureau of Magic have a role.
That role is to carefully consider
what the people desire.
That is why I sincerely hope that someday,
someone like you will become a Divine Visionary.
No need to tell me. I already plan to.
Wonderful. That's the spirit.
Allow me to explain how you will do that.
'Kay.
To be chosen as a Divine Visionary,
you must be the top student at this academy.
That requires gathering enough coins
through schoolwork and activities.
There are three types of coins.
Gold, silver, and bronze.
The type of coin you receive
is further differentiated by task.
It is tradition that every year, those who have
a certain number of gold coins... Huh?
He's passed out.
I overloaded him with information
to the point of unconsciousness.
Mash. Mash!
I'm sorry. I was overloaded with information,
so I couldn't help it.
Sorry. Let me condense it for you.
Earn high marks in your classes and school activities.
And acquire as many coins as possible.
I will handle the vice principal
and the Bureau of Magic.
Do you understand, Mash?
I am counting on you.
'Kay.
Then I'll be going now.
There is one more problem
you will eventually have to face.
But I have faith in you.
That you can overcome it.
And thus, Mash ended up
with no punishment.
However, by defeating
the infamous Cavill and vice principal,
he became someone who was acknowledged
by the other students.
When making cream puffs, it's all about
preventing the batter from cooling.
Uh, wow, I see.
You there, with the mushroom head!
How would you like to represent
Adler dorm in a Duelo match?
And let's burn out together
in this fire that we call life!
It's Lord Tom,
last year's Duelo MVP of the year.
He's such a sportsman that his stuffiness
actually works well for him.
And what's with that guy with that hairdo?
Totally a fungus.
Bet he collects pill bugs at home.
So, what is Duelo?
And what's this fire that we call life?
We compete using our brooms.
It's the number one sport in the Magic Realm.
A first-year playing Duelo? That's amazing.
But I can't ride a broom.
Don't be modest.
You blew everyone away in class.
Why are you shouting? Also, I said...
The game's tomorrow.
We're counting on you.
But I...
Shoot for the stars. Even if you miss,
you'll land among your dreams.
This guy's denser than I am.
Hey, I'm counting on you.
I heard you got a new world record?
Today's game is gonna be a piece of cake.
Let's give it our all.
But I can't ride brooms.
The first Duelo match this season
is Adler dorm vs. Lang dorm.
Which team will win this match
and earn silver coins?
Go for it!
What's with him?
It's like he's not even trying to fly.
Well, I said I can't ride brooms, so...
If you don't wanna be here, then go home!
- Stop screwing around!
- Go home already!
I want to go home.
If you go home, you won't be able
to become a Divine Visionary.
In order to regain your peaceful life
with Pops, fly. You have to fly, Mash.