I'm Wirth Madl.
Being worthlessly weak
is absolutely inexcusable. Got that?
Graviole.
I have no time to be your playmate.
Gravity magic, huh? What a surprise.
This might be fun after all.
Right?
Graviole.
Useless, so useless!
Mud clones.
So I have to crush the real one.
That'll make things quick.
I'll attack the whole field.
Graviole.
Too bad.
Burst!
My legs are stuck. When did he...
The Crown family is renowned
for their gravity magic.
You come from a good bloodline.
Your talent is wasted.
Perfect. You should join Magia Lupus.
Looks like your skills aren't too bad.
Bet you'd fit in nicely in our lower ranks.
And more than anything,
I feel sorry for you.
A magic user of your talents belongs
in an environment where you can flourish.
Your growth depends on those around you.
Surround yourself with garbage
and you'll undoubtedly start to reek.
Meaning?
C'mon! You really need me
to spell it out for you?
Those Adlers are trash.
You'll rot too if you stay with them.
People are supposed to be surrounded
by their equals.
Hang around with the dregs
and you just sink to their level.
Being a Magia Lupus is amazing.
We all have so much talent!
We also get excellent education,
tools, potions...
Our environment is designed
to bring out the best magic in us.
An environment to become stronger...
The strength of my conviction is not
superficial enough for the environment to matter.
Was that too difficult to grasp?
From my point of view,
you are second-rate.
Second rate? Is that so?
Do you understand what you're saying?
Graviole.
He shifted gravity sideways to a wall.
But it won't make a difference.
I cushion walls and floors with
a muddy environment to absorb shocks.
Gravity magic needs a place
to slam your opponent into.
As long as he doesn't figure
this trick out, I'm impervi...
He's shooting rubble created earlier
into the mud using gravity.
Did this kid already realize
what my anti-gravity trick is?
You said people become stronger
with a better environment.
Yeah?
Based on your logic, it appears
my environment is the superior one.
I am strong.
I was born with two marks.
I have a capacity for magic
beyond your average flunky.
I've been at Easton since middle school.
My joining the Magia Lupus was inevitable.
There, I received an education
reserved for Lang's best.
That's right. Of course I'm strong.
After all that, there's no way I couldn't be.
So there's no way I could be weak.
Pretty cocky of you, first-year.
You think you've beaten me?
This is concentrated magical essence,
extracted from other students.
We Magia Lupus are awarded this essence.
We're special!
His magic power further spiked.
Now I'll prove to you...
which of us is right.
Mudoros Secondth!
Mudoro Devilus!
All magic have tiers.
Basic magic, personal magic.
Then the more advanced conditional magic.
But Secondth is different
from magic used by single-liners.
It's higher-tier magic that only certain
double-liners are allowed to cast.
That's right.
Only the few worthy can use it.
You must understand, Wirth.
It's your achievements
that determine your worth.
I will be worthy.
And in this world, magic means everything.
Your magic determines your worth.
I will be worthy.
Those with an aptitude
for magic have worth.
Those without it are worthless.
You're wrong.
I'm more than my aptitude.
I earned the position
that I am standing in now.
I am worthy.
Because you hang out
with worthless flunkies, this magic
is at a level you'll never achieve!
You called them flunkies, but you really
don't understand anything, do you?
He reminded me of something important.
I'm too clumsy to make
rational decisions about everything.
So the only one allowed
to insult them as flunkies is me.
Graviole Secondth.
Torture Pole!
Mudoro Devilus's movement...
So these pillars...
That's right.
These pillars exert
strong gravitational pulls toward them.
And that monster surrounded by the pillars
will be pulled by gravity from all directions
and ripped apart.
My strongest spell was defeated?
Are you saying I was defeated?
But I...
Acknowledged by the top of your dorm?
You're striving to be the top at Easton.
Entering the Bureau alone will not
make you worthy as my creation.
Do you understand?
You are still worthless to me.
When will you finally show me
that you are worth something?
I'm worthless.
This is yours, right? It was on the ground.
That reference text
looks ragged from lots of use.
What do you think gives someone worth?
My parents measured worth by position
and social standing more than anything.
Based on your words and actions,
you and I were probably raised similarly.
When I grow up, I want to be a singer!
In that environment, it feels like
your worth is judged by aptitude and standing.
But I disagree with that.
Hey! You're thinking
I totally can't do it, aren't you?
But I think it's important
that I decided to try my best!
I don't like the way you talk or act.
But I respect all the effort you've put in.
That's right.
It's not like I wanted to become
a worthy person. The truth is...
Stupid punk.
I didn't ask for your respect.
You can't win. Not against me.
Acceleraise.
Do you understand now?
We're incomparable.
You can continue to challenge me,
knowing that.
But I will not go easy on you.
Even if—
It doesn't matter.
None of that matters. None of it.
"Live in peace with your family."
Is that right?
How revolting.
Your situation is similar to mine,
but those ideas...
You must've been blessed
with whoever was around you.
Fine then.
Please show me your best.
This device drains magic power.
In about 30 minutes,
your friend will lose her magic power.
She'll lose her mark
and the ability to use magic forever.
What do you think?
Now your friend will be just like you.
Doesn't that make you happy?
If you're seriously saying that,
then that mask
will be coming off in pieces.
Quite obstinate.
Very well.
Then I will not hold back.
Acceleraise Sphere.
Anyone can spout high-minded ideals.
But in the end, you're all talk.
Ultimately, you can't save anyone.
I can't pull out my sword.
Caught you.
Is he clenching his abdominal muscles?
My abs are pretty toned.
Right!?
That red eye. Is it...
Bloodshot?
You don't know what this eye means?
Nope.
I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
Okay.
This eye is called "Evil Eye."
The Eye of the Devil temporarily disables
the magic of all who fall under its gaze.
Magic is everything in this world.
Thus, I am a pariah. A target of scorn.
SLUMP...
I feel kinda bad now.
You can't use that eye on me at all.
It's fine.
I'm the natural enemy of all magic users.
I've been feared and despised my whole life.
By everyone. Even my parents.
Though, someone as seemingly blessed as you
probably can't understand.
There are people in this world
who should have never been born.
Acceleraise Secondth.
Force Field.
An arro...
Surprised by your lack of speed?
This field decreases the speed
of everyone else within it...
and grants that speed to me.
You won't get me a second time.
This is truly the end.
What is he...
So much power, even when slowed...
But at that level, my attacks...
I see.
He split the floor
to narrow down my movement route.
I need to pull back
and regain my balance...
My foot.
Got you... a second time.
Full Muscles Magic.
Hurricane Rush.
My Secondth spell
was shattered by ridiculous violence?
Glutes!
We're on entirely different levels.
If I lose here, I...
My reason for living will...
Acceleraise!
Forearm!
Quadriceps!
Pectorals!
Iliopsoas!
Erector Spinae.
I cannot help but think.
What if I'd been born normal?
I was still a young child
when my eye manifested.
My parents were shocked, of course.
I was an affront to God's gift of magic.
The Eye of the Devil.
Just like the markless children they cull,
my existence was aberrant to this world.
My family locked me in a cell in the basement
so people wouldn't know I existed.
At set times,
food appeared right outside my cell.
That was my life for a while,
until one day...
My parents tried to kill me.
They must have been at their wits' end
for having a child like me.
I had come to a realization.
That I never should have been born.
However, Lord Abel needed me.
Even if it was simply to be a useful tool.
I couldn't even meet that expectation.
Once again, I'm back
to being unwanted by anyone.
You're probably right
about me being blessed.
I can't even begin
to put myself in your place.
But we could become friends, then...
You're an amenable one, aren't you?
I honestly envy you.
But that's impossible.
As long as I have this eye,
your attitude toward me will shift someday, too.
But for your kindness,
let me advise you.
Please do not progress any further.
You cannot defeat Lord Abel.
What you saw when you faced him
was nowhere near his true powers.
Even if you've retained
some stamina in this victory—
Thank you for warning me.
But I have to give him
a good walloping. So, you know.
Oh, and I won't change my mind.
No matter how much
the world loathes your eye.
No matter what others say
about you because of it.
My attitude toward you won't change.
That's how Pops raised me.
Me, who can't use magic.
We should eat cream puffs
together next time.
Later.
What a strange guy.
NEXT EPISODE
MASH BURNEDEAD AND THE DIVINE VISIONARY