Abyss Razor.
Starting now, I will give your eye
a better purpose.
Starting today, you are my tool.
Come along.
Lord Abel.
Around the time when Mash and the gang
were victorious over Magia Lupus...
I wonder how Mash is doing now.
I hope people didn't find out he can't
use magic and make a big deal out of it.
I'm in trouble if he doesn't do his best
to become Divine Visionary.
It's part of my future planning, after all.
You don't need to work?
Time on screen is better than work.
Time on screen is important.
Yeah, it's important.
You want some more tea?
Yeah.
Allow me to regale it again.
This story is where Mash Burnedead with
no magical powers enters Easton Magic Academy,
Hip, hip, hooray!
and becomes Divine Visionary...
Wait, they're still getting carried away!
Main character! Main character!
Heroine! Heroine! I am heroine!
You are hero?
Oh yeah!
Hip, hip, hooray!
How long are they going to do that?
How long are they doing that?
Oh, is it all right if I go to the bathroom?
He must’ve been holding it all this time.
Anyway, guess that's over.
Right.
All the students that were turned into puppets
are back to normal now.
But this school
is such a hive of lawlessness.
And that thrill accelerates romance.
What the heck?
By the way, where is that handsome punk?
Did he lose or something?
I don't think Lance would lose.
Huh? That was really fast...
Who are you?
Get lost.
Ow! What the hell d'ya...
What's with the wounds?
Did you lose against someone?
You couldn't even rise
to the top of this school.
You're pretty pathetic.
But I do appreciate you...
for giving us intel
about Headmaster Wahlberg.
My hands are moving on their own.
You didn't find the one
we're searching for though.
But it turns out that
we don't need you anymore.
We don’t need—
We can all party with orange juice
and cream puffs.
Huh?
What's with that brat
who can't read the room?
Huh? It kinda feels like...
Mash, this is bad. We're in no mood
for stuff like that right now.
Wait, where did you get
those cream puffs from?
SPLCK SPLCK SPLCK SPLCK SPLCK
Was it coincidence!?
Was it intentional?
Um, sorry to bother you, but we were gonna
eat those, so could you give them back?
He's going to eat cream puffs in that state?
Shock!
SHOCK
Insolent boy.
What is this headache?
Is it resonance?
But I didn't have this headache
when I arrived.
It can't possibly be
this guy that just came in?
Really, him?
Huh?
Is this guy
the one we've been searching for?
What?
Oh, fine.
First, to finish what I came here for.
Killing Abel as planned!
It's useless.
Can’t you see? You’re no match...
for someone like me.
Now die.
Abyss!
Mask Guy.
I-I'm sorry, Mash.
It looks like I won't be able...
to eat cream puffs with you.
Take this.
A magic handkerchief.
My attack was not fatal?
That Mushroom Head threw a rock at me
right before my spell to alter the trajectory.
So this guy really is...
Abel's lapdog, huh? How admirable.
Is that your gratitude for being adopted
despite being an eyesore of society?
That's really revolting.
He's stomping the ground?
He caught it.
Amazing!
Hey. You're quite the rebel.
I won't hesitate to kill you too!
Huh? Why are you licking a rock?
Are you in that kind of phase?
Anyway...
I've gotta get Mask Guy to an infirmary.
Try to stop me
and I'll beat the stuffing out of you.
Beat the stuffing outta me, huh?
All right.
How does 30 minutes sound for how long
he has before he's beyond help?
Will you be able to save him?
What's wrong?
I thought you were going
to beat the stuffing outta me?
Or are you all talk?
He can't win.
There's too big of a gap
in the qualities they were born with.
Qualities.
Mother often said to me it was only
by chance that we were born privileged.
Birthright, talent, appearance.
It was chance that bestowed
those advantages on people.
That's why...
Don't zone out now, Abel!
Carborain!
It's impossible.
We are unquestionably inferior.
We cannot win against him.
Abyss was a fool.
He didn't have to make an effort
to protect me at all.
I think he was happy.
He was all alone for the longest time.
It was so tough for him to keep living.
And that's why I think
he was happy that you needed him.
I thought about how I would feel
if I was in a similar situation.
So...
I'm going to save him.
I think Mask Guy
wants to eat cream puffs, too.
It was only by chance
that we were born privileged.
Birthright, talent, appearance.
They're mere coincidences.
That's why, Abel...
Learn to put yourself in another's position.
If you can do that...
You will become
just a little bit kinder to others.
Yes, just a little... kinder to others.
Just accept it!
Carborain!
L-Lord Abel...
Abyss!
It's the Eye of the Devil! Run!
Stay away from me!
I wish I didn't give birth to you!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I was ever born.
I've heard you possess the Eye of the Devil?
I'm sorry.
I'll be careful not to make eye contact.
There's no need to hide it.
Will you use that eye for my sake?
I can't possibly do that.
Because of this eye,
everyone will avoid you as well.
That doesn't matter to me.
Starting now,
I will give your eye a better purpose.
Starting today, you are my tool.
Come along.
P-Please...
P-Please... run while... you can...
Always so noble.
Mother.
And Abyss.
Carborain!
Is that all you can manage?
You poor, pitiful, pathetic, miserable thing!
Hurry up, or you'll run out of time!
Mash.
This is bad.
Not only are those carbon-nugget things
rock-solid, but there's too many of them.
Mash is slowly pushing forward,
but he doesn't have enough time to get up close.
But then, if I headed over to help Mash,
the two left here will be in danger.
I can't move from here.
I'm getting bored of this.
Carbo Heavy Rain!
What? A higher-ranked version!?
Oh no. It's getting even more hopeless
to make it in time.
Should I go assist him? Damn it.
Mash!
The strong take from the weak,
and that's their right.
And...
The weak oppose the strong,
and that's also their right.
What's the meaning of this, Abel?
I'm seeing for myself what is righteous,
with my own hands.
Hmph. I see.
Carbo Heavy Rain!
Too bad.
You can't win with this kind of magic...
Hey there.
You're the first to break through
my rigid epidermis.
Even though I was caught off guard.
What magic did you use?
Huh?
I'm asking you what your personal magic is.
Huh... Um...
Power.
Power!?
Such magic exists!?
Hmph. So you're refusing to answer me.
Whatever.
That's...
the Spellflection Mirror!
A powerful magical item that reflects
any and every spell cast its way!
And the stronger the spell,
the more fearsome the mirror makes it!
The most feared magical item
that makes every magic user cower in terror.
I thought the Bureau of Magic
was guarding it. So why...
Mash, don't!
We magic users don't stand a chance
against that thing!
It'll send your spells right back at you!
One mistake and you're as good as dead!
If you're gonna beat it,
you have to do it without using magic.
But such a feat...
It's because you got in my way.
I'll make all of you regret it.
Now, use your magic.
You can fall to your ruin
with your own magical power...
if you can even do...
It's...
It's not magic!
Then, that time...
And that time...
This, that, and just now!
Y-You mean nothing until now was magic?
Mash did everything with his body alone?
Seriously?
- That would be unbelievable.
- Totally unbelievable, right?
That would be like something
out of a fantasy story.
Like, exactly from a fantasy story.
That sounds like a fantasy story.
What? It didn't work against him at all!
Did this appear because I touched that kid?
That headache earlier, too.
So he really is...
I see.
What is that?
Today was surprisingly productive
thanks to meeting you.
My name is Cell War.
INNOCENT ZERO
CELL WAR
I remembered I had an urgent errand,
so I'll be going now.
But we'll be seeing each other again soon.
Bye-bye.
If you're going home,
I'm thankful that you're going home.
Now, let's take Mask Guy
to the infirmary.
You don't have to worry about that.
Thanks to the handkerchief you gave him,
it looks like things won't be too serious.
P-Please treat me...
to cream puffs next time.
Mask Guy.
I will take responsibility
and take Abyss back.
I give you my thanks,
Mash Burnedead.
I will make sure to return the favor.
I guess that settles it.
Yeah.
Wait, hold up!
Whaddaya mean,
none of that was magic!?
That's actually amazing,
but isn't it terrible if people found out?
It's terrible, Mash! Being expelled
might not be the end of it!
N-N-N-N-No-No-No, I-I-I-I c-c-can use m-m-m-magic-c-c-c-c-c-c-c...
TREMBLE TREMBLE TREMBLE
He's losing it!
He must have a really important reason.
Anyway, we've gotta protect Mash's secret
so people won't find out.
Right!
If Mash's record gets tarnished,
it'll affect our married life, too.
Anyway, we can shelter Mash for now,
at least until we figure out a plan.
Thanks, guys.
He just said "thanks"!
I wasn't expecting him
to acknowledge everything.
But this is turning into a hell of a mess.
If they find out we're protecting Mash's secret,
we'll definitely be in trouble, too.
We might be expelled, too.
No!
I heard everything!
A student who can't use magic in our school?
That's an outrage!
I'm telling the teachers!
We're in trouble!
The students who were turned into puppets...
They had woken up!
A student at a magic school can't use magic?
Report him! Report, report, report!
HONK
This time has finally come.
He's not phased at all!
People have finally caught on
to Mash's inability to use magic.
What will you do, Mash!?
NOM NOM NOM
This puts a hard stop on a happy life
together with your Pops!
Father.
My apologies for taking so much time.
But I have found it. What was lost.
I see. At last...
At last, my most earnest wish will come true.
Go retrieve it.
DIVINE VISIONARY SELECTION EXAM ARC
SEASON 2 COMING IN 2024