What are we gonna do?
Fucking Sandy's mine.
Why's this runt even got it chipped?
Uninstall's gonna cost us a hot eddie.
Fuck! Meddling kid's
more trouble than he's worth.
What if we ice him?
How much would we save
taking it off his dead back?
Won't change that much.
But it'd be cheaper?
Just barely.
Hear that? I should just
rip the damn thing off myself.
Teach you not to steal people's shit.
Don't make a mess in my room.
Stay outta this!
Excuse me? I'm the one that found him.
You lied to me?
Shut up.
What the fuck are you doing
with my Sandevistan?
Your…?
Yeah, the one I bought from my supplier.
Except the moment I paid,
she fucking ghosted.
That's what you get for paying upfront.
Dumbass.
Shut it!
She's our people!
Said she needed cash real fast.
Guess everyone's a grifter nowadays.
Wait.
Your supplier's…
Gloria Martinez. Ring a bell?
She's my mom.
You're Gloria's kid?
The hell's she doing, giving it to you?
She died.
Just yesterday.
Yesterday? I was just
talking to her two days ago.
What happened?
The fuzz get her?
Car accident.
Some kinda gangoon drive-by…
Got caught in the crossfire.
Nothing to do with the Sandevistan.
Ow!
Checks out why she never called back.
Condolences, kid. But…
Don't think this lets you off the hook.
I didn't know it was yours.
Even so…
What kinda gonk just installs an implant
not knowing who it belonged to?
Kid's outta his damn mind!
He didn't know what he was doing.
You guys… are cyberpunks?
What's it to ya?
Let me keep the Sandy.
I'll pay you back one job at a time.
Not good enough. That's military-grade.
Can't just buy it off the shelf.
I'll pay you back what you paid my mom.
No deal.
Don't start cutting him up here.
Let me run jobs for you.
Now that's funny.
What am I gonna do with an amateur?
I can use the implant.
No way. Kid can't boot
the thing without keeling over.
You might be surprised.
Body his size would sizzle after two hits.
I did eight.
C'mon. That's bull and we all know it.
Yeah? Why don't I show you?
Sit your ass down, kid.
Chill. Just gonna klep his cig.
That's all…
Wha?
That makes it nine times today…
Or is that ten?
Well, fuck me. This kid's crazy!
Give me a chance.
Chance? What chance?
Take me on a job.
I'll make it worth your time.
Some balls you got there, kid.
Fine. One chance.
Here we go again.
I owe it to Gloria.
Thanks, you won't--
Hey…
Chill. Just slotting a tracer.
Don't want you to go AWOL on us.
I ain't gonna run.
Yeah, yeah. That's what they all say.
You'll be hearing from me tomorrow.
So those are the guys you roll with.
Yeah.
You could've said--
I didn't plan this at first.
Maine wouldn't shut up
about his prized Sandy going missing…
And saw you using it.
Looked into it and realized
you had the one.
Then you held me here 'til they showed…
Lied this whole time.
Just go home already.
Fine.
About your mom…
Sorry for your loss.
This is an exceptionally rare opportunity
and a great honor. Congratulations.
However,
there is still the matter of your recent
violent behavior on Academy grounds.
Now, I spoke with Mr. Tanaka
and he has graciously agreed
to strike several demerits from
your record should you offer an apology.
For details, please--
Over here, kid.
Morning, sunshine.
Data wasn't lying. He is just a kid.
Can he keep up?
We'll see.
Now, I know he's a sweet thing,
but don't go getting all soft on him.
Why do we even put up with you?
This is Kiwi. You've met Dorio and Pilar.
Take a seat.
I'm David--
Shut up.
Straight to business.
Slot the shard.
Say hello to Arasaka Corp driver
and bodyguard…
Maxim.
We're gonna swipe the navigation data
from the limo he drives.
The data? Not the limo?
We take the limo and Arasaka'll
set their ninjas on us like flies on shit.
No. We're only after the data.
How?
Betting on boxing is
this guy's sole joy in life.
You can bet his ass is in
one of those seats every weekend.
Always puts a stack on the Butcher,
banking on her skull-splitting uppercut.
Safe to say most people only go to see her
beat the shit out of the other boxers.
Except…
This weekend
the bitch is going down in round one.
How do you know that?
We just do.
He always drowns his sorrows
at this hole-in-the-wall when he loses.
You make your move
when he's three sheets to the wind.
Get the key and hand it off to Dorio.
She'll make a copy.
Then we sneak in and steal the navi data,
all while the corpo's still shit-faced.
Leave that bit to us,
but you'll have to get the key
back into his slot without him noticing.
And that's all there is.
Watch it!
Oh my gosh, I'm sorryyy.
I'll take care of it.
Get in.
You got this?
Shh. Focusing.
Arasaka's security
is such a pain in the ass.
Sorry again, dude!
That's alright, sweetheart.
I'll make it up to you next time.
Thieving bitch!
Huh? What do you mean?
You're so scary!
We're blown. Target's coming in hot.
-Status?
-Just a lil' more.
Time's up. Cut it!
Almost…
Done.
It won't open!
Open up! You piece of shit!
Hey! Stop! My car!
-I'll put in the route.
-Thanks.
Think we can do it?
All up to you now.
Look at you, Mr. Chauffeur.
I'm a natural.
Maybe, if the autopilot wasn't on.
Whatever.
Got company.
Tyger Claws?!
Maxim must've put up a bounty.
Already?
That's why you don't fuck with corpos.
They got more control here.
Get on the highway.
Why ya running, choom?!
Come back and fight, cowards!
Where ya going?!
Gonna lose them soon.
Shit. Traffic?!
Oh my…
Not good.
They're gaining on us.
Slow-ass!
-Strap up!
-Huh?
Get back here,
you murdering son of a bitch!
You're dead!
It's closed.
They should be here by now.
Well, at least the jammer is holding up.
When did the door unlock?
A long while ago.
Stay here. I'll check it out.
Come on now, don't run away.
Let's play a lil' more!
Die!
I'll make you bleed!
Ew…
Sorry for the wait.
Check this!
Well, not too bad for a rookie.
We cool now?
Welcome to the club.
But don't forget, kid.
There ain't no one in this world
you can trust more than yourself.
Don't use us as crutches, or you'll die.
Okay.
Check out the precision, chooms!
Can't beat these fingers!
From what I hear, those fingers
do a whole lotta beating.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'll give you a test drive
if you're asking for one!
Thanks.
Immunosuppressants.
About one month's worth.
And…
Your cut.
This is a lot.
Everybody gets a fair shake.
Only way I operate.
You still mostly organic?
Huh?
Once you have enough dough,
start fixing yourself up.
Skin 'n' bone won't be able to
keep up with the Sandevistan.
You're right.
Could've made easy work of that Tyger Claw
or any of the trash out there.
It ain't wasted ennies if it makes
you stronger. That's what I say.
Be it chrome…
or my crew.
Shit…
I believe I requested
the navigation data, not the limo.
We got what you asked for.
What I asked for was discretion.
We tried, but you know how things can be.
Had to improvise.
It was imperative to find
where Tanaka frequents.
So break down the navi and you'll know.
He has already changed sites.
Your joyride puts us back at square one
and put Tanaka on high alert.
Changed sites for what?
That is not for you to know.
Damn it! How we supposed to do the job
if you keep us in the dark?
The less information you have,
the lower the risk for us.
Get that through your head.
You are not being paid to think.
You are being paid to check off
the boxes on my checklist.
It is my place to see the larger picture,
it is yours to listen.
Are we clear?
Yeah. No problems here.
Good. Now will wait until
the target lets his guard down again.
I'll be in touch.
Yeah. Sure.
Who was that?
Faraday. He brought us this job.
He's also the best fixer around.
I thought you were the boss.
I'm the one that gets shit done.
He's the one who pays us.
If you ain't got cash, you ain't nothing
in this business. Easy and simple.
Don't think too hard on it.
We're celebrating today.
Yo.
Sorry, you're…
You don't remember me?!
After all we've been through…
You were at the bar.
You like my performance?
Sure.
I'm Rebecca. I heard you're
joining Maine's team?
Probably. Is this carbonated?
Cheers! Then I guess I'll be seeing
a lot more of you.
Cheers.
Uh, it's fine.
I trust you received the message I left?
Yeah, I got it.
Excellent. Now, about your
apology to Mr. Tanaka--
Pass this along to Katsuo for me.
Er, perhaps you should--
If he wants revenge, I'll be waiting.
But I'm done going easy.
You can all kiss my ass.