Sure enough, there aren't any more books written about the Philosopher's Stone.
Older Brother - 15
Younger Brother - 14
What that minister had was a fake,
and once again, we don't have any other leads.
How about we head
back to Central, then?
Brother!
Look!
"An Introduction to Alchemy."
This sure takes me back.
Huh, it does?
Hey,
this is boring!
Older Brother - 6
Younger Brother - 5
Hold on, just a little longer.
All right, done!
Watch this, Winry!
You said you were giving me a present.
And we're making your present right now.
That was our very first transmutation.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Take the memories of distant days, tear them up with your own hands,
kimi no te de kirisaite tooi hi no kioku wo
and squeeze the life out of your sorrows for me
kanashimi no iki no ne wo tomete kure yo
Come on, and pierce my heart as it yearns for your love!
saa, ai ni kogareta mune wo tsuranuke
Looking at the sky,
thinking tomorrow must be coming,
asu ga kuru hazu no sora wo mite
it's too much for my captivated heart to take
mayou bakari no kokoro mote amashite iru
As a bird flutters along beside me,
katawara no tori ga habataita
I wonder where he managed to find his light
doko ka hikari wo mitsukerareta no ka na
Say, would you carry me along on your back as well?
naa, omae no se ni ore mo nosete kurenai ka?
And leave me at the highest place there is,
soshite ichiban takai tokoro de
far away from kindness?
okizari ni shite, yasashisa kara toozakete
Take the memories of distant days, tear them up with your own hands,
kimi no te de kirisaite tooi hi no kioku wo
and squeeze the life out of your sorrows for me
kanashimi no iki no ne wo tomete kure yo
Come on, and pierce my heart as it yearns for your love!
saa, ai ni kogareta mune wo tsuranuke
Mother...
Winry, you were wrong to do that
after those two went to all that trouble.
That's right. Both Edward-chan and Alphonse-chan were doing it for you.
I'm really sorry about this.
No matter how much they learn,
the usual person gives up
somewhere along the way.
However, those boys are already magnificent alchemists.
But those boys shouldn't know anything about alchemy.
They are his sons after all.
So when did your dad
teach you about alchemy?
How could we learn anything from someone who isn't ever around?
It was written in that book.
You can understand something as difficult as this?
More or less.
Did we do anything wrong?
No, you did outstanding!
I think I'll brag to everyone about it.
Be sure to put the books back where you find them.
Once Dad comes home,
make sure to thank him. And lastly,
do not open that door.
Understood!
Here they are!
Dad departed without telling anyone where he was going,
so Mom started staring off into the distance a lot.
But still, once we began practicing alchemy,
she would smile at us
more frequently.
Mother was praising us.
We competed with each other
as we became absorbed in alchemy.
Mom!
Older Brother - 8
Younger Brother - 7
Look, look!
See?
Oh, my!
Brother made it!
I can still only do this.
Incredible, both of you!
You certainly are his children!
Would Father commend us too?
Yes.
Once he comes home,
I'm sure he will.
I'm going over to Winry's!
Brother!
Brother,
do you hate Father?
I wouldn't say I hate him...
I just don't remember him too well.
Whenever anyone talks about him, Mom makes a strange face.
That's what I don't like.
S-Sorry...
Let's go over to Winry's!
Wh-What do you mean?
Just like I told you!
My mom and dad are dead.
B-But your folks are doctors, right?
That's right. That's why they went to the war in Ishbal,
and now they're dead.
W-Winry,
our father is...
kind of in the same situation...
It's not the same!
If you're dead, that means
you can never come back again!
It's not as though you can't ever come back.
I read so in a book.
There's this artificial person thing,
called a homunculus.
It sounds sort of like a doll that doesn't have a mind.
But with alchemy,
your folks could probably be—
Stop right there!
That is something
which is not allowed!
Alchemy is not all-powerful.
That's why we Automail
engineers exist, you know.
Dirty old hag...
I feel sorry for Winry.
What's the matter with you two?
What's the matter, Edward? You're such a big boy.
This looks funny, you know.
Al, you're so slow!
Older Brother - 10
Younger Brother - 9
Mom, sorry we're late!
Mom...
Mom!
She hasn't been sick since just today or yesterday.
She must've been suffering
from this illness for years now.
Honey...
These here are letters
that came for him.
If we send a letter to
each one of them...
Someone will know where he is and tell him to come home?
I don't want him to come home!
But we don't have any choice! Damn!
Your dad...
left us this money.
I haven't touched it.
Use that,
and the two of you
take care of each other.
What are you talking about, Mom?
Would you transmute something for me...
Edward?
I know...
A corsage would be nice.
He... always...
made them... for me.
The reason Mom was so thrilled to see us practicing alchemy
was that it reminded her of Dad.
That's what we finally realized.
Brother...
I'm hungry.
I'm cold as well.
Let's go home.
Al...
Let's...
bring Mom back.
Look, here in his notes!
I don't understand it all,
but something about human transmutation is written here!
If we can decipher this...
But it's written here that human transmutation is forbidden.
If dead people can come back to life,
then of course it would make anyone happy.
Nobody has succeeded,
and they're all frustrated,
so the grown-ups have just prohibited it.
Al, if you, me, and Mom can all live happily together again,
then Mom would be thrilled!
Still, maybe we should
ask Dad about this first...
It's his fault that Mom died!
Mom was always waiting for him,
and he didn't even
come home for her funeral!
If this is something that he
couldn't do, then we'll do it!
We're gonna do it!
We found ourselves a teacher
and learned alchemy from the beginning.
And then, one day...
Water, 35 liters;
carbon, 20 kilograms; ammonia, 4 liters;
lime, 1.5 kilograms...
Phosphorus, 800 grams;
salt, 250 grams; saltpeter, 100 grams;
fluorine, 7.5 grams;
iron, 5 grams; silicon, 3 grams...
These are the elements that comprise an adult human—
the structural formula.
By including a soul in this,
we should be able to call Mom's spirit back and connect it with her body once again.
Brother, are you sure we should?
After we've come this far, Al?
But still, alchemy is about
equivalent exchange, right?
We've got the ingredients for the body,
but what do we exchange for Mom's spirit?
Don't worry, just stick out your finger.
Information...
about the soul...
That's everything.
Let's do it, Al.
The village of Resembool...
Brother, something's not right here!
Al!
Brother!
Brother! Brother!
Al!
The last thing I saw
was the sight of Brother's left leg
being broken down and disappearing.
And then...
What is this?
I'm sorry, Al.
Brother!
Brother, what happened to me? And...
your arm...
With just my right arm,
I was only able to bond your spirit to the armor that was sitting over there.
Brother...
So, what about Mom?
It wasn't...
human.
That can't be...
How come? Brother, your theories should have been perfect.
My theories weren't what was wrong.
What was wrong...
was us.
Grandma!
Brother...
Help my brother!
Al...
is that you?
You guys are back from your training?
So then, why?
Don't tell me you were thinking of creating your mom.
So that's it. That was the light
of human transmutation, huh?
I've never seen such a furious reaction in a transmutation before.
Pardon me.
A State Alchemist?
What business does
the military have here?
As you can see, these boys
have suffered grave injuries.
This letter came my way.
That's one that Brother sent to Dad's acquaintances!
We've been searching for your father, Hohenheim, for a long time.
We still don't know
where their father is.
There are hurt people here. Go away.
If they performed human transmutation
and escaped with their lives,
then I am more interested in them
than in their father.
They could make fine State Alchemists.
This boy hasn't done anything.
Go away, we have things to do here.
I am State Alchemist
Lt. Col. Roy Mustang.
Come pay a visit to Central.
Uh, good morning, Winry.
Al! You're awake?!
I-I'm sorry, I was just...
Grandma, in the house, there's some money...
You dummy, don't be worried over something as trivial as that.
That's not what I meant.
Use that money and fix me up
with some Automail.
I'm going to go see that Roy guy from earlier
and become a State Alchemist.
I'll need the freedom of my own arms and legs to do so, right?
You mean, you were listening?
I heard about them from my teacher. If I become a State Alchemist,
I'll be able to read valuable documents that the state is in charge of.
I'll also be provided an allowance
and allowed to do research on my own.
What's more, that watch
can amplify an alchemist's power.
Didn't your teacher tell you this?
Once war breaks out,
you will be brought into it,
and if ordered, use your alchemy to
take lives for the good of the people.
In the war that claimed
my own sons' lives,
there were State Alchemists involved.
I don't care if I have to become
a dog of the military or whatever.
There is something that I have to do.
Ed, are you still at it?
Just bear with us. This is the highest-quality stuff I can make!
We're okay! Don't come in!
I'm surprised.
Even adults scream at the pain of attaching each nerve to the mechanisms.
This pain is nothing...
compared to his.
It's been a while.
Shall we go at it,
Brother?
"To train the mind,
one must train the body."
That's what Teacher said.
But, Al, are you going to be able to handle it in that body?
I'm not going to lose
to some Automail!
Brother, are you serious about becoming a State Alchemist?
I don't know whether or not I can become one,
but I am going to go see that Roy guy.
Don't do it.
I've made up my mind.
Well then, I'll become one!
You can't.
Brother, are you still
planning to transmute Mom?
You said at the time that we were wrong to do so, didn't you?
I'll become a State Alchemist,
and then I'll find a way to
get your arm and leg back.
You don't have to worry about that.
But it's my fault!
If I had objected,
you wouldn't have lost your leg!
And then you lost your arm in order to bond my spirit...
What about you? What are you supposed to do with that body?
Brother...
I'm going to go find a way
to get you back to normal.
You won't try anything with Mom, right?
Mnye nye v chem tebya upreknut'
I have nothing to reproach you with,
It's likely that there isn't anything in the world
I ya nye obihen nichut'
and I bear no grudge at all
that we can exchange
equivalently for Mom's life.
And besides...
I don't want to lose you too.
Tyazhek, nash gryekh
Grievous is our sin
In that case,
I'm going with you.
khotet' byit' silneye vsekh
to desire to be stronger than anybody
But why?
Brother, you slack off too quickly! If I'm not around...
Milaya mama! Nyezhnaya!
Dear mother! Affectionate one!
That's what you're getting at?
And I...
don't ever want us
to get separated again.
Myi tak lyubili tebya
We loved you so much
No vse nashi silyi
But all our efforts
potrachenyi byili zrya
were spent in vain
Ya sam soblaznilsya
I was lured myself
Even though they
were our own bodies,
pryekprasnoy nadyezhdoy
with the beautiful hope
we would still be seeking to perform a forbidden human transmutation.
vernut' nash semeinyiy ochag
to regain our familial hearth
If unsuccessful,
this time we would probably
disappear from this world for good.
Ya sam vo vsem vinovat
It’s all my own fault
There would be no telling what further punishment we would receive.
There could be no
turning back for us.
And so, on the day
we left on our journey,
Older Brother - 11
Younger Brother - 10
we burned down our house.
With you always in my sight, I can manage to draw breath
itsumo no shisen ni kimi ga ite kokyuu ga dekiru
And for me, that ought to be enough in itself, and yet...
boku ni totte nara sore dake de mou juubun na hazu na no ni
All little old me ever does is repeat the same old mistakes
chippoke na boku wa kurikaesu ayamachi bakari
How much strength do I need to come by
dore hodo tsuyosa wo te ni shitara
before I can get by without hurting anything?
nanimo kizutsukezu ni sumu no?
I am not going to stray, I'm going to trust this love,
mayowazu ni kono ai wo,
and with it I will go on living!
shinjikite yuku
I'm going to take these wounds,
fusagaranu
the ones that will not close, and squeeze them tight!
kizuguchi mo gyutto dakishimete
The two of us must keep on walking,
futari wa arukitsuzukeru
since we can never return again
ato ni wa modorenai kara
Even now, deep within my heart,
ima demo kono mune no oku,
I still feel the pain of this indelible sin
kesenai tsumi wa itamu kedo
Darling
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Transmutation of Love
Episode 4: "Transmutation of Love"
When a doll takes on life, a man learns of his own foolishness.
And yet he'll do it again
if he can transmute love.