Nice of you to come.
I welcome you.
You don't look very welcoming.
I am he who was entrusted to guard this place.
For the time being,
you may call me Number 48.
Number 48?
It's been so long. I'm delighted to be able to go against someone so capable.
You have run out of luck
by coming up against me.
Do not think ill of me, kid.
And you, don't think ill of me for being the kid who defeated you.
Nice. You move well for your size.
That's more like it.
Who are you?!
I should respond when
asked who I am, huh?
My name is Number 66.
Although, that's just what they call me at work.
Number 66?
Yes. I do have my own, proper name as well,
but if you heard it, you'd be
so surprised you'd wet yourself.
I'll tell you when I finish you off.
His reflexes...
Why, you!
What?!
You brat!
He's...
the same kind of armored body as Al?!
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Ready, steady, can't hold me back
Ready, steady, give me good luck
Ready, steady, never look back
Let's get started, ready, steady, go!
The landscape blows on by me
fuki tonde iku fuukei
as I roll my way forward
korogaru you ni mae e
And even if things get desperate,
kurushimagire demo
I won't lose sight of the goal now!
hyouteki wa mou minogasanai
You can take those unreliable maps
ate ni naranai chizu
and just burn them up!
yaite shimaeba ii sa
I'm going to take those hidden truths
uzumoreta shinjitsu
and snatch them in the palm of my hand!
kono tenohira de tsukami torou
Delirious, (speedily),
I've broken through this far,
muchuu de (hayaku) kakenukete kita
Delirious, (speedily),
I've broken through this far,
muchuu de (hayaku) kakenukete kita
my heart beating so loud and hard, it feels like it's about to burst!
urusai kurai ni harisake sou na kodou no takanari
Your voice echoes as you call out to me,
hibiite (yonde) iru kimi no koe
but I just don't have the time to stop where I am!
koko de tachidomaru you na jikan wa nai sai
Ready, steady, go!
Please, trust me!
Soul of the Guardian
I knew it.
Just as I thought, you're hollow.
Surprising. You've done well to realize it.
I spar against someone like you all the time.
I could tell by
the way you moved.
There's someone like me
in the outside world, is there?
It bugs me to think
that there's some idiot besides me who
thought of bonding a soul to a suit of armor.
Fascinating.
Allow me to reintroduce myself.
"Number 48" is the label I had as a condemned prisoner.
Officially, I'm supposed to have been executed two years ago.
A condemned prisoner?
Which means that, sure enough, there's a connection
between the 5th Laboratory here and the prison next door.
When I had a flesh-and-blood body,
I was called "The Slicer."
I was a mass murderer,
who caused many public disturbances.
Nowadays, my skills have been called upon,
and I am the immortal watchdog over this place.
No, you're not immortal.
What?
Your bloodseal!
The iron within the blood is attuned with the metal of your armor,
and that is what keeps your soul
bound to this world.
If that seal is broken, you'll die.
It appears that after all this time,
I've encountered someone with a little backbone.
This should prove to be an interesting fight.
Your weak spot
has been exposed.
If you're going to surrender, now's the time.
I don't care!
I'm the type who seeks a little tension in battle, you see.
Now then...
En garde!
What was that? Just now there was something strange in my shoulder...
Since it's less heavy,
its strength has dropped as well,
so make sure you don't do anything reckless.
I have to finish this quickly, or I'm in trouble!
Just like a monkey, aren't you?
Hey, what'd you say?!
It's been ages since I've had
such responsive prey. I'm delighted.
However, judging by your wound and your exhaustion,
the end of this battle is in sight.
As you can see,
my body knows no fatigue.
Surrender. Right now, my companion is disposing of your partner outside.
You can't rely on him to help you.
Hey, this companion
of yours—is he strong?
He's strong although not to
the same extent as myself.
What's so funny?
In that case,
I don't need to worry.
I've been sparring with him
for a long time, but I've never won.
Why, you...
Hold still so I can chop you up!
You miserable behemoth!
I'm going to hurt you
for all you're worth!
So you tell me...
Now!
I'm taking a shoulder roast!
Now you've gone and done it.
My head fell off.
Your body...
Yeah. Thanks to certain circumstances, I've wound up with this body.
You can't tell who I am, can you?
Don't tell me you've forgotten.
Thanks to you guys catching me,
I was made a condemned criminal, after all.
Number 66 was my label on death row.
When I still had a flesh-and-blood body, the name people called me by was...
the serial killer, Barry the Chopper!
Barry the Chopper?
Barry? You mean, from back then?!
That's right!
After being caught and executed,
I've come back from the depths of hell
to take revenge against you!
You don't say.
Don't "you don't say" me!
People get surprised when
an executed prisoner is still alive, you know!
And what's more, when a beheaded suit of armor still moves around,
you should be more like "Gyaah!"
or like "Waah!" or like "What's the deal with your body?!" or like...
Gyaah! What's the deal
with your body?!
That's awful. You'll hurt my feelings, you know.
Are you a fellow
executed prisoner too?
I'm no criminal!
Even so, now that I know, this fight is all mine.
I know what your weakness is!
If I destroy the bloodseal within
that armor someplace, you will die.
Brace yourself!
The same goes for you too, right?
Yeah, but you don't know
where my bloodseal is, do you?!
And you don't know
where mine is, do you?
At this point,
I'll just have to slice you up and
find out where your bloodseal is!
What's with him? Jeez...
B Block and C Block have both turned up nothing.
He must still be in the area somewhere! Find him, whatever it takes!
Yes, sir!
He's pretty bold to be staging an attack on a military facility like this.
Still, why is Scar so preoccupied with coming after Edward-san?
So then, where are
the Elric brothers?
Uh, yeah, well, you see...
It's like this...
You're acting suspiciously!
Major Armstrong!
With your authorization,
could I have the forces here relocate?
What do you mean?
The Elric brothers are currently
at the Central 5th Laboratory.
Tell me more.
What's the matter?
Your movements are growing poorer.
Are you through already, Pee-Wee?
Who are you calling too small to even see, who doesn't even make for a good target?!
At least your spirits are high.
But I wonder how much longer that will last!
Not the Automail again!
You're open!
You hold me in too low a regard.
Did you think you could best me
from a spear's distance?
Ridiculous!
You've done well to have fought this long. However, you have reached your limits.
Resign yourself.
There is no way you can win now.
We'll see about that.
You're forgetting that I'm not alone.
Now, Al!
When did you get in here?!
What?!
That's not fair!
All is fair in battle.
What's wrong?
My bloodseal is not yet broken.
If your soul is in your head,
then once I cut it off,
your body is just a hunk of iron.
There's no reason to
fight you any longer.
Never mind that, there's something I wanted to ask you.
The Philosopher's Stone?
If you've come to investigate this place, there is little else you could be after.
In that case,
we can cut to the chase.
Why don't you tell me
everything you know about it?
I can't tell you.
What?!
Hey, beaten dogs
don't get to show me up.
I'll break your bloodseal!
I haven't lost yet.
That's...
impossible!
One set of armor isn't necessarily limited to one soul, you know.
The body has a bloodseal as well?
Are you okay,
my older brother?
Yeah, just barely,
my younger brother.
Younger brother?
Did I forget to mention that?
The mass murderer known as the Slicer...
was a pair of mass-murdering brothers!
An independent head and body, huh?
That reeks of foul play!
Who was it that said
"All is fair in battle"?
How dare you injure my brother!
You're going to pay for that, Pipsqueak!
Don't call me Pipsqueak!
Don't underestima—
Whoa, I'm not giving you any time to transmute!
I'm losing too much blood.
I'm seriously starting to get lightheaded.
This is serious trouble.
Am I going to die here?
Dammit!
If I die here...
who's going to return
Al back to normal?!
How dare you
do that to my brother!
I can do that too!
I won't give you
enough time to transmute!
I just remembered that nasty fellow.
What is this?!
He didn't perform transmutation,
just the decomposition technique?
Sorry about that.
I can't die just yet.
Dammit! Now you've gone and done it, you dirty brat!
Ick!
Why, you! Dammit!
I deserve better than this!
Damn. Brother...
As much as it pains me,
we've lost, Brother.
Don't tell me that there's
actually three of you brothers.
No, no.
Well done, kid.
This time, you truly are victorious.
Well then, this time,
tell me everything you know.
I cannot tell you.
Now, destroy us at once.
What?
Nothing remains for the defeated except death.
That is our rule.
I'm not about to kill anyone.
Hmph! You're far too generous!
With our bodies like this,
can you possibly call us "someone"?
I didn't tell you to kill us.
I told you to destroy us.
Come on!
If I were to concede that you aren't people,
I'd... I'd have to concede
that my younger brother,
Al, is not a person either.
Your younger brother?
Prosti menya, mladshiy brat!
Please forgive me, my junior brother,
Ya tak pred toboy vinovat
I’m so guilty towards you
Dammit!
Pyitatsya vernut' nyelzya
One shouldn’t try to regain
Hasn't this gone on long enough, already?
I'm concerned about Brother.
togo, chto vzyala zyemlya
what was taken by the earth
Brother?
That pipsqueak alchemist
is your brother?
Kto znayet zakon Byitiya,
The one who knows the law of Being
Brother gets angry
if you mention his height.
Ah, I see...
pomog byi mne nayti otvet
would be able to help me to find the answer
What?
Zhestoko oshibsya ya
I was grossly mistaken
So it was your brother who
gave you that armored form!
Ot smerti lekarstva nyet
There’s no medicine against death
That's right. He risked
his life to transmute me.
That's rich!
Milaya mama! Nyezhnaya!
Dear mother! Affectionate one!
What's so funny?!
Oh, how rude of me.
Myi tak lyubili tebya
We loved you so much
Brotherly love is so beautiful...
Even if it is false affection.
No vse nashi silyi
But all our efforts
False?
That's right! False love!
potrachenyi byili zrya
were spent in vain
That's not so!
My brother genuinely loves me!
Tebya soblaznil ya
I lured you
What a perfectly naïve fellow you are.
pryekrasnoy nadyezhdoy
with the beautiful hope
Suppose you were an imitation. What would you do then?
Suppose your personality and memories
vernut' nash semeynyiy ochag
to regain our familial hearth
were implanted in you as it suited
your brother. What would you do then?
Moy brat, ya vo vsem vinovat
My brother, it’s all my fault
Th-That just isn't so!
I am, without question, a person, whose name is Alphonse Elric!
As a spirit—something indefinite,
which cannot be seen with the eye—
how are you to prove that?
Your brother—and the people around you—
could all be deceiving you.
That's...
That's not...
Nye plach', nye pechal'sya, starshiy brat!
Please don’t cry, don’t be sad, my older brother!
My brother is a person,
Nye tyi odin vinovat
You’re not the only one to blame
and you guys are people too.
I don't want...
Doroga u nas odna
We’re along the same road
to kill you.
Iskupim vinu do dna
We’ll fully expiate our guilt
Brother?
Amusing... Quite amusing...
Milaya mama! Nyezhnaya!
Dear mother! Affectionate one!
For as long as I can remember,
Myi tak lyubili tebya
We loved you so much
my brother and I have made our lives
by stealing, breaking, killing, and being looked down upon as fiends and brutes.
No vse nashi silyi
But all our efforts
Now that we've abandoned our bodies, to say nothing of our hearts and minds,
potrachenyi byili zrya
were spent in vain
to think that, for the first time,
we're being treated as people...
Ya sam soblaznilsya
I was lured myself
It's so amusing!
pryekprasnoy nadyezhdoy
with the beautiful hope
I'm a person!
I'm Alphonse Elric!
vernut' nash semeinyiy ochag
to regain our familial hearth
Do you have any proof that you ever really existed?
Where is your body?
Ya sam vo vsem vinovat
It’s all my own fault
Huh?!
Well, it's...
It can't be...
For all of it to be false...
That couldn't possibly be...
Listen, Al...
There's something... I've been meaning to say to you for a long time...
but I've been too scared...
and I haven't been able to say it.
What is it?
What was Brother trying to tell me?
What was it that
he was too scared to...
too scared to tell me?
Brother!
We are still crying out
bokura wa ima demo sakenderu
You squeeze your right hand, as if to reassure yourself
tashikameru you ni nigirishimeta migite
Go on, take those annoying rules and dash them away!
uzattai housoku o buchikowashite yuke
If it comes down to having to rest your wounded feet,
kizutsuita ashi o yasumaseru gurai nara
you've gotta keep moving forward, if only just a step!
tatta ippo demo koko kara susume
We've pushed our way
through the twisting winds
yuganda kaze o kaki wakete
and gotten beyond the cold sky
tsumetai sora o oikoshite
Yet we still continue to wander
soredemo mada samayoi tsuzuketeru
We always find ourselves crying out
bokura wa itsudemo sakenderu
Just continuing to believe is not the answer
shinji tsuzukeru dake ga kotae janai
We must bare our weaknesses and wounds,
yowasa mo kizu mo sarake dashite
and continue to struggle,
or nothing will ever turn out!
mogaki tsuzukenakereba hajimaranai
Break on through to the other side of the door!
tsukiyabure tobira no mukou e
To the other side of the door!
tobira no mukou e
Fullmetal Alchemist...
The Red Glow
Episode 21: "The Red Glow"
If there's a color to people's lives...
that's probably the color it would be.