Tanjiro...
Listen to me...
Demon Slayer Corps
is not something you'd join for fun!
Guys like you gotta be purged!
Immediately!
Don't ever underestimate the Corps!
WISTERIA
Nezuko!
Zenitsu! Stop following her already!
Tan... ji... ro!
Let's be friends, Tanjiro!
Zenitsu! Don't keep chasing us! I beg you!
Oh, don't be like that, Tanjiro!
Nezuko!
- Tanjiro!
- Stop!
Nezuko!
Tanjiro!
Man, I'm hungry.
Pardon me, sir.
Those clothes of yours
are quite soiled, I see.
I'll clean them for you,
so please wear these in the meanwhile.
These are pleasant to the touch
and quite comfortable.
How does tempura for dinner sound?
You know, something
covered with batter and fried.
Hey, wait up!
Come back here, Nezuko!
Wh-What was that for?
Hold up! Hold up!
Stop chasing us, Inosuke!
Tanjiro!
EPISODE 15:
MOUNT NATAGUMO
You're fully healed.
North-northeast! North-northeast!
Your next mission is north-northeast!
The three of you are to go to Mt. Natagumo!
Head to Mt. Natagumo!
We're heading out now.
Thank you for everything.
Now then, for good luck.
Thank you so much!
What do you think you're doing, old hag?
What are you, a moron?
She's striking sparks for good luck!
It's a purification ceremony!
Because we're gonna go
on a dangerous mission!
Always live your lives
with great pride.
I wish you luck in battle!
"Great pride"? "Luck in battle"?
What does that mean?
Jeez, this guy is totally clueless.
Well, yeah, now that you mention it,
it's kind of difficult.
"With great pride"...
I guess it means
that you know your place
and that you behave properly
so that you're never ashamed of yourself.
And the old lady
is also praying for our safety.
So, what is this "place"?
What do you mean, "never ashamed"?
Well, it's...
What exactly does it mean
to "behave properly"?
Why in the hell would that old hag
pray for our safety anyway?
She has nothing to do with us.
Then, why?
She has no clue
what her own place is, does she?
He sped up!
I won't get beat!
Wait up!
Hold up!
Would you mind waiting a second?
Zenitsu? What's wrong?
I'm scared, all right?
Now that we're nearing
our destination, I'm so scared!
Why the hell is he sitting?
How creepy is that?
Who are you to talk, Pig Face?
Don't tell me you're not getting
any vibes from that mountain!
Still, what good will it do
to just sit there?
I told you, he's creepy.
I am not in any way creepy!
I'm normal! I'm the normal one!
You guys are abnormal!
What? What's wrong?
Hey...
What is this smell?
Tanjiro!
Come on!
Don't leave me here by myself!
Don't leave me!
H-Help me.
He's got our uniform on!
He's a Demon Slayer!
Something must've happened!
Hold up!
Are you all right?
What happened?
They were attached to me, too!
Help me!
I'm going.
I'll go on ahead.
You can follow me, shivering.
This is making me hungry.
Inosuke...
This is challenging enough for you, right?
Let's go!
What the hell is this?
A spider web?
Jeez, this place is full of spider webs!
What a pain!
You're right.
Inosuke?
What do you want?
Thanks.
You said you'd come with me,
and I felt encouraged.
That twisted, ominous scent
I was picking up from the mountain...
It made me freeze a little.
Thanks!
These are pleasant to the touch
and quite comfortable.
Always live your lives with great pride.
I wish you luck in battle!
Inosuke...
Let's go.
We've come for backup.
I'm Tanjiro Kamado, Rank Mizunoto.
Mizunoto...
Mizunoto?
Why didn't they send a Hashira?
No matter how many Mizunoto
they send, it won't help!
It's pointless!
Inosuke!
Shut up!
As far as pointlessness goes,
your existence itself has no point at all!
Now, tell us what's going on,
you spineless fool!
Who the hell is this guy?
Did you forget that I have seniority?
Th-The crow gave us the order!
And ten of us Demon Slayers came here.
Not long after we entered the mountain,
the Slayers...
The Slayers started killing each other!
I...
You did well to return.
So, most of my children
have been slaughtered?
We might find
the Twelve Kizuki there, then.
It seems I'll have to send in
some Hashiras.
Giyu...
Shinobu...
- As you wish!
If only humans and demons
could get along.
Don't you agree, Tomioka?
Impossible...
as long as demons eat humans.
DEMON SLAYER:
KIMETSU NO YAIBA
I wonder if they hate me.
Would you really leave your friend
by the roadside?
Wouldn't you talk him through it
if you were friends?
If they both tried to talk me into going,
Zenitsu...
I would've gone, okay? Sure I would.
But no, off they went on their merry way
up that scary mountain.
Poor me left alone here...
"Sulking isn't going to do you any good.
You have to go help your friends now."
Lucky you, you don't have
a care in the world.
You don't understand a thing
about humans, do you?
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
You're not cute at all!
I mean it! Not that side of you!
Seriously, you've got zero charm!
I mean, look how cute Nezuko is,
and she's a demon!
But you're a sparrow,
and you're so vicious!
He took Nezuko with him!
Why did he have to take
my precious Nezuko with him?
Damn Tanjiro!
Don't take a young girl into danger!
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
Nezuko!
What is this sound?
There it is again.
It's this sound again!
I heard this sound,
and the next thing I knew,
everyone started killing each other!
Where's it coming from?
These guys are all morons!
They don't know that it's taboo
for us Demon Slayers to fight each other!
No, that's not it!
They're not moving normally!
They're being manipulated
by something!
All right.
I'm gonna slash them to ribbons!
You can't do that!
They're alive!
Some of them are still alive!
Besides, we can't harm
the corpses of our teammates!
Stop denying me
at every turn!
A strange sweet scent from his back!
It's threads!
They're being manipulated by threads!
Slash the threads!
I already knew that
before you caught on!
Where's the location
of the demon controlling them?
What's this? What an irritating odor!
Though it was just for a second!
What's this?
Spiders!
So, the spiders are attaching them
to the puppet strings?
That means...
Now then, my sweet little dolls...
Dance until your arms and legs fall off.
It's not good enough
to just cut the threads!
The spiders are just gonna stick
more puppet strings onto them!
So...
That acrid smell again!
What is it anyway?
It's being carried here by the wind!
So, all we gotta do
is kill those damn spiders, huh?
That would be impossible!
Those spiders are tiny,
and I'm sure there are tons of them!
We gotta find the demon
who's controlling them!
It's no good, Inosuke!
Inosuke, if you have some kind of power
that can pinpoint the demon's location,
then help me out!
This weird smell has been flowing in,
and my nose isn't working great!
And also, um...
It's Murata!
Murata!
Murata and I will find a way to deal
with the people being controlled!
Inosuke, you...
Don't disturb my family's peaceful life.
He's floating!
No.
He's standing on the threads!
What did he mean by "family"?
Mother will kill you all right away.
Mother?
Damn you!
Where the hell do you think
you're going? Fight me! Fight—
Inosuke!
Why did he show up anyway?
That kid probably isn't the demon pulling
the puppet strings! So, first, let's...
Okay, okay, okay!
I hear you, all right?
You want me to find
where that demon's at, right?
Shut up already, Forehead!
Beast Breathing Seventh Form,
Spatial Awareness!
Found it!
There you are!
I won't let anyone get in our way.
The five of us are going to live
in bliss as a family.
No one can break our bond.
PREVIEW
Whoops-a-daisy!
Nezuko!
Tanjiro!
Where are you?
"First, let's calm down
and listen to the sounds around us!"
Nezuko's in danger!
Stop chirping and help me
find her, Chuntaro!
"I told you to calm down!"
"Now, it's time for a Taisho secret!"
"My real name is Ukogi."
"That's because my favorite food
is ukogi rice."
"But Zenitsu hasn't noticed yet,
so all I get is beans."
What are you so mad about?
Here, eat this and calm down.
"It's an ukogi rice ball!"
When you're done with that,
help me look, okay?
I mean, Nezuko's in danger!
"He's seriously worried."
Nezuko!
"I guess this is why
you just can't hate the guy."
Next, Episode 16,
"Letting Someone Else Go First."
TO BE CONTINUED