Blood Demon Art...
Exploding Blood!
The bond between Nezuko and me...
can't be...
severed by anyone!
EPISODE 20:
PRETEND FAMILY
Nezuko!
I-I won!
I won!
My father saved me!
I'm not sure why I was able
to unleash that attack
with the kagura that's been
in our family for generations.
But that was what saved me!
I was able to beat him!
Huh?
I can't see Nezuko!
Is it because I took
way too many breaths?
This ringing in my ears is brutal!
My whole body is throbbing with pain!
I gotta...
heal up fast!
I'm still not done fighting!
I gotta go save Inosuke!
Right away!
The scent of blood just got stronger!
Come to think of it,
it didn't give off the smell of ash.
Don't tell me...
Even though I chopped off his head?
You thought you'd defeated me?
Poor kid.
Did your pathetic delusion
bring you joy?
I cut off my head myself
with my own threads...
before you could chop it off.
Enough.
I'll kill both you and your sister.
I haven't been this enraged in a long time.
Get up!
Get up right now!
Get your breathing under control!
Hurry!
Right now!
But I wonder why you're not burning up.
It was only me and my threads
that caught fire, right?
LOWER FIVE
I don't know if it's your sister's power,
but thanks for getting me super-annoyed.
Now I can carve you up with no regrets.
If you use the correct breathing technique,
it makes no difference
how exhausted you are!
Blood Demon Art...
Murderous Eye Basket!
Don't panic!
Don't let it disrupt your breathing!
Calm down...
if you can calm down!
I can't raise...
my arm!
Somebody's here.
Is it Zenitsu?
You did a good job holding out
until I got here.
Leave the rest to me.
You're like an endless stream...
of lowlifes always getting in my way!
Blood Demon Art...
Cutting Thread Rotation!
Total Concentration...
Water Breathing...
Eleventh Form...
Dead Calm.
Eleventh Form?
Who cares about your Eleventh Form?
What?
What's going on? What did he do?
The instant I got up in his face,
the threads scattered.
Not one of them reached him?
The toughest threads of all got slashed?
That's impossible!
One more time!
I messed up!
And I was the only one
who never messed up until now
in this "Pretend Family" game!
We finally drove her into a corner!
Hey, look at that.
A demon?
It's just a kid.
But even if it looks like a kid,
it's still a demon!
If we let it go, it'll devour humans!
Hey...
You want me save you?
In return,
will you do what I ask?
I'll do anything!
I'll do whatever you want,
so please save me!
Then, become a part of my family.
I will! I'll do it!
What are they talking about?
All right, it's over for you!
Welcome.
Starting today,
you're part of my family, too.
DEMON SLAYER:
KIMETSU NO YAIBA
Drink this.
Our family's power belongs to Rui.
Since we were all weak demons,
Rui shared his power with us.
Because Rui is one of that person's favorites,
he gets special permission
to do this kind of thing.
Do you feel it?
You don't have to fear
those demon hunters anymore.
Now then,
time for the finishing touches.
All right, you can look up now.
Congratulations.
You're truly part of the family now.
We're only playing house.
What?
We have no blood ties.
We're just a clan of assorted strangers.
I'm so sorry!
I'll do better, Rui!
I'll practice! Forgive me!
I'm so sorry I couldn't do it well!
It's just that I revert
by accident sometimes!
I don't want to hear
your excuses, Mother.
Play the role of mother like you should.
I know what I must do, Rui.
We were all so scared
of the demon hunters
and just wanted companions.
It's not like we wanted to take part
in this baffling "Pretend Family" game.
But those who fail to go along
with Rui's demands and orders
get carved up or have their
intellect taken from them
or get strung up,
exposed to the sunlight.
I've had enough of this.
I'm going to pretend
I never heard you say that—
I know you're not a fool.
Unlike all the others.
Let's run away together.
I wouldn't say this to anyone but you.
You're the one person
I truly think of as my younger sister.
Tomorrow, Rui is going to be summoned
by that person and descend the mountain.
That's our chance to escape.
How disappointing.
They were all fools,
but I'm not like them!
Even so, I messed up!
Rui!
Mother's been killed!
And our elder brother, too!
What should we do?
The demon hunters aren't far behind.
Listen...
Sh-Shouldn't we make a run for it?
Don't...
You know, don't you?
I really hate it when your face reverts.
What are you looking at?
This isn't some show, you know.
I only got my face slashed,
so I got off easy!
A demon!
What the...
It's futile.
You'll never cut through them.
You see, my Ball of Yarn may feel soft,
but it's extremely hard.
Whaaa...
First, the solvent will melt
those clothes out of the way.
And then, it'll be your turn.
You'll be reduced to mush in no time,
and then I'll feed on you.
How amazing!
Do you release those threads
from the palms of your hands?
Good evening.
The moon is quite lovely tonight,
don't you think?
I can see you have no intention
of being my friend.
W-W-Wait!
I beg of you!
I'm being forced to do this!
If I defy him,
I'll be slashed to shreds!
Is that right?
That does sound tragic!
I'll spare you!
Let's be friends!
Y-You're going to spare me?
Yes!
But in order for us to be friends,
I must ask you a few questions.
Sweet young girl,
how many people have you killed?
Five.
But I was ordered to!
I had no choice!
There's no need to lie about it.
Because I already know.
That spell you cast to turn one of our men
into a cocoon was most impressive!
Help me!
Somebody!
You've devoured at least
eighty humans, haven't you?
No, of course
I haven't eaten that many.
I only killed those five.
But I came here
from the west, you know.
The west, my dear.
On the west side of the mountain,
I saw hordes of cocoons
hanging from the trees.
The human captives inside
had been liquefied.
All massacred.
In that spot alone, I counted
at least fourteen cocoons.
Fourteen humans.
All dead.
Oh, it's not that I'm angry.
I'm only trying
to confirm the accurate toll.
What good will it do you
to confirm that?
You'll receive the penalty
you deserve and be reborn!
Penalty?
That way, you and I
can become friends.
If you go unpunished
after having taken all those lives,
your victims will never get justice.
I could gouge out your eyeballs
or slash your stomach
to rip out your organs.
For every person you've killed,
I shall torture you.
And after you've suffered
through all of the pain and agony,
your sins will be forgiven.
Let's both give it our all!
Don't worry! Since you're a demon,
my dear, surely it won't kill you
and neither will there be
any after effects!
Who do you think you're kidding?
Die!
You damn witch!
I can see that we'll never be friends.
Oh, what a pity!
Insect Breathing Butterfly Dance...
Caprice.
My head...
hasn't been cut off!
That's the sword she's using?
I see.
She's too tiny and has no arm strength,
so beheading is beyond her.
That's someone I can defeat!
You mustn't think you're safe
just because you haven't been beheaded.
Because there are swordswomen
like me who use poison.
Demon Slayer Corps, Insect Hashira,
Shinobu Kocho.
I may be the only swordswoman among
the Hashiras unable to decapitate demons,
but as I've created a poison
lethal to demons, I'm also rather awesome.
Oh! Pardon me!
You're dead,
so you can't hear me, can you?
Careless of me!
Are you all right?
Just barely!
What happened to the demon?
Shouldn't you finish it off?
I killed her with wisteria poison.
She's already dead,
so if we leave her, she'll rot.
I'm a pharmaceuticals expert!
Your clothes did get dissolved,
but your body is more or less unscathed!
I'm so glad!
Now then,
as for the whereabouts of the demon
that forced this girl to do his bidding...
Did Tomioka beat me to it, then?
Nezuko...
Nezuko!
I'll kill them! I'll kill them!
I'll kill those siblings no matter what!
Siblings!
What is it that you want to do, Rui?
What do you mean by "family"?
I don't know.
Because I have no memories
of when I was human.
Is that why you made us
pretend to be your family?
I thought that if I could feel
a family bond,
my memories would come back.
The bond of a real family...
That's right.
I...
Nezuko!
PREVIEW
RUSTLE RUSTLE
That's amazing! To think you made
a poison that can kill demons!
I am a student
of the pharmaceutical sciences.
Being a Demon Slayer isn't just
about swinging a sword, you know.
I-I see.
And now, it's time for a Taisho secret!
I formulate my poison
inside my scabbard,
and no one knows how it's done
but myself and my swordsmith!
All right, I'm gonna shoot up
the ranks with a special sword, too!
First, you need to acquire the skill
not to get your uniform melted off!
Such a toxic way of putting it!
Next, Episode 21,
"Against Corps Rules."
It's always good to have high ambitions!
Let's give it our all!
TO BE CONTINUED