Wake up.
Hey, I said wake up!
Wake... Hey! Hey you!
C'mon, you! C'mon!
Are you gonna sleep all day?
Wake the hell up, will you?
Bummer. I heard he was
a Demon Slayer with a demon in tow,
so I was looking forward
to seeing someone flamboyant,
but that's one drab-looking dude, huh?
And now, we'll put this boy on trial!
I see!
To think that he's been protecting
his sister who's now a demon...
Now that's beautiful sibling love!
How brave!
Wh-Who are these peop—
DESTROY
Don't open your mouth
just yet, you moron!
Just who do you think
is standing before you?
You're in the presence of the Hashiras!
Hashiras?
What is a Hashira?
What's he talking about?
And who are these people exactly?
KAKUSHI
Where am I now?
This is the Demon Slayers' headquarters.
And you're about to be put on trial...
Tanjiro Kamado.
EPISODE 22:
MASTER OF THE MANSION
Before we start the trial,
why don't you explain
the crime you've comm—
There's no need for a trial!
FLAME HASHIRA
KYOJURO RENGOKU
Protecting a demon
is a clear violation of the code!
We're within our rights
to deal with him on our own!
We're going to behead him
along with the demon!
SOUND HASHIRA
TENGEN UZUI
In that case, I'll be glad
to decapitate him flamboyantly.
I'll show you the most flamboyant
bloodspray you'll ever see.
I'm talking max flamboyance.
LOVE HASHIRA
MITSURI KANROJI
What?
You'd kill such an adorable child?
That pains my heart!
It fills me with anguish!
STONE HASHIRA
GYOMEI HIMEJIMA
Ah, what a pitiful sight this boy is.
The poor soul...
I pity him for having been born at all.
MIST HASHIRA
MUICHIRO TOKITO
Um, what was the shape
of that cloud again?
What was it called again?
Where's Nezuko?
Nezuko!
Hey you...
The Hashiras are speaking.
What are you looking at?
These are the nine highest-ranking
swordsmen in the Demon Slayer Corps.
Hashiras...
Let's put him out of his misery.
Yeah! Let's do it. Flamboyantly.
Hey!
Nezuko...
Nezuko, where are you?
Nezuko!
Zenitsu!
Inosuke!
Murata!
Forget that.
What will we do with Tomioka?
Seeing him there without any restraints
is giving me a headache.
Based on what Kocho told us,
Tomioka's just as guilty
of breaking the Corps rules.
SERPENT HASHIRA
IGURO OBANAI
How will we deal with him?
How should we make him
take responsibility?
What kind of lesson
should we teach him?
Don't you have anything to say, Tomioka?
Because of me, now even Tomioka...
Iguro, you're as serpent-like
as ever! Such a nag!
I love how pesky you are!
Tomioka! All by himself at a distance!
How cute!
WATER HASHIRA
GIYU TOMIOKA
Oh, where's the harm?
He did come along without resisting.
Let's come up with a penalty later.
INSECT HASHIRA
SHINOBU KOCHO
What I'm more interested in
is hearing this boy's story.
The reason he's going on missions with a demon
in tow despite being a Demon Slayer...
I'd like to hear the explanation
from the boy himself.
Needless to say, what he's done
is against the Demon Slayer Corps rules.
You are aware of that, aren't you?
Tanjiro Kamado...
Why are you traveling with a demon
when you're a Demon Slayer?
No need to ask.
You can take your time.
Just tell us why.
She's my...
She's my younger—
I do believe you need some water.
You've injured your jaw,
so please drink slowly.
It contains a painkiller,
so it will make you feel better.
It's not as if your wounds are healed,
so you mustn't push yourself.
Now then, Tanjiro Kamado...
That demon is my younger sister!
While I was away, my family
was attacked by a demon,
and when I got home,
they were all dead!
My sister got turned into a demon,
but she's never devoured anyone!
She never has...
and never will!
She'll never hurt humans no matter what!
Spare us your absurd ravings.
If she's family,
no wonder you're defending her.
I can't trust a single word you're saying.
I, for one, don't believe you.
She's been possessed by a demon.
Let us kill this poor child immediately
so that she can be liberated!
Listen to me please!
I became a swordsman
so that Nezuko could be cured!
It's been two years
since Nezuko became a demon!
And in all that time,
she hasn't devoured one human!
Your story's spinning
in the most drab way possible, idiot.
The fact that she hasn't eaten anyone,
that she won't from now on.
Don't just give us lip service.
Prove it to us with max flamboyance.
What was that bird again?
Um...
Excuse me?
I do have my doubts, you know.
I just can't imagine the Master
being in the dark about this situation.
Do you really think it's okay
to deal with him without his permission?
Shouldn't we at least wait
until he arrives?
My sister...
My sister will fight with me by my side!
She can fight as a Demon Slayer
to protect humans!
So please...
KILL
Well, well, I see you have
some fun brewing here.
Is that the moron Slayer
who has a demon with him?
What the hell are you trying to pull here?
WIND HASHIRA
SANEMI SHINAZUGAWA
Shinazugawa!
You've gained even more scars!
How gorgeous you look!
This won't do, Master Shinazugawa!
Please, would you mind
putting down that box?
Shinobu looks pretty angry!
Now, that's unusual!
She's so cool!
Shinazugawa, please don't act out of line.
What did you say about that demon, kid?
That she can fight as a Demon Slayer
to protect humans?
You know what we call that?
A total delusion, you moron!
Anyone who hurts my sister...
Hashira or not,
I won't let you get away with it!
Is that right? Good for you!
Stop it!
The Master will be arriving soon!
Pardon me.
Damn you!
Even though Tomioka ran interference,
he still landed a blow on Shinazugawa.
If you can't tell the difference
between good demons and bad,
you should just quit being a Hashira!
You little...
I'll destroy you!
- The Master...
- ...has arrived.
So good of you to come.
My beloved children...
DEMON SLAYER:
KIMETSU NO YAIBA
- The Master...
- ...has arrived.
Good morning, everyone.
The weather is amazingly good today.
I wonder if the sky is blue.
It pleases me that we've made it
to our semiannual Hashira Meeting
with no personnel changes.
Wounded.
No, is he sick?
So, that man's the Master?
So quick! I couldn't even react!
This...
I am pleased to see you
in good health, as well, Master.
I fervently pray
for your continued good fortune.
Thank you, Sanemi.
I wanted to say that!
Offer my greetings to the Master!
If I may, Master...
Before we start the Hashira Meeting,
would you mind enlightening us
about this swordsman, Tanjiro Kamado,
accompanied by a demon?
He didn't seem to have
a drop of intellect or logic,
but he's speaking so formally now!
Right.
I apologize for startling you all.
About Tanjiro and Nezuko...
I've sanctioned their situation.
And I'd also like you all to accept it.
Even if it's what you desire,
Master, I cannot agree to it.
I'm flamboyantly opposed, as well!
A Demon Slayer traveling
with a demon is unacceptable!
I shall do whatever it is you wish, Master!
I'm fine either way...
since I'm going to forget anyway.
I won't trust them. I won't trust them.
In the first place, I loathe demons.
Although I respect you with all my heart,
that's an incomprehensible notion, Master!
I oppose it with everything I've got!
The Demon Slayer Corps' mission
is to annihilate demons.
I request that you penalize
both Kamado and Tomioka!
The letter.
Yes, Master.
This is a letter received
from a former Hashira,
Sakonji Urokodaki.
I shall read you an abridged version.
"Please allow Tanjiro to be accompanied
by his sister, a demon.
Because of her resilient mental strength,
Nezuko has not lost her human emotions.
Even in a starved state,
she never devoured humans,
and this has held true
more than two years later.
Although the situation seems somewhat
far-fetched, it is an indisputable fact.
In the event that Nezuko does assault
a human, Tanjiro Kamado, as well as...
...Sakonji Urokodaki and Giyu Tomioka
will atone by committed seppuku."
So, what if they commit seppuku?
If you want to die,
then rot to death for all I care!
It's no guarantee! Not by a long shot!
Shinazugawa is right!
If she kills and devours human,
there's no coming back from that!
It won't bring back
the people who were killed!
You do have a point.
In that case...
Master!
We can't guarantee
that she won't attack humans.
We can't prove it.
That said...
We also can't prove
that she will attack humans.
The fact is that Nezuko has refrained from
devouring humans for more than two years,
and also that there are three people
risking their lives for her.
To reject this notion,
those who reject it must offer
an even more convincing argument.
Do you all have the will to do so?
Also, there's something
I'd like to relay to you, my children.
Tanjiro here has met Kibutsuji.
No, impossible!
Even when no Hashira has ever
crossed paths with him?
You mean this kid...
What did he look like?
What about his powers?
Where did this take place?
Did you battle him?
What was Kibutsuji doing?
Did you find his stronghold?
Hey, answer me!
Shut up! I asked him first!
First, tell us what powers Kibutsuji has!
Kibutsuji has sent pursuers after Tanjiro.
Though his purpose may simply
be to silence him,
now that Kibutsuji's given himself away
for the first time, I don't want to let go.
I also believe something's happening
to Nezuko that Kibutsuji never saw coming.
Can you try to understand?
No, I can't understand, Master.
If it were human, I'd be okay
with letting it live, but not a demon!
Not after all that we the Demon Slayers
have gone through in battle!
Not after so many people
have lost their lives!
It's unacceptable!
What are you doing?
You're soiling the garden!
Master!
I will prove it to you myself!
The sheer ugliness of a demon!
Sanemi...
Hey, demon!
It's time to eat!
Sink your teeth in this!
No need to force yourself to hold back.
Just show us your true colors,
and I'll obliterate you right here!
Nezuko!
Shinazugawa, it's no good
doing it in the sunlight.
We have to go into the shadows,
or the demon won't show its face.
Master,
please forgive this discourtesy.
Stop it!
Come on out, demon!
Look, it's the human blood
you love so much!
I can't breathe!
I can't move!
Nezuko!
PREVIEW
Imagine, Shinazugawa falling victim
to a head-butt by a mere rookie.
That was a mighty fine head-butt!
Yeah! The sound it made was flamboyant!
How painful it must've been...
Namu Amida Butsu.
But the way that boy stood up
to a Hashira was so brave!
What is this, a free-for-all?
You know I could've dodged it
if Tomioka hadn't gotten in the way!
Excuses, excuses.
I see none of you have changed.
And now, time for a Taisho secret!
The first one among us to speak
gets to greet the Master,
so we all had butterflies in our stomachs
until the Master got here!
Oh, next, Episode 23, "Hashira Meeting."
TO BE CONTINUED