Finishing the outdoor class
held with Adler and Lang dorms,
Mash obtained a gold coin.
However, despite Lance's warning,
Mash got lost at school,
and somehow found himself
at the center of rivaling Lang dorm.
The headquarters of Magia Lupus.
You know
that's a doll you're talking to?
Thank you for bringing that to my attention.
You're welcome.
So you're the first-year with the gold coin.
Yes, that's me.
Why do you wish to be a Divine Visionary?
To live peacefully with my family.
Splendid. However...
You are misguided.
The Divine Visionaries
are the artisans of our world.
They literally are the vessels of God's divinity.
You lack the mettle necessary
to be a creator deity.
Then, what about you?
I will return this world to its rightful form.
Do you know why humanity has flourished?
Because we tirelessly pillage, use,
and devour those weaker than us.
But look at society now.
Sheltering the weak, fighting for equality,
encouraging compassion...
It's nonsense.
Society wants to shut their eyes,
and try their hardest to avert reality.
We are beasts by nature.
Even in human society, the weak are pillaged,
taken advantage of, and weeded out.
Thus, it is we, the superior beings,
who prosper.
That is the law of nature.
I get it.
So you're saying...
you want to live peacefully as well?
What is he talking about?
Was he listening at all?
I will take those words as hostility.
I didn't mean it that way. I'm sorry.
I see.
Then I will allow you to go,
in exchange for your gold coin.
How about no?
I see.
Well, you have no right to refuse.
A puppet?
That wasn't much of a challenge.
What's with this puppet?
It's been pumping iron
a lot more than the other one.
I will put this coin to good use.
I'm sorry I said
you weren't much of a challenge.
STOMP STOMP
Huh? Whoops.
Almost stomped someone to death.
Hey, I'm going to take him
to the nurse's office.
You're giving up your coin?
No, but I'm prioritizing.
Besides...
It doesn't matter how strong you are.
I'm not gonna lose.
Oh?
Now, if you'll excuse me.
His overwhelming confidence.
Is he simply thoughtless, or is he...
Something doesn't feel right.
My puppet is missing a button.
I think I just witnessed
something unthinkable.
When the puppet flung over the coin,
Mushroom Head ripped something
off the puppet,
sent it flying with tremendous force,
hit the coin mid-air,
and when it was floating...
he sucked the coin up
using the power of his lungs alone!
Wait, is that what I saw?
Interesting.
That was close.
What was a person doing
lying on the floor there anyway?
He's unconscious.
Better get him there quickly.
What the... I'm human again.
I can't remember anything that happened
after I was turned into a doll.
How the hell did I...
HMPH HMPH HMPH HMPH
BAM BAM BAM BAM
Wh-What the hell are you doing!?
Working my exterior obliques.
Oh... Okay.
Wait, the fact that you're here
means you brought me...
That's right.
Why?
I was your enemy.
Well...
When one of us is in trouble,
we're all in tr—
BITE
Mhy tohnge... Nearly bit it off...
I-I see.
Okay, I'm going now.
Take care of yourself.
Huh? Sure.
When one of us is in trouble,
we're all in trouble, huh?
Damn that punk.
Meanwhile, back at Adler dorm room 302...
RUMBLE RUMBLE
What do you think you're doing here?
And did you change your hairstyle?
That's my line!
I just got a new look. Call it a makeover!
Lemon seems to like guys
with bangs, so you know...
Lance, Dot, why are you two
arguing in my room?
His face clearly scores above 70th percentile.
And being so tall...
His difficulty playing the game of life is...
Easy Mode.
My dissatisfaction level is at 500%.
Now get outta this room!
But this is my room!
Just looking at ya pisses me off!
I hate good-lookin' guys to death!
I hate rude boors to death, too.
I can eradicate you
from this world right now, you know?
Bring it on. I'll triple-kill ya!
Um, err...
Very well. I will take you on.
Wait, no, please...
I beg you, if you're gonna
do anything, do it outside!
RAH
BANG
Right. You'll break stuff inside the room,
so can you take it outside?
The most contradictory of contradictions.
What a great contradiction.
Sheesh.
Gimme a break. Seriously.
Here, take this.
What is this?
What? Always have a gift when you drop by
someone else's place.
That's common sense.
Despite talking and acting like a ruffian,
Dot may have a good upbringing?
And it's herb tea to boot.
That one has a really good aroma.
It's my favorite.
S-Sure.
He looks like this, but loves herb tea?
Well...
All in all, today is another peaceful day.
NOM NOM NOM
Why are you so complacent?
We need to strategize ways to acquire coins.
Man, I want a girlfriend.
Not one of them are on the same page!
Big news!
Four men. One of me...
You beasts!
WRIGGLE WRIGGLE
We're not doing anything!
You're the one who came in here!
That's right!
Everyone, come with me!
What is this?
This Magic Scale displays
how many gold coins each dorm has.
Look closely.
Lang dorm has most of the gold coins for now.
On the other hand,
we Adler only have Mash's one coin.
Since the start of this school year, Lang has been
nabbing all the other dorms' coins.
Adler upperclassmen who could stop them
are all away for off-campus internships.
Lang dorm are blood-purists
with an exclusionary ideology.
If this keeps up, Lang will produce
this year's Divine Visionary.
Orca students basically
devote themselves to research.
Which means it's up to us Adlers
to put a stop to their plan.
Lemon's going out of her way
to break the situation down for us.
She's so sweet. I'm in wuv!
And so, please try hard, Mash!
'Kay.
I see.
This means I need to snuff out the guys
from Lang to fulfill my objective.
That's what this means.
All right, dammit! Let's kill 'em!
Everyone, best of luck.
These muscles will flex
in the name of peace.
About your actions... I decided I must
give you reprimand, even if superficial.
Therefore, you are to clean
the owl huts for a week.
So much for getting right into it.
I was a bit motivated, too.
I've come to help you out.
Huh? Why?
It's simple.
Lang guys might come into contact with you,
targeting your coin.
And I will hunt them down.
You're worried about me?
That's not it. I'll kill you.
Olore, did you know?
Once time passes, it never returns.
Stop stating the obvious
as if it's a profound statement.
It wastes time.
Now, shall we acquire another gold coin?
No one can stop the flow of time.
Mash was cleaning up the owl huts.
POKE
POKE POKE POKE
Did I do something to them?
It's disturbing
how much those owls hate you.
What in the world have I done?
Sea Field.
Mash!
Shuriketh.
Greetings, Adlers.
We've come for your coin.
You must be from Lang.
Yes, we are.
We are from Magia Lupus.
I'm Sixth Fang, Olore Andrew, and...
SIXTH FANG: OLORE ANDREW
Seventh Fang, Anser Shinri.
SEVENTH FANG: ANSER SHINRI
Interesting.
The one suited to become
Divine Visionary is neither of you.
So let's battle now for each other's coins.
* HELP ME. I'VE NEVER SWUM BEFORE IN MY LIFE.
I will join you soon...
Sea Shark!
BAM
The hunt's on.
Guess I'm left with you.
Let me tell you something important.
In a fight...
there is always a winner and a loser.
Damn him.
He states the obvious like it was a profound
statement, and even pauses in delivery.
I wish I didn't ask.
Shuriketh.
His magic merely controls
that disc-shaped weapon.
My gravity magic can...
Gravio...
The owls?
Shuriketh!
Oh no. Owls have nothing to do with this.
My gravity magic will get him.
Gravio...
Big Brother!
Don't pick on those poor owls!
You're right, my little sister.
Your big brother was mistaken.
What's wrong? This world
is about survival of the fittest.
Only the strong and the weak exist.
Shuriketh... Double!
Oh no, the owls behind me...
Your wand is made of magnolia.
You're the Crown family's kid, aren't you?
The prestigious Crown family,
famed for their gravitation magic.
I heard their eldest son ran off.
I can't believe...
he turned out to be so weak.
Did you leave due to your lack of talent?
I sympathize. You are one of the weak.
Did you know?
Overwhelming the weak
feels better than anything else.
Humans can evaluate themselves
only by comparing themselves with others.
Since there is someone below you,
you can acknowledge your own superiority.
There is a necessity for existences like you.
Graviole.
That's enough.
I will put you at ease.
By defeating a Crown, I can once again
acknowledge that I am a superior being.
Shuriketh Triple!
Why do I feel like something is off?
All the owls are in one spot?
Graviole.
The owls were in the way.
So I moved them over.
Impossible.
With the first spell, he controlled the shovel
hanging on the hut wall to cut open the bag of feed,
and lured all the owls over.
He wasn't attacking me the whole time
because he was worried about the owls?
Don't mock me!
Large Shuriketh!
This spell is my most...
Graviole.
What? We're both the same double-liners.
What is this overwhelming difference in power?
For you, battles are where you gain
a sense of superiority.
It's not the same for me.
I am forced to fight for the sake
of my dear little sister.
What are you trying to say?
Let me tell you something important.
Guys like you, who fight for themselves...
never stand a chance against
my determination to save my little sister.
You cannot escape from the Sea Field
that I have created.
Now, the hunt's on, Mushroom Head!
I felt like something passed by me
at tremendous speed.
But that's ridiculous.
Humans can't swim faster
than 10km per hour.
I must have imagined it.
Although I don't see Mushroom Head
anywhere. Where could he...
Wait, back when he fell under my spell...
didn't he say he couldn't swim?
"I COULD SWIM MORE THAN I THOUGHT."
What was that?
"I HAD THOUGHT I COULDN'T SWIM, SO THANK YOU."
He's thanking me for something.
I-I can't see him. Not even his shadow!
So this is how it feels to be hunted...
All right. I will get serious about this.
SeaShark Evolution!
Now that I am in this form,
nobody can stop...
You did it?
Yeah.
Magia Lupus.
If this is the power
of the sixth and seventh...
I think we've got this.
You saying it
kinda loses the dramatic tension.
Oh dear.
Such a terrible thing to say about us.
However...
Aren't you jumping to conclusions?
Graviole.
I can't use my magic?
Please calm down.
I'm only here for my allies.
You're quite menacing, though.
What was that just now?
Did he teleport?
Is this magic?
I apologize for seeming menacing.
I merely wanted a small glimpse.
But it is also true that I came here
to retrieve my allies.
You don't need to worry just yet.
We will meet again soon.
Now, good day.
I take it back.
Crushing them will be worthwhile after all.
In that moment...
Such speed, and with no magic...
Then he is the same type as me.
NEXT EPISODE
MASH BURNEDEAD AND THE WOLVES OF MAGIC