To be honest, you surprised me.
Abyss.
I thought Rayne was the only student
capable of facing his Evil Eye.
You can't possibly be a better magic user
than Rayne, a Divine Visionary.
But could it be that...
GASP
CLAMP
What's wrong, so suddenly?
No! It's nothing. Please, go on.
In any case, you seem quite capable.
PHEW
Which is why someone superior
like you should understand...
that this world does not treat
everyone equally.
I mentioned our beastly natures
to you once before.
I can't abide by inferior genes.
They're on the receiving end,
yet they take advantage of our kindness.
And they selfishly assert their rights.
Audacious, is it not?
We don't need to burden ourselves
with useless luggage.
Um, that means
people who can't use magic...
Yes, that's right.
We must dispose of them.
SHOCK
Merely segregating them
from society is too kind.
I will change that system.
This includes other underachievers
and people who shelter the weak.
Those sheltering...
Mash.
You really are a good, honest boy.
What? A double back somersault
at this age!?
Here, have my cream puff and...
He's eating it before I told him to!
Mash, I'm so proud of you, my son.
Okay, I understand.
Your way is kind of a problem for me.
So I don't think we can be friends.
I see. So you cannot understand.
It seems you're a little dense.
And inferior genes must be eradicated.
Phew, I sure worked hard today.
Huh? It's kinda broken.
Lord Abel and Mushroom Head
are fighting each other!
Talk about bad timing!
That doll has acid in it.
You should be careful.
Okay.
What exactly is his plan
under these circumstances?
Huh-wha?
Huh-wha-wha?
He took them out with one throw
without touching the acidic dolls.
STRIKE
Like a bunch of bowling pins!
So you mentioned something
about inferior genes earlier.
But if I beat you,
does that mean you have inferior genes?
You don't know when to keep quiet.
Also, what did you do with Lemon?
Lemon? I have no idea
who you're talking about.
All I'm doing is receiving
magical power from everyone.
All you're doing?
But everyone is getting sick because of it.
I told you.
The strong take from the weak.
That's our right.
You can't even stop them.
But that shows your current skill level.
It's over!
He has grown since last we met.
The strong take from the weak,
and that's their right, yes?
Then,
when I win,
you'll tell me where Lemon is.
I think I should move back home.
You're not just talk, I see.
Thanks.
And that's all I have to say about that.
What was that?
Sorry.
That was just too one-sided.
It lacks class.
Finn.
This is your friend, right?
I captured him, thinking
he'd make good entertainment.
Your spiky-haired friend
was too badly injured to be useful.
I'm looking forward to an interesting show.
Did I say you could lift a hand against him?
I'm sorry, but you're not allowed to attack.
If you break the rules,
I will break your friend apart.
I see, so that's the way you play.
You can break your friend apart
if you'd like.
If you don't,
you'll be the one who breaks.
You can't do that?
You can't choose to sacrifice?
Humans always want to believe
they are good.
But I'm saying that is a lie.
It seems the axe broke first.
It kind of sounds like...
you think you're a pretty deep person, huh?
War is on!
Oh, by the way,
you wanted my gold coin, right?
You finally feel like handing it over?
Yes, if you want it that badly.
He used the coin on the threads?
I'm sorry. I guess this coin just likes me.
I'm sick of you nitpicking on what I say.
I'm sorry I can't keep playing along with it.
It's useless. Human power can't resist it.
In the end, you are nothing more
than another puppet.
What I am doesn't matter.
I need to have you...
regret lashing out at my friends.
Marioness Change!
I am impressed.
You made me cast this spell.
But, it's still survival of the fittest.
The weak are but prey.
In my eyes, you are nothing more
than an unusually clever rabbit.
I will take your coin.
You were good sport for a rabbit.
But in the end, a rabbit is still a rabbit.
You cannot become a wolf...
What is this?
Oh!
Why is my cream puff
that I hid in my robe pocket here?
You don't normally put a cream puff
directly into your robe pocket.
But how could he...
He was fully transformed into a puppet.
How did he move on his own?
My puppet magic blocks
electric signals from the brain
and wrests away
voluntary physical movement.
He shouldn't have been able to move.
Was it...
a spinal reflex?
SPINAL REFLEX
Spinal reflex.
It's when you pull back
after touching something hot,
or when your foot jolts up when the part
below your kneecap is tapped.
In order to respond quickly
to external threats,
your neurotransmitters use a shortcut
that bypasses your brain.
It's true my magic only transforms
the exterior which I then puppet, but...
internally, they remain human.
A spontaneous response in puppet form
would have to be the result of a spinal reflex.
In other words...
BAM
An unconscious defense against a threat.
Hanging on to that cream puff
was that important to you!?
It seems hanging on to the cream puff
was that important to him.
Survival of the fittest demands that
the weak fight to protect themselves as well.
All right. I will acknowledge that.
I can extract magic power from my dolls.
And I can use the magic power
that I extract.
I'll crush you with the ultimate spell.
Marioness Secondth.
Harm Puppet!
Harm Puppet turns anything
within a 100-meter radius into puppets.
Transformation begins
the moment the strings touch you.
Strings you cannot see, of course.
That means me too?
When the strings descend upon you,
they will rob you of bodily control.
There is no way to counter them.
Once you are a puppet, your body
will be toyed with until you can't recover.
This is my respect for you.
Even against a rabbit,
I must use all that I have.
I had too much pride.
And I thank you for showing me...
Huh?
Am I being appreciated?
How did you stop the transformation?
I tore the strings.
He can't have!
It's impossible to see the strings
as they descend.
No human can stop them.
Lemme tell y'all what I saw.
Right after Lord Abel used his magic,
the dude turned his body in a peculiar way.
It must have been to delay contact
with the rest of the strings.
And most likely,
once he felt the strings on his left side...
before he lost control of his right side,
he snapped the strings!
A savage and way too instinctive strategy!
Impossible.
He's inhuman!
What's wrong?
You're sweating, Mr. Rabbit.
You really are amusing,
Mash Burnedead!
Ah... I'd never considered...
Erector Spinae Magic.
Hell Fall!
That yours truly could be...
the rabbit.
My mother was very kind
and compassionate towards others.
Though born into nobility,
she treated commoners just as equally.
My mother said it was only by chance
that we were born privileged.
Then one day,
my kind mother was stabbed.
She was distributing food to the poor
as she always did.
A man hoarded all the food for himself,
and stabbed my mother when she resisted.
He said that...
getting stabbed was a comeuppance
for always having it so lucky.
She believed in the goodness of humanity.
My mother, the noble.
My mother, the naïf.
My gentle mother was gone.
Mother was mistaken.
They don't need our pity.
The dregs of society
are there for a reason.
We can't live in harmony.
I sought the best talent for my plan.
Abyss and others like him,
those who are dissatisfied with this world.
I dipped my hand into powers
I never should have.
All for my goals...
You won't change my mind.
It's only natural to pillage weak scum.
No, they deserve to be pillaged.
Bad guys are bad
no matter what their social status is.
The majority of those fools
are at the bottom.
That is why the bottom class
should be cut off altogether.
That would be a problem.
Yeah, a problem. Really.
I heard you the first time.
That aside...
Could you tell me where Lemon is?
Since you lost.
You're right.
I will release the students
who I turned into puppets. I have lost.
Thanks.
Oh.
But since you did this
all for your mom,
I guess you're not that terrible a person.
I'm slightly relieved by that.
Marioness Liberation.
Oh, that's right.
I was captured by a puppet.
Mash! Lemon!
I'm glad! You guys were all right!
I'm sorry to make you worry.
I was worried, but I'm glad.
I'm really glad.
Hip, hip, hooray!
They're all such fools,
aren't they, Mother?
Hip, hip, hooray!
Coin, coin, coin, coin, coin, coin.
Hero, hero!
Husband! Husband!
Oh yeah! Oh yeah!
I was so scared!
- Thank you, Mash!
- It's cool.
Mash.
I'm really sorry about this.
It's my fault.
But really, um...
I really, truly thank you very much.
Yeah. I'm glad you're safe.
You cad!
Why?
Me too! I worked hard too!
Oh, Dot.
It's Dot.
Dot.
Hip, hip, hooray!
Truly, they're all fools.
Huh? By the way, where's Lance?
Huh?
Stop.
You don't belong
at this school, do you?
Whatever might you be suggest...
My magic was countered?
Spider counter maxed!
However did you find me out?
Guilty until proven innocent
is more expedient.
I see. So you were fooled at first.
I even chose the face of a student here, too.
Innocent Zero.
A dark magic organization
working in the shadows of society.
What are sewer rats like you
doing in this school?
Tell me.
If you speak nonsense, I'll kill you.
Searching.
Searching?
Yes, it's something
very, very, very important to us.
It should be in this school right now.
How strange.
SLUMP
We had Abel searching for it,
but he couldn't find it at all.
He's so useless.
That's not an answer, punk.
You're so dumb.
Why would I tell you?
We're not even friends.
To get information out of someone,
you have to open their heart first.
That's just common sense.
Oh, no, no, no.
I don't have time
to be doing things like this.
I have to go kill Abel
now that we're done with him.
Sorry. I won't be able to deal with you.
I'll be your opponent.
The serial killer and cannibalist, Jon Pierre.
This is bad. His power's on par
with a Divine Visionary's.
They won't stand a chance against him.
Hip, hip, hooray!
NEXT EPISODE
MASH BURNEDEAD AND THE MAGIC MIRROR