The universe has a beginning, but no end.
Infinite.
Stars have beginnings too, but
meet an end of their own making.
Finite.
History has shown that those with
wisdom are the greatest fools of all.
This could be considered God's
final warning to those who resist.
Okarin.
Let's go.
Now infiltrating conference
venue. El Psy Congroo.
Attendance is low. Must be
due to Organization interference...
What's about to start?
You came here without knowing that?
Oh, a time machine! Wow!
Dr. Nakabachi has beaten
us researchers to the punch
and is holding a talk about
his "invention of the century."
I want to hear all about it.
An earthquake?
No, it's from above!
What's this?
You called me here for this?
There aren't many in this series left,
but Mayushii's out of 100-yen coins...
Don't act so spoiled, Mayuri.
Even if we are childhood friends,
I'm not lending you money.
Aww...
Allow me to show you
the harsh realities of life.
What the...? This one's unpainted.
--A m-metal one!
--Huh?
It's a metal one! A Metal Oopa!
Is it rare?
Yeah! Really rare!
Then you may have it.
Are you sure, Okarin?
It's "Hououin Kyouma."
Thanks, Okarin!
I told you, it's "Hououin Kyouma"...
Dr. Nakabachi's conference is
about to begin in the 8th floor hall.
Please enter freely...
You'll find the basic structure of a time
machine on the materials I've passed out.
As such, I'll use this time to explain
the fundamental theory behind it.
Scientists around the world have...
"I think I dropped my Metal Oopa.
I'm going to look for it."
Currently, there exist over ten main theories...
--The basic structure of a time machine...
--...of time travel and its possible framework.
Very briefly, these theories are...
Doctor!
Oh, is something the matter?
Don't give me that! Your time
machine theory is what's the matter!
Kerr black holes! World lines!
All you've done is rip off John Titor's story!
Titor, a self-proclaimed time traveler,
posted this very same
theory on the Internet in 2000!
Don't feign ignorance!
How rude! Of course I'm aware!
Don't compare my
theory with that hogwash!
Then please kindly explain
how your time machine theory
is any different from Titor's!
Come here a minute.
H-Hey...!
Titor, huh...
Come to think of it, John Titor's
book did say the same sort of stuff...
Who are you?!
That's my line.
What?
You tried to tell me something earlier.
Earlier?
About fifteen minutes ago.
That's crazy talk--
Makise Kurisu...?
You published that paper in Sciency...
I'm impressed. Do you work
at a university lab or some--?
Curse you!
Don't tell me you're an
agent sent by the Organization!
What organization?
--I just want to ask you a--
--And I've no reason to answer!
It's me. I've been caught
by one of their agents.
--Yes. Makise Kurisu. No, there's no problem.
--Who are you talking to?
I'll give her the slip somehow--
Huh? It's off...
I-I'll let you in on the secret.
That's actually a cell
phone for special missions.
It automatically shuts off
whenever anyone but me touches it.
Ah. You were talking to yourself.
I'll keep it short.
What did you try to tell me earlier?
You tried to tell me something
fifteen minutes ago, remember?
You had a very distressed look on your face...
I-I see right through your tricks.
When next we meet, genius
girl, we shall be adversaries.
--Huh?
--Farewell.
Wait...!
What was that about? She said she met me...
Oh!
Okarin!
Mayuri! Where were you?
I messaged you. I can't find my Metal Oopa.
I even wrote my name on it, too...
--Did you drop it somewhere?
--I think so.
--Forget about it.
--Huh?!
Metal Oopas go for
10,000 yen on online auctions!
10,000...?!
Yeah...
Find it! Our lab is almost
as broke as an old drum!
Huh? I'm not going to sell it, though.
With 10,000, we can procure all
kinds of parts for our Future Gadgets!
I'm not going to sell it...
Was that...?
Get outside!
Hey.
Is someone there...?
Makise... Kurisu...
--What the...?
--What happened?
Okarin!
What's wrong? You look really pale...
Someone died...
--Huh?
--On the 8th floor...
Wh-What the...?
What's going on?
Too-too-roo!
Here, Okarin!
Wh-What's happening here...?!
Huh? What do you mean?
--Why did... everyone just disappear?!
--Disappear?
Yes! Everyone here suddenly
vanished right in front of us!
--They did?
--Don't give me that!
You saw it too!
--Right?! Right?!
--No...
What are you saying?!
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
Hey, you there!
Can you see us?
Why won't you answer?
I'm talking to you, the stupid-face
on the other side of the screen!
No matter. This is the
Future Gadget Laboratory.
Allow me to introduce our research staff.
First is Lab Member 001, the
lab founder and mad scientist:
yours truly, Hououin Kyouma.
"Okarin" is much cuter, though...
Silence! Okabe Rintaro is my cover name.
Next is Lab Member 002,
the cosplay costume creator and
our only female member: Shiina Mayuri.
Too-too-roo! Call me Mayushii!
Last is Lab Member 003:
Hashida Itaru, the super hax0r!
"Hacker," not "hax0r," n00b.
That's our staff.
Y'know, isn't it time you give up on it?
You can't expect much from
a 500-yen bargain bin game.
Listen well!
To get to our lab, go down Chuo-dori,
hang a left at the Suehirocho Station
intersection onto Kuramae-dori,
then find the multi-use building in
the alley just before the next light.
The goal of the Future Gadget Laboratory
is to transform the world's ruling structure...
To produce inventions that cause chaos.
Do you understand?
In that case, reveal your secrets this instant!
Say, do you think maybe we
seem like a game to Alpacaman?
I don't think he's even capable of grasping
the concepts of "games" and "reality."
So is that true for the 2D girls you like too?
They're different. They're my wives.
No one cares about your wives, Daru.
Still, it's an interesting idea, y'know.
If we were inside someone's screen,
would we ever be able to know?
--No.
--That was fast!
Consequently, such discussions are pointless.
It'd be far more productive to brainstorm ways
to oppose the Organization and
shatter the world's ruling structure.
Ugh, again with those delusions? Lame!
Hold thy tongue, super hax0r!
You're speaking to the mad scientist Hououin...
...Kyouma!
That's your made-up character.
Come now, Daru. I'd listen carefully
to what others say if I were you.
Oh, is this today's "You're
in no position to talk" thread?
Oh, looks like the press chopper's arrived.
At approximately noon today, an
object believed to be a space satellite
came crashing down in Akihabara.
As you can see, even from the ground...
What happened back there?
This morning, Mayuri and I left the lab
and headed to the Radio Building
to catch Dr. Nakabachi's conference.
But before I knew it,
a satellite had crashed into it...
And that's not all.
--I did?
--Yeah.
We saw the crash on TV, and you said,
"So the Organization
has finally made its move!"
And then we came here.
Canceled?!
You were all ticked-off this morning,
saying how the doc got
cold feet and called it off.
Dr. Nakabachi's talk?! But it
started at noon at the Radio Building!
Seriously, it was canceled.
Good thing, too. You would've
been a satellite pancake otherwise.
This inconsistency in my memories...
Has the Organization
manipulated my memory?
Oh! That's it!
This must be the choice of Steins Gate!
More role-playing?
That "Stein" thing of yours makes no sense.
Daru! Future Gadget #1!
You made Alpacaman mad.
--Because you changed the channel.
--Here.
Damn Mr. Braun! Forcing
this shoddy junk on us...!
He gave it to us for free.
--Daru! Carry the TV!
--GTFO.
It's hot out.
Besides, don't assume
I'm strong just 'cause I'm fat!
That's not a badge of honor!
Mr. Braun...!
Huh? I keep telling you, call me Tennoji-san.
I would like you to
repair this... immediately...
Huh? You busted it already?
Damn, you got no love for CRTs.
It'll cost ya 1000 yen.
Wha...?!
If anyone's at fault here, it's you for--
Is that any way to talk to your landlord?
I will happily pay your fee.
I'd quit hangin' around with
this guy if I were you, Mayuri-chan.
Mayushii is Okarin's hostage, though.
Hostage, indeed...
Hmm? It's broken here,
too? Make it 2000 yen.
--Wha...?!
--Take it or leave it.
What's it gonna be?
It's me.
It appears the Organization has
gotten to that chrome-dome as well.
Sabotage is afoot...
Here you go.
You sure love Dk Pepper, Okarin.
It's the intelligent
drink of choice individuals.
The sound of the cicadas is amazing...
Daru!
Now that the Organization has
used Mr. Braun to sabotage us,
we've no choice but to set the
you-know-what plan into motion!
What plan?
You know, the plan!
What else would I be referring to
besides a field test of Future Gadget #8?!
Oh, the Phone Microwave (Temporary Name)?
But how do you "field test" a microwave?
We've known each other for
what, three and a half years now?
More like two;
we never talked 'cause we were
in different classes in high school.
Never mind the details.
Basically, we've known
each other a long time.
Isn't it about time you learn
to follow my train of thought?
No-can-do.
So you wanna give it
another whirl? It's all ready to go.
Mayuri! Bring the bananas!
Huh?
You're going to make more
gel-nanas? It's such a waste...
We can't defeat the Organization
by being tightwads all the time!
We don't need to, though...
Mayushii pays for these
bananas, just so you know.
I know.
This is RENG, the Phone
Microwave (Temporary Name).
You can set the timer from here.
Please press the pound key, followed
by the number of seconds desired.
One-two-zero-pound.
Nice turntable, huh?
This one rotates in the
opposite direction than normal ones.
The opposite direction?
That could hold some major significance!
Looking at it at the quantum level,
Hund's rule of maximum multiplicity might--
Yeah... Not a chance.
--No?
--Nope.
Same as before. Neither
warmed-up nor cooled-down.
--Mayushii's Juicy #1 Chicken Tenders did freeze once--
--In any case, whatever's happening
is clearly related to Steins Gate!
Not that again...
--Daru. Don't you want to try these bananas--
--Hell no.
Then you may have the honors, Mayuri.
I dunno, gel-nanas are all
goopy and squishy and bland.
You ate one?
Mayushii...
Try saying, "Your banana's all squishy."
Umm, your banana's all squi--
Don't make her say that, you perv!
This area is currently closed off.
Please use the east entrance--
I'm melting...
We haven't even been
outside the lab ten minutes yet.
Faris-tan's place is as far as
I can go during the summer.
Wish they'd hold this at
May Queen Nyan² instead...
A college lecture at a
maid café... That'd be the day.
I'd totally ditch if it wasn't
required for course credit...
Whew! Nice and cool!
Ah, I'm alive again.
A satellite came crashing down, huh?
You're still stuck on that?
You don't wanna check
out the Radio Building, Daru?
Probably so crowded you can't see anything.
I'm keeping tabs on Snake's
live coverage on @channel anyway.
Oh, work's suspended? Another uproar?
That's right! When it happened...!
--Give me your phone.
--What for?
Just give it here!
This is a violation of privacy!
I'm totally gonna--
--I sent you an e-mail!
--Huh?
One that said Makise Kurisu was stabbed.
Oh, that one from last week?
Last week?
You broke it into three parts.
I thought were you spammin' me!
See?
Received July 23, at 12:56...
Last week...
My message outbox!
It's not here! What's today's date?
Huh? It's the 28th.
What is it?
My e-mail was sent back in time...
Huh?
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now