Whoa... Okarin?!
How...?
How?
Real...!
She's really real...
You're not a ghost?!
Do you want me to call the cops?!
I just wish to know the truth!
You were stabbed right around...
What do you mean by "truth"?!
Are you an idiot? Are you gonna die?!
Louise-chan's famous line, FTW!
You were stabbed!
I saw it with my own two eyes!
Three hours ago, during Dr. Nakabachi's
press conference at the Radio--
Okarin! "Ix-nay" the "elusions-day"!
Dr. Nakabachi's conference
was canceled, remember?!
But...!
Makise-san! It's almost time!
Right!
Hold it! You're running away?!
You're...
Don't call me "you"!
I'm Hououin... Kyouma!
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Thank you all for coming today.
I don't have much
experience giving lectures like this,
so please bear with me.
Makise Kurisu is our lecturer?
I guess she isn't a ghost...
You're still stuck on that?
I've been asked to speak
about time machines today.
Although it wasn't the
topic of my paper in Sciency,
I'd like to give it a try.
Time machines?
Basically, my belief is that "time
machines"... are nothing but nonsense.
I'll now explain how
I was led to this conclusion--
Objection!
Huh?
"Time machines are impossible?"
You're jumping to conclusions!
You've really lost it, Okarin...
You...
I disagree. I believe they
are theoretically impossible.
Do go on.
In that case, let's switch to
a discussion format instead.
That should make it easier for
certain stubborn individuals to grasp.
Don't you agree, Hououin Kyouma-san?
Makise Kurisu...
From this, we see that
time travel is unrealistic
in the context of cosmic string theory.
Any arguments, Hououin-san?
I see.
Then please find some
exotic matter for us, Hououin-san.
That concludes my line of reasoning,
but if you have any rebuttals
I'm all ears, Hououin-san.
Argh! Thinks she's hot stuff,
just 'cause she's kinda smart!
Wait. She's probably an
agent for the Organization.
In fact, the lecture itself
may've been tactical psychological
warfare targeted right at me...
I won't fall for it.
Eight...
Nine...
Just one more!
Ready, go!
Ten!
You're great, Ruka-kun!
Oh, Okarin! Too-too-roo!
Huh?
Okabe-s-- I mean, Kyouma-san...
You've forgotten the code words, Rukako.
Huh? Oh, E-El Psy C-Congree...
--Congroo.
--S-Sorry.
So, what do you need me to carry?
These.
Sorry to ask.
Mayushii didn't think she
could carry them all by herself.
They were given to my father,
but we can't eat them all.
I see. I appreciate your
donating food to the lab.
It should increase member morale.
I'm so glad you like them!
Oh, err, uhh...
Ruka does her sword-swinging
practice every day!
Yes. I promised Oka-- I mean,
Kyouma-san, that I would.
Aye.
The Supernatural Sword Samidare
shall demonstrate its true power
once it deems you a worthy wielder.
--Do not forget that.
--Right!
And it only cost 980 yen at
the weapons shop! What a deal!
Now, let's see the results of your training.
--Can you perform an exorcism?
--Huh? I-I suppose so...
But for a proper exorcism,
my father is much--
A-An evil spirit has
possessed my right hand!
Hurry and exorcise it!
--Before it fully overcomes me!
--Right!
That's the opposite hand from last time.
Th-The spirit chose this one today!
Urushibara Ruka.
The voice and mannerisms of a woman...
No, even more feminine than a woman.
But he's a dude.
Taller than Mayuri, and
with such a slender figure.
But he's a dude.
Looks great in a shrine maiden outfit...
The sun is setting, yet it's still so hot out.
The cicadas are buzzing.
But...
...he's a dude.
Bye-bye!
It's incredible that Ruka-kun
can perform exorcisms!
He's the son of a shrine family, after all.
Whoosh! Whoosh!
Sorry!
It's blocked off?
Yeah, this leads to the
back of the Radio Building...
The Radio Building...
Give me yours too.
Huh?
You got work, right? Give 'em here.
Okay. Thanks.
I have a late shift today, so I'll probably
just head straight home after work.
Mayuri!
You really didn't hear a scream?
A scream? When?
Today, at the Radio Building.
I don't think so...
Oh.
Okay, then.
Huh? You're so goofy, Okarin.
No one remembers at all...
Not Mayuri, Daru, or Makise Kurisu...
Closing early today, Mr. Braun!
I told ya to quit calling me that.
I'm interviewin' a part-timer today.
A part-timer?
At a dingy shop with no customers,
run by some filthy old man?
Say again?
Whassup!
Huh?
Huh? I heard that's a
trendy way of saying "hello"...
Don't tell me she's your part-timer?
Got a problem with that?
--Name?
--Amane Suzuha.
--Age?
--18.
--Reason for applying?
--I love CRT TVs.
--You're hired.
--Hooray!
What is this, a comedy skit? A joke?
Who are you, anyway?
Name's Okabe. He's an
idiot who rents a room upstairs.
It's not "Okabe"! It's Hououin--
Shut up! Don't make me double your rent!
--I'm Okabe Rintaro.
--Nice to meetcha!
Hey, what's in the bags?
Oh. Intelligence Corn
that was donated to the lab.
If you want some, appropriate compensation is--
Corn? Like with the little bumps?
--Wow, so this is what it starts out like!
--You've never seen corn before?
--Can I see--?
--Whoa, there.
The Organization has targeted
many who've crossed paths with me.
Sara, Claudia, Simone...
Oh. You can talk to me about it, if you'd like.
Don't take him seriously. He's delusional.
Oh?
Yes, just keep telling yourself that.
Someday, the world will kneel before me.
Wow. So that's what's trendy these--
It crashed around noon...
Mayuri and Daru were right.
The conference was canceled?
"Makise Kurisu incident"...
Did I just hallucinate it all...?
John Titor?
SERN maintains a strict monopoly
on the time machine market.
Neither civilians nor
corporations can acquire one.
They've used them for their personal
gain, to create a dystopian world.
I've come to change the future.
To destroy SERN's
dystopia and restore freedom.
So you're saying SERN = dictators?
Ah, the so-called "Grandfather Paradox"?
It doesn't exist.
It's possible to meet your past self.
You'll simply change world lines if you do.
First, time isn't a single line
moving from past to future.
It's comprised of infinite parallel lines
called "world lines" that flow like a river.
For example, let's say a
maniac murders you today.
If I go back in time to prevent it,
it would create two divergent worlds:
one in which you die and
one in which you survive.
So now Titor is Japanese, huh?
A self-proclaimed time traveler
who appeared on the American Internet in 2000...
He claimed to have come from
the year 2036 to save the future.
It took the Internet by storm, and
many books were written about him.
I just can't believe there's an idiot
pretending to be John Titor now...
Just click this link and go read up on Titor...
Dammit, Daru. You deleted
the link about Titor...
Twelve results? That's impossible.
Even if it was ten years ago,
it still caused a huge uproar!
That can't be right!
They're gone! They're gone!
How come?! I had books about him right here!
Damn!
Hello?! Daru?!
What is it? I'm with Faris-tan--
--Where are the books?!
--Huh? What books?
The ones about John Titor!
They were all on the bookshelf! Where are they?!
--Hold on, Okarin.
--What?!
Who's... John Titor?
I stayed up almost all night
trying to find out about John Titor.
I scoured the Internet for
whatever information I could find.
But...
I have a question for you, Titor.
About ten years ago...
The year 2000, in other words.
That's an interesting thing to ask.
Unfortunately, however,
I've never visited the year 2000.
Nor do I have any plans to...
H-Hey! Wait!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Not so fast! I mean, wait! If you'd please!
You just took a picture of me!
You should delete it, for you own safety!
I apologize if I've displeased you.
What were you taking pictures of?
Proof.
Proof of where I was
today... Of what I saw...
I want to ask you something.
Huh?
This.
--That's a pretty old PC.
--You recognize it?
--Oh, no.
--Do you know someone who would?
I bet you Daru might.
Who's that?
That's none of your business.
Make sure you delete that picture!
Give me his e-mail address.
I refuse!
Are you trying to blackmail me?
If you tell me, I'll delete it.
V-Very well.
But I won't sell out my comrade!
I'll give you my address instead.
What's your name?
It says "Hououin Kyouma" right there!
Let me do it.
Send me a blank message.
I'll send you a reply later.
Welcome home, Master! Meow!
Oh! It's Okarin!
Welcome home, Okarin!
Yo, Mayuri.
It's "Mayushii Meow-Meow" while I'm working!
Say, I just realized that "Okarin"
sounds kind of like "ocarina," huh?
--Uhh... Where's Daru?
--He's inside.
Oh! Kyouma?!
It's about time, meow!
What happened to your promise
to visit every three days, meow?!
My apologies. Organization
interference has been terrible--
What?! The Organization is that close now?!
Are you holding another top-secret
meeting to overthrow them then?
Indeed. My usual Stealth Field, please.
You got it, meow! I wish you'd let me join too--
No! You're not a match for the Organization!
Faris has a forbidden secret move, meow.
What?! You've actually mastered it?!
That's right!
After months of difficult
training in the Guiana Highlands
and overcoming the death of
her master, Faris at long last...
...acquired the skill!
I'll never forgive you. Ever.
So, about the mail I sent you...
I feel talking to a winner
would make me a loser.
Ugh...
Don't worry. I've no interest in
a girl who spews nothing but lies.
Oh, is this today's
"Shut your filthy mouth" thread?
Be quiet, cheater! Your 2D wives are crying!
Faris-tan doesn't count!
She may be 3D, but she has a 2D soul!
Whatever. Just take a look at this.
This photo...
Oh! This is an IBN 5100, right?
IBN?
It's an ultra-rare retro PC.
About a month or so ago
there was a rumor going around
about one lurking somewhere in Akihabara.
She probably caught wind of that.
--And?
--It was never found.
Even the "Quick as Lightning
Knight Heart" tried to find it to no avail,
so it must never have existed
in the first place. Final answer.
It's that valuable?
It was sold over 30 years ago.
Prices were still so high that
nobody could buy computers back then.
That's how stuff turns super-rare.
Hmm...
That girl from earlier...
"I'm mailing you already.
My name is Kiryu Moeka.
I'm 20. I'm a freeter. Like it or
not, I'm gonna keep mailing ya!"
This is the same girl?
What's up?
Be thankful I didn't sell you out.
"It's a rare PC. Probably none in Akiba.
El Psy Congroo."
Master! Your food's ready, meow-meow!
W00t!
"The World's in Danger" FTW!
Down the hatch!
--Please enjoy!
--Calm down.
Whoa, this is seriously good!
Analysis at the university laboratory
indicates that the gel-nanas have
been torn apart at the molecular level.
Meaning they turned into non-bananas?
That can't be good. What's causing it?
The only theory I have
for now is that it's caused
by the EM waves from the Phone
Microwave (Temporary Name)...
--Based on...?
--A mad scientist's sixth-sense.
Gotcha. No basis.
'Kay! All hooked up!
Excellent! Then let us use these!
Aren't these Mayushii's?
Fear not. I used research funds
she donated to buy them myself.
--Uhh, that makes them hers--
--Now let's toss 'em in and see what happens.
One is enough, IMHO.
Can we really test the true power of the
Microwave Phone (Temporary Name) like that?
We really need to drop the
"(Temporary Name)" thing. It's annoying.
We cannot hope to alter
the world's ruling structure
by being cheap with our experiments!
You're the only one who wants to do that.
--Is that so?
--Indeed, it is.
It's done.
What is it?
The banana... It's gone!
That's absurd!
It's me! Emergency order
#666! Activate the cool-off!
Government approval?!
This is no time for that--
Acting fail!
Shut up! Where'd you hide it?!
Wha...?! You're the one who hid it!
Aha, I got it! This must
be a microwave teleporter!
Wh-What?!
That's crazy talk.
Then how do you explain how a
banana we pulled from the bunch
and put into the microwave suddenly--
A gel-nana...?
I-Is it just me, or is it
completely attached to the bunch?
--You took one off a minute ago, right?!
--I-I'm pretty sure...
Could it really be a teleporter?
You think so?
You're conducting a very
intriguing experiment, Okabe Rintaro.
No, Hououin Kyouma-san, was it?
Makise Kurisu...!
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru