Makise Kurisu...!
I tried knocking, but...
H-How did you find this place?
I asked Hashida-san.
He called it a laboratory, so
I expected something a little more proper--
Daru! Did you betray me?!
Huh?
You were taken in by this 3D girl's spell!
You'll pay for this! Indeed, you shall!
You bitch!
Could you do something about him?
Just think of it as situational confusion.
Emergency situation.
The Organization has
finally sent an agent here.
What?! This is the
choice of Steins Gate as well?!
Steins Gate...?
One of his neurotic fantasies.
It doesn't really mean anything.
Hardly surprising. It's a
jumble of German and English.
No shoes.
Oh, I'm sorry!
I was in America for so long...
Allow me to reintroduce
myself. I'm Makise Kurisu.
You can't even shake my hand?
Japanese men have no sense of etiquette.
You're acting too afraid.
Yes, it must be the aura
of bloodlust surrounding you.
Is this what they call "martial arts"?
Where are you going?!
Actually, I came to see if you
really had witnessed me being stabbed
or if it was just an excuse
for sexually harassing me.
But more importantly...
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
Their attachment site is undamaged.
There's no trickery involved.
She may be planning to plant explosives.
Keep a sharp eye on her.
Get real...
--Have any tweezers?
--No.
Okay.
The inside's squishy.
It tastes like...
Nothing. Yuck!
You vile zombie! If you're hungry, just say so!
I can give you a banana!
No thanks. Who'd eat a
pervert's banana anyway?
Pervert?!
You started poking and groping
me the moment you met me.
--Miss Makise, Miss Makise.
--Yes?
Could you say, "Who'd eat a
pervert's banana anyway?" again?
With a distressed look, if possible.
--Distressed?
--Yeah.
What are you blushing for?
Oh, did you imagine something?
Tell us, genius girl! What did
your gifted mind just envision?
Please, do tell!
It would appear that you're both perverts.
--You're too kind...
--That's not praise.
I'd say the one with the
perverted imagination is the pervert...
Perverted genius girl!
Who are you calling a pervert?!
Okay, I'll be frank.
I could easily sue you for
sexual harassment this very minute,
but I'll overlook it for now.
For now?
So give me the details.
This banana has something to
do with that microwave, correct?
That's top-secret!
Future Gadget #8, the Phone
Microwave (Temporary Name),
is our laboratory's secret weapon.
Actually, if anyone, Miss Makise might
be able to explain this crazy functionality.
But...
Seriously, we're never
gonna figure it out on our own.
But this is classified
Future Gadget Laboratory--
You! Christina, you said?
I never said that.
I'll tell you the secrets of the
Phone Microwave (Temporary Name),
but only on certain conditions!
First, you must become a member
of the Future Gadget Laboratory.
So you want me to join your lab?
But I'm returning to America in August.
Until then, then.
--Second...
--There's more?
You must forget about all
sexual harassment I have committed.
Those are my conditions!
You're petty, Okarin. Seriously petty...
That's what I love about ya!
Shut up!
--So? A good deal, wouldn't you say?
--For you, maybe.
Sheesh. You're causing me
to secrete excess noradrenaline.
What do you say, Christina?
Don't call me that!
My bad, The Zombie!
Say it right, Hououin Pervert Kyouma!
Be quiet, pervert genius girl!
Two perverts staring
each other down! That's hot!
Shut up, pervert!
Oh, all right. Fine. I accept.
Just quit with the "pervert" stuff.
I'll quit treating you like one too.
Very well.
Then, as of now, you are
officially Lab Member 004...
...Christina!
And don't call me that!
Juicy #1 Chicken Tenders! Wow!
--I'm back!
--It's a teleporter?
It's dangerous to jump
to conclusions, you know.
Then what do you think is it?
Well, it didn't teleport the chicken tenders...
--...or the banana bunch, right?
--One, two, three, four...
Oh? A visitor?
Hello. I'm Makise Kurisu.
I'm sorry for visiting unannounced.
I'm Shiina Mayuri.
It looks like I'm a lab member now too...
--A lab member?
--Yes.
A girl lab member!
I-Is it that rare?
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
You're the first girl member besides Mayushii!
Really?
Nice to meetcha!
--Yes! Likewise!
--What?!
What is it?
There was an electrical discharge!
Huh? Why didn't you mention it sooner?!
Give me all the details!
Huh? Well, uhh...
Lightning-ish stuff came
outta the microwave, and...
--When was this?
--Yesterday, around noon.
You'd rushed out after seeing
the news about the satellite crash,
so I hooked my own cell phone up to it.
So, wait, when I sent that e-mail,
your phone was connected to the
Phone Microwave (Temporary Name)?
The e-mail about Miss Makise getting stabbed?
That was last week, man.
No! I sent it at noon yesterday--!
Where is it?! Where is it?! Why isn't it here?!
What was the microwave doing
when the discharge occurred?
I was doing an operations test,
so I think it was spinning
in reverse at the time.
Sounds like we should try to recreate it.
Mayuri! Bring the Juicy #1 Chicken Tenders!
Okay!
Oh, do you all want some?
You can each have one!
Does something need to be inside?
I want to see what happens to an object inside
when it's spinning in reverse.
Daru.
Assistant. Send a message to my phone.
Since when am I your assistant?
Besides, I don't even know your e-mail address.
Lousy useless assistant.
Daru. Your phone will do.
--What should it say?
--Hmm...
"Christina is a pervert..."
I told you, that's not allowed.
Then I'll meet you halfway
and go with, "Okarin is a pervert."
--Wha...?!
--Hashida-san! Good job!
Okay! Gonna send it now!
Now we wait for the message to arrive...
They should be ready about now!
Wait!
--You okay?!
--Yeah...
Ventilation! Ventilation!
What just happened?
Was it the EM waves?
Don't be stupid.
A microwave oven's EM waves
couldn't wreck a desk in such a short time.
Ahh! They're charred black!
I just bought 'em, too...
What about the hole in the floor?
Mr. Braun's totally gonna
freak when he sees it...
--Well?
--It's here...
Received July 24th, at 5:30 pm...
It really did go back in time...
--Have you figured something out?
--Yes! It all connects!
Now I see! The one answer
that connects this string of events!
Really?
The banana returned to
the bunch it was torn from!
And this e-mail traveled
five days into the past!
No, you don't mean...
Indeed, I do!
This Phone Microwave (Temporary Name) is...
...a time machine!
Thirteen messages...?
From "S. F."...
Oh, right. That girl I named "Shining Finger."
Man, look at all these...
"E-mail me right away."
"Are you asleep?"
"How long are you gonna sleep?"
Daru...
Wanna go for a walk?
--What's wrong?
--Critical damage...
We worked all through the night for nothin'...
I regret even trying.
Why aren't they turning
into gel-nanas anymore?
Beats me.
That was the only time we
managed to send an e-mail, too.
Maybe we should ask Miss Makise back here?
You know that's not gonna happen.
No way... A time machine...?!
And then she never came back.
What was her deal?
What's this?
The LHC.
Huh?
The Large Hadron Collider.
SERN's particle accelerator.
It's such a soothing sight...
SERN maintains a strict monopoly
on the time machine market.
John Titor...
Oh, that guy you mentioned before?
@channel's going crazy over him now.
What's SERN?!
Titor said that SERN
completes a time machine by 2034!
You're making no sense...
Just tell me! What's SERN--?!
Cut it out!
It's the acronym for the European
Organization in Nuclear Research.
It's based just outside Geneva.
As its name suggests, it focuses
mainly on particle physics research.
It boasts some of the
finest facilities in the world too,
including the Low Energy Antiproton Ring,
the Proton Synchrotron Booster,
the Large Electron-Positron Collider,
and the last boss...
...the world's biggest particle
accelerator: Large Hadron Collider-tan!
There were even rumors that the
LHC could produce mini-black holes.
Black holes...
--Daru.
--Yeah?
Doesn't one theory suggest
that time travel is possible
through the use of mini-black holes?
Yeah, but you heard
Miss Makise's lecture, remember?
She said it's impossible to
generate black holes to begin with.
But with the LHC, it's possible--
Good point! Not.
SERN publicly denied it.
But where there's smoke there's fire.
It's me.
Yes. I know.
El Psy Congroo.
Who exactly are you battling?
At this juncture, we've
but one course of action.
Go visit Faris-tan!
No! You're a super hax0r, right?!
Just grin and go along with everything I say!
It's "hacker," not "hax0r." Get it right.
--You know your next task, right?
--Not a clue.
Hack into SERN.
That is all.
Okarin... You're joking, right?
Unveil their evildoing and
find out about their time machine.
Your skills will determine whether
the Phone Microwave (Temporary Name)
becomes a usable time machine or
ends up in the back of our lab's closet.
Don't blame me for whatever happens!
Two beef bowls. That'll be 800 yen total.
Okarin!
Slacking off again?
Uh-huh.
There's nothing to do
at the shop. It's so boring.
You're more like a bicycle shop now.
Say, what are you guys up to upstairs?
It's called the Future Gadget Laboratory, right?
H-How do you know that name?!
Very well, then. If you know that much...
We're battling a secret organization
that controls the world from the shadows.
In fact, we're just about to
launch a hacking offensive against it.
Oh, then is "SERN" that secret organization?
How do you know that?!
I'm sorry. I heard you guys talking up there...
Like I said, it gets really boring. So I just--
You were spying on us?!
I can't help that I can hear you.
But don't worry! I'm great at keeping secrets!
Not again.
What is it? A death report?
A what?!
O-Oh, I'm just kidding...
It's just this girl with a rabid obsession
with some retro PC called an IBN 5100...
An IBN?
You've heard of it?!
Y-Yeah...
--You overheard that too?
--No, no! I saw it online!
You know, that time
traveler guy. John Titor, was it?
Titor?!
I read about it on @channel.
The IBN 5100 was built
before PCs could run BASIC,
so it can read IBN's proprietary
programming language or something--
--Really?!
--Y-Yeah...
Come to think of it, the Titor
who appeared in 2000 also said...
You all seem to have fixed
views about the concept of time.
Time is not like a single
river flowing from past to future.
For example, let's say I go back in
time and kill someone we'll call "A."
Doing so will change what is
known as the "divergence number"
and the world line will
move to a world without A.
When a world line moves,
people's memories are reconstructed.
In other words, memories of the
world in which A existed are erased
and replaced with memories of
a world line where A doesn't exist.
I've been wanting to know for a while now--
how exactly does SERN, a research organization,
wind up as an administrative
body that rules the world?
Do not take SERN's word at face value.
They have already succeeded
in producing micro black holes.
Perhaps the easiest way to
describe this dystopia would be to call it
a revival of communism with
18th-century living standards.
In 2036, SERN possesses most of
the world's science and technology.
And you need an IBN 5100
to alter this future of yours?
Correct.
The IBN 5100's abilities are
needed to halt SERN's plans.
As I recall, the John Titor who
appeared in 2000 said something similar...
The "me" who appeared ten years ago?
As I said before, I've unfortunately
never been to the year 2000.
However, it's possible you
saw me in another world line.
I'm intrigued. I'd very much
like to talk with you sometime.
This is my e-mail address.
If you contact me, I'll reply.
Almost there...
If I can just get ahold of the SQL table list...
--...grabbing the password will be a cinch.
--Too-too-roo! Good morning!
Oh, Mayuri.
What brings you here so early?
I heard you pulled two all-nighters
in a row, so I brought some stuff!
Tadah!
Canned oden stew!
Many thanks! Continue to bring more, Mayuri!
Mayushii doesn't have enough
pocket money to treat you all the time.
I need to buy Rai-Net sausages too, after all!
More Oopas, huh?
So I hope you'll savor and enjoy this!
There's some for Daru-kun and Kurisu-chan too!
No, not there!
He doesn't hear me at all.
I keep telling him to take a break.
His super hax0r soul is burning brightly!
It's not "hax0r"!
It isn't nice to pry into
others' business, you know.
It's to expose SERN's plot.
Still...
I think Kurisu-chan ran out
because she was mad about it.
No, she left on her own,
not because of the hacking.
I hope she'll come back...
Huh? What?
I'll trade a fishcake for a beef strip.
Oh? Then I'd rather have a quail patty.
Nope. Quail patties are my
second favorite, after beef strips.
Mayushii likes them too, though.
Then take a fish tube instead.
--I guess that's better than a fishcake...
--Excellent. We have a deal.
Then here's Mayushii's beef strip--
--Huh?
--Already took it.
Huh?! When did you...?
Pretty good.
Got it!
I got it! I got it! I got it!
Now give it up and reveal everything to me!
--Yes! Got an ID!
--You're in?!
Mission complete!
You're amazing! Even if
I don't understand why...
Well, I did hack our way in,
but there's only so much we
can see without an admin ID...
Like only getting to see a character's boobs!
You're so naughty, Daru-kun.
--So what did you find?!
--Just a few e-mails so far.
English?! Let's consult Dr. Excite for help!
Forget that! Too annoying!
Translated, it says, "Hi, Paul!"
--The acting is unnecessary.
--Aww.
Let's see...
"The LHC is working well.
It's as fickle as a cat,
but things have been going
surprisingly well this past month."
--What does that mean?
--You got me.
Never mind that! Are there
any mentions of a time machine?!
The phrase "time machine" doesn't show up,
but the term "Z-Program" was used
about 100 times in the past month.
Let's see here...
"Z-Program Experiment Report 137..."
"As the aim of generating mini-black
holes has already been established,
that report is omitted."
Mini-black holes...
Seems so!
They publicly announced those
experiments were a failure, though!
What's after that?!
"Experimental result..."
"Human is dead. Mismatch."
Human is dead?
Yeah...
Someone...
...died?
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now