Let's see...
"Experimental result: Human is dead. Mismatch."
Human is dead?
Yeah...
Someone...
...died?
Yeah... I think so.
What else does it say?!
Umm... "The details are
in Jellyman's Report #14."
Jellyman's Report? What's that?
How would I know?
But there's this strange
database on the server...
What's this?!
I think it's some kind of programming code.
--Daru-kun?
--I have no idea!
I can't make any sense of this!
Die! Dammit!
Maybe we should stop.
I've finally experienced one of those,
"And I was so close too!" moments.
Good work. You can rest now.
Don't have to tell me that. I'm licked.
I got some canned oden, Daru-kun!
Thanks.
Programming code...
The IBN 5100 was built
before PCs could run BASIC,
so it can read IBN's proprietary
programming language or something--
The IBN 5100's abilities are
needed to halt SERN's plans.
I'd very much like to talk with you sometime.
This is my e-mail address.
If you contact me, I'll reply.
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
So much laundry!
Yeah, with all these all-nighters,
Daru and I haven't been home yet.
What's more, all of Daru's
clothes--from T-shirts to underwear--
are size XXXL.
--Oh! It's Faris-chan!
--Okabe Rintaro!
Whassup!
Let me warn you.
First, my name is Hououin Kyouma.
--Second, that greeting is dangerously--
--Whassup, Suzu-san!
Not you too!
Wait, since when do you know each other?
We share the same building.
It's natural to at least be acquaintances.
Suzu-san gave me this Rai-Net card!
A gold one!
Where are you going?
To do laundry.
Okarin and Daru-kun have
been up all night for days now.
Part-timer!
Take your work seriously or I'll fire you.
Yikes...
And keep your hands off my part-timer, Okabe.
Are you sure you're not the
one lusting after her, Mr. Braun?
Talk like that in front of
Nae and I'll seriously kill you.
Nae? Oh, that little critter?
Don't call my daughter an animal!
Why would I lust after my
part-timer anyway?! She's just a kid!
I'm not a kid! I'm a full-fledged warrior!
Huh?
That's a nice look, part-time warrior.
Always remember it
and someday you'll change
classes and become a true warrior--
Be quiet. Every time you talk--
Really, I am a warrior!
Why do all the weirdos gather here?
Later.
We're also--
That's one of Mayuri's habits.
I've dubbed it the "Stardust Shake Hand."
I wonder if I can reach the stars...
You can't even see them.
The stars are still there
during the day too, you know.
Those were powerful EM waves.
They definitely could've caused
a cell phone to malfunction.
But that banana...
This Phone Microwave
(Temporary Name) is a time machine!
Yeah, right.
Faris-chan...
How did this happen to you?
--I'm closing it.
--Okay...
Daru is just like the
universe--continually expanding.
Shining Finger, huh?
What's taking Titor so long?
He told me to message him!
"Tell me how to contact the Super hax0r..."
Man, she's persistent!
Thank you for contacting me.
Regarding the image of the program you sent,
it's indeed an IBN
proprietary programming language.
To decode it, you will require an IBN 5100.
Listen up!
The Future Gadget Laboratory will
now initiate its top-secret emergency plan!
What's going on, Okarin?
Wake up, Daru!
Our battle with the massive secret organization
that rules the world from
the shadows begins now!
Hnn? Whazzuh...?
I'm talking about SERN!
They're a worldwide
organization bent on evil research
and the mastermind of a vast conspiracy!
The world doesn't need two mad scientists!
We must beat them to the
punch before they beat us!
I don't understand a thing you're saying.
First, we need to get
our hands on an IBN 5100!
Then we decode SERN's mysterious program!
--Prepare to depart!
--But Mayushii has work today...
So it's all up to me now...
Trading information might be an idea...
Oh, Assistant.
Not so fast.
--What do you want?!
--Come with me.
H-Hey!
You messed up the shoulder part here...
"Almost no info here."
Useless louse!
--So why are you glaring at me?
--Fear not. You aren't the cause.
I'd appreciate you not taking
your frustration out on me.
Sulking, are we?
Mayuri was worried that you might be cross.
You're too old to be
acting like a kid, you know.
You're in absolutely no position to talk.
Anyway, what did you want to talk about?
It's simple.
Quit sulking and come back
to the lab to work, Christina.
You can at least stick to calling me one name.
Listen when people are talking, The Zombie!
You're the one not listening here!
How did I ever get involved with this guy?
I want to punch myself for
being so curious back then.
Wha...? Again?!
Are those messages that annoying?
It's absolutely insane how--
Wait, could she be an Organization agent too?!
Organization? What's that?
The Organization is the Organization!
A secret, transnational organization that
controls the world from the shadows and--
Sounds like an average
conspiracy theory. Thank you very--
--What's wrong?
--N-Nothing.
Really! It's nothing!
Keep asking me and I'll slug you!
Lashing out, huh? Come with me.
I'll give you your mission...
after we retrieve the laundry.
Huh?
Do you honestly think I'll just blindly follow--
Laundry?
Oh, so this is where it is.
You don't have one at the hotel?
No, it's a pretty fancy hotel.
But it's not my style to send
everything I wear out for cleaning.
You found it, thanks to me.
Be grateful and--
--Still no change?
--Of course not.
You don't think spinning will
cause something to happen, do you?
The answer is often hidden
in what seems most obvious.
Who would've imagined hooking
a phone up to a microwave...
--...would produce a time machine--
--It's not a time machine!
Huh?
It's some kind of mistake!
Time machines are nothing but pseudoscience.
I refuse to have any part of it.
Why do you insist on denying what you saw?
I'm not.
Could it be due to past trauma?!
Yes, when she was five,
Christina was struck by
lightning on the plains of Arkansas--
No, I wasn't.
Then why?
I already explained why.
It's theoretically impossible.
Theories are nothing more
than lexical entertainment.
Just accept what you saw.
No.
--Why are you so stubborn to--
--I said no!
I won't...
I won't repeat my father's failure!
I'm sorry. I got emotional.
Don't worry about it!
I purposely angered you
to ascertain how you think--
Anyway, the Phone
Microwave is not a time machine.
Understood.
I apologize for forcing you to join our lab.
You needn't come anymore.
But I will tell you this...
The title of Lab Member 004
will be set aside forever.
That number will always be yours.
Quit trying to act cool!
What's the big idea?!
That was the perfect farewell speech!
And it annoys me!
You still have laundry here. I'll leave.
Bye.
--What?!
--That's payback.
I suggest you reflect on the error of your ways.
Yeah, fine. Bye.
Wait.
Quit grabbing me there!
Do you know anything about the IBN 5100?
IBN?
An old PC.
--What are you going to use it for?
--Curious to know?
You are, aren't you?
Urgh...
Just a little.
The IBN 5100 is connected to SERN's secrets.
Huh?
SERN is researching time travel,
and we need the IBN 5100's unique
functionality to decode their secret program.
Well? Are you shocked?
Ridiculous. What a waste of time.
Y-You scoffed at me!
Curse you!
Well, I'll show you!
Just you wait, Christina!
I told you not to call me that...
--SERN is researching time travel...
--We need the IBN 5100's unique functionality...
What nerve. I only told her
'cause she said she was curious...
A PC?
Yeah, an old one.
I think it costs 5100 yen or something...
5100? Could you mean...?
Too-too-roo!
Guess what, Okarin! Mayushii
found out something amazing!
--No cell phones.
--Faris-chan said she's seen the PC you're looking for!
No cell phones!
H-Hey!
Geez...
You didn't leave enough!
Faris Meow-Meow! Faris Meow-Meow!
What is this?!
Everyone!
Thanks for coming, meow!
We're about to start the daytime Faris Cup!
Try your hardest to beat Faris
and win an order of special
Meow-Meow Omelet Rice!
Faris Meow-Meow! Faris Meow-Meow!
Wh-What dimension is this?
Oh, Okarin!
Too-too-roo!
Mayuri...
What's going on here?
Was there a space-time distortion?!
No, it's the Faris Cup!
Huh?
Faris-chan is going to play
Rai-Net Battler with all the visitors here!
Oh, Kyouma!
Are you going to compete too?
Faris can play against
up to ten people at a time!
--So it's not too late--
--I refuse!
Never mind that! The IBN 5100! Where is it?!
Well...
I'll tell you if you compete.
Don't be stupid!
The future of the world's
structure hangs in the balance!
--A silly game isn't--
--I'm sorry, then. Please leave.
A lowly maid is telling her master to leave?!
--The IBN 5100--
--Can't hear you!
I'm in a hurry.
I'm sorry, but I won't hold anything back.
Meow, meow. You're really
confident in yourself, meow.
Can you win, Okarin?
Faris-tan is a top national player, you know...
"Can you win?"
You should ask Faris that question.
I have a surefire,
infallible strategy up my sleeve!
A strategy?
Strategy Code...
K.B.O.O.M.!
Otherwise known as K-Boom!
Oh!
That sounds awesome!
Interesting.
Act tough now, while you still can.
For when this strategy detonates,
you may very well lose your life!
You're serious about this, Kyouma.
Just so we're clear...
Once I've participated,
you'll tell me everything you know.
All right?
Cat ears never lie.
I challenge you!
Now you'll learn there are some
opponents you can never beat!
--I surrender!
--That was fast!
Mayushii is disappointed.
What the hell strategy was that?
I'm not sure.
But Kyouma kept charging at me,
like he wanted to go kaboom.
Kaboom?
K-Boom...
K-Boom?
Thank you very much
for that terrible word play.
--However!
--WTF?!
--Now tell me what you know, Faris!
--He recovers fast!
You're stuck-up for someone who lost.
I told you I'd participate only
if you told me what you know.
In other words, winning never
mattered to me from the start.
Is that right?
I don't really remember...
Remember it! It was an ingenious strategy!
Ingenious? More like underhanded, I'd say...
Shut up!
Where's the IBN 5100?!
--I don't know...
--You don't?!
I know Daddy had one when
I was little, but it's gone now.
Curses!
Is that the secret sidestepping
technique you mastered
in the Guiana Highlands?!
How did you know?!
Well done, Kyouma. You saw
right through my Ignoring Shoulder.
Is that really all?
Yeah. The last time I saw it
was at a shrine in Akihabara.
A shrine?
"Kurisu. Thank you for messaging
me all the way from Japan."
"Regarding your query,
I consulted the professor and he said
that the IBN 5100 could indeed
analyze special programming languages."
He was telling the truth?
Huh? A PC?
I'd have to ask my father...
It's an IBN 5100.
If he doesn't recognize the name,
just say it's an old computer.
Okay, I'll ask him.
I'm counting on you.
Now end with the code phrase...
E-El Psy Congree...?
Congroo!
Hello?
It's me, Makise.
Makise?
Sorry, doesn't ring a bell. Where did we meet?
Paris? London?
Akihabara. I just saw you!
Oh, is that you, Assistant?
You should've just said it's Christina.
Don't call me that!
Man, you're as loud and annoying as ever.
Only because of a certain someone else!
What do you want?
Where are you?
Why?
No reason.
I'm just on my way to Yanabayashi Shrine to--
What?! Was that just a prank call?! Was it?!
What was with that phone call?
All I wanted was your location.
I don't remember anyone asking you here.
No one did.
Sorry to keep you waiting!
Oh, did you ask him?!
Yes! My father said
there's one of those PCs here!
--Really?!
--A PC...?
Do you mean an IBN 5100?!
Yes.
--Umm, who might she be?
--My assistant.
--So, the IBN--
--Hold on!
What kind of offhand introduction is that?!
Besides, I'm not your assistant!
I didn't come here to introduce you!
It wouldn't even take ten seconds!
Geez, you're annoying.
This is Makise Kurisu. My assistant.
Fine, whatever. I'm your assistant.
So who are you?
I-I'm Urushibara Ruka.
How old are you?
--I turn seventeen this year.
--That's one year younger than me...
Oh, really?
You look so grown-up and mature, Makise-san.
And pretty.
Oh, no. You're much prettier.
Huh? U-Umm... I'll go get my father!
Ignorance is bliss, as they say.
What do you mean?
Wow, I can't believe it really happened...
Wh-What do you mean?
Well, you see, the person who
donated this computer also said
to take good care of it, for a young
man in need of it would someday appear.
About ten years ago, I'd say?
I see.
This is truly a coincidence of fate...
The choice of Steins Gate!
Not that again...
IBN 5100 Portable Computer.
No doubt about it.
Is that what you're looking for?
Umm, could we possibly borrow it?!
Of course.
Thank you!
--Assistant! Haul this back!
--No u.
What kind of assistant are you, Christina?!
I'm not your assistant! And don't call me that!
I'll go get a cart.
Oh, no, we couldn't ask any more of you!
Hey, Assistant! Take a hint, will you?!
Huh?! You're telling me to talk a hint?!
You're certainly good friends, I see.
Be a good friend to them too, Ruka.
Right!
Wait here a moment.
You have a nice father.
Do you think so?
I won't repeat my father's failure!
What?
Nothing.
I'm sorry!
The cart seems to be broken...
How did I get stuck doing this with you?!
Just shut up and carry it.
We've still a long way to go!
--Say...
--What?
Never mind!
What's with the attitude, you?!
Hey! Wait! You're making me walk backwards!
Walk briskly, Assistant!
I can't! I can't do this walking backwards!
I know you can do it, Assistant!
Thank you for the encouragement! But I can't!
I request we walk sideways!
No, we have to! Or I'm gonna fall!
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru