Hey, part-timer! Need ya up front!
Right!
I never said that!
Did too! You said taking
breaks would be more efficient!
You're the one who
has to rest every few steps!
That was meant to throw
the Organization off our trail!
--Get real. No one's coming after us.
--Okabe Rintaro!
What's this?
Curious to know?
Under normal circumstances,
I'd be unable to tell you
as that information is top-secret. However...
Come on! Put it down if
you're going to take a while!
Endure it, Assistant.
Then stop making a big deal
out of it and just tell her already!
Nonsense! This is an extremely important item!
If this isn't a big deal,
then I don't know what is!
Is it an IBN 5100?
Wha...?!
She knows, Christina!
Where did you find it?
It was being kept at Yanabayashi Shrine
when I, the mad scientist
chosen by God, descended upon--
Talk or put it down! Choose one!
Makise Kurisu...
Huh? Y-Yes.
Who's she?
A part-time worker at the CRT Work... shop...
Huh?
U-Umm...
Hey! Part-timer! Quit loafin' around!
Why was she glaring at me?
--'Cause you look sinister, obviously.
--Huh?!
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
Wow, it's so big!
It's almost like a tiger rug!
It's like a futon!
Mayushii is lying on my shirt...
The sight of it sets my heart ablaze!
Okay! Put it down slowly.
--You don't have to tell me!
--Kurisu-chan!
I'm sorry for visiting out
of the blue like this again.
No, you can come anytime you like!
You're a lab member, after all!
I distinctly recall her stating
yesterday that she'd never come back.
You're a capricious one, all right.
I'm not here because I want
to be! You asked me for help!
Huh?! You mean you don't like it here?
Huh? Oh, no, it isn't that.
It's not that I hate it here...
So, what's in the box?
Curious to know?
--Under normal circumstances--
--An IBN 5100.
Seriously?! Sweet!
Okarin FTW!
He does what we can't,
with the greatest of ease!
--All his base...
--...are not belong to me.
A-Anyway, let's boot it up!
We found it thanks to Mayushii, you know!
Yes. You deserve all the credit this time.
It works!
So now can you analyze that programming code?
Easier said than done.
I don't know how to use this thing.
It was built long before the Internet,
so there's no way to hook it up to anything.
For now, I'll need these parts.
All right. You heard him, Assistant.
Please stop calling me that as if it were fact.
--You are my assistant.
--Am not!
You go, Okarin. I doubt she
knows Akiba well enough anyway.
Oh, all right.
Mayuri! Let's go!
Mayushii will stay here
and focus on showing Kurisu-chan
around the lab so she'll like it!
Christina! Curse you!
--Don't tell me you've charmed Mayuri too!
--I've done nothing of the sort!
Miss Makise seducing Mayuri...
Yuri development FTW...!
Stop imagining things, pervert!
It's nice for girls to be
together, don't you think?
A-Anyway, could you show me around?
Okay!
Then we'll start with the
shower room in the back!
Huh? There's even a shower here?
Yeah.
But sometimes the hot water
gets cold if you use it for too long,
so be careful!
Wait... Do you actually use this sometimes?
Yeah, once in a while!
Please! Promise me you'll
never shower here again!
--It's too dangerous!
--Don't look at me!
It's practically suicide...
Why are you even here, anyway?
Did he blackmail you or force you
into becoming a member somehow?!
Mayushii is Okarin's hostage.
--I think I need to call the police.
--Wait!
She just said she's your hostage.
That's irrefutable evidence.
It's not like that.
Mayushii chose to be his hostage!
Huh?
What does she mean?
--I'm off.
--Bye!
I'm fairly certain this will
work as a suitable replacement...
'Sup!
How's the IBN 5100? Seem useable?
Shh! Don't speak that name here!
Oh, you're gathering parts?
Want some help?
I never would've imagined a part-time
warrior would know so much about PCs.
Yeah, I used to know an IBN expert.
Really?! Then please
put me in touch with them!
I can't.
If you refuse, be prepared
to experience hell on earth!
Really, I can't.
Don't you value your life?!
I can't... because he's dead.
He died years ago.
My apologies.
No, I should apologize for earlier...
Has my assistant done something wrong?
No. Nothing at all.
Did she glare at you first or something?
Oh, did she scoff at you too?
No. She hasn't done anything.
Then...
She doesn't know anything yet.
But beware of Makise Kurisu.
What does that mean?!
An air raid?!
They're broadcasting the fireworks.
I'm pretty sure it's today.
Fireworks... Fireworks...
Oh, I've heard of those!
Huh? You've never seen any before?
Where are they?! Which way?!
Follow that street toward the
river and you should see 'em.
Thanks!
Give me your e-mail address!
A festival?
It's a fireworks display!
Fireworks, huh...
Want to go see it?
Huh? N-No, not really...
Oh! Okarin!
Too-too-roo!
--Heading home?
--Yeah!
--Did you find the parts?
--All right here.
I see. I take it you're
going to try things out now?
Interested?
You are, aren't you?
Urgh, all right! Just a little!
But I'm not interested in any of
your SERN conspiracy nonsense!
I simply want to know the truth.
--I'm sorry.
--What for?
I'm going back to the laboratory after all.
Oh. Mayushii is going home, then.
Okay.
--Kurisu-chan?
--Hmm?
You'll visit again, right?
Yeah. I'm a member until
I return to America, after all.
Yeah!
Bye!
What absurdity was that?
You're my assistant;
of course you'll come to the lab.
She said you're childhood friends.
How did you grow up in the same
environment yet end up so socially inept?
Yes, Mayuri's always been a little "off."
I'm referring to you!
"Here's my first e-mail!
Better than I imagined!
Fireworks are amazing!"
Oh? It hasn't worked once since then?
I'm borrowing this.
I feel so much calmer in a lab coat!
Yes!
My judgment steered me right!
You're perfect!
Wh-What's going on? You're creeping me out...
A lab coat!
Inside a research organization,
a lab coat is a uniform!
I keep telling that to Daru and Mayuri,
but they just don't understand.
But you do!
Now, then! Let us stand together
with our hands in our pockets!
--Huh?
--Quickly!
--L-Like this?
--Yes!
This is a pose of intelligence and ecstasy
given off only by those who
dedicate their lives to research!
--That lab coat is my gift to you.
--Itchy...
Let us enjoy them together
to our hearts' content!
I can't help but feel you're insulting me--
Hungry, are we?
Sh-Shut up. I haven't eaten since lunch.
Very well, then. I'm feeling charitable today.
--Kindly shove it down.
--Are you serious?!
--Dissatisfied?
--Of course I am!
Don't you have anything else?
We do have some cup ramen.
But I doubt someone raised
in America would ever want--
Cup ramen?
I'll have that.
What flavors do you have?
Soy sauce and salt!
I'll have the salt flavor.
...And a fork.
Better hurry before
time runs out and you lose.
Maybe you should give up? You clearly
have a virus card at the end there.
It's too obvious.
Feel free to believe so.
Then I'll just put this here and...
There. Check.
Oh? You enjoy Dk Pepper, Assistant?
Well, I did spend seven years in America.
I bet we'll make great drinking buddies!
Sorry, but I'm underage.
I meant Dk Pepper drinking buddies.
Just that one drink?
That gives it true significance.
Together we can share our passion
for Dk Pepper, the intelligent drink!
Could you stop trying to peek
under my card as you say that?
Okay, I win.
I have to be honest--you lack the
ability to see the big picture, Okabe.
You only focus on your own strategy;
you never consider what your opponent
is thinking or if something's a trap.
--Seriously, you--
--Hold on!
What?
What did you just say?
Th-That you lack the
ability to see the big picture.
I-It's the truth.
Before that!
You said "Okabe"!
So?
I know I'm younger than you, but since
you have no sense of respect as it is--
No!
I am Hououin!
How many times must
I repeat myself, Christina?!
From now on, you will call me Hououin!
Or Kyouma...
Are you crying?
No!
I wasn't terrified of a scary man yelling at me,
thereby causing me to
cry afterward out of relief!
That didn't happen at all!
Daru. Why is my assistant crying?
I believe she just told you why.
Let's see... This goes like so and... Huh?
Then, if this goes here...
Ah, it goes like this.
Assistant.
I'm not your assistant, but what?
Perhaps you should return
to your hotel for the night?
--It's nearby, right?
--Don't worry.
I'm leaving if it doesn't work by morning.
Shouldn't you contact your family or something?
My mother's in America,
and I haven't seen my father in seven years.
Thus I have no one to contact.
Ah, so you're a prodigal perverted genius girl.
Quit adding weirder things to it.
I got it...
I got it!
You did it?!
Mission Complete II!
So what did you find?!
I haven't checked anything yet.
But here's that "Z-Program" thing...
It says 1973?
Yeah...
--When was SERN founded?!
--1954.
--When was the IBN 5100 made?!
--1975.
Meaning SERN implemented
a special programming language
in the IBN 5100 solely for this project?!
That's a little too farfetched.
But it is possible!
We'll know for sure once
we read this report, right?
I bet it's just an old
report about particle physics
and nothing conspiracy-related at all.
WTF, a JPEG file?!
I can't copy-and-paste that!
Oh, it's not in French...
Let's see... "Space-time Control
and its Destruction of History..."
Oh, right! You can read English, Miss Makise!
Good work, Assistant!
All the time you spent in
America was entirely for this moment!
Get real.
Let's see...
"In other words, creating a
utopia spanning from past to future
will be the purpose of SERN's
existence in the 21st century."
A utopia...?!
Dystopia!
That can't be right! Skip these
intro remarks and go to the main text!
I think you'll have to find it...
Let's see...
"As this is a classified experiment..."
That's not it.
"Those working on the program..."
That's not it, either.
Here!
"The Z-Program will test the
feasibility of spatiotemporal transferal
through the use of
high-energy proton collisions."
Spatiotemporal transferal?
They mean time travel!
--You can't be serious!
--No, it's true!
Just as I thought, SERN's been
conducting time travel research
for over forty years now!
Wait! Let's not jump to conclusions!
"Program Stage 1: construction and
application of the Large Hadron Collider."
"Program Stage 2: practical
application and tuning of the lifter."
What's a "lifter"?
Remember all that hubbub a long
while ago about "ionocrafts" or whatever?
Let's see here...
It's floating?!
It apparently occurs when running a
high-voltage current through aluminum.
What does that have to do with time machines?
I don't know, but that's what it says here.
In other words, it uses the
power of a black hole and a lifter.
What else does it say?!
"Program Stage 3: animal experiments."
"Program Stage 4..."
What is it?!
"...Human experiments."
"Human is dead. Mismatch."
What?
We found that in an
e-mail when we first hacked in.
After that, didn't it say...
"The details are in Jellyman's Report."
Can we see that report, Daru?!
I think so, but is it really a good idea?
If this is real, it's totally
top-secret, confidential stuff!
Now you're scared, after coming this far?
Think about it. This is SERN we're dealing with.
And this is a top-secret report,
hidden away for the past 40 years.
Then you're not going to read it?
You need to leave.
Huh?
Learning any more than
this may put you in danger.
You're a genius with a
successful future ahead of you.
Wait... Are you worried about me?
Of course I am!
You're...
You're my assistant, after all!
Why, thank you.
But I'm not going anywhere.
I won't be able to sleep with this on my mind.
--You won't regret it?
--No.
What about you, Daru?
Well, I am a super hacker;
I can't imagine screwing up so
much they'd be able to trace us.
All right.
Then we will now commence our
analysis of the Jellyman's Report!
Additionally, I hereby dub
this operation "Laegjarn's Chest"!
Why Norse mythology?
In fact, why does it even need a name?
Daru! Commence operation!
Righty-o.
Is this it?!
Hmm, there are 14 files in all.
I'll just pick a random one.
"Jellyman's Report #10.
Subject: James McCarthy.
Birthplace: America.
Date of Experiment: January 28, 2005.
Z-Program 4 Experimental Result...
Human is dead. Mismatch."
That again?!
"It is believed that the
subject was unable to withstand
the supergravitationally-induced
infinite compression
or the transit through the
singularity inside the Kerr black hole."
--A newspaper article?
--Looks like it.
Look at the date!
April 3, 1921!
"A man was found dead inside a
building wall on 14th Street, in New York.
The body of this unidentified
man was squishy and jelly-like..."
WTF...?
Does it mean they've succeeded
in time travel, even if it isn't perfect?
"Report #8.
Subject: Linda Hill.
Birthplace: England.
Z-Program 4.
Date of Experiment: February 15, 2004.
Experimental Result: Human is dead. Mismatch."
"October 2, 1972.
The body of a woman was
discovered in a gelatinous state
on a road in Dharmapuri, Tamil Nadu, India.
The bottom half is believed
to have been destroyed
after being abandoned and hit by a car."
And this one?!
"Report #7.
Subject: Michael Lang.
Birthplace: Germany.
Z-Program 4.
Experimental Result: Human is dead. Mismatch."
--A Japanese article?!
--Yeah.
"May 24, 1936.
Body discovered at foot of Mount Hiei in Kyoto."
There are fourteen of these?
Wanna see more?
No, I've seen enough.
Okarin...
I'm gonna get something to drink.
He's really shaken up.
Still, why did they all turn to jelly?
Judging from the data so far,
I think SERN is developing technology
to facilitate time travel via Kerr black holes.
If so, then they're shoving 10-24
kilograms into a 10-19 meter-wide space
to send it to the past.
It would be like trying to stick
this sponge through this hole.
Doing so "empties" what's inside...
Basically, it's a really tight fit?
Yeah. You're squeezing
into something really tight.
Whoa, explanations
don't get any dirtier than that.
Huh? What do you mean-- Huh?!
Hashida, you pervert!
I'd say you have quite the imagination yourself.
Don't put me on your level.
What do you plan to do?
Say something.
I know it comes as a shock,
but now that we know, we have
to reach some sort of conclusion.
Okabe?
Conclusion? There's only one conclusion.
Huh?
We have Future Gadget #8, the
Phone Microwave (Temporary Name).
We'll build a flawless time
machine first, before SERN does!
And then we'll reshape
this world's ruling structure!
You're too much to deal with.
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now