It has been five days since the space satellite
crashed into the Radio Building in Akihabara.
Throngs of people have gathered
again this morning to get a look at it,
but the satellite's country
of origin remains unknown
and it is unclear just
when it will be removed.
Excuse me, do you have a moment?
Are you here today to see the satellite?
Could you tell us where you're from too?
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Oh!
So this is a...!
It's great!
You've never had a beef bowl before?
Nope! I'd only heard about them!
They really taste great!
They're even greater with raw egg on top.
If you fancy yourself a warrior,
I suggest you become capable
of visiting beef bowl shops by yourself.
Well, Daru and I do come here often.
Just ask and we'll join you anytime.
Oh! I just remembered!
Okarin! You stiffed me with
the bill the last time we ate here!
Yes, that possibly might have happened...
Not "possibly"! "Definitely"!
Pay me back!
Unfortunately, I have no money on me today.
It's me.
Transfer the funds into my
Swiss bank account immediately.
What?! The Organization has hacked its way...
--...into the Geneva servers?!
--No cell phones.
--Damn! I can't believe this!
--Oh, it's just an act.
Too-too-roo!
I didn't know you were with them, Suzu-san!
Yeah, I just happened to be on my lunch break.
You could've eaten with us
too if you'd come a little earlier.
Then let's all eat there tomorrow!
--Okarin's treat!
--What's that?!
The Organization's sabotage will
keep the servers offline for a full week?!
Oh! It's Kurisu-chan!
Oh, Assistant. Did you get good rest last night?
Don't call me your assistant.
Hey, part-timer!
If your lunch is over, get back to work!
What's her deal?
A round table meeting?
--Aye.
--Whazzat?
A lab member meeting.
Have we ever done one before?
I don't even see a round table here...
Not a physical one.
But as lab members, there's a round
table within our hearts. Isn't that so?
So or not so, don't go putting
weird things in other people's hearts.
Do you think there's
one in Mayushii's heart too?!
Indeed, there is.
Really? I'm glad!
But what's a round table?
And why a round table?
Who are you, King Arthur?
I'm a limited-time-only lab member anyway.
Whatever the case, it's time
for a round table meeting.
We need to fill Mayuri in
on the situation now facing us.
Situation?
So, to beat SERN to the punch,
we must work as quickly as possible
to perfect the Phone Microwave
(Temporary Name)'s time machine functionality.
Oh? That's too complicated
for Mayushii to understand...
All you need to know is that SERN is evil.
What do you mean by "perfect" it, though?
We've already successfully
sent messages back in time.
Only twice!
And we still don't know what
conditions trigger the phenomenon.
With the last experiment, it only worked
when there was an electrical discharge.
That's it!
Did you figure something out?
No, "Mail Sent to the Past" is too hard to say.
Let us first begin by
figuring out a name for them.
Huh?!
--Not more parenthetical names!
--Don't give that tone!
No one mocks the
great Hououin Kyouma and--
You just want to come up
with another absurd name.
How rude! Then I'll tell you!
I've named the phenomenon of
sending e-mails to the past thusly!
I dub it "Nostalgia Drive"!
Incidentally, it's written with the
characters for "nostalgic journey across time,"
but it's read as "Nostalgia Drive."
Too complicated. Rejected.
Hold on! Assistants
have no authority to reject--
Let's vote on it, then.
Who's for "Nostalgia Drive"?
Mayuri! Daru! You backstabbers!
I think Kurisu-chan is right.
Mayushii can't remember such a long name.
You're majorly delusional, man.
I think we should focus on keeping it simple.
Since it's going against the flow
of time, "Contrari-Mail" sounds nice.
--What's "contrari"?
--That's hardly simple at all.
It should clearly be "The Mail
That Leapt Through Time."
--No, that's too stiff and hard to say.
--You're in no position to talk.
Your "Nostalgia Whatever"
was long too, you know!
It has romanticism! That's all that matters!
Then I'll shorten it to "Time Leaper."
That doesn't tell you what leaps through time!
An e-mail? A girl? Bananas?
Too-too-roo!
Mayushii has a name too!
It's... "Back to the Mail"!
That means you're going back
to the e-mail. That makes no sense.
Then "DeLorean Mail"!
That makes even less sense!
Say...
Why don't we just go with
that and shorten it to "D-mail"?
Oh! That sounds good!
It's decided then.
We will now begin our D-mail
(Temporary Name) experiments.
We can drop the "(Temporary Name)" part too.
This will be known as Operation Urd.
We don't need that, either.
But we don't know what causes
the D-mail phenomenon to occur,
or what the electrical
discharge has to do with it.
That's precisely what we're about to find out.
I, Hououin Kyouma, have a hypothesis.
We've overlooked the simplest
and most crucial condition of all...
Namely, the time they occurred!
The first D-mail was sent
between noon and 1:00 pm.
The second occurred at around 6:00 pm.
In other words, if we re-conduct
the experiment at those times,
it could occur again! ...Maybe.
That's way too simple if you ask me.
But it's worth trying.
Mayuri! Bring a banana!
Mayushii is getting low on bananas...
Is it really necessary to insert the banana?
"Insert the banana!"
Daru. This isn't the time.
We need to see if it turns
into a "jellyman" or not.
Now, hurry, Assistant. Put the banana inside.
"Put the banana inside!"
Knock it off, you pervert!
Sorry. I'll buy you a new one later.
Really?! I'm so happy!
Okarin and Daru-kun never buy me any.
Sheesh...
Oww!
--Drop the cute and clumsy act.
--I'm not acting!
Pain, pain, fly away!
Thanks, Mayuri.
Quit making a Yuri Field over
there and help set up the D-mail!
Yeah, yeah.
Is 120 seconds on the timer okay?
Aye.
Commence Operation Urd!
Now!
Yes... Yes!
Where's the banana?!
It turned into a gel-nana!
Ooh!
I finally figured it out!
Just as I thought, the time of day is
a key part of the D-mail phenomenon!
Good thinking, Okabe. It was
so simple it never occurred to me...
Feeling vexed?
Your recognition of my praiseworthiness
is nonetheless admirable.
Anyway, has the D-mail arrived?
Yeah, it worked.
It arrived five days ago.
Did you send two messages, Miss Makise?
No. Only one.
It's been split into two messages!
What does this text mean, anyway?
Look it up yourself.
Say, come to think of it,
our D-mail the other day
was split into multiple
messages too, with part of it cut off.
That one went back five days too.
Yeah. Must be some sort of physical law-- Oh!
Which means that message...
...called me a no-brained idiot?!
Took you long enough.
How dare you, Christina.
Trying to sneak your insults--
Whoa, why are you buying so much?
Nonperishable cup ramen
is all the food we need.
And one bag of the
cheap chocolate is enough.
But it's to celebrate the experiment's success--
Just put it back.
Tightwad.
That's right...
I was so excited by the experiment's
success that I almost forgot
that we learned SERN's terrifying secrets
and that we've dragged Mayuri into it too...
Is this really a good thing?
Oh, it's you, Shining Finger.
What?
What are you doing?
You... don't have your phone?
Hououin Kyouma's cell phone is
not here, for it is currently being used...
--...in a truly historic experiment.
--All set. Oh...?
O-O-Okarin!
This wood-inducing-- I mean, sexy 3D girl...
Just who might she be?
Yes, allow me to introduce you.
This is Shining Finger, Kiryu Moeka.
N-Nice to meet you, Kiryu--
There was a short time when
even I had hope for the 3D world...
Oh! Yo!
Are you guys making merry or something?
Indeed.
We're conducting experiments
that will go down in history--
That's nice and all...
...but my boss is really ticked off.
He says all the shaking
upstairs is getting out of hand.
"I'll raise your rent 10,000 yen,
dammit!" and stuff like that.
10,000?
All right, I'll handle this.
Daru. Go tell my assistant to
halt the experiments for a while.
Roger.
Remember the eye of the tiger...
Is Makise Kurisu still up there?
Oh, yeah. You glared at her again earlier...
Just what's your deal with her?
Did something happen in the past?
No, nothing in the past.
Yes. It was the summer you were eight.
The red-eared slider that got away
on that dry Mississippi riverbed--
Nothing happened! I never met her before!
Never mind that--I'd go
apologize to my boss if I were you.
What the hell are you guys doing up there?
You've been shakin' the whole
damn place for a while now...
Actually, we're conducting
the experiment of the century
that will rewrite the history of science.
But you needn't worry,
for we're done for today--
I told her to stop!
What are you doing?!
I told you to stop the experiment!
Miss Makise said she
wanted to do one last one...
I sent you an e-mail. Did you not get it?
Of course I did not!
--I warned you five days ago, too.
--Quit screwing around--
Oh, actually, your cell phone rang a lot
even when we weren't running experiments.
--Why won't she just talk to me?!
--What's wrong?
I don't know either, but I think
he's not getting enough calcium.
I'm not the one to blame here!
Well, it doesn't matter much now,
since I got enough data to mostly
figure out how these D-mails work.
What?!
One second on the timer equals
one hour backward in real time.
So 120 seconds equates to 5 days in the past.
Is it me, or is it awesome that she's discovered
how to control how far back it goes?
But we can only send a
maximum of 36 English characters,
or 18 Japanese characters.
That's not enough. I'd like to improve on that.
I guess you can't send
big stuff or lots of stuff, huh?
Oh, I bet it's because that Carb black hole--
Kerr black hole.
Yeah! I bet that hole is too tight!
Could you repeat that
part about the hole, Mayushii?
Knock it off, pervert!
At any rate, we'll figure out the
details tomorrow and afterward.
But I will proclaim this!
August 2, 2010 is a day that
will forever go down in history!
For on this day,
our Future Gadget Laboratory
has successfully developed mankind's...
...very first time machine!
But it's not the first. SERN
already made one, remember?
Besides, we didn't "develop" anything.
We only got it to work by accident.
How dare you all make light
of my majestic declaration...!
--But, Okarin...
--Yeah?
I'm glad your experiments worked out!
Where am I?
You aren't moving.
Time and space have switched places here.
An event horizon?
You can't move through space,
while time stretches forever.
One second for you will be an eternity for me.
The ends of space are drawing away?
No, it's being pulled away!
What is, though? The universe?
Me?
You must not look back.
Eternity isn't infinite.
Even if time stretches
toward eternity, an end still exists.
When will it be one second later?
Look forward.
Reach it.
You must not look back.
Not that spammer girl again...
She's as persistent as ever...
"Sorry about yesterday."
"Can I come over?"
Did you not think maybe I was asleep?
Don't give me "oh"! Of course I was!
What?
Why are you e-mailing me?
I'm like right here!
I'm not reading it. Tell me to my face.
You can see it; I just wasn't
expecting you this insanely early--
Aha! You want an interview
with me! That's your aim, isn't it?!
Why won't you talk?
I see. So that's your deal.
You're terrified of mad scientist
Hououin Kyouma's evil aura!
I feel more comfortable... sending messages...
So... please show me... the IBN 5100...
Very well.
But you only get to look.
Once you've seen it, you leave! All right?
Maybe she's just really into retro PCs?
Anything but my face.
Photograph my face and
I'll be forced to silence you--
"I'd like to borrow it--is that okay?"
"If you could help carry it--"
Why am I suddenly lending it to you now?!
Besides, if you really want to borrow it,
you can at least ask me to my face.
Will you let me borrow it?
Unfortunately, I can't.
I'm only borrowing it for a short while myself.
Once I'm done with it, I have
to return it to its original owner.
Its original owner?
Yanabayashi Shrine.
Guten Morgen!
Oh! Aren't you Miss Kiryu from yesterday?
Oh, I didn't introduce you yesterday, did I?
This is my favorite right arm,
Daru the super hax0r.
Seriously, dude, it's "super hacker."
Oh, anyway, I'm thinking of
improving the Phone Microwave a little.
It's a real hassle to set everything up
to send D-mails to the past, y'know?
I-It's nothing at all. You misheard.
He didn't say, "...sending mails to the past."
He said, "Sen ding ma ilsto thep ast."
In archaic, ancient Sumerian, it means,
--Too-too-roo! Good morning, Okarin!
--"Have you had breakfast yet?"
Can Mayushii use the microwave
to heat her chicken tenders...
--...before you do your time machine experiments?
Okabe. I had a realization
about the time machine...
It's me.
The situation is ugly.
No, not that.
Information about #8 has
been leaked to an outsider.
--Yes. I'll handle it somehow.
--What's going on?
--He's fancifully ignoring all three of us?
--Yes, I'll silence her if necessary.
We cannot let the Organization learn--
Don't mail me while I'm on the phone!
You don't mean...?
FB?
All right. I'll spill the beans.
Now that you know our
secret, I'm left with no choice.
Kiryu Moeka.
As of today, you are Lab Member 005!
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru