Tremble, right arm of mine.
By our agreement, I order you...
Swathed in flames of pure
blackness, fulfill my desire!
Now I can't heat up my
chicken tenders anymore!
--Are you sure about this?
--Mayuri.
--This is how lab members get treated...
--It's not a microwave; it's a time machine!
That's so mean!
You should go buy us a new microwave then!
I haven't the money.
I told you, no pictures of me!
--As a memento.
--Huh?
Whatever! No pictures!
Okay! Programming's done!
The Phone Microwave 2nd
Edition Version 1.03 is complete!
Now we can send a D-mail
to any number we want!
Excellent work, Daru!
Then let's restart the experiments!
Is it really... a time machine?
Not a word to anyone, got it?
I hope the shopkeeper
won't get mad at us again...
Part-time warrior!
--Hi! Too-too-roo!
--Too-too-roo!
--Mayuri! Be quiet!
--Where's Mr. Braun?
--Who?
--Dad's name isn't Mr. Braun, you know.
--Oh, the boss is out doing a house call.
--He should be gone for a while.
--Really?!
I wouldn't be slacking off otherwise--
Mayuri.
This is...!
Oh, there was a light...
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
Juicy #1 Chicken Tenders
are tastier if you ask me...
Hey! You forgot the Dk Pepper!
They were out.
Then you should've kept
looking until you found some!
That's what any true Dk Pepperian would do!
They were out of it! Don't blame me!
Have this instead.
Geez...
What kind of mad scientist
worries about his vegetable intake?
Now let's begin our round table meeting!
Man, it's hot with all the windows shut.
What are you doing, Daru?!
What if the Organization learns our secret?!
Delusion FTL!
As of now, we're moving
to Phase 2 of Operation Urd:
experiments into making
D-mail more practical to use.
Barley tea's great in the summer!
Would you like some too, Moeka-san?
What exactly do you mean by "practical"?
We're going to change the past.
Hold on! It's too dangerous!
What if we cause a time paradox?
Assistant.
As a scientist, are you not intrigued to see
if D-mails can alter the past or not?
Th-That's not what--
But what are you going to change?
I'm glad you asked.
My aim of this operation is...
...to win the lottery!
Okarin... Mayushii is sad.
Count me in!
--I'd be able to buy PC parts and visit May Queen as much as I want!
--Don't you think we should use it
to help with world peace or something?
We could give everyone in the world
--You couldn't aim any lower, Okabe.
--an Oopa cushion!
We're seeing if we can alter the past or not!
And this is the easiest way to tell!
--But it's still about the money.
--Silence, Celeb 17!
Celeb? Huh?!
Celeb 17!
Someone who lives in a
hotel on her parents' dime
has no place criticizing me!
I'm eighteen.
There's all kinds of lotteries, though, y'know?
Which should we do?
Aye. I would have to say...
--What's wrong?
--Oh, nothing.
Where did Moeka go?
Huh?
Stop right there!
There.
Man. Can't even look away for a second.
You didn't reply, so...
Is she an honest-to-goodness
ditz or something?
Christina! Stand guard and make
sure she doesn't wander around!
Stand guard...?
Oh, do you want to see the lab, Moeka-san?!
Then I'll take you on a tour of
it later! Mayushii's great at it!
In fact, I gave Kurisu-chan the tour too!
I wonder where we should start!
Ah! The Loto 6!
The winning numbers are
announced every Thursday.
So we'll send them to the past.
--We're really going to do it?
--You got any other ideas?
Which winning numbers should we send?
Incidentally, the jackpot is...
...around 200 million yen!
2-200 million?!
Hold on, Daru!
--200 million is a bit much...
--Huh?
H-Hitting the jackpot would
attract too much attention.
And with the Organization out to get me...
Scaredy-cat.
--What's the second prize?
--Let's see...
23 million yen.
Third prize?!
700,000.
That one!
You're such a chicken, Okabe.
--You're always scared of time paradoxes!
--And this is an Oopa cushion!
You hug it tight when you're
tired or need cheering up!
And this is the refrigerator!
Today, we have...
Umm...
Hey! Shining Finger!
Here is your first assignment as a lab member.
Oh! It's your first job!
Come up with the D-mail message.
Something that'll convince me
one week ago to buy a Loto 6 ticket.
Seven days back equals 168 hours...
So about 170 seconds on the timer?
Aye.
This should do it.
Okay, everything's set.
At last, Steins Gate shall be opened!
Not that again. You never let up, do you?
Why do you always gotta be a wet blanket?!
You seemed to be having fun...
--Huh?
--F-Fun? Are you kidding me?!
"Man, this assistant is a total tsundere!"
Who're you calling a tsundere?!
Oh! You know what a tsundere is, Miss Makise?
N-No!
No, you acted like you know...
Seriously, I don't know that word!
Okay! I'm gonna start the microwave!
It's too dangerous!
What if we cause a time paradox?
This is no time to wimp out...!
El Psy...
...Congroo!
Okarin!
Okarin?
Are you okay?
I-I just...
How long have I been standing here?
Huh?
About 30 seconds, I guess?
30 seconds?!
You don't remember?
You were just talking about the
D-mail experiment to alter the past.
And then...
You suddenly came over to Phone
Microwave-chan and went, "Ahh, ahh..."
Mayushii, could you say, "Ahh, ahh," again?
--Knock it off, pervert!
--Yes, Ma'am.
It arrived...
Are you sure you're okay, Okabe?
The money! The Loto 6!
Celeb 17! Did we win third prize?!
Don't call me that!
Wait, what are you talking about?
Wh-What do you mean, "what"?!
Okarin?
You know, the experiment!
The D-mail experiment to change the past!
That's what we were just doing--
coming up with a message to send.
Huh?
Mayushii thinks we should use it to
help with world peace or something!
They really don't remember...?
Come in!
Oh, Ruka-kun! Come on in!
I'm sorry, Kyouma-san!
Ruka-kun?
Here...
02, 12, 18...
They're the same...
Rukako! Where'd you get this?!
Oh? You, umm, told me the numbers, and...
I did?!
You told me to buy a ticket because
they might be winning numbers...
Wha...? When?
A week ago.
Oh! You're psychic, Okarin!
So, did you win the Loto 6, Miss Ruka?
Well, actually...
I got one of the numbers wrong, and...
Whoa, so close!
Crazy close!
Okabe... Did you use
the Phone Microwave to...?
You forgot the Dk Pepper!
They were out of it! Don't blame me!
I'm certain I sent a D-mail.
But there's no record of it...
Could it be that the past was rewritten?
They had no memory of the experiment.
We discussed it and observed it together...
...yet I'm the only one who remembers.
I'm the only one...
This feels just like then.
What does this mean?
What's that?
Something dear to me.
What's wrong?
You look like you've been brainwashed.
Brainwashed...
Maybe.
Perhaps I've been brainwashed, or they have--
What are you--?!
You're not chipped.
It's okay! You haven't been brainwashed!
Ch-Chipped?
What's "brainwashed"?
It's, well...
Hououin Kyouma shall tell you.
It looks like Nae is afraid of Okabe Rintaro.
I have a question for you.
A discharge? The thing that shakes the place?
There was one a while earlier.
There should've been one ten minutes ago too.
I didn't notice that one...
--Did you, Nae?
--No.
You're such a creepy perv!
Am not!
I'm a perverted gentleman!
See? I told you you can hear everything.
I didn't know it was like this...
Wait, did you hear us talking
about time machines too...?!
Yep! Good going, by the way!
--I have to warn you--
--I know, I know.
I won't tell a soul.
Oh! Is your time machine
what's troubling you?
Then why don't you ask John Titor for advice?
Come to think of it, Titor did
mention that going back in time
and altering the past will change
a so-called "divergence number"
and set the world on a different world line.
And when it happens, all memories
of the previous world line are erased
and replaced with memories
of the new world line...
The D-mail moved the
world from a world line
where Rukako didn't buy a
Loto 6 ticket to one where he did.
The world line changed, along with the past.
In this world, we never sent
the Loto 6 D-mail back in time.
So it isn't that they don't remember it...
...the experiment itself never happened here.
But then why do I still remember?
Crap!
Nae! Don't tell him I was
slacking off, no matter what he asks!
Can I ride your bike later?
Sure! Of course!
Okabe Rintaro!
I'm rooting for you!
Th-Thanks...
Bastard!
Dad!
Okabe!
What were you doing to my daughter?!
Huh?! W-Wait! I didn't do anything--
Shut it!
All alone with my adorable daughter...
Ain't no way a guy like
you could hold his lust back!
You're one to talk!
To begin with, we weren't all alone!
Suzuha was here the entire time too!
What?!
Is that true, Nae?
I promised I wouldn't
say she was slacking off!
What?!
Hey, part-timer!
--Oh, god...!
--You were goofin' off, were ya?!
What the hell?! The 42-inch is still in pieces!
I-I'm sorry!
I'll explain why later.
I'm calling off today's experiment.
Everyone please leave.
Okarin...
You there, Assistant.
You're not going to leave?
Just doing some thinking.
I see.
You want my company because
it's lonely back at the hotel...
--Isn't that so, Childish Celeb 17?
--Seriously, quit calling me that.
I have important e-mails to send.
If you insist on staying, be silent
and don't disturb me, The Zombie.
That's the name that irks me the most...
You're like a girl in love,
waiting for an e-mail from
the object of her affection.
Do you want my company that badly?
Who are you messaging?
John Titor.
Huh?
Daru?
Hello?
Oh, Okarin?
I just realized I made a grave error!
You did?! What is it?!
Well... You see...
I left my wallet back at the lab!
What?
Now I can't get into May Queen!
Okarin. I hate to ask--
Too-too-roo! Okarin!
Oh, it's you, Mayuri.
Daru's with you, isn't he?
You don't have to lend him money.
Okay.
Anyway, are you feeling any better, Okarin?
If you're not, you have
permission to hug Mayushii's Oopa!
That should cheer you up!
Heh, okay. I better go now.
Have a good day at work.
Thanks! Bye!
Okabe. You're smiling.
He replied!
I read your e-mail.
As you've surmised,
there is no doubt that you've altered
the past and moved the world line.
The one thing I don't understand
is how you still retain memories
of the past before it was altered.
Are you telling the truth?
I am. Something similar happened before, too.
What do you make of it?
I don't know.
The idea of using e-mail to alter the past
was never considered
in the year 2036 I'm from.
You've now altered the past
and caused the world line to move.
However, until now,
no one has ever been known
to maintain their memories across
world lines and observe their changes.
Even so...
Kyouma. It might be
that you have that ability.
You might be the one person
who can guide the world...
...beyond 1% divergence.
"Guide the world"?!
What does "beyond 1% divergence" mean?!
What exactly is there?!
Beyond it lies true freedom.
The future will always end in dystopia
unless that barrier can be crossed.
My goal is to change the future.
And you might have the
ability to make that happen.
Okabe? What's wrong?
What is he saying...?
Me, save the future...?
That's absurd...
Kyouma, I ask you...
...to be our savior.
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now