Me, a savior?
Nonsense! I'm a mad scientist!
I long for destruction and chaos!
What's gotten into you, dude?
We're recommencing Operation Urd.
Huh? But Mr. Braun's downstairs...
--I don't care!
--Wait!
I told you before. I'm against it.
What gives? You were
all for it this afternoon.
This afternoon?
So you really did go and...?
Yes. The experiment took place.
The D-mail has already altered the past.
You serious?
You're saying the world line changed?
Most likely.
That's why you've lost some of
your memories prior to the change.
Are you talking about that Loto 6 thing?
Yes.
So, why do you still have memories of it?
Titor said I might have an ability...
We need to move the world
line again to find out for sure.
An ability?
The ability to retain
memories across world lines...
The all-seeing eye... "Reading Steiner."
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Daru.
Nothing in the outbox. The inbox has...
Oh! The D-mail arrived five days ago!
It worked.
Well, did the past change?!
How would you remember this if it did?
We sent a D-mail to
Daru five days in the past,
telling him the positions
of cards at the Faris Cup,
which should've let him win...
Oh, Mayushii? I got a question for you.
That Faris Cup the other day, did I--?
Huh? I lost? In the blink of an eye?
Oh. I see.
Thanks. Bye.
The message for Daru
didn't change the past.
It should've changed the flow of the game.
I guess it takes more than
that to move the world line.
We need an easier way to tell
if we've changed the past or not...
Oh?
I-I'm not saying that I agree
with these experiments, though!
So, what do you think about it?
Why are you the only one
who retains your memories?
I already told you--I have
the Reading Steiner ability.
To find out for sure, though,
I'll have you send the next D-mail.
I don't want to.
Worried about a time paradox?
Changing the past
somehow just feels... unfair.
I've only been alive eighteen years,
but I don't want to change any of it.
It's my life, failures and all.
But you also love experiments.
--Isn't that right?
--S-So?! What's wrong with that?!
In other words, you prefer to sit back
and watch with a grin on
your face as others are sacrificed.
Indeed, you're a true mad scientist.
Whatever!
Seriously, though--
Seriously, though, the only
way to perfect the D-mail system...
...is to perform more experiments...
Kiryu-san?
She talks too much!
Can I?
She completely overwhelmed us...
Here we are! Home sweet home!
--Those were good crepes, huh?
--Yeah!
Oh? You look like you got nothin' to do.
I'm waiting for someone.
Hey, now! I told you to quit scarin' Nae!
I haven't done a thing!
Come on, Nae! Let's
forget about this loser and go!
Good morning!
Big Sis Mayuri!
Too-too-roo!
For you!
Wow, thanks!
And for you, Okarin!
Yo!
Good morning, Suzu-san!
Part-time girl!
Hey, tell me! What happened afterward?
--What are you talking about?
--The time machine!
--Did you talk to John Titor?
--Oh, yeah.
But now I'm not so sure if he's right...
Huh?!
--What do you mean?!
--Huh?
Why are you so worked up about it?
Ah, you're a Titor fangirl, aren't you?
No!
Oh, Kurisu-chan!
Too-too-roo!
Good morning.
Ah, she sent sparks flying again, huh?
Sheesh, what's her problem?
Fighting is sad.
Oh, don't worry! Everything's fine!
Thank you.
Keep it a simple, impersonal message,
preferably one that'll make it easy
to tell if the past was changed or not.
"I got a new phone four days ago,
but I wanna tell myself not to buy it."
I see. If the past changes, so will her phone.
The result will be obvious.
Then let the experiment begin!
Okay!
All right!
Start up the Phone
Microwave (Temporary Name)--!
It's so round!
What's this for?
This is, umm, to make up
for messing up the Loto 6
ticket you asked me to buy.
Oh. That's very nice--
You possess providence, indeed.
Soon your mind's eye shall finally open.
Thank you! Well, I should be off now!
You're leaving already?
You seem to be in the
middle of something, so...
Goodbye!
Come try on Mayushii's
costumes sometime, okay?!
I-I'm sorry. That's not really my thing...
Aww, you don't want to?
I think you'd look nice in them, though...
See you later!
Yeah! Bye-bye!
What a nice person.
I felt it this time...
Which means...
...the past changed?
Wh-Where did Shining Finger go?!
"Shi"? Huh?
Japanese, please.
Did Rukako stop by...?
Ruka-kun? No, he hasn't.
Then what about Moeka?!
What about her?!
Moeka-san? Who's that?
Kiryu Moeka! Did she not come by today?!
Well?!
Huh?!
Who are you talking about?
Kiryu Moeka? I've never
heard of her either.
What?!
Wait, did we send another D-mail?!
Huh? Then what does this mean?!
Did we change the past
and cause Kiryu Moeka
to cease to exist entirely...?
That can't be!
I still have mail from
her up until July 31st!
"What's the matter?
Sorry, but I'm a little busy.
I'll e-mail you later."
In short, the past--and this
Kiryu Moeka-san's actions--changed
when she received the
message four days ago,
causing her to never visit the lab?
Pretty much.
And your ability to remember...
Your "Reading Steiner," was it?
That's an embarrassing term, by the way.
I'd drop it if I were you.
Your personal opinions are unneeded.
Your ability to retain
memories across world lines...
Is it real?
Okay, I'm ready!
We can talk more tomorrow.
See you tomorrow, Okarin!
The ability is real.
Then...
...am I...?
Honestly, I don't know
how they can sleep in that lab.
They say that's what a mad scientist does!
Say! We should have a sleepover sometime!
Sure, if it's girls-only.
Oh, I know! Want to
come to my hotel room?
Can I?!
Of course.
Okay!
Then I'll come visit you sometime!
Ruka-kun! Too-too-roo!
Huh?!
Really?!
What?!
You didn't bring the
Supernatural Sword Samidare?!
--Huh? Uhh...
--Stop that, Okarin!
Ruka-kun is Mayushii's guest today!
You wanted to try on my costumes, right?!
I-I, uhh...
Okay, Ruka-kun! Let's transform you!
Transform, transform!
A-Actually, I...!
Now, let's get those clothes off you!
Don't touch there...!
Okay! I'll put it on myself!
Just please look away...!
It's tricky putting this on, though.
P-Please, don't take that off...!
It's very... yuri.
Not quite. Rukako is a guy.
That makes it...
...even more indecent!
It's Kirari-chan from Rai-Net!
I was right! It looks cute on you, Ruka-kun!
Wearing this is embarrassing...
It's okay! Cuteness is just!
I have the urge to get an upskirt shot...
What do you think, Okarin?
Well...
It's me! I've been subjected to
intense psychological warfare!
Oh, no! My mind! It's... being eaten away!
Wh-What's wrong, Kyouma-san?
Sheesh, what's all the fuss about?
Kurisu-chan! Too-too-roo!
Perverted Assistant.
Quit gawking at Rukako's body.
I'm not!
Another indecent development!
What do you think? Does this
costume look nice on Ruka-kun?
Y-Yes! It's very cute!
C-Cute...? That's not...
Let's try on some other clothes!
Wait...
I came by today because
I have a favor to ask.
You didn't come to try on my costumes?
Th-That's what I kept trying to say,
but you wouldn't hear me out.
Sorry! I was just so
happy that I couldn't help it...
So, what is this request of yours?
Umm, well, you see...
I want to send a message to the past too!
Yesterday...
I brought a present to make up
for messing up the Loto 6 ticket,
but then...
Wait, did we send another D-mail?!
Huh? Then what does this mean?!
Did we change the past
and cause Kiryu Moeka
to cease to exist entirely...?
That can't be!
I'm sorry! I didn't mean to eavesdrop, but...!
Ruka-kun. What message do
you want to send to the past?
Well, actually...
I want to be a girl!
Huh?!
I don't like the way I look...
I've always felt that I might
feel more confident with myself
if I were a girl...
H-Hold on!
What on earth is she talking about?
Assistant. It appears
you've made a crucial mistake.
A mistake?
Rukako isn't a girl. He's a guy.
What kind of joke is that?
How short-sighted.
If you're a real scientist,
then observe for yourself.
Someone this cute
can't possibly be a boy...
Sorry, I hope you don't mind.
Are you okay?
I'm serious about this!
I really want to be a girl!
Please!
Still, I'm not sure sending a
D-mail can change your gender.
I've heard that if you eat lots
of meat while you're pregnant,
you'll have a baby boy.
And that if you eat lots of
vegetables instead, it'll be a girl.
So you want to send a D-mail telling
your mother to eat lots of vegetables?
Yes. Could I?
Very well. I will grant your wish.
Thank you so much!
--That's great news, Ruka-kun!
--Yes!
Wouldn't changing
someone's gender be a bad idea?
Do you seriously think some vegetables
can change something like that?
That's true. There's not
even any scientific basis for it.
He's clearly been struggling with this.
If it'll make him feel better...
Rukako. As of today, you
are one of us: Lab Member 006!
R-Right!
Now, then! Let us get
the experiment underway--
You're 17 this year, right?
Huh? Yes.
Which would mean you were born in 1993...?
Why do you ask?
When did cell phones
start to take off in Japan?
Around 1996, it looks like.
Ones with e-mail capabilities
might've been even later.
In other words,
Urushibara-san's mother
might not have had a
cell phone when he was born.
Then we can't send a D-mail?
Oh, no...
Maybe we could hack the microwave
to send psycho-waves instead?
You two are all the psychos we need.
Yes...! That's it...! Abuse me more!
I got it...
My genius frightens me!
I'm afraid to ask...
If cell phones are out, then
let's just send it to a pager!
Pagers were miniature receivers
that signals could be sent to via phone.
They enjoyed widespread use in the 1990s,
but their popularity waned
after cell phones were introduced.
--Pagers?
--I've never seen one before!
You sure know a lot. You're more
like "Celeb 30" than "Celeb 17."
It's written right there. Read for yourself.
Lab Member 006, Urushibara Ruka!
This is your first mission.
Find out if your mother had
a pager and obtain its number!
R-Right!
My mother had a pager!
--This is the number!
--Excellent!
You decided on the message too, I hope?
Yes!
"Eat vegetables for a healthy baby."
I heard you can only send
18 hiragana characters, so...
You can only send
numbers to pagers, though.
We'll have to convert this into numbers...
Just a sec.
It looks like voiced consonant
marks need two numbers.
Huh?
We can send 36 half-width
Japanese characters at most.
That makes this message
four characters too long.
Hmm. In that case...
Converting this into numerical form, we get...
--Okay! We're gonna start it up!
--Right!
Are you sure about this?
Don't worry.
The Reading Steiner took effect! Meaning...!
...people like this too?
Yeah! It's cute!
I think it'd look
wonderful on you, Ruka-chan!
R-Really?
Is this...?
Hey, pervert!
Watch where you're staring!
N-No! It's not like that...!
Hold on!
I can't just up and ask
if Rukako's a girl now...
But...
I guess it failed...
Knock it off, will you?!
What kind of perverted thoughts
are you having, grinning like that?!
Sheesh, Okarin!
Honestly, now! You two
pervs never let up, do you?
I'm not a perv! I'm a perverted gentleman!
Whatever! Same difference!
But... the world line did change.
Something's changed.
What, exactly?
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru