From previous experiments,
we've established that our
D-mails are being sent back in time.
But we couldn't change how
I fared against Faris-tan in our game.
I'd say that's your problem.
I guess there is an issue with
accuracy, given Ruka's case too,
--but a few improvements and we'll have a real time machine--
--Time machine?
You eavesdropped?!
Faris only brought your order, meow!
--Would you like some sugar syrup or milk, meow?
--No!
Then I'll give you all of it, Kyouma.
--Meow, meow!
--There it is!
Special Technique: Eye Contact Stir!
--I'm jealous, Okarin! Go die in a fire!
--Kyouma!
--What's this about a time machine, meow?
Do you really think such attempts
at seduction will get me to talk?
I see you're im-purr-vious to it, Kyouma.
Daru!
--Daru would never betray--
--We made a machine to send e-mails to the past!
--I did most of the work!
--Have you no shame at all?!
E-mails to the past...?
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
--Damn Daru, leaking confidential information to an outsider...
--Why?
Why do you see it that way? I just--!
No! It isn't like that at all!
I'm...!
Wh-Wh-What?
I wasn't crying.
I wasn't crying, just so you know!
It sure seemed like you were to me...
Your eyes are still red.
I-It's not what you think!
--There's just something in my eye...
--Are you out of an old drama or something?
I wasn't crying, okay?!
So don't pester me about it! Got it?!
Actually, I haven't said a word about it.
Sh-Shut up!
--Christina--
--Shut up! Don't talk to me!
I'll just say this: I cherish you as a friend.
You can talk to me anytime.
Okabe...
Precisely as planned!
She fell right into my trap!
Yes! Now she's wrapped
around my little finger!
Hey, now...
Good work today, meow!
Oh, Faris-chan!
Are you going to see Kyouma now?
Yeah. He asked me to
pick up something for lunch.
Say, have you seen the
time machine, Mayushii?
Time...?
Oh, Phone Microwave-san?
Phone Microwave?
It makes this lightning
that's all, "Crackle! Zap!"
It's all tingly and kinda scary...
Wow! That sounds like a time
machine straight out of the movies!
Yeah.
But Mayushii wishes they
wouldn't do stuff with it...
Why not?
It feels kind of like Okarin is
getting further and further away...
This round table
meeting will now come to--
Okarin, Okarin!
--What?
--Isn't it strange?
Mayushii said she isn't cosplaying, but...
She isn't. That's her school uniform.
I had school today.
An ultra-realistic portrayal
of a school uniform...
You know, talking like that is
usually considered sexual harassment.
Here's yours, Okarin!
Thanks.
Get it right! This is a round table meeting!
You're the one who asked me
to pick up something for lunch.
Don't worry about it.
I doubt he has anything
important to say anyway.
Perhaps you'll change your tune when
you hear today's topic of discussion!
By which I mean... physical time travel!
Mayuri. Is there any
barley tea left in the fridge?
Just a sec!
Ultra-realistic...
It's me!
The Organization has begun to
bring the lab down from the inside!
My fellow lab members no
longer pay heed to my words!
It's always been that way.
Then how can you just brush
aside this great topic of discussion?!
Because it's obviously impossible.
We've sent e-mails back in time!
--Who says we can't--
--We can't.
We can only send a little over 36 bytes.
Three messages six Japanese
characters-long. Any more is impossible.
But if you'd like to try, why
not experiment on yourself?
If you don't mind turning
into a Gel-Okarin, of course.
Oh, a Gel-Okarin?
Ooh, burn!
SERN's experiments have proven
the difficulty of physical time travel.
If the LHC, the world's largest
particle collider couldn't do it,
there's no way this equipment can.
Then how were we
able to send the e-mails?!
I don't know. That's the real question.
As we discussed before, SERN
is attempting to achieve time travel
through the use of a black hole and a lifter.
This Phone Microwave most
likely works in the same way.
Yet, whatever functions as
our lifter isn't in the microwave.
Where is it, then?
I don't know.
Plus we're only able to send
D-mails at certain times of the day.
For a machine that sends e-mails
back in time, it's still very shoddy.
We need to solve these mysteries
before we move any further ahead.
That's no fun!
99% of science is unexciting humdrum.
If you profess to be a scientist, then--
I told you, I am not a scientist!
I'm a "mad scientist"!
This guy's hopeless. Better do
something about him quick...
Miss Makise?
Don't tell me you're quoting...
Shut up! Don't say
any more! It's not like that!
Just get to the point!
All right, then. Status updates.
How is the translation of the data on
SERN's server coming along, Christina?
--Or shall I say... @channeler!
--I told you, it's not like that!
--Yet your ID is bright red.
--Is not!
Th-There's nothing of note to report.
I see. Continue to investigate...
--...@channeler!
--Don't call me that!
You're next, Daru.
How's the hacking coming along?
No change.
Pretty much at a
standstill until we can analyze
the mystery program on the other server.
Can't the IBN 5100 handle that?
Easier said than done, dude.
What do you mean?
You haven't deciphered it yet?
Huh? How would I do that?
--The IBN 5100! Where is it?!
--How should I know?!
It can't be...!
What's gotten into you, Okarin?
Christina...
Have I not found the IBN 5100...?
Huh? We don't even know
where to find one in the first place.
I see.
So, I'm to believe you
actually found an IBN 5100?
Yes. The two of us carried it here.
But you're the only
one with any memory of it.
The D-mails must've greatly altered the past.
Greatly?
But we've only sent simple messages!
It's the "Butterfly Effect."
Sending a message back in
time causes the world line to split.
From a world where we didn't buy a
Loto 6 ticket to one where we did, for example.
As a result, events and facts that
happened before change ever so slightly.
Like billiards, a single change
can trigger further changes,
resulting in even greater changes.
It's one of the most famous
risks of altering the past.
Then where is the IBN 5100?
Let me turn the tables: Where did you find it?
Yes.
Yes, my father said it was stored at the shrine,
but now it's nowhere to be found...
Oh...
Well?
There was an IBN 5100
at the Yanabayashi Shrine...
...but not anymore.
They're not sure who took it, or even when.
A dead-end...
Storing a computer at a
shrine sure sounds strange!
I wonder who did it...
--Faris-chan!
--Meow?
Here are the ten questions I came up
with for the maids at the next event...
Let's see here!
"If you could go back in time and
redo one thing, what would it be?"
What would you do, Faris-chan?
Good question! Faris...
...doesn't focus on the past!
As cat-girl maids who
bring happiness to everyone,
it's our duty to always move forward!
Oh! Phone, phone!
Hi! This is Faris, meow!
Kyouma?
Meow? A computer?
An IBN 5100.
Is it true that you stored
one at the Yanabayashi Shrine?
I don't really remember,
but Daddy did have lots
of old computers, meow.
Kyouma...
Does this have something to do
with this time machine of yours?
Wow, look!
An Oopa! A Metal Oopa!
Oh, you still want a Metal Oopa?
"Still"?
How long are we gonna
stand here? Let's get going.
Oh, wait!
Daru-kun!
Sorry for the wait!
What are you shopping for?!
Couldn't help it! I spotted
some limited edition swag!
As you'd say,
"This fateful encounter was
truly the choice of Steins Gate!"
Don't use that term lightly!
Why are you two tagging along anyway?!
You should just hold down
the fort with my assistant.
STFU! I can't turn down an
opportunity to visit Faris-tan at home!
Mayushii wants to visit her too!
Why the heck did she invite me over anyway?
Oh, it's Kirari-chan!
Hey! Mayuri!
Sheesh...
The IBN 5100...
Shining Finger!
Hey! Wait!
Shining--!
Moeka! Kiryu Moeka!
Why...?
FB said it would be there...
Okabe-kun...?
You mentioned the IBN 5100 just now--
Do you know where it is?!
You don't know either?
You don't know...?
Okarin!
Oh, Moeka-san?
Yeah...
Okarin!
Moeka-san is so pretty and stylish!
I bet she'd look amazing if she cosplayed!
Yeah...
Hold on, Mayuri.
You know who Shining Finger is?
Huh? Yeah.
How?! How is that possible?!
You brought her to the lab...!
After Moeka sent her D-mail,
her existence was
erased from their memories.
And now, after Ruka's D-mail,
everyone knows who Moeka is again...
Each time a D-mail alters the past,
things start to change little by little?
You're sure this is the place?
I'm sure!
Let's see... It looks
like she's on the top floor.
The young mistress will be here shortly.
Please wait here.
Butler cafes aren't really my thing, you know...
A real-life butler! I've never seen one before!
Look! The people are like garbage!
What a magnificent view!
Okarin...
I knew he'd say that.
Sorry for the wait, meow!
Oh, Faris-chan!
Now I get to witness Faris-tan in plain clothes!
What good fortune!
--Faris Meow-Meow!
--Meow?
It would seem prudent to
ask who you really are now.
Faris is...
...Faris, meow!
Don't toy with me!
If you won't explain, then I'm leaving!
Fine, meow...
Faris' family originally owned...
...all the land around here!
Wait, does that mean Akiba is...?
Yep! That's right!
Huh? What about Akiba now?
It's part of her real name: Akiha Rumiho-chan!
La-la-la-la! I can't hear you!
Faris-tan's real name is Faris-tan!
An embarrassing attempt at escaping reality...
Incidentally, Faris was the one who asked
for moe culture to be
introduced into Akiba, meow!
Wha...?! You're that influential?!
And, being the angel
you are, you use May Queen
to personally spread moe
culture throughout the land!
She's so l33t!
And I have l33t eyes for
recognizing someone so l33t!
But please don't tell
anyone else about this, meow.
I want everyone to treat me with
the same "Faris love" as always!
I will! With every ounce of my being!
Thanks, meow, meow!
Never mind the meows!
We're here about the IBN 5100!
Oh, that, meow?
But before that, I have a small request...
Are you trying to extort us?!
I promise, it's nothing much!
I just want to use the
D-mail one time, that's all!
But of course! You can
send as many as you'd like!
Hold on! No one outside the
lab is allowed to know about--
Then can't we just make
Faris-chan a lab member too?
No, wait! Hold on!
It's too dangerous to send any more--
So you get to send messages about
the Loto 6 for your own personal greed,
but Faris-tan doesn't?!
It's just one time!
No, that's not what it's about...
Still, there's no guarantee
we'll find the IBN 5100 on our own.
If she can help us track it down...
All right.
But you will have to become a
lab member, just as Mayuri said.
As of today, you are
Lab Member 007: Akiha Rumi--
La-la-la-la! I-I can't hear you!
Done!
You're sure you want
this sent ten years back?
I'm sure, meow!
What's it say?
It's... a secret, meow.
That won't do!
As the head of the lab,
I need to know this sort of--!
Too bad.
Boys aren't allowed to
meddle in girls' private lives!
I think it's wrong to
read other people's e-mail.
I totally agree!
Oh, all right...
Okay, wait with your
finger on the send button.
Hello?
It's me. Give me a status report--
--She hung up on me!
--I don't blame her.
Lousy Christina!
You're supposed to be my assistant!
Hello?
It's Hououin Kyouma. Don't hang up on me.
Hououin?
Oh, it's you, Okabe.
I thought it was a prank caller.
You clearly saw it was me calling.
Still, you were so creepy-sounding
that I couldn't help it.
In other words, you fear the great Hououin--
She did it again! She hung up again!
What's taking so long, Okarin?
Hold on!
Curse that cold-hearted,
prodigal, perverted genius girl!
--Hello?
--Now you listen here, The Zomb--!
Hello?
My name is Okabe Rintaro...
How can I help you?
I humbly asketh you to activate the
Phone Microwave (Temporary Name)
as per the settings
provided in my prior e-mail.
You should've said so at the start.
You used "asketh" wrong, by the way.
You're an embarrassment to yourself.
Also, it's about time you
drop the "Temporary Name"--
Sh-Shut yer hole, Celeb 17!
Think you're so great even though you suck--
--Oh, nothing.
--Are they not on good terms?
--No, I humbly ask...
--Actually, I think it's the opposite.
--...that you remain on the line.
--I agree with Mayushii.
Maybe I...
Maybe I don't need to after all...
Faris.
The discharge has begun.
Send it!
Umm...
Who are you?
Huh?
Daddy!
"Daddy"?
Were you talking with Kyouma, meow?
Yes.
Well, I must be going.
Please, make yourselves at home.
Your father sure seems dignified, Faris-chan!
He's Faris-tan's progenitor, all right!
Umm...!
Are you familiar with the IBN 5100?
That name certainly takes me back.
We're looking for one!
I gave mine away long ago, I'm sorry to say.
Did you happen to give it
to the Yanabayashi Shrine?
A shrine? No, I'm afraid not.
Well, I must be going.
Before Faris sent her D-mail,
the IBN 5100 disappeared
after being stored at the shrine.
But now it was never
stored there to begin with.
With each message,
things change more and more.
There could be things changing
out there I don't even know about.
It's possible we've done things
now that can never be undone...
Okarin! Okarin!
Mayushii's going to buy an Ai Sword
doujinshi in Nakano before going home.
Ai Sword? Oh, by Kouga Yui?
Nakano's a pretty long way to go.
Yeah.
I wish they'd open a
Toranoana shop here too.
What are you talking about?
There's one right--
Huh?!
Don't be silly, Okarin.
You know there isn't one in Akiba.
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now