How?
What's going on?!
Akiba is completely devoid of "moe" now?!
--Wait up, Okarin!
--Okarin... Oka--
--What's gotten into you?
Where did Toranoana and Animate go?!
Where's Mandarake and Gamers?!
What are you talking about, Okarin?
You know there aren't any in Akiba.
That's why Mayushii has
to go all the way to Nakano--
Mayuri! You work
part-time at May Queen, right?!
What's "May Queen"?
May Queen Nyan²!
That can't be...
Faris was the one who asked
for moe culture to be
introduced into Akiba, meow!
Did she send a D-mail
back in time to undo that?
An entire city, completely
altered by one e-mail...
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
It's hard to believe
May Queen once stood here.
May Queen? Like the potato?
Summer's all about cold dipping
noodles, not buttered potatoes.
I'm not talking about potatoes here--
If May Queen doesn't exist,
how did we meet Faris?
Actually, buttered potato
ramen is how we met Faris-tan.
What do you mean?!
You forgot?
The day of the Rai-Net
competition in Ikebukuro,
I got a stomachache from the
buttered potato ramen I had for lunch
and had to drop out.
And then?!
You and Mayushii competed in my place
and squared off against Faris-tan.
You got your butts kicked,
but she and Mayushii have
been friends ever since, remember?
I see...
Look, Ruka-chan!
I bought this cosplayer
photo book in Nakano yesterday!
--Wow! That's so cute!
--So even though the past has changed,
our relationships are
still essentially the same?
You seem to have a lot of time
on your hands this Obon holiday,
Lab Member Girls.
Hello!
--Cute, huh?!
--Oh!
It's Sedona from Blood Tune!
Look how detailed it is!
There's a swimsuit version, too!
I wish I could be as stylish as her.
Don't worry about it! Small boobs are just!
Oh, I know! We should all
go to the beach sometime!
Kurisu-chan too!
Can you all wear school swimsuits?
Me, swim with these perverts?
Aww...
O-Oh, but I'd be more than happy
to come along if it's a girls-only thing!
Just admit it, Christina.
You just don't want us to see
the birthmark on your rump.
--Am I right?
--I-I don't have a birthmark!
Besides, if it were a girls-only
thing, then Rukako here couldn't go.
Huh? Why not?
I told you the other day--Rukako
is an honest-to-goodness boy.
Huh?
Wha...?
You're pathetic.
Calling a girl a boy...
Mayushii doesn't like it
when you act like that...
Definitely crossed the line.
H-H-Hold on! Why are you crying?!
Apologize to Urushibara-san right this minute!
Wh-What for? I'm telling the truth--
It's okay!
Is that how you've
always seen me, Okabe-san?
--Hold on, Rukako! You're a guy--
--How long are you going to keep this up?!
I should go!
Wait!
Quit fooling with me!
You're a guy and you know it!
Seriously, you even have a--
It's gone... It's gone...
It's gone!
Okabe-san... Please stop...
Rukako...
You're... a girl?
That's what we've...
...been telling you!
Yo-yo-yo!
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing.
--Just tortured a little...
--Tortured?!
By Makise Kurisu?!
Yeah... But I cleared
up our misunderstanding.
...I hope.
She hurt your legs?!
Y-You mustn't touch them yet!
She forced me to sit on my knees for an hour--
No, I mean, I was tortured.
Oh, that doesn't count as torture.
You sound like someone
who's been through real torture.
Well, I am a warrior!
This is the perfect day to go cycling...
Is it?
Say... want to go cycling?
Y-You call this cycling...?!
I haven't told you this, but
I actually came to Tokyo to find my dad.
Find?
Did he run away or something?
I haven't seen him in years. I don't
even remember what he looks like.
I just know he's in this city.
This is my only clue: A pin he once had.
Then this is no time to
be working a part-time job.
It's hard to explain, but
I basically only have one shot at it.
Huh?
I think my dad might show
up at a certain place tomorrow.
But if I miss that chance,
I'll have to leave the city.
There's somewhere else I need to go.
I'm pretty busy myself, you see.
My plan was that if it doesn't work
out, I'll just give up looking for him.
So you're ill at ease.
I know that feeling all too well.
However!
Unfortunately, Part-time Warrior,
you just shared your
story with a mad scientist!
As of today, you are Lab Member 008!
You will be our guinea pig!
--Wh-What are you going to do?
--Change the past.
Feel free to think it a fiendish plot.
But there is no escaping it now.
You will send a D-mail to
your father before he absconded.
One that says, "Don't leave your daughter."
You're a nice guy.
What?!
I somehow feel a little better.
Well, I gotta get back.
Thanks for being concerned about me!
Listen!
Promise you'll come to the lab tomorrow,
whether or not you meet your dad!
We'll conduct a D-mail
experiment using your grief!
You're a mad scientist, all right!
You're cruel and heartless!
I will now explain the
basics of Operation Eldhrimnir.
Again with the Norse myths?
If the part-time warrior
finds her father, we'll celebrate
by holding a "Last Supper in Tokyo" for her.
If she doesn't find her
father, we hold a pity party
and then conduct our D-mail experiment.
Huh? Daru-kun isn't here.
He said he can't make it 'cause
of a meet-up with online friends
or some such nonsense.
But I've already taken measures.
I sent this message ahead of time.
"The choice is yours: Faris'
home cooking or your meet-up?"
Oh? But I thought Faris-chan couldn't come?
I can let Faris off the hook since
she's never met the part-time warrior,
but Daru is duty-bound to
participate in this operation.
Umm, I've never met this
Suzuha-san either, actually...
No matter!
You girls will do the
shopping for our little party.
What about you?
I'm going to follow the part-time
warrior and report in detail.
Don't do that. Just let
them have some time alone.
Yeah! You can come
shopping with us, Okarin!
--I'm going to follow--
--Did you not just hear me?!
You're my assistant!
You don't get to order me--
Feel like sitting on your knees again?
For three hours this time.
Well, then! Let's get ready for the party!
What's the matter, Okarin?
I-It's nothing...
What in the...?
Should we get mild curry?
Or should we get spicy?
Which do you think she'd like?
O-Oh. Spicy is fine.
Oh, right! Suzu-san is
a part-time warrior and all!
And warriors love spicy food!
Let's see... Next is meat!
Wow, beef is so expensive!
Say, Okarin. You don't seem yourself.
I kind of expected you to say,
"The Organization's sabotage
has caused beef prices to skyrocket!
When does Operation Bargain Sale begin?!"
...Or something like that.
I would've used Norse mythology
for the name, not "Bargain Sale."
It's me.
Due to Organization
sabotage, Operation Audumbla
has incurred unforeseen expenses.
I request additional operational funds.
Oh! The first star of the night!
Venus, huh...
Hey, Okarin.
Remember in grade school when you
were stuck in bed with that terrible fever?
Yeah.
It was right around the time
everyone was freaking out about Y2K...
Mayushii was actually
really afraid you'd die.
So I prayed to the sky!
And then suddenly a
shooting star went flying by!
Mayushii chanted, "Please
don't die, Okarin!" to it three times!
The next day, your fever was
gone and you were wide awake!
So you owe Mayushii for saving your life!
No, you got it wrong.
It was the choice of
Steins Gate that I survived.
Aww. Really?
Really.
Oh.
Say, do you remember what you said
after you collapsed from your fever?
You said that everything looked mixed up,
that you were too dizzy to stand,
and that you felt like you'd been shocked.
That's how you seemed
back at Faris-chan's place too.
That feeling I had when I had that fever...
It was just like how
I feel when I move world lines.
Was that when I first gained
my Reading Steiner ability?
We're back!
Welcome back!
What's that smell?
It's probably Kurisu-san's apple pie...
What?! This stench?!
Can Mayushii help?
You could boil some eggs...
Sure!
Let's see...
Do you think I could
use the Phone Microwave?
D-Don't! Raw eggs explode in microwaves!
--I can cook it.
--Aww...
You can cut up some
mushrooms then, Mayuri.
Okay!
H-Hold on!
Boiled eggs and mushrooms
don't go in apple pies!
They're for a side-salad.
Uhh, I don't think egg and mushroom
salad goes with apple pie either...
--Chop! Chop! Chop!
--You there!
--Quit chopping mushrooms!
--Move!
It's me.
It appears I've inadvertently freed an evil god.
If I don't call within the next
hour, tell my parents I loved them.
Okabe-san. Do you have a rice cooker?
Faris-tan! Wherefore art thou, Faris-tan?!
You've been tricked, Hashida.
Faris-san said she couldn't come.
S-Serious?!
Okarin!
I'll talk to her about it next chance I get!
What the hell, man?!
I missed my time machine
forum meeting for this!
Time machine forum meeting?
With people from a sci-fi BBS I frequent.
A professional writer was gonna come, even!
This is a neat-looking camping kit!
--Don't touch that! That's no camping kit!
--Hmm, how does it open?
--It's Future Gadget #4: Moad Snake!
A Claymore mine?!
Just a replica. It's a super-instant humidifier.
Oh, here we are!
S-Stop!
I'm so sorry, Okabe-san...
What's done is done.
Just watch what you touch from now on.
Hey, couldn't we use this?
A vacuum cleaner?
Nope! It's Future Gadget #3!
Or was it #2?
#5.
Known as "I've Connected Yet
Another Trifling Thing - By Goemon."
It's basically a hair drier that uses
the heat exhaust of a vacuum cleaner.
Hand it here.
Wait!
You have to unplug
everything else first, or else--!
...the breaker will trip.
Huh? Where's the flashlight again?
I-Is this it?!
No, Miss Ruka. That's a daikon.
Let's see... Where's the breaker?
Hey! Don't go wandering around!
Told you so.
Oww...
The breaker's by the front door.
You okay?
What's so funny?!
Sorry! It's just...
My laboratory back in America
has top talent from all over the world,
but they're all so arrogant and callous.
Your lab is childish by comparison,
but I feel like I really fit in.
Th-That's not a compliment, though!
I'm just saying that's how it seems...
For me, I guess I just wanted some friends.
I, umm... consider you a friend.
You said before that you
cherish me as a friend too.
That actually made me pretty happy...
Do you have a fever or something?
N-No!
What's your problem?! I was just
starting to rethink my opinion of you!
You dummy!
Suzu-san's sure taking a long time.
I wonder if she found her father...
I bet they're spending quality
time together as we speak.
Either way, I clearly told
her to come to the lab...
But it's pretty late now.
The operation's off. You guys can go.
Why, that little...!
Is she just going to leave
like that, sad and all alone?
Hououin Kyouma will not allow it!
Damn!
Where is she?!
I got it.
I can use a D-mail to tell myself to
follow Suzuha this afternoon at all costs!
But...
Can I really afford to send any more D-mails
and alter the past even more?
You're a nice guy.
I somehow feel a little better.
I'm Hououin Kyouma, the mad scientist.
Nothing strikes fear in my heart!
"Ignore assistant..."
"...tail Suzuha!"
Yo.
Morning, Part-time Warrior! Slacking off?
Yeah, that party went way
into the night. I'm so sleepy...
Last night, we held a "Last Supper"
where you acted as our test subject
since you never found your father.
Correct?
Yeah, but we never did the experiment
because I didn't know
my dad's e-mail address.
I'd like to double-check one thing...
How did I get you to come?
Did you drink last night?
You're underage.
You know better than that.
Just tell me.
Well, I was leaving my time
machine forum meeting when...
Time machine forum meeting?!
Was that where you thought
your father might show up?!
Yeah. My dad goes by the name "Titor."
John Titor?!
No, Barrel. Barrel Titor.
I told you yesterday, remember?
Didn't you record it on your phone?
Yesterday was so much fun!
It would've been even more fun
if Makise Kurisu hadn't been there.
Her apple pie tasted like death.
But Urushibara Ruka's curry was top-notch!
You guys have a nice lab!
You get along great
and are always having fun.
That was the first time in my
life I ever felt like I really fit in.
Then feel free to visit anytime you want.
You are a lab member and all.
Yeah.
I think I'll keep looking for
my dad for a little while longer.
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru