I need you to distract
Mr. Braun for just five seconds
so he won't notice the
shockwaves from the experiment.
No prob! This calls for some womanly charm!
Feel for yourself!
I have rock-hard muscles!
--Oh, you do.
--Right?! So just leave it to me!
--You are turning on the charm, right...?
--Yeah! Why?
Never mind. Do your thing.
Okey-dokey!
Now!
Assistant! Commence!
What the...?!
O-Okab--!
Ack... I failed...
How many damn times do I hafta--?!
It stopped?
Was it my assistant? No, wait...
Could it be...?!
Could it be...
...what?!
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
In other words, the 42-inch
CRT television downstairs
just happened to act
as a replacement lifter?
And we were only able to send D-mails
while it was on during business hours?
That would explain it!
Not so loud... My head's killing me...
Are you okay?
Damn Mr. Braun,
resorting to violence like that...
You reap what you sow, I guess.
You're the one who wanted
to run the experiment...
At any rate, now we know how the
Phone Microwave works for the most part.
Which means now...
...We should consider how to
make physical time travel possible.
--Can't.
--Don't split-second reject it!
You'll wind up in gel
form no matter what we try.
Compressing an entire
human into 36 bytes is just too--
Showing off at a time like this?
Why would I care
about showing off to you?
Look at the title of my paper.
"An Analysis of Neural Pulse Signals
in Relation to Memories
Stored in the Temporal Lobe."
In Japanese, please?
Basically, it's about human memory.
I specialize in brain science.
In simple terms, memories are
stored in the brain via pulse signals.
It's a type of electrical data.
Data...
--Are you saying...?!
--Yes.
Physically sending someone is
pretty much out of the question,
but it might be possible
to send their memory data.
To where?
To their past self.
You'd convert your memories into
data and send it just like a D-mail.
Basically, you take what's in your head
now and implant it into your past self.
In other words, you go
back to your earlier you?!
It's not so much "time travel"
as it is a "time leap."
It's me.
It's all come together.
The plan has entered its final phase.
Commence Operation Verdandi--the
goddess who rules the present!
--No idea what that means.
--Oh...!
Care to explain what that is?!
I'm talking about using
this "time leap" of yours!
Begin at once.
It's not that easy. I need
all kinds of materials first.
But we should be able to find them in Akiba,
since we only need to read the
memory signals in the temporal lobe.
It's just...
What's wrong?
The Phone Microwave
probably isn't powerful enough
to compress all that memory data.
And...
And what?
Nothing.
All right. Here are all the parts I'll need.
Mayushii doesn't understand any of this.
Christina already explained it.
We can send your mind,
as it exists now, back in time.
Sounds kinda scary.
Can't we just stick to D-mails?
D-mails introduce too many uncertainties.
A single message can have
completely unexpected results.
But sending memories back is okay?
At the very least, it'd give us some
control over the changes that are made,
such as all of Akiba transforming.
Transforming?
Oh, nothing.
Oh, but what happens to this you
after you send your memory back in time?
Your body doesn't get sent, right?
Hmm, well...
Plus, you know how
we're talking right now?
Yeah.
So let's say Mayushii goes back
a week and redoes the last week.
What would happen if she
avoids talking to you this time?
Well, my guess is that
you'll retain your memory
but the fact that we talked will disappear.
In other words, Mayushii will
remember us talking, but you won't at all?
Right.
Then I'd feel kind of sad.
For me?
For Mayushii.
Oh, there's Moeka-san!
Moeka-san!
Too-too-roo!
You look rather glum, Shining Finger.
"Did you scrap the time machine?"
No, we're still using it!
And now we might be
able to "time leap" with it!
--Don't just blurt our secrets out!
--Huh?
But Moeka-san's a lab member too!
Yeah, but still...
"What's a time leap?"
It's exactly as it sounds:
Making memories "leap" back in time!
Memories...?
Moeka-san?
Oh! Moeka-san!
Is she okay?
Guess I'll hit Akibaoo first.
More efficient that way...
Big Sis Mayuri!
Now it's you, Nae-chan!
--What are you doing here?
--'Sup!
Y-You're still dressed like that?!
Yeah, my boss yelled at me and
told me to stay like this all day...
That's poison for children's eyes.
Poison?
I usually try not to carry poison with me.
Huh?
Anyway, Nae was looking
all over for you, Okabe Rintaro.
She said she has something to tell you.
To tell me?
Yeah.
I'm sorry my dad was
so mean to you earlier!
Nae-chan...
You came all this way for that...?
What a well-bred critter you are.
She's not a critter.
Don't worry.
I'm always causing
Mr. Braun trouble. Now we're even.
That isn't like you, Okabe Rintaro.
Oh? Okarin is always like this!
Well, Mayushii should get going now!
--Meeting someone?
--Yeah! Fubuki-chan, a cosplayer!
--I'm giving her a costume!
--Oh, right, Comima is coming up.
Yep. Bye, now!
And for Suzu-san and Nae-chan: Too-too-roo!
See you later!
Well, should we head back too?
No, I still have to find some
parts Christina asked for...
Makise Kurisu... works for SERN.
A SERN spy?
That can't be true...
--Never gonna...
--...give you up.
Don't sneak up on me! That's not fair!
So you were posting on @channel...
--H-Hold on--
--I've known you were a...
--It isn't like that...
--...cheeky @channeler for some time now.
Am not!
There's no point trying to hide it now!
FML...
But no matter. I hereby officially
grant you the title of "Channeler"--
Don't give me any more weird names!
At least just don't tell anyone else!
Why not?
You should list it on your resume.
"Hobbies: @channel"!
If @channel knew a scholar was posting,
they'd make a thread or two about you!
I don't care.
Then maybe you can
do an AMA on /b/ instead?
I hate that I know what that means!
But now I'm relieved.
Someone who's so bad at hiding
her secret life can't possibly be a spy.
Huh? What are you talking about?
Oh, the part-time warrior
claims you're a SERN spy.
You know I'm not. That's ridiculous.
Of course.
You're an agent sent by the
Organization who's had a change of heart
and works as my assistant now.
--That's wrong, too.
--So, how is the work coming along?
Work?
The time leap! I bought
all the parts you need!
Oh, right. I guess I need to put it together...
We've come this far and all...
What's the problem? Getting cold feet?
Yes, partly.
I'm worried what'll happen
if we really go through with this.
But, more than that...
What?
I guess I should tell you.
You've figured out
enough about me as it is...
But not here.
Let's go somewhere
where I can't see your face.
My father and I have some
issues between us, you see...
Then it's true your father fell to the dark side
after you were struck by lightning in Arkansas--
If you're going to joke
around, then never mind.
All right. Tell me more.
Basically, my father doesn't like me.
No, he detests me.
And not as his daughter,
but as a scientist... As a rival.
He was a physicist.
When I was little, I loved hearing
him talk about complicated physics.
As a result, I was able
to understand his papers
before I was in middle school.
And then I started writing papers
and winning awards of my own.
But I didn't care about the awards.
I just enjoyed debating with my father.
We would share papers through
e-mail and debate more and more...
But, at some point, he stopped talking to me.
During our debates,
I kept disproving his theories.
By pointing out all his mistakes,
I unknowingly damaged his pride...
He started taking it out on my mother.
His confidence was shot, and he
found himself abandoned by academia.
The last time I saw him, he told me this...
"Do you pity me? Do you look down on me?
How dare you. You're my damn daughter."
If I do create a time leap device,
I'm absolutely certain it'll make my
father more furious than ever before.
That's why you're hesitant to build it?
Don't worry, though.
I'm obviously going to build it.
Because you're right...
I love to experiment.
I always need to be
testing or confirming something.
Just like my father did.
Just like during the time he and I shared...
In that case, let us begin
Operation Verdandi at once!
We've no time to waste!
The Organization is at our heels!
You sum it up with that?
But of course! I am Hououin Kyouma!
It is my mission to reform
the ruling structure of this world!
This was a mistake.
And we'll reconcile things!
--Where is your father now?
--Huh? Oh, in Aomori.
Then we will require funds for traveling.
When you've decided a time
to go, let me know right away.
D-Don't tell me you're planning on coming too?!
Of course I am!
I need you working at peak mental
efficiency if I'm to achieve my ambition!
Hououin Kyouma shall accompany you,
bring the topic up in a
wonderfully compassionate manner,
and clear the air
between father and daughter.
Get serious. You're a
self-proclaimed mad scientist.
You're not supposed to be compassionate.
Well, I, err...
Why are you laughing?!
The trouble with you is that
sometimes you can be a nice guy.
If you recognize my greatness,
then get back to work.
Yeah, yeah.
Just so you know,
since it's set in stone now,
I will drag you along if I have to.
Sounds good to me.
Too-too-roo...
Oh! Mayuri-chan?
What's with all the heavy bags?
Shouldn't you ask that
Okarin or whoever for help?
I'll be okay...
I'm almost there...!
Look right here! It clearly
has "Makise" written on it!
It could mean "Makise Pudding"!
You know, like "Morinaga
Pudding" or "Koiwai Pudding."
Don't give me that!
--Who is "Makise" anyway?
--It's my name!
Christina Makise, huh?
If you had just written "Christina" then,
I could've avoided ingesting
unnecessary caloric content.
You have some nerve,
eating other people's stuff!
In fact, that's my spoon!
I didn't say you could use it!
Well, you use the lab's forks
without permission, you know!
I made it...
Oh, what's in the bags?
Costume materials and
Mayushii's sleepover kit!
Sleepover?
Yeah! I'm making costumes for Comima!
Is it really okay? Did you ask your parents?
I just told them!
You're spending the night too to
upgrade the Phone Microwave, right?
Huh? Oh, right.
I was considering it, but I think
I'd be miserable staying the night here.
Some Hououin guy keeps
eating other people's pudding.
It's "Hououin Kyouma"!
You can at least remember my name!
Like you're anyone to talk!
And don't brush the pudding issue aside!
Maybe I should go home after all...
Huh?
Oh, I don't mind staying,
as long as Okabe leaves.
S-Say what?!
My lab is where my soul dwells!
I shall not leave!
They're the ones sleeping over;
why do I have to go shopping?
I feel like I've been my assistant's
errand boy ever since yesterday...
Huh?
Christina, huh...
"Don't get cocky. Don't forget
your duty as a lab member."
I'm not acting cocky, you idiot.
Oh?! What now?!
Oh, it's nothing!
Hurry and get in, before Okabe comes back!
Right!
My assistant again?
What the...?!
Mayuri...
Mayuri! Mayuri!
U-U...
Unforgivable!
I'll never forgive you for this!
Okarin. Mayushii is very sad and embarrassed.
Geez! You peeped on us
and forgot to buy anything?!
You're unbelievable!
--Hey, Okabe...
--Okarin?
Daru-kun!
What are you doing here so late?
Well...
I thought so.
Something seemed weird when
I tried to remotely log in to this PC...
Did something happen?
It looks like this is directly
connected to the heart of SERN.
SERN?!
You've taken control of their system?!
It was a piece o' cake.
...Or so I'd like to say, but I really
have no idea how it happened.
It's almost like SERN was on
pins and needles just waiting for this.
--They were excited?
--Hold on!
If we didn't connect to them,
does that mean SERN took
notice and is trying to access us?!
But I'm certain I didn't screw
anything up that'd get us caught...
--Now we can use the LHC all we want!
--Could it be...?!
--SERN?!
--Really? The LHC?
Okarin?
Did something happen on your phone?
No...
It's nothing.
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now