This is Earth, 70 million years ago.
Mayuri?
You were sent here by a time machine.
Is that you, Mayuri?
Mayushii has chased you through
many, many, many world lines
to try to find you.
Mayuri...
You could say that the Okarin
here is just one of many Okarins,
and you also could say that he's the original.
You could say that the Mayushii
here is just one of many Mayushiis,
and you could also say that she's the original.
Anyway, I think Okarin and
Mayushii are going to die here.
But I feel certain their
wills will carry on all the way
to the Okarin and Mayushii in
Akihabara 70 million years from now.
So...
...it's okay.
Okarin!
Kurisu-chan says you should come!
She's almost finished with it!
Mayushii's costume is almost done too.
Come on! Hurry, hurry!
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Think you could hold this for me?
--Like this?
--Yes, just like that!
Hold it nice and wide!
Oh, that's a cute ribbon!
Isn't it, though?
Do you want to try it on? I have
plenty of other costumes for Comima!
Cosplay, huh...
Oh, are you interested?
O-Of course not! I couldn't
dress like that in public--
It's done!
Tadah!
Mayushii wins!
--We were racing!
--You got us.
But we're done too.
It's finished now.
This is... the time leap machine.
Wow...
It looks kinda like a hypno-gizmo
an evil organization would have.
It seems like Phone Microwave-chan,
but with a headset.
It might not look like much,
but theoretically it should be able
to send your memory back in time.
Especially now that we can use the LHC.
The LHC has something to do with it?
Yes.
Simply put, it's an issue of compression.
As I explained before,
this machine reads the signals
in the memory part of your brain and
converts it into 3.24 terabytes of data.
The Phone Microwave can only
send a little over 36 bytes of data.
Sending terabytes is
obviously out of the question
so first we send the data to the LHC
and compress it using a black hole.
Then we take that data and send it
back in time like we would a D-mail.
Like sticking a blanket
that won't fit in a closet
into a vacuum storage bag first?
Strictly speaking, it's different,
but that's one way of looking at it.
Just like with D-mail, we send
the data to a cell phone in the past.
Then, using the spread
signal from the cell phone,
your present memories are
copied into your past brain,
producing a version of
you with your future memories.
We can only send the data
back 48 hours at most each time.
Sending it any further back
could cause the copy to fail
due to too many neurological differences.
--And there's one other problem.
--What's that?
Unlike with the Phone Microwave and D-mail,
we can't try it out... without
a test subject to use it on.
As we're sending memories,
the only way to tell if it works
or not is to test it on a human.
In other words, one of us
has to be the guinea pig?
I'll pass.
Okabe. Give me your opinion.
Not Hououin's opinion. Yours.
--Daru.
--'Zup?
I take it you still haven't figured
out how we got connected to SERN.
Right.
But there's no sign they noticed my hacking.
I agree with his assessment.
If they had noticed, they
would've taken some sort of action.
Is it really possible to transcend time?
Part of me wants to find out.
O-Oh, then can't we just have a
banana Mayushii bought time leap?
I explained it earlier, Mayuri.
Bananas don't have memories.
But we won't do the experiment.
We'll go public with it instead.
We'll give the time leap machine
to an appropriate organization.
Oh. I agree.
If that's what you want, then...
Mayushii totally agrees!
Let's see. Hashida ordered pizza, right?
Yeah.
Hmm. Then I guess I'll just make a salad.
--That just leaves--
--Wait.
What?
--You said "salad," right?
--That's right. A grapefruit salad.
Then why are we buying
natto and ground beef?
Mixing stuff in makes it tasty.
The grapefruit's sourness makes
it a perfect match for anything.
N-No, it doesn't!
Does to. You should try it.
There's a salad right here!
One that's already ready!
--And it's 50% off--
--Ready-made stuff's no fun.
Sheesh, this is why men who only
care about experiments are no good.
Oh! Here's the cilantro!
It's me. The Organization
agent is finally making her move.
Request immediate backup!
You're almost like a cat back from the vet.
You look relieved, like, "I'm finally free!"
I'm surprised.
I figured you would've wanted to
do a time leap test right off the bat.
Does that bother you?
Well, you know...
Humans are essentially temporal beings.
That's what Heidegger said.
I was honestly relieved when you
said we won't run the experiment.
I think everyone was, in fact.
Say, can we invite Ruka-chan
and Faris-chan to the party too?!
It's a development conference.
I think Mayuri might've wanted
us to stop for a long time now.
Yeah.
It's possible she saw
everything with clearer eyes
while we were so
focused on the experiments.
--When do we go public with it?
--The sooner the better.
Give me advance notice.
I want to let my mom know.
Also...
...this means my dad's going to
find out I made a time leap machine.
Might have to forget about Aomori.
This is going to be a big deal.
Don't worry.
You're a fellow lab member.
I'll solve your problems.
Right. Because you want an
assistant to push around, I'm sure.
Because you're a dear friend.
Th-Th-Thanks...
Huh?!
H-Huh?
W-Wait-- What are--?
Oww!
What's the big idea?!
Do you have a fever?! You're not
talking like an assistant at all!
I-I wasn't showing
appreciation to you just now.
I was just... thanking you out of formality.
--You're such a tsundere.
--Am not!
What's your deal?!
You're always talking crazy-talk and
now you suddenly bring up friendship!
You have no consistency whatsoever!
Don't be stupid. I'm always consistent.
Lab members are my allies,
and the world is my foe! That is all!
--You leave me speechless...
--You're speaking right now.
Quit nitpicking everything I say!
Welcome back.
Sneaking slices while we're gone?
That's bad manners, you know.
Cold pizza's no good.
More importantly, why did you
order three of the same type?!
My personal preference.
Why, you!
Do you honestly think you can
get away with such selfishness?!
See? It's a good thing we
picked up other food too.
Hold on while I whip something up.
--Why didn't you stop her?!
--I tried! With all my might!
Okarin! You promised to
protect your fellow lab members!
Don't lose heart! We aren't done for yet!
Who knows, maybe that apple
pie of hers was just an accident.
--Maybe she's actually--
--Oh, I forgot the radishes.
I'll just use shallots instead.
After this meal, I'm returning to
my hometown and getting married.
--I'm back! Too-too-roo!
--Mayuri!
Oh, thank goodness! Hurry to the kitchen--
Yo!
What's this, now? Something smells great!
Oh, the pizza's already here?
Mayushii bought chicken tenders too--
Why are you here, Makise Kurisu?
Because I'm a member of this lab.
--Why are you here?
--Because I'm a lab member.
--What's goin' on?
--No idea.
Kurisu-chan. Did something
happen between you two?
No. She just makes
weird accusations about me.
--Like me being a SERN spy--
--It's not an accusation. It's the truth.
What makes you so sure about that?
--Do you have proof?
--No. But it will happen.
Huh?
Consider it a prophecy. I know
more about you than even you do.
I know what kind of
person you are deep down
and what sorts of things you're going to do.
I'm sorry.
Your theory is so full of holes
I don't understand a thing you're saying.
K-Kurisu-chan... Suzu-san...
Step back, Mayuri.
It appears only Hououin Kyouma
can pour oil on these troubled waters.
Assistant!
I don't remember
raising you to act this way!
And I don't remember you raising me.
Your journey to becoming
a mad scientist means you--
I never asked, nor do I intend to be one.
Part-time Warrior!
I warned you, Okabe Rintaro.
I told you to beware of Makise Kurisu.
Y-Yes, you did say that, but...
Oh? And you believed her just like that?
N-No, I didn't...
--But you didn't argue I was wrong, either.
--W-Well, that's because...
--I think your good intentions backfired.
--Shut up!
Let's see you try! You're the one who--
Umm...
Mayushii hates when people argue.
Mayuri...
I-I don't really like it, either...
When we're all together,
I think it'd be more fun if we get along!
Think long and hard!
Is that card a link, or is it a virus?
Part-time Warrior.
Your fate as a warrior and the
last piece of dessert depends on it!
When in doubt, attack! That's my motto!
You fell for it, little girl!
You now have three viruses!
If you give up now, I will
grant you the cherry on top.
Miss Amane is too direct and honest.
You're being mean to her, Okarin.
In the world of competition, it's live
or die. Yes, that's how I was raised.
Those ones lined up in the
corner are definitely link cards.
Wha...?!
It's obvious, based on Okabe's
personality. Take 'em for yourself.
--Oh!
--She's right!
Assistant!
You would betray me?!
What kind of assistant are you?!
Quit calling me that! I can't stand
that high-and-mighty tone of yours!
You'll get no thanks from me...
Oh! Mayushii will help!
Oh, then could you
make tea for everyone?
Sure!
Now, then...
Thank you, Kurisu-chan.
For what?
For getting along with
Suzu-san. Mayushii is happy.
Ah.
I wouldn't say we're on good terms now,
but I thought you made a good point.
It'd be more fun if we all got
along when we're together.
Okabe and I were even saying earlier
about how you probably see
this lab with clearer eyes than us.
Huh?
For just that one moment,
Okabe had a gentle look on his face.
--It was a little creepy, though.
--Aww, that's not a nice thing to say...
Sorry! It's just...
Why, you...!
Part-time Warrior!
You did not win on your own!
--Don't get a big head!
--Wow! This really is good!
I'm going to devise a plan for Round 2.
Savor it while you can...
The last dessert of your life, that is!
Maybe you should check on him?
I'll handle things here.
Okay!
Okarin!
Whoa, what the...?
I couldn't find a flashlight.
That Glow Stick Saber is
Future Gadget #6. It's valuable.
--Don't use it as a flashlight.
--Aww, but it's so nice and bright...
--You seem to be having fun.
--Yep! I am!
The pizza was yummy,
and Suzu-san and Kurisu-chan
seem to be having a good time!
Well, I'm not.
Say, we have lots of lab members now, right?
So I've been thinking there
are things we could use lately...
--Like what?
--Let's see...
We could use some chairs,
oh, and some dishes...
Just wait a little longer.
Once we go public with
the time leap machine,
I'm sure we'll get paid
in some way or another.
That'll solve everything.
For real? We can buy chairs and dishes?
Yep, we sure can.
And if I said we could get even more?
A microwave too, then!
I don't like how I can't
heat up my chicken tenders!
Aye. I'll consider it.
It's strange.
You seemed so sad earlier this spring...
The lab was so quiet. There was
only the sound of your computer.
But now there's Daru-kun, Kurisu-chan...
...Ruka-chan, Suzu-san, Moeka-san...
...Faris-chan, Mr. Braun, and Nae-chan...
Mayuri.
I guess Mayushii doesn't really
need to be your hostage anymore, huh?
Okarin! Mayushii!
Come quick! The trains have stopped!
Again, a bomb threat has shut
down all trains on the following lines:
Yamanote Line. Soubu Line...
Terrorist threats cause so much trouble.
I'll need to call home...
This party is to celebrate the completion
of the time leap machine, right?
That's right. Why do you ask?
Are you guys still hacking into SERN?
Not exactly; we're already
pretty much deep inside...
What do you mean?!
We have a direct
connection with SERN now.
There's no time, you guys! You have to--
I'm sorry. I have to go.
Huh? Suzu-san?
What's with her?
What are you gonna do, Mayushii?
You gonna take a taxi home?
Hmm, I don't have the money for a taxi...
Huh? Mayushii's watch has stopped...
That's strange.
I wound it up just a little while ago...
--Wh-What is this?
--Hold on...!
Wh-What's going on?!
...all train lines remain on--
Don't move. Everyone put your hands up.
Moeka-san...
Kiryu... Moeka...
SERN will take your time machine now.
SERN?! What do you mean?!
Makise Kurisu...
Okabe Rintaro...
Hashida Itaru...
You three will come with us.
Wh-What about Mayuri...?
Shiina Mayuri...
...is unnecessary.
Stop...
Please stop...!
For FB...
FB... FB...!
Mayuri...
Mayuri!
What is this...?
What is this?!
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru