SERN will take your time machine now.
SERN?! What do you mean?!
Makise Kurisu...
Okabe Rintaro...
Hashida Itaru...
You three will come with us.
Wh-What about Mayuri...?
Shiina Mayuri...
...is unnecessary.
Stop...
Please stop...!
For FB...
FB... FB...!
Mayuri...
Mayuri!
What is this?!
Get away from her.
Okabe!
Get away! Before she kills you too!
I'll get you for this...
She was my...!
The 42 inch CRT...
It's on now.
Hurry!
Okabe!
I'll go!
But if this doesn't work...!
Just hurry!
Okabe!
Leap!
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
Mayuri's grandmother died when
Mayuri was still in grade school.
Mayuri would visit her grave
every day for the next six months.
With her grandmother's
pocket watch in hand,
she would always,
always, gaze up at the sky.
Almost as if she was waiting for
her grandmother to come get her.
Then, one day, there was a light.
Crepuscular rays...
Sometimes known as an "Angel's Ladder."
It almost seemed like it was
about to take Mayuri away.
It seemed like she was
about to vanish forever...
Mayuri!
Okarin?
I won't let you get taken away.
You're my hostage.
You're my living sacrifice
for my human experiments.
What came out of my mouth
was a line I picked up as a kid.
A line a mad scientist inanely shouted
on a TV show we'd seen together.
Oh.
So Mayushii is Okarin's hostage?
Then I guess that's just how it is...
What's with you?
Did you doze off or something?
--What time is it?!
--Huh?
--What's your problem?
It's almost 5:00.
We're going shopping, remember?
Shopping?
Okay, I'll order some pizzas then!
Thanks! Just no Hawaiian pizzas, please.
--I can't stomach them.
--Agreed.
The time leap worked...?
Okabe.
Mayuri!
Where's Mayuri?!
What brought that on?
Mayushii just left, remember?
She went to invite Miss Ruka to the party.
Are you going shopping?
The development conference is canceled!
Canceled? Why?
Did something happen?
We're done for today!
Both of you, go home immediately!
--What are you talking about?
--Just go!
Got it?! Just do as I say!
What's his deal?
His phone rang, and then suddenly he's all...
His phone?
Too-too-roo! This is Mayushii!
I can't come to the phone right now.
Please leave your message--
The world line hasn't changed much,
unlike whenever we send D-mails.
I've really gone back to 5:00 pm today...
Clackety-clack!
Bullet train!
No, honey, bullet trains are white.
After this, Mayuri brings
Suzuha to the lab and...
Should I go to the police?!
No, no one would believe that
I've time-leapt from the future!
I have to do something
within the next three hours!
Mayuri! Mayuri!
O-Okab--
I mean, Kyouma--
Where's Mayuri?!
--She already left...
--She left?! When?!
A-About half an hour ago.
She said she was heading back to the lab.
Is she not back yet?
Umm, I'm sorry.
It was very nice of you to invite
me to your party, but today I have to--
Any mention of stopping by somewhere first?!
You mean Mayuri-chan? No...
If you see her, have her call me right away!
O-Okay.
If the world line hasn't changed,
then neither will Mayuri's actions--
unless I can change them somehow!
Where is she?!
Meow, meow!
Faris can't come to the
phone right now, meow!
Please leave your message at the--
Where are you, Mayuri?
Mayuri?!
Sorry to disappoint.
It's you, Assistant...
I told you we're done for today. Leave at--
Just answer me this.
You time-leapt from the future, didn't you?
How did you know?
It was like you completely changed
the instant you answered your phone.
Given your behavior,
I take it something's happened?
Yeah. But I don't have time to explain now.
Just run.
Where to, though?
Anywhere. Just as far
from the lab as possible!
Got it?
--You better explain later.
--I will.
Tell Daru, too.
All right.
Okabe.
Yeah?
Don't do anything crazy, okay?
I know.
Okabe Rintaro!
--Hey, which way is Ochanomizu--
--Have you seen Mayuri?!
Shiina Mayuri?
Yeah, she just invited me to your party--
--Where?!
--Turn right at that corner--
Hey! Which way is Ochanomizu?!
I'm supposed to take
Nae there to go shopping!
Just ask a policeman!
Also, when you take her
there, do not come back!
Why not?!
I'll explain later!
Mayuri...
Mayuri!
Oh, Okarin!
Look! The first star of the night!
--Wh-What's going on?!
--Just come with me!
Huh? What about the party?
It's canceled!
I've already told Kurisu and Daru!
Huh? How come?
I'll explain later!
But I already invited Suzu-san,
and Daru-kun ordered pizza--
Just do what I say!
Okarin...
Sorry.
Mayushii doesn't understand...
You always do things
she doesn't understand,
but today you're really hard to understand.
I guess... you wanted to
do the experiment after all...
Mayuri...
That's not true.
But, please, listen to me for now.
There's no time.
I promise I'll explain later.
Okay.
Sorry. Mayushii was just really shocked...
Don't apologize.
You haven't done anything wrong.
Look at all these people...
Yeah, it's rush hour.
Oh? But the platforms are empty...
Again, a bomb threat has shut down
all trains on the following lines...
They still don't know when
the trains'll be running again.
--Urgh! What a pain!
--How could I be so careless...
...at a time like this?!
--Okarin?
--Mayuri!
The subway! Hurry--!
Okabe Rintaro, I presume?
What's wrong?
You're coming with us.
Hey! Don't block the way! Move!
Run!
As fast as you can!
Who are they?!
Okarin!
Get out of here!
Run, Mayuri!
The deceased is Shiina Mayuri.
Okabe-kun-- I mean,
Okabe Rintaro has been secured.
Mayuri!
Damn you!
I won't let you kill her!
I will save you, Mayuri!
I will!
I swear it!
Canceled? Why?
Did something happen?
Yes. You see...
I have intel that Mr. Braun will
be storming the place tonight.
Okarin. Did you get into trouble again?
Yes. You know how it is.
--But what about Mayuri?
--I'll tell her myself.
In any case, it's dangerous to stay here.
You're dismissed for today!
Was that too forceful?
No... I don't care if
I seem suspicious or not.
What matters most is getting
everyone away from the lab!
Too-too-roo! This is Mayushii!
I can't come to the phone right now.
This keeps taking me too long!
It's going to be just like last time!
I have to find Mayuri somehow...!
--Hello?
--Rukako!
It's me! Okabe!
Oh, Okabe-- I'm sorry.
I mean Kyouma-san!
--Mayuri!
--Huh?
Is Mayuri there?!
Oh, Mayuri-chan?
--Yes, she's leaving--
--Stop her!
Tell her to absolutely
stay put until I get there!
--But she's going to the lab--
--Just do it!
R-Right!
Mayuri-chan!
Clackety-clack!
Bullet train!
No, honey, bullet trains are white.
Mayuri!
Oh, Okarin! Too-too-roo!
Are you okay?
I was just about to fix Fubuki-chan's
costume and head back to the lab...
Fubuki-chan? A cosplayer friend of yours?
Yeah!
She just texted about some loose
threads in the costume Mayushii made--
So that's where she was?
I'll go straight to the lab when I'm done!
I'll make it in time for the party!
Wait! The party is...
The party is cancel--
--...It's been postponed.
--Huh?! How come?!
We can't use the lab, you see...
It's out of our hands.
Oh...
Anyway, I need you
to come with me, Mayuri.
Right now.
--What about Fubuki-chan?
--Sorry, but she'll have to wait.
This is extremely important.
Umm, did something happen?
Yeah. We're going on a little outing now.
--A trip.
--Huh?!
Th-Th-The two of you are?!
Oh, I mean...
I can always go see Fubuki-chan
tomorrow, but this is so sudden...
--Where are we going?
--I'll tell you later.
We have a train to catch.
But Mayushii hasn't packed,
and we'll need money--
Don't worry about that.
Now let's go.
Oh! Wait, Okarin!
Umm...!
--Huh?
--B-Be safe.
Yeah! See you soon!
Isn't Akihabara's train station over there?
We're taking the subway.
Oh.
It's been so long since you last
walked with me in tow like this!
Yeah.
--Let's turn back.
--Huh?
All right. Let's go!
Just Kurisu...
Huh? Mayushii's watch has stopped...
That's strange.
I wound it up just a little while ago...
It sure is crowded.
They shut down the Soubu Line.
Huh? They did?
Yeah.
Apparently they got a
phone call about a bomb.
Oh...
Say, Okarin.
Umm, Mayushii has lots of things to ask you,
but she'll hold them in for now, okay?
Just promise you'll explain
everything when this is over.
Yeah.
I promise.
--I'm sorry.
--Huh?
I'm sorry I'm not very useful to you.
Let's hold that party someday.
Yeah.
Someday.
Someday...
...for sure.
Big Sis Mayuri!
...mean to...
I didn't mean to...
All I wanted was to surprise her...
I won't let her be killed...
I will save Mayuri...
I will!
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now