After that, I time-leapt over and over...
...to try to save Mayuri.
But...
...no matter how hard I tried...
...Mayuri kept dying.
Even without Moeka's thugs attacking,
it was as if fate itself was killing her...
It was like the whole world...
...was conspiring to kill Mayuri.
We haven't moved an inch!
'Cause the trains have stopped.
Please hurry! A back
alley or anything will do!
There's not much I can do...
Huh? Mayushii's watch has stopped...
That's strange.
--I wound it up just a little while ago...
--Not again...
Not again!
Mayuri!
The deceased is Shiina Mayuri.
Okabe-kun-- I mean,
Okabe Rintaro has fled.
No matter what I do or
what I try, she keeps dying.
It's almost like this is fate!
I see. This must be--
No, there's no such thing!
The Organization, Steins Gate,
choices made by destiny...!
None of it...
...is real!
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
What's the deal?!
Explain!
I just hit a story branch!
At least let me save!
I'll do it for you!
Just get out of Akihabara!
--Got it?!
--Okabe?!
Mayuri's already left...
It's the same...
However hard I try to help
Mayuri escape, it's always...
Even the e-mails are the same.
E-mail...?
"Shining Finger.
I have new info about the time machine.
I want to talk with you, alone."
Don't move.
Hands up.
Just who are you people?!
I work part-time at Arc Rewrite.
I know you're going to raid our
lab tonight and try to abduct us!
--How?
--Because I came from the future!
Understand?! Now answer me!
--I'd prefer e-mail--
--No! Answer me now!
Are you guys with SERN?!
We're Rounders.
"Rounders"?!
Our mission is to retrieve the IBN 5100.
--Are you the one who stole it?!
--I don't know what you mean.
Don't play dumb!
That D-mail of yours was what--!
Oh, right.
When the world line changed, Moeka
lost all memory of sending that D-mail.
Why attack the lab, then?!
The IBN 5100 isn't there anymore!
--I can't--
--Answer me!
Three reasons.
One: you've learned
things you shouldn't have.
Two: you created a time machine.
Three: you tried to go public with it.
You knew that much...?
SERN knows that much?!
I receive my orders from FB.
"FB"?
A group inside SERN--?!
FB is... my all.
Where am I...?
Don't move.
Are you John Titor?
You're the only
possibility I can think of...
No!
This is...
The bomb threat stopped
all the trains, just as planned.
Secure Makise Kurisu and Hashida Itaru.
All others are expendable.
Wait--!
W-Wait!
I beg you! Don't kill... Don't kill Mayuri!
I apologize!
I was in the wrong!
I wasn't trying to expose SERN or anything!
I'll give you the time leap machine!
I won't tell anyone about this!
Commence operation.
Please! I'll do anything!
Please! I just let my
curiosity get the better of me!
I was just playing around!
Please, just don't kill Mayuri...!
It's too late.
Mayuri...!
Mayuri!
Shut up!
Mayuri...
What's with you?
Did you doze off or something?
--That again?
--Huh?
I...
--...can't take it anymore!
--Okabe!
WTF...?
You don't have to break it!
You decided not to do
the time leap, remember?
What brought that on?
We're going shopping, right? For the party...
The party is...
Hey! Okabe!
Clackety-clack!
Bullet train!
No, honey, bullet trains are white.
Oh, Okab-- I mean, Kyouma-san!
Where's Mayuri?
Oh, Mayuri-chan left earlier...
--I know.
--Huh?!
I also know she came
to invite you to the party,
that she's visiting her cosplayer
friend on her way back to the lab...!
And that she's looking forward to the party!
I know it all!
I'm sorry...
Yet...
Yet, I'm...
What are you doing there?
Kurisu...
Oh, you used my actual name for once.
What happened? No, what happens?
You time-leapt here, didn't you?
It's all... because of me.
Okabe...
It's all because of me...!
I should never have asked
Daru to hack into them...!
I should never have suggested
making a time machine...!
I should never have
made Moeka a lab member!
It's my fault that Mayuri gets...
You dummy. You couldn't
be any more reckless...
There's no guarantee that the
time leap machine is safe to use.
For all we know, it could even
make you cease to exist altogether!
Humans are essentially temporal beings.
Heidegger. I was just
about to say that myself.
You taught me that quote.
That's kind of creepy. It's like
you're peering into my brain.
But maybe that's just how time-leaping is.
What should I do?
When does the lab get attacked?
After 7:30.
I can think of several
possibilities why Mayuri keeps dying.
But there's no time to discuss that.
Let's go.
I consider Mayuri a close friend.
I want to save her too!
--Sorry to drag you into this...
--Don't apologize.
I want to help.
I'll be...
Come on, mad scientist!
You're bent on reshaping the world's
power structure or whatever, right?
"But of course!"
...Right?
I've set it to about five hours ago,
around the time the time
leap machine is finished.
Any earlier and you risk the chance
of the machine not being completed.
You'll leap there, and once it's
completed, you'll have everyone leave
and then re-tell me what you told me earlier.
If you tell me you came from
the future, I'll probably believe you.
How can you be sure?
I know myself the most.
Besides, I was the one who developed
the time leap machine in the first place!
Meaning you're confident
of your own machine?
I guess. I was convinced when
I saw the way you acted earlier, too.
I realized you'd time-leapt.
Shall we decide on a
pass phrase just to be safe?
"What I most want right
now is my own personal fork."
You do? Your own personal fork?
Yep. I already have my
own personal spoon, so...
Wait, don't take an interest in that!
Just get ready!
Okay.
I guess the version of me five hours ago
won't know you called
me "Kurisu," will she?
Think you could hold this for me?
--Like this?
--Yes, just like that!
Hold it nice and wide!
Oh, that's a cute ribbon!
Isn't it, though?
Do you want to try it on? I have
plenty of other costumes for Comima!
Cosplay, huh...
Oh, are you interested?
O-Of course not!
I couldn't dress like that in public...
Ah. Five hours earlier
places it before Mayuri leaves.
As I recall, the time leap machine is
finished just as Mayuri's costume is.
It's done!
Tadah!
Mayushii wins!
--We were racing!
--You got us.
But we're done too.
It's finished now.
This is--
We won't do the experiment!
Huh?
Crap, was that too sudden?!
What do you mean?
I-I figure you're all exhausted, so...
I'll explain later; you're
all dismissed for today!
--One beef bowl.
--One bowl, coming up.
Why here?
I got your e-mail just after I ordered.
I never imagined you'd be a regular here...
I-I'm not a regular.
Mayuri told me about this place.
So, what is it you need to tell me?
First you tell me to leave,
and then you e-mail me...
The truth is...
...I'm from five hours in the future!
Huh? What kind of lame line is that?
H-Hey! That's not what you said you'd say!
"I'll probably believe you," my butt!
What nonsense is this now?
I'd never use such specious
words as "probably" or "believe."
But you did!
You said, "I'm the one who made the
time leap machine in the first place!"
All smug-like!
Are you crazy?
I can't help but ROFL.
Oh, how I wish I could slug her...
"What you most want right
now is your own personal fork!"
Well?
I really said that five hours from now?!
You also said, "I already have
my own personal spoon, so..."
Curse you, five-hours-from-now me...!
Now do you believe me?
Yes...
So the machine...
...really does work?
Here's your beef bowl!
I see. If this is all true, then
this is a pretty serious situation.
Yeah.
Rather than help Mayuri escape,
what about Moeka-san
and her... Rounders, were they?
Could you try stopping them instead?
I tried.
But I still wasn't able to
prevent Mayuri's death...
Oh.
Things always occur due to the
existence of an underlying cause.
Death can normally be attributed
to a directly-related event
such as an illness or an accident,
but they aren't necessarily the cause itself.
The Rounders are directly
driving Mayuri to her death,
but the real underlying
cause is probably something else.
That's why she continues to
die even without their involvement.
Then what is the cause?
I don't know.
Who knows, it could be that Mayuri's birth
is the cause that results in her own death.
You're referring to her lifespan?
That's fatalism, then!
Yes. So I don't support that hypothesis.
The cause must be something that
acted as the trigger for these events.
The trigger...
Do you think if this never
gets finished, she could--?!
Wait. It's dangerous to jump to conclusions.
But...
Makise Kurisu is right.
Do you know something?
Your theory is mostly right.
It's true that it'll be tough to solve
this without the time leap machine.
To save the world, you need to overcome
the 1% divergence barrier
and reach the "beta world line."
The "divergence number"
indicates this world line's location.
And this Divergence Meter is our
only indication of what that number is.
Nixie tubes... Whoever
made this has good taste.
Well, of course. You're the one who built it.
Me?!
You have the ability to retain
your memories across world lines.
Your future self used that to
create a gauge that numerically shows
how different the current
world line is from the previous one.
0.337187...
That's this world line.
World lines are a lot like yarn or this rope.
At first glance, this looks
like a single piece of rope,
but it actually consists of
a bunch of smaller threads.
These threads are world lines.
They're all independent of each other,
but they all lead to the same end.
You're saying they all
lead to Mayuri's death?
Yeah.
But the result would be different
if there were a big enough change
to cross the 1% divergence barrier
and move from this alpha
world line to a beta world line.
--Okay. You guys use that one.
--Huh?!
W-Wait! We can't climb up on that alone!
Fine.
Wait right here.
Who is she...?
She's definitely a pro. Of some sort.
Okay, come on. Hurry.
The alpha and beta world lines
have very different
results--futures, in other words.
It's normally impossible
to travel between them.
Not even changing the past with
D-mails and time leaps will get you there.
But there are a number of points
in time where major events occur;
events with branching world
lines that lead to separate futures
depending on what choices are made.
Recent examples include the Gulf War in 1991,
the Y2K problem in 2000...
...and 2010, the year the
time machine was developed.
Is that...?
Only at such branches
is it possible to move
from the alpha line to the beta line.
How do we do that?!
--How do we move--
--Wait!
First things first.
Tell us who you really are.
Is this...?
A time machine.
I'm from the year 2036.
Suzuha...
I'm the time traveler...
...John Titor.
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru