Is this...?
A time machine.
I'm from the year 2036.
Suzuha...
I'm the time traveler...
...John Titor.
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
In the year 2036, SERN ruled the world.
They had complete control
of everything; it was a dystopia.
The people, stripped of their freedom,
lived as if they were already dead.
And anyone who stood up
in opposition was slaughtered.
I was a member of the resistance
that fought to free humanity from SERN.
I boarded a time machine my dad left me...
...to change this dying world.
And to alter the future.
Then all those posts on @channel were...?!
Yeah. Most of them are true.
But SERN's a research
organization, not a governing body.
I pointed that out to
John Titor many times online!
Hold on, does that mean
you're the one who posted
under the name
"Chestnut Rice and Kamehame-ha"?!
The person playing Titor has revealed
herself, so it's only fair that I do too.
Then I'll follow suit.
I posted under the
pseudonym "Hououin Kyouma"--
We know.
SERN succeeded in developing a time machine.
Being the only ones capable of
meddling with the 4th dimension of time,
they were able to reshape the world order.
And Makise Kurisu contributed the
most in developing SERN's time machine.
She was revered as the
mother of time machines.
Me, help SERN?! That's nonsense!
Why would I help creeps
who use people as guinea pigs?!
Well, you did, in the future.
Is that why you were always
antagonistic toward me?
What about my future self, then?
Okabe Rintaro was a famous terrorist.
A terrorist?!
An anti-SERN terrorist.
And...
In 2036, you're both dead.
--Well, I got to go.
--Wait!
You're just gonna say that
and then return to the future?!
No, I'm going to the past,
to change the future.
Back to the year 1975.
1975?
SERN succeeded in
developing a time machine
because of the one built in Akihabara in 2010.
--You mean the Phone Microwave?
--Yeah.
SERN used a global monitoring system
to gather any and all information
regarding time machines.
And, Okabe Rintaro,
I think the first D-mail
you sent set off their system.
The one I sent in front
of the Radio Building...?
Yes. So if we can just delete
that e-mail from SERN's database...
...the future will change.
We'll move to a beta world line
where SERN never
completed its time machine!
Will that save Mayuri too?!
Probably.
Then let's hack SERN's
database right away and--!
We need an IBN 5100 for that.
Oh! So that's why--!
My mission is to go to 1975,
obtain an IBN 5100,
and get it into Okabe Rintaro's hands.
But I've wasted too much time in
this time period looking for my dad.
I should've gone sooner.
Is everything okay?!
Oh, no!
It's broken...
--Not good!
--What now?!
I'll figure something out! You two
hide and get away when you can!
Someone in here?
--Who are you?!
--Stay back!
I'm currently on an assignment
to thwart an Organization plot!
This is a Level 17 top-secret mission!
Now leave at once!
Catch me if you can!
--Hey!
--Get back here!
Let's make a run for it!
Hurry!
I don't know what happened in the future,
but right now we're fellow lab members!
Okabe!
You made it out?!
Let's scram!
Now what do we do?
We can't go back there again...
--So the time machine broke?
--After it crashed into the roof?
It didn't "crash."
I miscalculated the coordinates,
and that's just where it materialized.
But it wasn't broken when I arrived.
Then when...?!
The only possibility I can think of
is that thunderstorm the other day.
It was either the
lightning or all that rainwater...
It's my fault.
It's because I stopped you that night...
But I can use the time leap machine!
It can only go back 48 hours at most, though.
That makes it out of reach...
Oh, Okarin!
And Kurisu-chan and Suzu-san!
I thought you guys went home?!
Mayushii said we should
celebrate its completion after all.
So Daru-kun and I picked up some things!
I told you to leave for today!
I'm sorry, Mayuri.
We have important things to discuss now.
Okarin?
Just go home for today.
We'll still celebrate, just some other time.
Okay.
But don't do anything dangerous, okay?
Mayushii worries about you.
We'll be okay. I promise.
See you tomorrow!
Yeah.
--I hear they stopped the trains.
--You serious?
Our only choice is to repair the time machine.
First, you'll jump to five hours ago--
when the time leap machine
is finished, in other words.
Then you'll jump another
48 hours back, to 2:00 pm on the 11th.
I guess that's all the
time we have to work with.
I'll do whatever it takes to fix the
time machine within those two days.
If it doesn't work out, then
I'll just keep redoing those two days!
This isn't about saving the world.
It's about saving Mayuri!
Okabe?
What's the matter?
Get all the lab members here right away.
I have something to tell you.
Sweet! Future people FTW!
Can you fix it?
You can't fix it yourself, Miss Amane?
I have no idea how it works.
My dad's the one who made it.
We can't possibly fix a time
machine from 2036 with current tech--
We won't know unless we try!
Just figure something
out within two days, Daru!
--You're our only hope!
--Why two days?
Well, uhh...
Just do it in two days!
If you can fix it in two days,
I'll do whatever you ask!
Deal!
I want to go on an
all-day date with Faris-tan!
All right. I'll make it happen somehow.
--No, there's no way.
--There's nothing I can't do!
Trust me!
Serious? You swear?
I promise! Just get it done!
Very well!
One more thing?
If I fix it, bring us back the IBN 5100
and an animation cel from the
legendary 1975 magical series,
"Radical Girl Omit-chan"!
Have some self-respect!
Shall I help too?
No, you have the important task
of completing the time leap machine.
--You should probably get back to the--
--Hey, everyone!
Is it me, or are you forgetting something?
What about finding Suzu-san's dad?
--My dad doesn't matter anymore--
--Don't say that!
I know you used the machine
because you have a mission and stuff,
but you also did it to see your dad, right?
So Mayushii wants you two to meet!
Your father's name was Barrel Titor, right?
That's his code name.
I don't know his real one.
--What about "Amane"?
--I got it from my mom.
My only clue is this one memento:
a badge my dad used to have.
You're dad's in Akihabara in 2010, right?
In that case, Mayushii will
begin investigating at once!
Shiina Mayuri is a nice girl, huh?
Think you can fix it?
I'm not 100% sure yet, but
after giving it a quick look-over
I noticed it's actually kinda
like the Phone Microwave...
Then you might be able to fix it?!
Yeah.
You know, I wonder if your
dad's someone close to us.
After all, you knew we
were in Akiba in 2010...
Probably. He didn't tell me himself, so...
I've never actually met my dad;
it was all written in his will.
He was doing his own time
machine research separate from SERN,
to try to change the future.
And now I'm here to carry out his wish.
I'm seriously sorry.
But I'm sure everything will
work out after I fix the time machine!
I'll keep looking for your dad
until you come back from 1975!
So keep it a secret from Okarin
and snag me a legendary "Radical--"
This is such tedious work.
For a so-called Future Gadget Laboratory,
you'd think we'd have a
more futuristic way to do this.
If only it were that convenient.
Future Gadget #2,
Alternative Edition, Version 2.67.
Known as the "Bamboo-copter Camera."
It has a CCD camera installed in the bottom.
That's actually a decent idea!
Couldn't we conduct an aerial search--
The camera spins with it, so the
footage it takes spins rapidly too.
That hasn't been fixed, even by Version 2.67?
That's the prototype.
Daru gave it the name and version
number for fun. There's no meaning to it.
--Where's Daru?
--Still there, working on it.
The Divergence Meter...
I thought you should have this.
You created it, after all.
The future will change
if this number passes 1%.
And since you're the only one
with the Reading Steiner ability,
only you can perceive
how the number changes.
Did my future self give that
to you just before he died?
No. I've never met him.
You were a founder of the
resistance group I'm a member of.
A founder of a resistance group...
That's pathetic.
Not only do I let Mayuri die,
I go on to live a carefree life
and do something so delusional...?!
It's not pathetic!
Liberating the world is a
brave and admirable ambition!
Uhh...
Hey, mister!
I am mad scientist!
So cool!
Sunovabitch.
Yes, can I help you?
Oh, you know Japanese...
I got a question for you.
Do you recognize this?
I wanna know where
it's from. Can you find out?
Oh, remembering is...
Sorry. No can help.
Actually, I'm not so
sure about his Japanese...
If you remember anything, contact me here.
Maybe it doesn't exist yet because
it's made sometime in the near future?
I guess maybe I'm just
not destined to meet my dad.
--Let's call it quits.
--You're just gonna give up?!
We still have a day left, you know!
--Why are you upset--
--More than anything...
...I want to make saving Mayuri my main focus!
Even so, you're a fellow
lab member and a friend!
You're a friend in need, so I want to help!
But you can't just give
up at the drop of a hat!
D-Don't yell at me.
Sorry.
--Please, I need your help! Please!
--What is she...?
There was a kidnapping yesterday!
I'm looking for the kidnapper!
He was wearing this badge!
I would appreciate your help!
Oh! Okarin!
Look! Look!
Mayuri...
Good plan, huh?
It was Mayushii's idea!
I thought it might
make everyone go, "Oh!"
The plan's name is "Mayushii
Pamphlets Her Way to Victory!"
Don't you think saying there was
a kidnapping is going a little far...?
What happens when
the police take notice of--?
--Oh, no! Let's get outta here!
--Huh? What for?
You, there!
Hey, wait!
I'm sorry...
From now on, run all plans--
and plan names--by me first...
What are you doing?
Oh, it's just you, Christina.
This is good timing. I just
found out something terrible.
What?
When I went to buy lunch,
I overheard the shop clerks talking.
I think your father might
be a kidnapper, Amane-san...
Wh-What? What's going on?
How's it going?
For you.
WTF, dude. This work clearly
calls for ice-cold, no-calorie cola.
Well? Do you think you can repair it?
Should have it done by tomorrow.
Wow! I know it's a rush job, but wow!
Daru's got serious skills, all right.
He seems so unhealthy and
drab on the outside, though.
Don't judge a book by its cover.
Right! I've changed my opinion of him!
Then you can help me too, Miss Amane.
And, inside the cramped time machine,
the sweltering heat will be so much
that we'll forget our
embarrassment and strip our clothes...
Have some self-respect, pervert!
--Daru-kun and Suzu-san sure make a good match!
--Huh?! A good match?!
In what way?!
I can't quite put my
finger on it, but they just do.
--What's going on?
--Oh, nothing.
Mayuri's just being weird.
Still, I'll be really worried about you
after the time machine
is fixed and you leave in it!
I'd go with you, if only
it could carry two people.
What help would you be?
Isn't it obvious?!
I'd hold Suzu-san's hand real
tight and support her by saying,
"Don't worry! You'll be fine!
Mayushii's here for you!"
Listen, I feel like I might never
get another chance to say this,
so I'll just say it now...
Oh? That sounds a little over-the-top.
I'm really grateful to you all.
When I first came to this
time period, I didn't know anyone,
and even though this
era's so much more peaceful,
I found it really frightening.
But now I have so many friends.
I really had a lot of fun, coming to
this era and spending time with you.
Even if it was for a short time, I'm
glad to have been a fellow lab member.
I'm glad... I could be with you guys.
Suzuha...
Okabe Rintaro!
Promise you'll change the future, okay?
Make it a free world, like it is now!
Suzuha...
Yes?
Hello? Mad scientist so cool?
The street vendor from this afternoon?
I just remembered.
Yesterday night. A man with that badge.
You found her father?!
Hang on! I'll be right there!
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now