Yes. That guest say,
"Make me please a badge."
Same as one you had.
So this guy asked you
to make that badge?!
What did he look like?!
Look like?
Hmm.
Like a barrel.
--A barrel?
--Barrel Titor?!
Titor?
No, no.
Just like barrel.
Just like barrel...?
--"Barrel" in Japanese is "taru"!
--"Taru"?!
I learned it from the
Rai-Net anime a while ago!
There was a bad guy
called the Barrel Monster--
Yes.
Just "taru."
...Or balloon?
So he's a big guy who looks
like a barrel or a balloon?
How can we contact him?!
Sorry.
Private information. Nothing.
No leads, huh...
But he'll go back to pick up his
badge when it's finished, right?
Apparently he left without placing an order
when the guy said it'd take a week to make.
Oh.
Maybe it's a lost cause after all...
No.
There's still another way.
If I wait for the time leap
machine to be finished tomorrow
and then go back in time...
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Where's Suzuha?
She just left, remember?
What's gotten into you?
I'll explain later!
Crap!
I forgot to ask what
time the guy showed up!
Hey, how can I help you?
Is that him?!
He does have a barrel-ish,
balloon-ish silhouette...
Daru?!
Ack! Okarin?!
Geez...
Why would you make a
fake copy of the badge?!
I'd feel bad if we never found
Miss Amane's old man, y'know?
So I figured I could at least show
her the badge and make up a fake Titor!
So you were gonna
give her false happiness?!
Lies come in two types:
lies that harm and lies that comfort--
Do you honestly think Suzuha
would be happy if she found out?!
Miss Amane told me
not to tell anyone, but...
That time machine...
...can only go backward in time.
Once she leaves, there's no coming back.
How's it going?
For you.
Oh! An ice-cold, no-calorie
cola is just what I needed!
You're Mr. Nice Guy!
Well? Do you think you can repair it?
Should have it done by tomorrow.
Wow! I know it's a rush job, but wow!
Daru's got serious skills, all right.
I told you, don't judge a book by its cover.
Huh?
You did?
But you're right; he does seem so
unhealthy and drab on the outside!
Yeah! I've changed my opinion of him!
Then you can help me too, Miss Amane.
And, inside the cramped time machine,
the sweltering heat will be so much
that we'll forget our
embarrassment and strip our clothes...
Have some self-respect, pervert!
Daru-kun and Suzu-san
sure make a good match!
Listen, I feel like I might never
get another chance to say this,
so I'll just say it now...
I'm really grateful to you all.
When I first came to this time
period, I didn't know anyone,
and even though this
era's so much more peaceful,
I found it really frightening.
But now I have so many friends.
I really had a lot of fun, coming to
this era and spending time with you.
Even if it was for a short time,
I'm glad to have been a fellow lab member.
I'm glad... I could be with you guys.
Once she leaves, there's no coming back.
Okabe Rintaro!
--Promise you'll--
--I will change the future!
I'll make it a free world, like it is now!
Okabe Rintaro...?
You don't...
You don't regret making
memories with us, do you?
If parting ways is inevitable...
You don't regret being friends with
us and wish it never happened, do you?
Wait, did Hashida Itaru tell you...?
He's concerned about you too.
I am going!
Changing the future was my dad's--
But don't you care what that'll mean for you?!
The 70s aren't so bad either.
I can make some
more friends like you guys
and live a life of freedom!
Here goes nothing!
I think it should be okay now, but
you might wanna do one last check.
Right!
Yeah! It looks okay!
You're really amazing!
You should be happier!
You just fixed a time machine!
What month and day in 1975 should I pick?!
Should I go to a Capricorn day?
Or maybe an Aquarius day?
No, that's for weddings!
Oh, but an Aquarius day sounds good.
You might make new
friends faster that way...
Friends, huh?! I can't wait!
"FG204"...?
Say, Suzu-san!
Yes?
Is this...?
Oh, that's the time machine's name!
My dad came up with it!
M-My bicycle...?
We thought it might fit
if we took the tires off!
You're really fond of it, right?
Yeah. I'll cherish it.
Thank you.
Aha!
Mayushii knows who
your father is, Suzu-san!
--What?!
--Huh?!
Not only that, he's right nearby!
Wh-Where?!
I kept thinking they were a
good match for some reason!
But now I know it's because they're family!
W-Wait! You're not saying...?!
Suzu-san's father...
...is Daru-kun!
Huh...?!
That's not a funny joke!
Besides, who would
ever marry this pervert--
Whoa, no need to be mean!
Explain! What led you to this conclusion?!
First, "barrel" is "taru" in Japanese, right?
Taru... Daru...
Daru-kun!
--Word play?!
--You call that a legitimate reason?
But Suzu-san's resistance
group was founded in part
by Okarin and Barrel Titor-san, right?
And the only one who'd know
about your independent time
machine research in Akiba in 2010
and that you have the Reading Stinger--
"Reading Steiner."
Yeah. The only one who'd know
about that is Daru-kun, right?
And the best evidence of
all that Mayushii found is...
The time machine's name?
FG204.
It's a Future Gadget!
A Future Gadget?!
And see the writing next to it too?
Future Gadget 204, 2nd Edition, Version 2.31?!
That naming style...!
Dad...?
A-At times like this,
you should call me "Daddy"!
This is no time to act like a pervert!
Dad...
Y-Yeah.
I came.
I came to see you, Dad.
In the time machine you built...
Yeah...
I will accomplish what you strived to do!
So watch me.
I-I will.
I swear it.
Incidentally...
Was your mom cute?
I'm hoping for someone short with
a baby face and humongous boobs...
I think I'll keep it a secret!
Well, I should probably get going.
Yeah.
Don't forget about us, now!
Be careful.
I'll be okay.
I will get the IBN 5100, just you watch!
And then I'll get it into your hands!
So, please, change the future.
I'll see you again in 35 years!
I guess it'll only be a
few hours for you, though.
Suzu-san!
Suzuha!
Let's meet again, okay?!
I'll stay strong until then!
So you stay strong too--!
Good luck...!
We've just received word that
the space satellite on the roof
of the Radio Building in
Akihabara has gone missing.
Hey, do you think these
were our initials on this badge?
Okabe's "O," Hashida's "H," Shiina's "S"...
Oh!
Then the "M" is for "Makise,"
and the "A" is for "Amane"!
A lab member badge!
Wanna make one ourselves?
Good idea!
What's wrong, Okabe?
The Divergence Meter's
number hasn't changed.
Maybe it'll change after the present-day
Amane-san brings us the IBN 5100?
Suzuha should be 54 now, right?
My own daughter's over
three decades older than me...
She could be married and
have grandchildren by now!
I-In other words, I could
see my own great-grandkids
while I'm still so young!
You'll need to spoil them like
crazy, like a good great-grandpa!
It's her!
Mr. Braun?!
A letter?
Hashida Suzu...?!
Could it be Suzu-san?!
Seriously?! Then why is Mr. Braun...?
That letter's from someone
who helped me out long ago.
She asked me to give it
to you on this exact day.
Where is she now?!
She's dead.
Died ten years ago.
"Dear Okabe Rintaro...
It's been a long while. This is Amane Suzuha.
For you, it's probably
only a few hours since I left.
It's currently June 13, 2000.
I'll get straight to the point.
I failed.
I failed. I failed. I failed.
I failed. I failed.
I failed. I failed. I failed. I failed.
I only remembered
who I am a mere year ago.
I had amnesia the 24 years before that.
The time traveling didn't work right.
The repairs were incomplete.
But it wasn't your fault, Dad. It was mine!
I should've just gone straight back to 1975.
I should never have stopped by 2010!
I shouldn't have been so selfish!
The future won't change now!
I couldn't get the IBN 5100.
I'm sorry...
I'm so sorry!
Why did I even live to this age?
I forgot my duty and
lived a carefree life instead!
Forgive me!
Forgive me! Forgive me! Forgive me!
Okabe Rintaro, after that
time machine forum meeting,
you stopped me
from going back to 1975.
You stopped me,
and the thunderstorm that
night broke the time machine.
If you can turn back time, I ask
that you don't stop me that day.
My life...
...was a waste."
Mr. Braun.
What do you want?
What's with the long faces?
Please, tell me how Hashida Suzu-san died.
What's it to you?
I need to know how she died!
I need to etch it into my mind,
no matter how it happened...!
Sounds like it's more
than just simple curiosity.
But what kind of relationship
did you have with Suzu-san?
We were... old acquaintances.
Very old.
But even now I remember the time
we shared together like it was yesterday!
I don't really wanna talk about it, but...
...it was suicide.
She hanged herself in her home.
She'd been mentally unstable
the year leading up to it.
But she'd always been a
cheerful, kind woman before then...
It's my fault...
The time machine broke
because I stopped Suzuha that night...
If only I hadn't sent that D-mail,
she could've safely traveled to 1975!
Okarin...
Hold on, Okabe! What are you doing?!
At this rate, Mayuri will end up...!
You're sending a D-mail, Okarin?!
It'll all disappear if you do that!
I know...
All the memories we made with
Suzu-san will never have happened!
I know!
So, please, change the future.
Okarin!
What do you want, Okabe?
Hashida Suzu, huh...
That name brings back memories.
You knew her?
Yes...
Umm, do you know where she is now?
It's been almost ten years now, I'd say...
She really helped me out.
I wish I could've at
least looked after her...
It was a suicide, then?
Huh?! A disease did her in!
I live in her old house now!
That bike...!
Yeah. Suzu-san cherished it like crazy.
I couldn't bring myself to throw it out,
so it's been sitting here for 10 years.
At first, Suzu-san and
I were just regular neighbors.
When I lost my house in a
fire--along with everything in it--
she rented out a room here to me.
Was she all alone until then?
I don't think she ever married.
She was an unusual woman.
I once asked her why she was being so nice
to a complete stranger she had no relation to.
She smiled and answered with,
"People's lives are a cycle
of helping and being helped.
So someday you'll need to
help someone else yourself."
Oh, yeah. Just a minute.
This used to be Suzu-san's.
Do you know what the number means?
When she was sick in bed, she
always gazed at this, saying things like,
"Is this number before the change
or after the change? Did I change it?"
It was always on her mind to the very end.
The divergence number's changed.
But it's still under 1%...
The train on the outer loop
line will be arriving shortly.
--Please stay behind the yellow line.
--The Yamanote Line is running now?!
Mayuri!
Damn!
What's with you, Okarin?
Nothing.
Oh, Mayushii's phone was
ringing earlier. Was that you?
She was so fast asleep I couldn't wake her up.
Suzuha...
Has the world changed now?
Has Mayuri been saved now?
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru