Yesterday, after I came
back from Mr. Braun's house...
...nothing ended up happening.
Moeka and her thugs always
appeared on Friday the 13th.
Did telling myself to stop following
Suzuha change the world line?
If so...
...will Mayuri remain alive now,
without anything else happening?
Huh?
Mayushii's watch has stopped...
That's strange.
I wound it up just a little while ago...
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
What's going on? What's this about?
Help me...
Mayuri dies two hours from now?
Wait, so you've time-leapt
over and over trying to stop it?
It must've been hard on you...
According to Amane-san, we can save Mayuri
by moving from this alpha
attractor field to a beta world line.
For that, we need to use an IBN 5100
to erase the data SERN has about you guys.
But the IBN 5100 that's supposed
to be at the Yanabayashi Shrine
disappeared when the world lines changed.
Only a few D-mails we
sent changed the world line:
the Loto 6 one, Kiryu-san's,
Urushibara-san's, Faris-san's,
and the one about following Amane-san.
Undoing the one about tailing
Amane-san delayed the raid by a day.
So maybe if you undo
each D-mail in reverse order,
you can return to the original
world line where the IBN 5100 is there?
It's only a hypothesis, though.
There's no scientific basis for it...
Even so...!
If there's a chance, then...
I know it was my idea and all,
but undoing all those D-mails...
Yeah. It'll be pretty tough work.
But it has to be done.
Be careful.
B-Because your brain is a valuable sample!
You retain memories even across world lines
and it's endured the time leap process!
--We need to map it--
--Thank you, Kurisu.
I'm going to forget you
called me "Kurisu," aren't I?
What?
Nothing.
Going in reverse order,
the next one to be undone...
...is Faris' D-mail.
Hello?!
Daru. Do you know where
Faris might be right now?!
Sure do!
Where?! Where is she?!
The UPX conference building!
The final match of the Rai-Net ABGC just ended!
ABGC?
WTF, dude! It's short for "Rai-Net
Access Battlers Grand Championship"!
It's like a competition between all
the Rai-Netters throughout Japan,
and it just ended with
Faris-tan as the winner!
I'm excited to the max!
After Faris sent her D-mail,
Akiba went back to being an electronics town.
I don't know what her message said.
Just who did she send
it to, and what did it say?!
Kyouma!
Faris! What's going on?!
Sir. The cat's with a guy in a lab coat.
Don't let her get away!
Not that she can, though.
For no one escapes from my dark force...
Who's chasing you?!
The Viral Attackers, meow.
Viral Attackers?
A bunch of no-good Rai-Netters
who'll do whatever it takes to win!
They ambushed Faris to get
even for beating them, meow!
--Ambushed--?!
--This way!
Where'd they go?
Gotta be around here somewhere.
Yeah.
That reminds me, you called earlier...
Oh, right!
I need to know what your D-mail said!
D-mail?
The e-mail you sent back in time!
Back in time? What are
you talking about, meow?
The Faris in this world line
doesn't know about D-mails...
O-Oh, err, I mean to say--
There they are!
Tell me, just hypothetically...
Would you believe me if
I said we built a time machine?!
--I'd believe anything you say, Kyouma!
--Really?!
Faris just developed an
interdimensional transporter herself!
Let's pretend Akiba was
a town full of moe culture!
Oh?
If you could use the time machine to
make it an electronics town like this,
how would you do it?!
What kind of logic game is this?
Please, just tell me!
I don't really know...
But a town full of moe
sounds like a lot of fun!
Actually, I once talked to my daddy
about maybe opening a maid café in Akiba.
But he said no, sadly.
You mean May Queen?
How do you know that name?
I didn't even tell my daddy...
May Queen used to exist!
Here, in Akiba!
Akiba used to be full of moe!
Kyouma?
And you loved it more than anyone!
But the instant you sent your
D-mail, the entire city changed!
What message did you send?!
--Please! Tell me!
--I found 'em! Over here!
What is it?
This is it!
This is where May Queen was!
The café you wanted to start!
Meow...?
You worked here!
Mayuri, too!
Daru was a regular here!
This is where we met!
Welcome home, Master!
--Ice coffee, please.
--Certainly, meow!
We're about to start the daytime Faris Cup!
--Strategy Code... K.B.O.O.M.!
--"The World's in Danger" FTW!
So many masters visited
today! It sure was lively!
Faris!
I-I'm okay.
What happens if you don't undo the D-mail?
Mayuri's life will be in danger...
You're kidding, right?
You're kidding, right?!
What do you mean
Mayushii's life is in danger?!
Do you know what the D-mail said?!
Tell me! Please!
I have to undo the D-mail!
I can't.
Why not?!
Don't you care...
Don't you care if Mayuri dies?!
Of course I care!
--But...
--Faris!
My daddy died ten years ago.
I brought him back to life.
Huh?
I changed the past... so he wouldn't die!
Kyouma!
Kyouma...
Not so cool now, are ya, dude?!
Okay! Now you're
comin' with us, Princess!
Let go!
Kyouma!
Yes, the cat's in the bag.
--My badass aura's been itchin'...
--He'll be here soon.
--...to dye her black for a while now!
--Until then, we can enjoy...
Stop...
Oh ho ho!
Let her go...!
Kyouma!
C'mon, now, dude.
You still wanna act cool?
Stop! Please!
Stop!
--Shit!
--Run for it!
Daddy!
Oh!
Stop right there! What were you just doing?!
Prepare yourself! The great 4ºC has arrived!
Huh?! Who the hell are you shits?
Huh?!
The... police?
Wha...? I'm under arrest?
Thank goodness...
Oh, what a relief...
Daddy...
Thank you.
I hurried over to celebrate
after I heard you won,
but you were nowhere to be found.
You wouldn't answer your phone
either, so I looked everywhere for you.
Okabe-kun. I don't know
how I can thank you enough...
Oh, no, I didn't do anything.
Had I gone to watch the tournament,
this might never have happened.
You had work, Daddy.
You couldn't help it, meow.
Rumiho...
An IBN 5100?
Yes. I heard you gave
away one you used to have...
Do you know where it is now?
Could you get it back?
Some things happened, you see,
and I had to break my
promise with Hashida-san.
Hashida-san...
Do you mean Hashida Suzu-san?!
Oh, you know her?
She's the one who gave me the IBN 5100.
I'll be okay.
I will get the IBN 5100, just you watch!
Suzuha... got it for us...
Daddy. You can tell him, meow.
But...
He did save my life and all!
Rumiho was kidnapped
a long time ago, you see...
My company wasn't as big as it is now,
so I couldn't come up
with the ransom money.
But then someone offered to buy
the IBN 5100 for a large sum of money.
So you got rid of it?
I was able to pay the
ransom with that money.
I've made it a personal rule ever since
to keep my promises with
my daughter, no matter what.
Even for the smallest
of things, no matter what...
Daddy!
My daddy died ten years ago.
I brought him back to life.
I changed the past so he wouldn't die!
If I undo the D-mail, he'll...
You're sending a D-mail, Okarin?!
It'll all disappear if you do that!
But if I don't, Mayuri, you'll--
Can I come in?
Yeah...
Faris...?
Umm, thanks for earlier.
It was really scary...
I've never run into so many
black-hearted people before.
C-Come to think of it,
they were all dressed in black...
Oh, I'm trying to be serious here.
Sorry.
What's the matter, Faris?
Please call me Rumiho.
If you hadn't been there
Kyouma--no, Okabe-san--
I don't know what would've happened.
Don't correct yourself.
Just call me what you always do.
Anyway, I'm really grateful, Kyouma.
You're my prince.
P-Prince?!
I-I'm no prince!
I'm a mad...
Mayushii's life...
Is Mayushii's life really in danger?
Yeah.
Ten years ago, on my eighth birthday,
my daddy promised
to go have fun with me.
But he couldn't go, because of work.
It couldn't be helped, but I was so sad...
I thought maybe he didn't love me...
I said, "I don't care about you
anymore! I wish you would just die!"
And then...
...that ended up being the
last thing I ever said to him.
So I sent the D-mail to change that...
So your dad avoided the accident,
which kept you from spreading
moe culture throughout the city
and left Akiba as an electronics town...
I was so happy these ten years...
Far-- Rumiho...
I'll send a D-mail.
My daddy died in an accident ten years ago.
That's what really happened.
These past ten years have been a dream.
I got to spend more time with him
and learn how much he loved me.
But Mayushii's my friend.
I can't be selfish at a time like this.
Are you really okay with this?
No...
It's not okay...!
I remember what happened
before the world line changed.
But I also remember what
happened after it changed!
It's all mixed up in my head now...
I almost can't tell what's real anymore!
There might still be a way!
--Yeah! I'll consult with Kurisu again--
--No! I don't want to burden you anymore!
You're my prince and all!
It's time for me to wake up from this dream.
But I have one thing to ask...
Can I cry, just for a little bit?
Yeah...
So, did Faris-san...?
Yeah. She came to terms with it.
Get everything ready.
Here I am, meow!
Huh? What's the matter, Kyouma?
You're looking glum!
By the way...
When the world goes back to normal,
will I lose all my memories of this?
You have memories right now from
before and after the change, right?
So I'm sure you'll remember!
Thank goodness...
Faris doesn't want to forget the
time she shared with Kyouma...
Thank you.
It's on, Okabe!
Bye-bye, Daddy...
Kyouma!
Have you seen Faris' cell phone?
--Faris...
--Mayushii hasn't seen it...
...so that just leaves you, meow.
Wha...?!
Kyouma! Did you look at you-know-what?!
If so, forget what you saw! It needs
to be sealed away forever, meow!
Come on, Kyouma!
You're supposed to answer back with,
"What do you mean by 'you-know-what'?"
Y'know?!
Faris!
Hey, stop that, you!
Quit grabbing her!
--Planning another perverted act, are you?!
--You're so daring, Okarin!
Kyouma and Faris fought a great darkness
and loved each other in a previous life!
They have a deep connection!
--Huh?!
--You sure fight lots of people!
Don't tell me you're as
out-there as Okabe, Faris-san...?
I'm sorry...
The IBN 5100 wasn't at Yanabayashi Shrine...
Faris did store it there ten years ago
and it was there until last year, but...
Where in the world could it have gone?
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now