Rukako.
Stay calm and hear what I have to say.
The truth is, you really used to be a guy.
Again with that?
Wait! Don't cry!
Just stay calm and hear me out!
This is all for Mayuri's sake.
I need you to go back to being a guy.
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
What's with you?
You look like you messed
up making yakisoba noodles
and tossed them all into the sink.
"You look like you worked hard to
fill up your store discount stamp card
but then it expired just
before you redeemed it."
...Is what I'd prefer.
Looks like you still have
enough in you to joke around.
Okarin!
Mayushii is disappointed in you!
Wh-What are you talking about?!
Don't pretend you don't know!
You made Ruka-chan cry!
H-How did you find out?!
She suddenly burst into tears
when I invited her to the lab!
When I asked what was wrong,
she said you called her a boy!
Did she tell you about the D-mail too?!
D-mail?
Don't try to talk your way out of this!
You should apologize to Ruka-chan!
Okabe!
Did you really say something so mean to her?!
W-Wait! It's not what you think!
--I have a reason for...!
--Like what?!
Come with me, Assistant!
--Huh?!
--Just come!
H-Hey! What are you doing?!
So the next D-mail I have to undo
is the one we sent to Rukako's
mother's pager before Rukako was born.
Urushibara-san is actually a boy...?
That's unbelievable.
But it's the truth... was the truth.
Her, a guy...
A guy like Hashida?
Now that would be bad...
No, he still looks exactly the same.
That's acceptable, then.
At any rate, we have to
turn Rukako back into a guy
if we want to save Mayuri!
But this time you
know what her D-mail said.
Can't you just quietly undo it without
discussing the situation with her?
I don't know her mother's pager number.
Besides, I feel it would be more
responsible to tell her the truth
rather than resort to cheap trickery.
And that "responsibility" wound
up making her cry, remember?
You're just playing around as usual, right?
You're just joking, right?
That's so mean!
I can't believe you'd say such things to me...!
I think you jinxed things for her.
Jinxed?
It's not like I said anything like,
"Once this battle is over, I'm getting married."
That's a jinx that ends in death.
I'm talking about love here.
Love?!
Yeah. Hearing her beloved
Okabe say, "You're a dude,"
has broken her tender heart.
B-But Rukako is a guy!
In a previous world line, maybe.
"I have something important to discuss.
Could you come to the shrine?"
Okabe-san.
Sorry about earlier.
No, I'm sorry for bursting into tears...
So, you had something important to discuss?
Yes. I have a favor to ask...
A favor?
I believe what you said.
So, umm...
In exchange for turning back into a boy...
...I-I ask that you be my boyfriend!
Boyfriend?!
Wh-Why me?!
Because I like you.
Because I like you, Okabe-san!
So, tomorrow, for just one day...
...please be my boyfriend!
B-But, you're a guy--
Okay! I'll do it! Just don't cry!
Very well! If it's just for tomorrow,
then I'll be your boyfriend!
R-Really?!
Why are you crying?!
I can't help it, I'm just so happy...!
That was actually kind of touching...
So now you're going on a date
with Urushibara-san tomorrow?
Yes.
A mad scientist, going on a
date with a high school girl?
Get off my back!
I'm swallowing my pride and asking
my lowly assistant for dating advice!
I told you, I'm not your assistant!
Oh? You're going on a
date with someone, Kyouma?
I brought your order! Two ice coffees!
Who's the date with? Mayushii?
Or... maybe this girl?
No, this is my assistant.
I know you're trying to master
your special technique and all,
but you chase way too many girls, meow!
Oh? Way too many girls, huh?
Hey! Don't just spout misleading
statements and then leave!
Say. Would you, umm...
Would you do anything to
master your special technique?
Huh?
No, err, I mean, would Hououin
Kyouma do anything for it?!
Why are you talking about that too?
--I don't get you.
--I-I'm just asking!
I was wondering if he'd do whatever
it takes to master that technique
if there was someone he already loved...
--There's no meaning behind it, though!
--Why are you getting mad?!
I'm not mad!
Anyway, if that's how your character is,
then just go on a date with Urushibara-san!
I already told you I plan to!
Okarin...
Can you fill me in on all the juicy details too?
If you want dating advice, I'm your man!
I've had happy kissy time with dozens of girls!
Nene-chan, Shiori-chan,
Honoka-chan, Rinko-chan...
Those are all game characters.
This is a real-life date.
Somewhere popular, like Aoyama,
Omotesandou, or Nishi-Azabu...
"Fashionable and trendy..."
"Premium night..."
"Special dinner..."
It's no good. This stuff's a world all its own.
A world not part of reality.
But one you still have to accept.
I'll have you know that
the great Hououin Kyouma,
with his 170 IQ--which is the same
as Isaac Newton's, I might add--
finds research more interesting than girls--
You're clearly a virgin. Thank you very much.
What about you, then?!
Do you really have that much
dating experience under your belt?!
See!
You're so absorbed in
your studying and research
that you have zero experience in such things!
Your adolescence was clearly a lonely one!
Shut up! So what if I'm a virgin?!
"The key to a first date is making
the best impression possible."
"Clothing-wise, brand names are
unnecessary; a sense of cleanliness is--"
Sounds like I'm A-OK in that department.
Nothing says "clean" like a lab coat.
No one wears lab coats on dates.
"The same holds true
when choosing where to dine."
"Don't feel compelled to select
an overly expensive restaurant."
"Any place you visit regularly will suffice."
Regularly...?
--This place is out of the question.
--Obviously!
Who would have a date
in a place this savage?!
Then that just leaves...
...May Queen.
Huh?! A maid café on your first date?!
--An old weapon shop.
--Weapon-shopping on a date?!
You're just reading straight
from a dating manual!
Quit acting so high and
mighty, you American virgin!
--Who are you calling an American virgin?!
--Who else but you?!
Yes! I'm a virgin! The end!
Uhh, maybe you'd prefer
this instead of that lousy book?
--That's a hentai game strategy guide!
--So?!
They have dates in hentai games!
Holding hands and stuff
is totally erotic, y'know?!
Walking arm in arm, with
your elbow touching her boob...
That's totally hot!
And then you kiss and embrace
at the end of the date! Hot damn!
Screw you real-lifers!
It's already morning
and I still don't got a plan...
Quit your grumbling and put it on!
Geez, take off the tags!
That's no way to tie a necktie!
You're unbelievable!
Sheesh! You're a lost cause!
There!
I feel like I'm wearing a leash now...
Here's a handkerchief.
Do you know how to use it?
Doesn't this one mean, "I'm waiting
for you, even after all this time?"
That's the yellow kind.
How do you even know
obscure trivia like that? That's old.
You know it too, though.
S-So?!
You're actually supposed to spread
it out when a girl sits on a park bench.
Whatever.
I'll covertly follow you and text
you advice if anything comes up.
--You're going to follow us?!
--Yeah, Hashida too.
Huh?!
Commence Operation Valkyrie!
Why Norse mythology?
"When meeting your date,
time is of the utmost importance.
Be sure to arrive at least 15 minutes early."
Okabe-san!
I'm sorry!
I thought I had left early...
Have you been waiting long?
Oh, no... I, uhh, just got here too...
That's a relief.
Sh-Shall we go?
Yes!
I've never seen you
without a lab coat before!
W-Well, it is a date and all...
"When walking with a girl,
subtly take the side with oncoming traffic!"
Is something the matter?
Oh, no, it's nothing...!
Whoa! What's that?!
That's not subtle in the least...
"And casually guard her from
any passing cars and motorcycles!"
--Whoa!
--Did he guard her?!
Okabe-san?!
--Oww...
--Are you all right?
Wait, he just tripped?!
On top of that, a maid had to help
him up?! And he took her tissue pack?!
Miss Makise. Is it me or are you on edge?
Th-The weather is nice today.
Y-Yeah.
But there are clouds, too.
Yes.
This cake tastes very good.
Yes. The coffee, too.
Why?!
I could hold a normal
conversation just fine before,
but as soon as it turned into a date...!
This is a wonderful place!
--Do you come here often?
--No...!
This is going terribly!
"The key is to play 'conversation catch'!"
T-Today is actually my first time...
He tossed it back!
Speaking of firsts, today is August 14th,
the anniversary of the very
first patent issued in Japan!
Tossed it back where?!
You certainly are knowledgeable, Okabe-san!
W-Well, you know how it is...
Can we go now, Miss Makise?
We're no help at all;
we're just sitting here watching.
No. We have to see it through to the end.
Thank you for coming!
Umm...
Do you find it boring after all?
Going on a date with me...
Wha...?! D-Don't be silly!
Next is a nice walk around town! Come along!
Ruka-chan?
It's so hot...
He just walked straight to Ueno and back...!
Okabe-san.
Do you remember when we first met?
A bunch of men with cameras
suddenly overwhelmed me,
but then you showed up
to save the day, remember?
Yeah...
Th-Thank you!
I'm sorry, though...
What are you apologizing for?
For, well, being a boy
even though I look this way...!
It makes no difference
whether you're a boy or a girl!
None of that matters!
Those words you spoke made me so happy!
Those words are what made me like you!
"None of that matters," huh...
W-Wait a second!
Isn't that memory from when you were a guy?!
Huh? What?
What... What am I saying?
I'm feeling confused...
It's just like what happened with Faris...
She's regaining memories
from an earlier world line...
Thank you for today.
Being my boyfriend made me so very...
So very happy!
H-Hey, now!
This is my mother's pager number.
"Meat meat veggies veggies
meat meat veggies veggies..."
This should make Urushibara-san's mom think
that the previous message was just a prank.
We're all set!
What's wrong, Okabe?
Too-too-roo!
Guess what, guess what?!
Mayushii saw Ruka-chan out
on a date with someone earlier!
Oh, that was Okarin.
Huh? No way!
That definitely wasn't Okarin!
He was wearing regular clothes
and seemed like a real gentleman!
Exactly!
That wasn't me!
Ruka didn't have a date with the real me!
Okarin?
O-Our date isn't over yet!
Huh? But, Okabe-san...!
It's "Kyouma"! Have you
forgotten my name, Rukako?!
All that male, female,
boyfriend, girlfriend stuff...!
I was the one who was confused!
None of that matters!
I've finally realized that I'm me
and you're you: Rukako, my pupil!
Right!
Good! Then go get the
Supernatural Sword Samidare!
That's it!
--Keep it up!
--Right!
Now listen well, Rukako.
The legends surrounding
this supernatural sword
can be traced back to the time of Yoshitsune.
On a night of a crimson full moon,
--Welp, there he goes...
--a wandering samurai lost his way...
That's wonderful!
He's made up with Ruka-chan!
Looks like we aren't needed anymore.
Please help Mayuri-chan.
The old computer you're looking for...
The IBN 5100?!
It was in our storehouse
until last New Year's Day.
But I accidentally broke it,
while I was cleaning the storehouse...
So it's my fault!
Please, Okabe-san!
Please save Mayuri-chan!
I'm really glad I was able to train
with you again. It's been so long.
--Ruka--
--Please go now.
Before I start crying...
This is the perfect time
for that secret phrase, isn't it?
El Psy Congree...
Congroo.
El Psy...
Honestly, I don't want to turn back.
If I...
If I go back to being a boy, I'll have
to seal away my feelings for you!
As a boy, I won't be
allowed to like you...!
Rukako...
And if I go back to being a boy,
I'll forget today ever happened, won't I?
I'll forget we went on a date,
that we trained together again...
That I could touch you the way I am now...
If being a girl means I have
to go through this much pain,
then I should never
have wished to be one!
You'll always be Rukako to me, even as a boy!
Nothing will change!
You're right.
It's like you said,
whether I'm a boy or a girl...
"None of that matters!"
Still, all I ask...
Is that you remember me
when I used to be a girl...!
I will. I'll never forget.
Never.
What's the matter, Okabe-san?
Urushibara Ruka.
The voice and mannerisms of a woman...
No, even more feminine than a woman.
Tell me, Rukako...
Yes?
Do you... like me?
Wh-What brought that on?!
Do you?
Umm, err...
I respect you!
But... he's a dude.
That just leaves one more D-mail...
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru