For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
I'm starving...
--Are you going to Comima--
--You're going again tomorrow, aren't you?
Huh?
Yeah...
--Will you be back around this time?
--I think so.
Say! You should come with me, Kurisu-chan!
Crowded places aren't really my thing...
It shouldn't be too crowded on the second day!
You should come too, Okarin--
Come with me, Okabe!
What's with you?! You've been
moody ever since you got back!
Can't you tell Mayuri's trying to cheer you up?!
I know she is.
But I can't just stay calm!
Huh?
It happens tomorrow!
Even if she's fine today, tomorrow she'll be...!
How many times have
I explained this to you now?
Okabe?
There's something I have to tell you.
Mayuri does?! Tomorrow?!
She'll most likely end up dead.
At first, it'd happen on
the night of Friday the 13th.
But each D-mail I undid
pushed it back one day.
Tomorrow, I'll go with her to Comima.
Is there a way to save her?!
--I'm going to watch her die.
--What?!
I need to determine her
precise deadline on this world line.
And then I'll time leap again.
There's no other way.
So the next D-mail to undo is the
one by this "Kiryu Moeka" person?
Yeah. I even know what it said.
She kept her past self
from switching cell phones.
We'll need to send a message
from her phone this time.
You go look for her!
I'll go with Mayuri to Comima!
Are you...?!
If we're lucky, maybe Mayuri won't--
Maybe I can keep it from happening!
Do you know what you're saying?!
If I don't find Moeka, then it'll mean--!
I'll contact you immediately!
Also, you can talk to me
about anything, you know.
If you need help, for
anything at all, I'm there for you.
Yeah... You always have been.
Never forget.
Whatever world line
you're on, you aren't alone.
I'm there for you!
"At Ariake now.
Huge crowd here, worse than I imagined.
Save me..."
"No reply from Moeka,
but I found where she works.
I'll check with them."
"Roger. Don't do anything crazy."
Kiryu Moeka?
Ah, I think I remember her.
She worked for a couple days and then quit.
Her address?
I have it... but who exactly are you?
Understood.
Excuse me...!
Kiryu Moeka... committed suicide?
--You're certain of it?
--Yeah.
--When did it happen?!
--Last night.
They took her body to Third Chiyoda Hospital.
We were at a real loss, though.
--This can't be...
--Couldn't find any relatives to contact.
Hey, are you okay?
Suicide?
Why?
Did one of her partners kill her?
Before killing Mayuri?
But...
It doesn't matter why!
Mayuri's still gonna be...!
A time leap!
If I time leap to before Moeka dies...!
--Hello?
--O-Okabe...!
Sh-She's dead... Mayuri's...
Mayuri's...
--The deadline is 7:52 pm...
--Mayuri!
I'm sorry.
Huh?!
Okabe! Did you eat this?!
Look right here! It clearly
has "Makise" written on it!
Hey! Are you listening to me?!
Never forget. You aren't alone.
Yes. You're right, Kurisu.
Huh?! Wh-What did you just say?
Do you know a girl named Kiryu Moeka?
Huh? Who?
I just did a time leap.
What do you mean?
FB...
FB... FB...
Answer me...
Please...
FB...
Why won't you message me?
Please... Reply to me...!
FB...
Kiryu Moeka...
--I did everything you asked me to do...
--It's me, Okabe!
Give me orders, FB!
Can't you hear me?! Hey!
FB... FB...
FB...
N-No! No!
No! No...!
I'll never forgive her!
Never...!
Give it back...
Give it back! Give it back!
Give it back!
--It's me! You have her phone?!
--Just stole it! Get the D-mail set to go!
It's ready!
--What's that sound?
--Never mind that! Where's Mayuri?!
The CRT Workshop. The 42-inch TV's on!
All right!
Kurisu!
Activate it!
Right!
Give it back! Give it back!
This is the last one.
Once I send this...
...Mayuri will be...!
Give it back! Give it back!
Give back my phone!
--Huh? Nothing's happened!
--Give it back!
--What's going on?!
--Did you send it?!
Yes! Did you activate it right?!
The discharge took place! What's happened?!
My Reading Steiner hasn't kicked in!
Huh?!
My Reading Steiner hasn't activated...
How can this be?
--Give it back! Give it back!
--Geez, what are you doing in there?
Give it back! Give it back! Give it back!
It's not working!
A D-mail's effects greatly depend
on the person who receives it!
Could it be that your message
wasn't enough to change her actions?!
What do we do, then?!
It didn't change!
She didn't change her cell phone!
What do you mean?! Are you sure?!
"I got a new phone four days ago,
but I wanna tell myself not to buy it."
She must've sent a different
message at the last second!
What! So we don't
know what her D-mail said?!
There should be a record of it in here!
I'll check--
Give it back! Give it back!
--What's going on?! Okabe! Okabe!
--Give it back!
I'll call you back!
Give it back! Give it back!
Give it back!
Come on! What are you doing in there?!
Give it back...
Okabe!
Give it back! Give it back!
Sheesh! What is going on in there?
Hey, you...
Sheesh, couples these days can be so scary...
What can I do...
What can I do... to make you give it back?
Do you remember sending a D-mail?
A D-what...?
You should've received a
strange e-mail two weeks ago.
From your future self.
How do you...?
Tell me what it said!
And then you can have it back!
What's the matter?! Can't tell me?!
Was it about the IBN 5100... or the Rounders?!
Oh, am I right?!
Tell me! What did the message say?!
Don't you want your phone back?!
--I can't betray--
--Betray who?!
This "FB" of yours?
My orders come from FB.
FB is everything to me...
So this person's calling the shots?!
You can't betray FB? How nice and loyal of you.
But this FB of yours doesn't
seem to give a damn about you!
FB has abandoned you for good!
That's not true...!
You've lost all contact, right?!
You've been betrayed!
--You've been tossed aside!
--You're wrong!
FB isn't like that!
FB saved me...
No, you were used!
Do you know how I know that?!
FB is like a mother to me...
"What sort of work would I have to do?"
I have a type of time machine.
The e-mail from the future is proof!
"Even work I could do?"
FB... made me feel needed...
"I've never had a job before.
I don't have any skills, either."
I've seen what happens!
You...
In four days, you commit
suicide in this very room.
You keep waiting to hear from FB...
...until you die all alone in this room!
--You're lying.
--It's the truth!
You'll never hear from FB again!
You've been abandoned!
You're lying...
When's the last time FB responded?! Huh?!
You've been waiting all this time,
haven't you?! Odd, don't you think?!
You're going to die here!
No...
In this dark, empty room...
...you, Mayuri's killer...
...all alone, abandoned, and
betrayed, like a piece of garbage...
--No...
--...end your life!
No one comes to help you!
Not even FB!
No!
I'm sorry...
You said FB's like a mother.
Is FB a woman?
I think so.
You "think"?
We've never met...
I never want to...
I'm sure she'd hate me if we did...
Sounds like you've never
even talked on the phone.
How could you take orders
from someone like that?!
She gave me a place where I belong...
A place where you belong?
You're a fool!
Okabe?!
Don't worry me like that!
You... were worried about me?
N-No!
I'm sorry.
So?
So the IBN 5100 was stolen by...
By Moeka.
Where is it now?!
That's all I've got.
We'll undo the D-mail as planned.
Got it. Approximately 11:00 am on July 31st.
It's activated!
This should do it...
Why?!
--Well?!
--It didn't work!
Did the Kiryu Moeka in the
past not believe the D-mail?
Maybe she believed the
first one, just to be safe?!
Let's send another, different message!
No...
I think there's only
one person she'll listen to.
If we can send a message from her
phone, Moeka will obey without question!
Huh? Who are you talking about?
I'm going to look for FB.
Any idea where she might be?
I guess you wouldn't tell me anyway.
Earlier... You said I killed someone...
Is that in the future?
Yeah. You'd kill if FB ordered you to, right?
I would.
Even if you knew you were being used?!
That's how you die!
Over-dependent and abandoned!
In four days, on August 15!
The world has set your death
in stone! There's no escaping it!
But I refuse to accept that!
I'm going to fight the world!
I will save Mayuri!
The coin locker...
In front of the Dai Building...
The IBN 5100...
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now