That's how you die!
Over-dependent and abandoned!
In four days, on August 15!
The world has set your death
in stone! There's no escaping it!
But I refuse to accept that!
I'm going to fight the world!
I will save Mayuri!
The coin locker...
In front of the Dai Building...
The IBN 5100...
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
Okabe! What's going on?!
Okay! This should do it!
Stop!
The IBN 5100's in a coin locker?
Moeka confessed!
And it hasn't been picked up yet!
So...?
Isn't it obvious?!
--I'm gonna bust into it and--
--Calm down and try to remember.
Remember what?!
Everything so far.
Even after all the D-mails you've undone,
the IBN 5100 has still eluded you.
I think it might only be possible if
you return to the original world line.
And the only way to do
that is to do things in order.
Just when it's within arm's reach...
At least we have a lead now.
Kiryu Moeka will do
anything this FB person says,
since FB's in charge of the Rounders, right?
In which case...
Maybe I'll find FB if
I stake out the IBN 5100...!
What do you want?
I... want to meet FB too...
I thought you didn't want to?
That she'd hate you if she met you...
I want to know the truth...
Why?
I don't know.
Did you really think I'd cooperate with you?
Well, since there's no
talking sense into you anyway...
Huh?!
What's wrong?
N-Nothing.
Kiryu Moeka is with you?!
How did that happen?!
Seriously, she's--
That's just how it turned out.
I'll let you know if anything happens.
Hey! Wait!
Urgh...
Okarin?
Huh? Yeah.
What's the matter?
It's just...
It feels like Okarin and I haven't
talked at all in a long time.
Oh, Big Sis Mayuri!
Nae-chan!
Too-too-roo!
Too-too-roo to you too, assistant girl!
Call me "Big Sis Kurisu."
Hey, there.
Hello. Sorry about yesterday...
Tell Okabe I'm upping his rent 5,000 yen.
O-Okay.
Come to think of it,
I haven't seen that bum all day.
He sick or something?
They say idiots don't catch colds, though...
Oh, I think he's out looking
for stuff for his experiments...
Experiments, huh?
Man, what a happy-go-lucky guy.
Huh?
A student with a room all his own,
has friends like you guys,
and does whatever he wants...
Doesn't get much better than that.
But I'll tell you this...
We hafta hurry, Dad!
The sale's about to end!
Okay! Let's go, Nae!
Yeah!
Bye-bye, big sisters!
Bye-bye!
What should we have for dinner?
Hmm, lemme think...
Old messages from FB?
Can I see?
"I think you made the right decision, M4.
To be honest, no one has worked
as hard and intently as you, M4."
"M4"...?
The code name FB gave me.
Only FB and I know it.
It's a secret.
"Maybe you do have a hard
time dealing with other people, M4.
But I think that's part of what makes
you unique. Wouldn't you agree?"
Sounds like a mom, all right...
That's definitely it.
The IBN 5100...
Then is he FB?
No.
FB is a woman.
He's...!
Damn!
What's wrong?
I'll explain later.
Mr. Braun...
--Say, how long since you last drove?
--Since I got my license.
Let's take it nice and easy, then.
Do you recognize that man?
I've never seen him before.
What does this mean?
In four days, on August 15!
The world has set your death in stone!
There's no escaping it!
A plane headed to France...
That's where SERN is.
We didn't see any women
who could've been FB.
You can at least call!
I've had my hands full.
I personally don't care.
It's just...
It's Mayuri who's...
Now that you mention it, I feel like
I haven't talked to her in a long time.
She said the same thing.
I'm sorry.
--Let's go.
--Huh?
Our only option is to confront him directly.
Confront who?
Someone we know very well.
Oh! What brings you
here so early in the morning?
Well, come in.
So, what do you want?
Come to pay the extra
6,000 yen on your rent, huh?
Hey, this is the part where
you're supposed to butt in and say,
"That's 1,000 yen more than you said!"
I would like to ask you something.
Geez, why so formal?
You know about someone
named "FB," do you not?
We've seen everything.
Including the IBN 5100
being hauled away from here.
We mean you no harm.
We simply wish to meet with FB.
Please, tell us. Where can we find her?
Looks like you're a traitor, M4.
FB gave me that code name...
It's a secret name only FB and I know...
--Are you saying...?!
--How can that be?!
Ever heard of Ferdinand Braun?
The Nobel Prize physicist
who invented the CRT?
Impressive.
And what are his initials?
"F.B."...
So you're...?!
No... That's not possible...
First, overdependence, and now escapism?
Nae is asleep. Let's go elsewhere.
This damn city just keeps changin'.
Are you really FB?
Yeah.
But the e-mails...!
I wrote 'em all.
Why did I write like a woman?
To fool you, of course.
--That can't be--
--It ain't just you.
I do it with the others, too.
I send them e-mails pretending
to be whoever they most need.
It helps that people like
you are also the easiest to trick.
Why'd you cut off contact with her?
She outlived her usefulness the
moment she found the IBN 5100.
So I got rid of her.
We gather members using text messages.
People like that are easiest to deal with...
...and easiest to get rid of
once they're no longer useful.
They have nowhere they belong, after all.
I can't believe you're a SERN lapdog...
A dog?
Suzuha didn't...
Hashida Suzu-san didn't take care of you
so you could go and do this!
How do you know Suzu-san?
This has nothing to do with her.
This has nothing to do with Suzu-san!
--But...!
--What would you know?!
You ever slept in a manhole
in the middle of winter?
I was still just a kid...
The concrete was freezing.
Bone-chillingly cold.
I wouldn't eat for
three or four days at a time.
And whenever I'd lie down, they would come...
Huh?
The rats.
They'd gnaw at me,
mistaking me for a corpse.
That's when I saw a thread dangling down.
A spider's thread...
I had to climb up it, y'know?
Even if following it meant
getting my hands dirty.
So I climbed the thread...
And before I knew it,
I was a puppet on strings.
There's no escape.
Once a puppet breaks loose from its strings...
"Traitors get death," as they say.
Well, they off you after you've
served your purpose, anyway.
You called me a dog earlier.
We ain't dogs.
We're livestock.
I thought about escaping before.
But now I have something precious to me.
I didn't wanna drag her into this.
But... failure isn't allowed.
Try to run, and they'll
go after your family too.
I've failed, too.
But Nae doesn't know a thing.
If I just die...
Wait--!
O-Okabe... kun...
Okabe-kun...
S-Sorry...
I'm... sorry...
O-Okabe! His phone!
The D-mail!
Okabe!
Moeka...?
You don't need it...?
Hello, this is Urushibara!
Oh, Kyouma-s--
Huh? An IBN 5100?
Actually, we do!
This is it...!
Daru!
Hashida's not here.
He said he's going to Comima, remember?
I beg you!
Hear my request!
I see.
The only way to prevent Mayuri's
death is to leave this alpha world line
and return to the world line that
exists before you send your first D-mail...
The beta world line, in other words.
And the only way to do that
is to delete that data
from SERN's database.
All this stuff about Mayushii dying
and Miss Amane being my future daughter...
If this is all just in your head, you
could totally be a light novel author!
Nothing would make me happier.
Do you believe it, Miss Makise?
As a hypothesis, at least.
I'd love some actual, objective data,
but that's obviously impossible.
The time leap machine
you built worked perfectly.
Huh? R-Really?
I mean, o-of course it did!
Not to mention...
What?
--Never mind.
--Wh-What?!
I said never mind.
All hooked up!
I gotta config some stuff, but
we'll be good to go in 10 minutes.
We're counting on you, Super hax0r!
"Super hacker"!
The first D-mail, huh?
That's the one where you said
I got stabbed or whatever, wasn't it?
I bet you tried to feel me up, huh?
Undoing all our D-mails will
return us to the original world line.
A world line where SERN's
dystopia never occurs...
A world line where Mayuri lives...
And a world line where...
...Makise Kurisu...
...dies.
kisei sareta shikai mujihi naru
juuni no shihai nogarerarenai
ansoku no asu o negatta
te no naka no toutoi jishou no chihei e
torawareshi meiyaku
arawareta gishou no rinkaku
seimei no tenchi wa
moumoku na jikan o kizanda
habatake batafurai kiseki
no batafurai anata e sasagu
namida no batafurai
mabushii batafurai subete ga
ima kakikaerareru