If we return to the beta world line...
...Makise Kurisu...
...will die.
--I'm gonna run the hack now.
--Wait!
The hacking...
...is canceled.
For you, billions and billions of heartbeats
are nothing at all; just the blink of an eye
Although I'm trapped by
the past and lament the future
inevitability won't allow for
even a speck of a miscalculation
Our dreams and futures that
form and expand into "infinity"
allow us the right to be vain,
while the two hands
point out what is "finite"
All of which leads to a cruel
contract and choice to make
Hacking to the Gate
So, now, with each passing
second, I'll cross world lines
to protect that smile on your face
Then, once again, into a
time loop without sadness
I will be swallowed up as a lone observer
Where's Okabe?
Unknown! I've been busy!
--Well, good luck to you, Mayushii!
--And to you, Daru-kun!
Aye!
--Is today the last day of Comima?
--Yeah.
Do you want to come too?
There'll be lots of girls doing cute cosplays!
I-I'm not interested in that sort of thing...
I wonder what Okarin's up to.
Beats me. He called off
the hack and then just left...
Who knows what he's thinking...
It's supposed to get up to 35ยบ Celsius today!
It's important to keep
hydrated or you'll get heat stroke!
Aren't you going to Comima today?
Yeah. I'm just about to leave.
I see. Be careful.
Right!
The sun's really strong today.
See you later! Too-too-roo!
Mayuri...!
August 17th...
Each D-mail I've undone has
pushed Mayuri's death one day back.
It started out on the 13th
and moved to the 14th when
Suzuha's message was undone.
Faris... Rukako... Moeka...
If each one has delayed it by a day,
then Mayuri will die on
the 17th on this world line.
Today, just before 8:00 pm.
That's the deadline...
Okarin!
Find what you were looking for?
Yeah! They were almost sold out, too!
I even snagged some for Daru-kun!
Oh, I also saw a book about
robot anime I bet you'd like!
Want to see?
No, that's okay.
Why not? You're here and all...
I just... have some things on my mind.
Oh.
If there's anywhere you
wanna see, just let me know!
Yeah.
Are you okay?
Do you want to leave?
D-Don't be silly!
I just meant I'm concerned
about the Organization
assassins lurking at this venue.
We must outfox them somehow.
They might spot us if we aren't careful.
We will proceed as planned until evening falls.
I don't think there's anyone that bad here.
I'm going scouting.
Reconvene here at 1500 hours. Understood?
Okay!
Okarin! They're selling drinks and
stuff over there, just so you know!
Five hours left...
Don't give up.
You have to find it before then...
A way for Mayuri to survive
without changing world lines.
Huh?! Why do I have to help Hashida--?!
A notebook listing all the clubs there?
I don't see anything like that.
The bookshelf?
The second shelf has--
Huh? Stay away from the second shelf?
Oh...
I'm seriously going to sue.
--What?
--It's me.
What's going on with the hacking?
You called it off, so it's been
at a standstill for three days now.
It's time you start explaining.
What exactly happened?
Mayuri... dies today.
You already told me.
That's why we're doing
the hacking, remember?
--Once we delete the first D-mail you--
--No!
No hacking.
I need to come up with a way
to save Mayuri without hacking.
Why?
Because something new has come up.
Like what?
I can't explain right now.
There has to be a way. Some other way...
What do you mean?
Please!
Explain to me.
I can't help you fix things
if you leave me in the dark.
It's soon, right? This is no time
to hide things from me, Okabe!
We're finally back!
Say, want to stop by the lab, Okarin?
Mayushii was thinking
of getting something to eat!
Are you all tired out, Okarin?
No...
It's almost time...
It's almost time for Mayuri to die again...
Should we run?
No, it'll still end like always...
Okarin?
Let's go.
Say, Okarin.
Why did you come with me today?
You hardly looked around at anything.
I could've shown you around more if
there was anything you wanted to see!
Mayushii usually doesn't
know more than you, you know?
Okarin...
Thanks for today!
This was our first time
going to Comima together!
Mayushii was glad!
Mayuri...
I had hoped to see Rukako acting
embarrassed in a cosplay outfit!
It's a shame he didn't come!
Yeah! I'm sure he would've been really popular!
Definitely!
Then his pictures would get
posted on blogs everywhere
and he'd become a worldwide superstar!
And then Mayushii would see
that and think, "He's come so far!"
That almost sounds possible.
I think I'd love it even more
if you cosplay next, Okarin!
I'll think about it.
Really?
But only if you cosplay too, Mayuri.
Huh?
I know, let's invite Rukako and Christina.
And then you can
convince them to cosplay too.
Only then will I, the mad
scientist Hououin Kyouma,
descend upon Comima as its star attraction!
Oh, we have a tough road ahead of us!
But Kurisu-chan was interested!
Mayushii will try hard to convince
them before the next Comima!
The next--
Huh?
Mayushii's watch has stopped...
That's strange. I wound it up--
Okarin?!
No! No more!
I've come so far! Why does it still...?!
Okarin?!
Just stay right here!
Okarin!
I will change it!
I'll change fate myself!
If I...
If I get run over here...!
If I let myself die...!
Something will have to change!
It'll have to!
Okarin!
Mayuri?!
Mayuri!
Oka... rin...
I was finally... finally helpful...
Mayuri...
Mayushii...
...was finally...
...helpful to you...
...Oka... rin...
Hey, Mayuri...
You can hardly see any stars from here...
This just isn't fair...
I'm gonna run the hack now.
Okabe?
Okabe...?
How long are you gonna stay up here?
I told you I want to be alone.
You did.
But you've been on the roof
for hours, completely silent.
Of course I'd be worried-- I mean, I wouldn't.
Tell me. Why did you call off the hack?
You yourself said we shouldn't.
You're afraid the fuzz'll
get you, huh? That must be it!
Call it the awakening of a law-abiding citizen.
This isn't like you.
Where did your usual self-righteous attitude go?
--What kind of a mad scientist--
--This is no time for self-righteousness!
A mad scientist? Hououin Kyouma?!
That's all just nonsense! Make-believe!
Haven't you realized that?!
I knew from the moment I met you.
Don't tell me you've
done another time leap?!
What happened?
I've helped you so much already.
Don't hold back now.
Putting our heads together
is what's gotten you this far.
This far...
Suzuha, Faris, Rukako...
Sacrificing all their hopes and
dreams has finally led me here...
And this is how it ends?
What do you mean?
Why...?
Okabe!
Listen, Okabe...
You were crying back there.
You had Hashida worried too.
He thought maybe you had
a bad dream or something.
Tell me.
I want to help you!
On July 28th...
Mayuri and I went to Dr. Nakabachi's conference.
It was there...
It was there I found Makise Kurisu
on the ground, stabbed by someone.
I sent a message to Daru's phone, which
was connected to the Phone Microwave.
The very first D-mail...
It's what moved us from the beta
world line to this alpha world line...
Deleting that message
from SERN's database
and returning to the beta world line...
...means returning to that world.
If we return to the beta world line...
If we undo that D-mail...
...you'll die.
Answer it.
Answer it...
Mayuri?
Yeah.
What's up?
Well, Daru-kun said you
were acting strange, so...
Nothing's wrong. He was mistaken.
But...
I'm sorry.
Mayushii was so caught up in Comima
she didn't pay any attention to you.
Remember how you used
to tell me all sorts of things?
Like, let's see, the
Organization has four leaders...
Geppu, Sudachi, Seiyuu, and Jakko?
Genbu, Suzaku, Seiryuu, and Byakko.
Yeah, that's it.
All that stuff you'd tell me was really neat!
Anyway, tell me if I ever
feel like a burden to you, okay?
Well, I'm gonna go for now!
If there's anything you want
to talk about, just call, okay?
Mayuri! Wait!
You should go right now.
I could guess what she was
saying from the tone of your voice.
You should go to her right now.
Sitting here talking about me
won't solve anything right now.
That's why you were
up here all alone, right?
So you should go see Mayuri.
Having you sit here and worry
about me will only hurt my pride.
I'm going now.
This is Mayushii!
I can't come to the phone right now.
It's me.
Yeah, some cosplayer
said she left a while ago.
I see.
I'm sorry.
You came to see me for
Obon, didn't you, Granny?
Actually, I've been having
these scary dreams lately.
Something terrible always
happens to Mayushii in them.
Like getting shot by pistols,
getting into car accidents,
and getting hit by trains...
It all feels so real and
scary and painful and sad...
I try really hard to
shout for help, but I can't...
I wonder why I have these dreams.
And then, at the end of them,
Okarin always comes to save me.
Mayushii tries to thank him,
but he can't hear her.
He holds Mayushii tight
and looks really sad.
He never cries, but I can tell
he's fighting hard to hold back.
So Mayushii tries to say she's
sorry, but he can't hear her...
And then I wake up.
Sorry, I'll talk about something nice now!
We've gained a lot of lab members lately!
There's Kurisu-chan, Moeka-san,
Ruka-kun, Faris-chan, and Suzu-san.
I remember when we started
out with only two members!
Kurisu-chan is really smart
and talks about tons of
complicated stuff with Okarin.
It's so nice and lively!
And Okarin seems happy,
being able to talk so much.
But, you know, sometimes I think back...
...to when Mayushii first visited the lab.
It was snowing, even
though it was early spring...
I went to the lab after school,
but Okarin wasn't there.
And then, while I was
tidying up the place, he arrived.
I said, "Welcome back!"
but he didn't say, "I'm back!"
Instead, he replied with, "Good work!"
After that, I spent about
two hours there every day,
even though we barely ever talked.
But it wasn't a bad silence.
We were just "there."
Slowly and gently, time would pass...
Mayushii almost felt like she was a hostage!
Did something good happen?
Mm-hmm!
Yes... but no!
Oh? Sounds like you were hallucinating then.
It could be the work of the Illusion
Conductor, a top Organization leader.
Really?! Then I better be careful!
--But I don't think this Illusion Condor--
--Conductor.
Oh, right.
I don't think he's actually a bad guy!
Okarin and I don't talk as much anymore.
I used to be able to tell what he was
thinking just from seeing his face...
But lately I can't tell at all.
All I can tell is that he's in pain...
That he's suffering...
He always looks ready to cry...
And I know it's because of Mayushii...
I don't mean to be a burden to him, though.
I'm sorry! I started
talking about sad stuff again!
I guess maybe Mayushii's feeling lonely.
Granny...
I can't stay like this forever, can I?
You can.
O--
Okarin!
How did you know where to find me?
I always know where my hostage is.
You will never escape my clutches.
Never.
Don't push yourself too hard, okay?
Hououin Kyouma is not so weak
that he needs you to worry about him.
I'll tell you everything...
...when the time comes.
Okay.
--Let's go.
--Oh, but first--!
I know.
You want to get another Oopa, don't you?
With my vision restricted, there's no escape
from the merciless control of the twelve
Wishing for a tomorrow of repose,
I embark for the horizon of the
sacred phenomenon in my hand
Trapped by the covenant and
shown the outline of false evidence
the heaven and earth of
life lets time blindly flow by
Flutter, butterfly, oh, miraculous
butterfly! I give myself to you
Oh, butterfly of tears,
dazzling butterfly! It's all...
...about to be rewritten now