If we return to the beta world line...
If we undo that D-mail...
...you'll die.
suu juuoku mono kodou no kazu sae
anata ni wa matataki teido no saji na toukyuu
kako ni torawarete mirai o nageku mo
chiri hitotsu gosan o yurusanu hitsuzen
mugen ni hirogaru yume mo egaku mirai mo
bokutachi ni yurusareta kyoei no kenri
yuugen sore wa futatsu no hari ga shimesu
zankoku na yakujou to sentaku e
Hacking to the Gate
da kara ima ichi byou
goto ni sekaisen o koete
kimi no sono egao mamoritai no sa
soshite mata kanashimi
no nai jikan no ruupu e to
nomi komarete yuku kodoku no kansokusha
There you are.
You'll get heat stroke if you stay up here.
So? You're always lying on the roof of the lab.
Besides, it's cloudy out.
Did you find Mayuri?
Hashida didn't see her at Comima.
Yeah. I saw her afterward.
I see.
Say, Okabe...
Yeah?
All right.
Hey.
It's raining.
W-WTF!
You could've said something sooner.
Even my underwear's soaked. Sheesh...
I did tell you.
It's your fault for not paying attent--
You pervert!
I didn't mean to look!
You're the one who chose
to wear such thin clothing--
I'd forgotten that you're a pervert!
Do you honestly think your
scrawny, naked body is that--
Say any more and I'll turn your
cerebral neocortex into pickle juice!
--What kind of threat is that?
--Get away from me!
What's that?
Oh.
Must've torn it somewhere
while looking for you...
What a klutz!
M-My class is a "mad scientist"--
Uh-huh. You're nothing
but trouble, you know that?
Give it here.
I happen to have a sewing
kit with me. I'll fix it for you.
A sewing kit?
Believe it or not, I'm decent at home-ec stuff.
Now take it off.
Just as a heads-up, it's dark in
here, so don't expect too much.
And you'll have to wait until we're
outside to see what color the thread is.
Black, red, or pink...
Each has a one-out-of-three chance.
I'll just pray I don't get pink.
Hey--! Stay away.
Don't worry. I've no interest
in seeing your scrawny, naked--
I told you. Pickle juice.
Sheesh...
Where did you even get a rip like this anyway?
Well, today I went to the lab...
The laundry...
For a walk...
And then the hotel you're staying at.
You went to the hotel?
Don't blame me.
You wouldn't reply to my
messages or answer my calls.
Wait, were you actually worried--?
It's my job as the head of the
lab to look after my assistant.
--Aren't you done yet?
--Hold on.
Catch!
Brr! Hey...!
Just put it on.
I've no interest in seeing a mad
scientist's scrawny, naked body, after all!
I bet it was right around here, huh?
The place where I was stabbed...
How do you know that...?
Just as I thought.
The pain and desperation
felt too real to be just a dream...
Kurisu... Don't tell me you...!
Yeah. I have hazy memories inside me, too.
Faint memories... Almost like illusions...
Not just of being stabbed.
I have faint memories of you, too.
You're desperate to save Mayuri...
You keep pushing
forward, all alone and hurt.
You're never able to re-right the world...
Yet you desperately fight.
You desperately call out Mayuri's name...
And cry.
I see you struggling so hard to save her.
Every time I see that look on your face...
I realize how irreplaceable Mayuri is to you.
I realize it's possible for someone
to care about someone else so much...
It made me want to work with you...
It made me want to help you.
Listen, Okabe.
Save Mayuri.
You have to save her.
What about you?
If I go to the beta world line...
...you'll die!
But... it's the only option.
You know that more than anyone.
There's only one choice.
You want--
You want me to just abandon you?
What other way is there?
I've gone over it since yesterday.
I thought I could find some way
around it, some sort of solution,
just like all those other times...
But it's no use.
This time there really is no other option.
The only way is to go the beta world line.
Okabe!
I refuse to accept this...
I refuse to give up!
There's no way I can just abandon Kurisu.
I can't just let her die and then move on...
What would the point be in that?!
I...
Running will...
Running will only make it worse!
Shut up!
Time-leaping won't get you over
the 1% barrier, however hard you try!
We don't know that for sure!
You'll only end up watching Mayuri die!
Again and again...
It'll break you!
It won't.
Do you know how many times
I've seen Mayuri die already?
I've seen it again and again...
And again, and again, and again...
...and again, and again...
It won't break me now!
It doesn't matter how many times--
Do you know what you're saying?
Mayuri is going to keep suffering and dying!
You can't be okay with that!
If that doesn't affect you...
...then your heart is already broken.
Stop this. It really will destroy you...
I know.
I've realized it for a while.
I stopped being shocked as
Mayuri kept dying and dying.
At some point, my heart grew numb to it.
Sometimes I even waited to time leap
just to find out her precise time of death.
At some point, I stopped
being affected by her deaths...
Some part of me would
casually say I could just redo things...
Save Mayuri...
Otherwise it really will break you.
If you let Mayuri die, you will regret it!
The wish to save her is what's
brought the two of us this far!
If you give up now, you'll
regret it for the rest of your life.
But if I save Mayuri, you'll--!
I'll just go back!
To the initial world line
where the D-mail was never sent!
It's what's best for me... and for you!
We've fought so many
times over these twenty days...
We've said nasty things to each other.
We've shared our problems.
Whenever I was a in a bind,
I turned to Kurisu for help.
It was Kurisu who quietly
listened to me and believed me...
A girl prodigy who published
a scientific paper at 18.
Always calm, always headstrong...
Always full of pride and nosy...
So indulgent that she's diligent...
Her theories always mesmerized me.
I remembered every word she said...
And watched every move she made...
She's not just a fellow lab member.
To me, Makise Kurisu is...
I...
...can't save you...
I'm sorry...
Thank you...
For suffering so much for me...
Why you?
Why'd it have to be you?
Say, what does it mean to
change world lines anyway?
Who knows, maybe you'll
completely cease to exist in this world line
the moment you go to the beta world line...
Or maybe you'll switch
places with a different Okabe.
It doesn't matter.
That's not true.
I won't have died.
Even if I'm dead in the beta world line,
there's no guarantee I'll die here!
Maybe there are doubles of
me on countless world lines.
Maybe all their minds are
connected, forming a single "me."
That sounds wonderful, don't you think?
Being in all times and in all places.
A strong love for someone...
A strong belief in something...
A strong wish to convey something...
If all those things go
beyond time to create "you"...
...then that would be magnificent.
So don't think of it as "letting me die."
Even if the world line changes,
as long as you don't forget me,
I'll always be there.
So...
I'll never forget you.
I could never forget the
person I care about the most.
Is that...?
It's the truth.
Wh-What...?! This is so sudden!
I love you.
What about you?
Wh-What do you mean?!
I want to know.
How do you feel about me?
You really want to know?
Yeah.
Your face...
Close your eyes.
What for?
Just close them!
I-I didn't do that because
I want to, just so you know.
It's just...
Intense experiences accompanying
certain actions--such as your first kiss--
are stored in the hippocampus
and thus harder to forget.
--So I thought--
--Too bad.
That wasn't my first kiss.
--You stuck-up virgin!
--Shut up, untouched maiden.
My first kiss wasn't romantic at all, though.
Still, this one wasn't enough to be memorable.
Let's do it over.
I don't want to forget. I need to be extra-sure.
Okay?
I-I guess so.
Just a kiss, though.
Time is passing by so quickly...
I almost want to complain to Einstein right now.
You know, Okabe...
Time speeds up or slows down
depending on a person's perception.
The theory of relativity...
It's so romantic...
...and so sad.
Well, this is it.
Are you sure about Mayuri and Daru?
Having everyone see me
off would only hurt more.
If it's just you, I can leave Japan
without any hesitation whatsoever.
I'm joking.
A gift for you. Take it.
I don't want this...
It's been upgraded to Version 2.67.
How annoying.
But I'll accept it anyway.
Well...
--Kurisu--
--Oh, yeah.
A gift in return!
What were you aiming for?!
Just go get it.
Yeesh...
Okabe...
I'm sure that, from now on,
you're going to suffer.
You'll be in a world where no
one but you remembers me...
You care about your friends
more than anything else...
...so I think it'll be painful for you.
I'm sorry.
But that pain will mean a lot to me.
Whenever you're sitting around in the lab...
Whenever you sip a drink...
Whenever you walk around town...
Whenever you kiss someone someday...
It doesn't have to be every time.
One time out of a hundred is fine.
All I ask is that you remember me...
Because I'll be there...
I'll always be there, beyond the 1% barrier.
Okabe...
Whoa! I found it, Okarin!
I totally found it! This is it, right?!
If we delete this...
Mission complete?
Are you okay, Okarin?
I'm fine.
The final phase of Operation
Verdandi will now commence!
Our victory has come!
After fending off the
many plots against us and...
...and holding true to our convictions...
...we have, at long last,
prevailed in the battle of Ragnarok!
I am grateful to my friends who
fought to make this victory a reality!
I am grateful for all the
sacrifices that had to be made...!
What awaits now is the world I sought...
A world entirely chosen by Steins Gate!
The world will now...
...be reconstructed!
Kurisu...
I'm sorry...
Okabe!
Okabe... I feel...
Kurisu!
I feel the same! I love--
Mayuri...
Who's Lab Member 004?
004?
We don't have a 004.
The battle of Ragnarok is now over!
I, the mad scientist Hououin Kyouma,
faced with assaults mounted
by the Organization and SERN,
have achieved complete victory by
manipulating time and space itself!
The world's power
structure has been reset,
and a future of chaos awaits!
This is the choice of Steins Gate!
Okarin. It's okay now.
What? I just delivered
a grand victory speech...!
You don't have to talk that way anymore.
Mayushii's okay now.
So now you can cry for yourself, Okarin.
We don't need the
Phone Microwave anymore.
It was because of this
machine that I met Kurisu.
But it was because of this machine
that so many people were hurt.
Just as Hououin Kyouma has died...
...so, too, must the Phone Microwave.
Life isn't about doing things over.
This is for the best.
Right, Kurisu?
Hello?
Huh? Wh-Who's this?
"Dad"?
What's that? Okarin?
Okarin! Some mystery girl wants to talk to you!
Who's this?
Please! Come to the roof of
the Radio Building right away!
Huh? Who are you?
I'm from the year 2036!
I'm Hashida Itaru's
daughter, Amane Suzuha!
Suzuha...?
Hold on! What are you doing here?!
Please! Believe what I have to say!
You have to stop World War III!