World War III...
It results in 5.7 billion deaths
worldwide by the year 2036.
This is what starts it all.
This does? What is it?
Looks like a robot to me.
I bet it even transforms and stuff!
It's a time machine.
--Huh?!
--For real?
Impressive, Uncle.
You already know what it is.
That simplifies things, then.
You have to come with me.
I refuse.
Okarin?
I came here from the alpha world line.
I've altered the world line over
and over these past three weeks...
...and only made it to this beta
world line by sacrificing Kurisu.
I can't just let it all go to waste now!
Kurisu-san...?
Kurisu...
Oh, wasn't that the name of that scientist
who got stabbed at the
Radio Building a while back?
Okabe Rintaro...
What if I told you avoiding a world war
requires preventing Makise
Kurisu's death on July 28, 2010?
What do you mean?
I don't know the details.
I have only one mission:
to rescue Makise Kurisu
and go to the only world line
free of attractor field interference...
...Steins Gate!
For you, the assertion of
life and its meaningless proof
are so comical they don't
even help pass the boredom
Those of a foolish race,
acting as if they ruled over all,
presented a conceited, childish theorem
"Infinite" love and the far reaches of the sky
are part of a hypothetical
freedom we've been shown
"Finite" is the merciless march of time,
leading to a choice to deny even tomorrow
Hacking to the Gate
The countless brilliant days
and promises made to my friends...
I must not "undo" any of it
So I'll use what tricks I have left to deceive time,
as a lone observer who no longer has doubt
Steins Gate...
Your future self came up with this plan...
...along with Dad.
It's entirely conjecture.
It's possible that your theory is wrong
and there is no such thing
as a Steins Gate world line.
But I'm going anyway.
I'm going to bet on the unknown
chance that a bright future awaits.
And if you have it in
you to come with me...
...then take my hand.
Umm, Mayushii doesn't
understand anything you just said.
But if she--this Kurisu-san--is dear to you...
...then I think you should try.
This World War III stuff sounds
so much like your crazy delusions
that you're probably the
only one who can handle this.
I don't care about 5.7 billion
people in the future.
I just...
Thanks.
Climb in!
It can carry two people?
Of course! It's my dad's
greatest masterpiece, after all!
Okarin...
Leave your phone behind.
We can't risk interfering
with your phone in the past.
I'll be back.
Okay.
Good luck!
--So this is a time machine...
--Yeah.
It's in good, working condition.
I already stopped by 1975 and 2000.
It is starting to get low on fuel, though.
Huh? Wait, it can go forward in time too?!
Of course it can. It's a time machine.
I see. It must've been because
that was a different world line...
Sit down.
We're going to just before noon on July 28th.
I can't change our location,
so if we jump too far back
we risk causing a scene at the Radio
Building and altering Makise Kurisu's actions.
The G-forces are pretty
rough the first time, so be ready.
Okarin...
What are these?
They always appear.
They're like fragments of time.
Pretty, huh?
Let's go!
W-Wait.
My gastric juices are coming up...
Geez, you're a wimp.
Hurry up!
Try not to run into your other self.
It'll cause a major time paradox.
How long until she gets stabbed?
Twenty minutes, I'd say...
I'll go prep the time machine.
You protect her, Uncle.
Stop calling me that.
July 28th...
The day I found Kurisu on
the ground, soaked in blood...
Mayuri and I had come here to see
Dr. Nakabachi's press conference...
Then we heard something on the roof...
That's right. Mayuri goes to the
Oopa machine on the 7th floor now...
Oh no!
You called me here for this?
There aren't many in this series left...
--...but Mayushii's out of 100-yen coins.
--No other choice. I'll have to take
the far stairs back to the 8th floor.
--...but Mayushii's out of 100-yen coins.
--I'll have to take the far stairs back to the 8th floor.
It's a metal one! A Metal Oopa!
Is it rare?
Yeah! Really rare!
Should be safe now...
Oh, pardon me--
K-Kurisu...
Huh? How do you know my name?
She's... alive...
Have we met before?
Kurisu...
Are you even listening--
What's your problem?!
Answer my question!
I'm...
I'm here to...
Dr. Nakabachi's conference is
about to begin in the 8th floor hall.
Wait! Stop!
You'll find the basic structure of a time
machine on the materials I've passed out.
As such, I'll use this time to explain
the fundamental theory behind it.
Scientists around the...
It said in the plans that you'd
be able to identify Makise Kurisu.
Can you?
Yeah.
I should also mention it'd be
dangerous to take her outside.
Without knowing who
killed her or how she died,
we should assume her
death is an inevitability.
Just like with Mayuri...
Doctor!
Oh, is something the matter?
Don't give me that! Your time
machine theory is what's the matter!
Kerr black holes! World lines!
All you've done is rip off--
Soon, this is where Kurisu will be...
Will she really come?
Is it possible she gets stabbed
elsewhere but ends up here?!
Oh, I hadn't thought of that...!
Kurisu...
So this is where it happens...
What's that she's reading?
Time machines...?!
So that's why she's the
key to changing world lines...
Damn punk kid...
What do you want?
Umm, I'd like you to read this...
...Daddy.
"Daddy"?!
Dr. Nakabachi?!
You contacted me for
the first time in seven years
and invited me to your
press conference, remember?
That's what inspired me.
--Don't tell me it's her father who...?!
--I did some brainstorming...
...and realized a time machine
might actually be possible!
I wanted to get your opinion, Daddy.
If it's accepted, you can show everyone
in academia who kicked you out--
I was not kicked out!
I got fed up with them and cut off all ties!
I'm sorry...
It's not bad.
Really?!
I was thinking, if you're okay with it,
that we could publish it
under both of our names!
After all, you helped inspire--
Don't be stupid!
--Go home!
--Huh?
I will publish this paper myself.
What...?!
You're going to steal it, Daddy?!
I was sure you'd never stoop that low--
Be quiet!
How dare you call me a thief...!
How are you so smart?!
A daughter shouldn't be
smarter than her father!
If it weren't for you, I'd still
be a distinguished scientist!
If it weren't for you...!
You're that kid...!
So that's how it is...
The two of you conspired
to ruin my press conference.
Now I see.
So that's how it is...
Daddy!
I have to protect Kurisu!
I'll teach you...
...to insult me!
Bastard...!
Stop this, Daddy!
Please!
Don't you dare...
--...tell me what to do!
--Crap!
You don't know anything!
This feeling...
This humiliation...
This living hell...!
Daddy...
If it weren't for you...
Stop...
If it weren't for you...!
Stop!
Daddy!
Kurisu...
K-Kurisu...!
Fools!
This is a fitting end for you two!
I'm sorry...
...for dragging you into this...
Why...?
Because he's my father...
I just wanted him... to accept me...
Kurisu...
I'm scared...
I... don't want to die...
I don't want to die...
I don't... want to...
Kurisu...
Kurisu!
They're back already!
Okarin!
...killed her...
--Okarin... That blood...
--I killed her...
--It's okay. It isn't his.
I killed Kurisu... I killed Kurisu...
I killed Kurisu...
Okarin...
I know you're in pain,
Uncle, but you can't give up yet.
We have enough fuel
to go back one more--
Shut up!
It'd just end the same anyway!
The attractor field convergence
will always result in Kurisu's death...
Oh? It's Okarin's phone...
An e-mail?
Open it.
--But...
--Just do it.
"Turn on the news..."
The news?
Despite a fire in the cargo bay,
the airplane carrying Dr. Nakabachi
managed to land in Russia,
to which he recently defected.
Talk about a close call!
If this hadn't set off the metal detectors
my paper would've burned up!
--Oh! That's Mayushii's Metal Oopa!
--WTF?!
See! Mayushii's name is right there!
You're right! But what's it doing in Russia?
That paper is the start of it all...
Huh?
This pits the world's
superpowers in an intense race
to develop a time machine.
Because to control time is to control the world.
Ultimately, it leads to world war.
The lives of 5.7 billion people are at stake.
Save Makise Kurisu!
Change the world line!
I can't.
It's just like what happened with Mayuri.
However hard I try, it'll always end the same...
With Kurisu dying.
How can you say that?!
You've only failed once--!
Once?!
Don't be stupid.
Do you know how many times--how
many dozens of times--I failed?!
I know.
I know how insane this time loop is...
I know how cruel of a fate it has in store...
I knew...
I knew this would happen...
I'm tired...
I've had enough...
You aren't the type of person
to give up halfway through!
Mayushii knows that!
You never give up!
Even when Mayushii couldn't
say goodbye to her grandma,
you never stopped coming
to her grave every day!
That's what helped me say goodbye!
That's what helped Mayushii get better!
So... you can't give up.
You should've received
a video file on July 28th.
July 28th...
You should be able to view it
now that you've failed
once in saving Makise Kurisu.
What do you mean?!
I'm sorry for misleading you.
Failing once was part of the plan.
It was so you could see this.
Is this...?
Greetings...
...me from 15 years ago.
It's Okarin!
If you've opened this message,
then that means you've
failed to rescue Kurisu.
It must've been painful for you.
But that pain also gave me determination.
So I couldn't afford to undo it.
It helped paved the way, you could say.
Now we can move to the real focus of our plan.
The plan is this: save
Makise Kurisu and enter Steins Gate.
There are two conditions.
You must destroy the
paper on time machines
that Dr. Nakabachi takes to Russia.
You must also save Makise Kurisu.
If I could do that--!
The thing is, avoiding her
death and altering the past
is impossible due to
attractor field convergence.
Right?
I'll just say it. It is possible to save Kurisu.
You're just going about it the wrong way.
Now listen closely.
You must not alter established past events.
You must not undo what your first self saw.
Doing so would alter
the past. All would be lost.
Think back to your
experiences on the alpha world line.
It was only three short weeks,
but you should have memories of
the time you spent with Makise Kurisu.
Of the many sacrifices you
both made trying to save Mayuri.
All the time you spent
adrift in those world lines...
It mustn't go to waste.
You must not undo it.
It's because of that journey
across countless world lines
that you're there, hoping to save Kurisu.
It's why I've devoted everything
into developing a time machine.
You've only managed
to get as far as you have
because of our shared wish to save her.
So... trick yourself.
Save Kurisu, without
changing the fact that she died.
Convince your past self that
she's dead when she's really alive.
Do so, and the past won't change.
I see...
--What does he mean?
--Do you understand, Okarin?
I'm sure you understand.
Incidentally, the time machine is a Type C204.
I doubt I need to tell
you what the C stands for.
Christina...
I was also the one who named
the target world line "Steins Gate."
I'm sure you know the
reason for that name too.
It doesn't really mean anything.
Isn't that right?
I will now outline your
final mission: Operation Skuld.
You must change the outcome
without altering established past events.
Okabe Rintaro observes Makise
Kurisu on the ground, soaked in blood.
You must change the outcome
without altering that established event.
Deceive your original self.
Deceive the world.
That is the only way
you can reach Steins Gate.
Good luck.
El Psy Congroo.
What the heck?
Was that you 15 years from now?
He sounded so suave!
"Operation Skuld"?
"El Psy Congroo"?
I still act like that when I'm 33?!
It's like I've gone full-on delusional!
Okarin...
I'll do it...
If that's the choice of Steins Gate!
I am the mad scientist... Hououin Kyouma!
Fooling the world is nothing to me!
Whoa. He's back to his old self again.
Mayushii likes this Okarin better, though!
I'll say it again!
I am the mad scientist...
...Hououin Kyouma!
The world is in the palm of my hand!