I will now outline your
final mission: Operation Skuld.
You must change the outcome
without altering established past events.
Okabe Rintaro observes Makise
Kurisu on the ground, soaked in blood.
You must change the outcome
without altering that established event.
Hand me that screwdriver, Dad.
--Why do you keep calling me that?
--Just hurry up.
Looks like this is it.
There's only enough fuel left
for one trip to the past and back.
You mean you can't return to your time?
I never intended to.
Changing the world line
here will change the future,
so I won't need to go back.
It's just...
If we don't change things,
then I'll be stuck here for good...
...living a life of regret.
That's nonsense.
Uncle...
Don't call me that.
I am Hououin Kyouma.
A mad scientist...
...and the destroyer of
this world's ruling structure.
Failure is out of the question.
Okay. I believe in you.
We will now set Operation Skuld into motion!
The time has come!
For you, the assertion of
life and its meaningless proof
are so comical they don't
even help pass the boredom
Those of a foolish race,
acting as if they ruled over all,
presented a conceited, childish theorem
"Infinite" love and the far reaches of the sky
are part of a hypothetical
freedom we've been shown
"Finite" is the merciless march of time,
leading to a choice to deny even tomorrow
Hacking to the Gate
The countless brilliant days
and promises made to my friends...
I must not "undo" any of it
So I'll use what tricks I have left to deceive time,
as a lone observer who no longer has doubt
Where is it?!
I know I put it around here somewhere...
"The time has come!" you exclaim!
But then you shamble back to the
lab because you forgot something...
Hurry up.
We can't leave the time
machine up there for too long.
I think this is...
The Glow Stick Saber?
What are you gonna do with that?
The fake blood planted
in the tip is what I need.
Huh?! I didn't know it had that...
I see. That's going to serve
as Makise Kurisu's "blood," huh?
Indeed.
If the July 28th version of me finds
her unconscious in a pool of fake blood,
the established past will remain unchanged.
That's what Operation Skuld is about.
Well, your idea is sound, but...
Doesn't that seem too simplistic?
It felt like the future Okarin
was talking about
something way more enigmatic...
Hououin Kyouma is the type
to exaggerate about a plan
the more simplistic it is.
Fool.
I already see through your ways!
I don't know whether to be impressed or not...
Sadface.
Say, Okarin.
Did Kurisu-san used to sit here with you?
Mayuri...
She'd always talk a lot with Daru-kun...
I never understood her,
but she would talk so excitedly...
She and you would argue all the time,
but I could tell you were good friends...
What are you talking about, Mayushii?
Makise Kurisu is a scientific genius.
She'd never come to a lab like this.
You're right. That'd be strange.
Maybe I just dreamed it...
Could it be she has the Reading Steiner too?
No, there's no such ability.
But... some part inside remembers
what's happened in other world lines...
Everyone remembers, somewhere deep down...
Kurisu did everything she could to save Mayuri.
It's because of Kurisu that
Mayuri--no, that we're--here now.
Huh?
Say, Okarin.
Do you like Kurisu-san?
Christina is my assistant...
...a dear friend...
...and someone special to me.
Ah!
And she's also in love with me.
No way! This is so real-life...
Then you definitely have
to save her. No matter what.
You have to save her!
Yeah...
Promise you'll come
back, okay? With Kurisu-san...
But of course.
U-Umm...
Miss Amane...
If you really are my daughter...
...then who's my wife?
I'll leave that a secret.
Again?
Let's go!
I've brought us to the
exact same time as before.
The rest is up to you.
I know.
Leave the Glow Stick Saber at the spot for me.
No problem.
Changing the outcome without
altering the established past...
The first order of business...
...is this.
I don't know how it connects to all this.
But if I get the Metal Oopa now,
it'll reduce the chance of
metal getting into that envelope.
Just as I thought.
There aren't many in this series left,
but Mayushii's out of 100-yen coins...
Don't act so spoiled, Mayuri.
Even if we are childhood friends,
I'm not lending you money.
Aww...
Allow me to show you
the harsh realities of life.
It's an Oopa!
Is it rare?
No, but it's really cute, don't you think?
Okay. Next up...!
Oh, pardon me--
K-Kurisu...
Huh? How do you know my name?
Have we met before?
Kurisu...
Are you even listening--
What's your problem?!
Answer my question!
I'm...
I'm here... to save you.
Dr. Nakabachi's conference is
about to begin in the 8th floor hall.
Wait! Stop!
I never thought I'd have
to pretend to be myself...
So Kurisu picked up the
Oopa after Mayuri dropped it...!
But since this one isn't metal,
Nakabachi's envelope should
burn up in the airplane accident now.
Now I just need to drive Nakabachi away
and find a chance to knock Kurisu out...
The fake blood's dried up?!
I see...
It was left unused for so long
that the air exposure solidified it...
--What do you want?
--Umm, I'd like you to read...
--Think... Think!
There's gotta be something!
Something...!
Think.
Getting rid of Nakabachi
should be easy enough.
The problem is the blood.
I just need something
else that looks like blood!
Be quiet!
How dare you call me a thief...!
That's it!
Stop it!
Who the hell are you?!
I am the seeker of chaos, the destroyer
of this world's ruling structure...
...and...
...the shatterer of your ambitions!
Do you wish to hear it?
My name is...
...Hououin...
...Kyouma!
What nonsense is this?
You're that kid...!
I see. So that's how it is...
The two of you conspired
to ruin my press conference.
Now I see. So that's how it is...
Daddy...!
--Run!
--I refuse!
What's wrong? What's the knife for?
Wh-What?!
Just acting tough?
Afraid of my god-like power, are you?
L-Like hell I am!
What's the matter?!
You're shaking. Are you scared?
How long are you going to mock me?!
In the end, you're just a pathetic little man.
If you can't even appreciate
your own daughter's abilities...
...then you could never kill me!
Never...!
Never!
N-No...
N-No... This can't be...
Th-That'll teach you...!
--Stay calm... Just a little more...
--Th-That's what you get for mocking me...
H-How dare you...
I'll kill...
I'll kill you...!
I'll get you for this!
D-Don't move!
L-Lie down! I'll call an ambulance!
Hello?! Emergency services?!
Come right away!
--Someone's been stabbed!
--I...
...told you...
...I would...
...save you...!
This is...
...without a doubt...
...the Kurisu I saw.
Uncle...
Goodbye...
--Wait...
--Huh?
Just hold on a minute...
This is no time for that!
If we don't hurry, you'll...!
Please...
Hey.
Is someone there...?
Good luck.
You're about to begin...
...the longest and most important...
...three weeks of your life.
That was too reckless!
Just how stupid are you?!
What do you mean, stupid?
The plan worked, didn't it...?
I've only superficially stopped the bleeding.
Go straight to the hospital when you get back.
It'll be tough, but stay strong.
Here we go!
Is this...?
Steins Gate is a world line unknown to all.
Suzuha...
But if your theory is correct,
that paper will burn up,
the time machine development
race will never happen,
and World War III will never take place.
I can't stay with you.
So I'll thank you while I can.
Thanks.
See you again, in seven years...
Okarin!
Huh?
That paper on time machines
was the key to mankind's future!
But it burned up!
His comments are incoherent,
and the Russian government
is poised to deny his defection--
Ruka-kun! Okarin was here?!
I must've just missed him...
Oh, when he was here...
It identifies you as Lab Member 006.
Huh? When did I become a lab member?
Perhaps those memories
reside in a previous life.
Oh?
I wonder what these letters are...
Kyouma?
He was just here, meow!
He was?
Did he give you anything, Faris-chan?
Actually...
It's a badge for Lab Member 007.
If you ever need help, hold it tight
and chant, "La Yoda Stasella!"
Oh...
Huh? If you're lookin'
for Okabe, he was just here.
Big Sis Mayuri!
Too-too-roo, Nae-chan!
--And...?
--Ah!
This is our new part-timer as of today!
I'm Kiryu Moeka...
She helped Nae after she took a spill.
She said she didn't have a job,
so I brought her on board.
I'm Shiina Mayuri!
She sure is popular.
Ol' Okabe started hitting
on her as soon as they met...
Visit our lab anytime you want.
Umm...
Thank you...
Too-too-roo!
Welcome back-arin!
Did you combine "Welcome back" and "Okarin"?
Yeah!
Where's Okarin?
Oh, he went to buy some things.
Oh...
Oh!
These? He says they're lab member badges.
Lab Member 002 and 003!
When did we gain so many members, though?
He said they go all the way up to 008...
There's "O" for Okarin...
Shiina, Hashida, Urushibara, Faris...
Huh? What do M, K, and A stand for?
Beats me.
He also put one in a box.
Lab Member 008 will
appear seven years from now.
More of your delusions?
It's an inevitability. For you.
Me...?
Seven years from now...
I can't wait! I wonder
what that person will be like!
I can't even imagine that far ahead...
I don't think the lab will ever change, though.
No matter how much time passes...
Where are you now?
Are you working on a paper at
an American research institute?
Are you pulling an all-nighter on
an experiment to test an idea of yours?
Maybe you're still troubled by
what happened with your father.
You have no memory of the
three weeks you spent with me.
But that's okay.
Somewhere out there
you're breathing, speaking,
thinking hard about something...
That's all that matters.
Because somewhere out there
you're looking at the same world I am...
...this world with an unknown future.
I... finally found you...
I've been looking everywhere for you.
I wanted to thank you for saving me...
It's me.
What is she doing here?
What? You want me to protect her?
Sheesh. Talk about an indulgent order.
But no matter.
If that's its choice...
El Psy Congroo.
"Elp Sy"...?
We meet again, Christina!
I told you, I'm not
"Christina" or your assistant!
Huh?
Welcome, assistant of mine...
...Makise Kurisu.
No, Christina.
No one knows what the future holds.
That's precisely why, just as
this reunion demonstrates...
...the possibilities are infinite.
This is the choice of Steins Gate.